<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442851356089608</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/sport/crows-doing-everything-to-keep-lever-mcgovern-says-chief-executive-andrew-fagan/news-story/960146df21cd6568aeadecff7c15988f</url>
  <title>Crows doing 'all they can' to keep Lever, McGovern</title>
  <content>
OFF-CONTRACT star Crows defender Jake Lever meeting Melbourne officials and exploring options is to "be expected", Adelaide boss Andrew Fagan says.
However, Fagan insists the club has done everything it can to retain key defender Lever and fellow young gun Mitch McGovern.
Melbourne coach Simon Goodwin threatens to lose favourite Crows' son status if he poaches Lever. Fagan has no issue with Lever meeting with the Demons to discuss his future despite knee deep in Adelaide's quest to end a 20-year premiership drought.
"I don't get concerned by those reports and whether Jake has or hasn't is irrelevant. We assume that people will go through a really thorough decision making process, engage with their partner, families, manager and other football clubs and us as a football club," Fagan said.
"He will go through the process as he needs to and the discussions have been ongoing."
Fagan has revealed the club will leave McGovern, 22, and Lever, 21, to decide whether to re-sign or return to home towns Perth and Melbourne where clubs are queuing up with long-term, big-dollar deals.

AFL: Travis Boak & Taylor Walker ahead of Showdown 43.

Travis Boak & Taylor Walker ahead of Showdown 43
"I know it is tough for the fans and empathise with them. They almost need to put that aside and know the club is doing all it can," said Fagan, with speculation regarding Lever and McGovern's contract intentions threatening to prove a distraction in September.
"The players are going through the process they are going through and make a decision when they are ready to make it."
Half forward Charlie Cameron covets reuniting with family in Brisbane. Forward McGovern is understood to be the subject of a five-season, annual $750,000 bid by Fremantle.
Lever has met with Melbourne but also has Collingwood, Hawthorn and Western Bulldogs linked in a hunt for his services with an asking price of $800,000 per season.
Fagan noted premiership favourite Adelaide's list management had delivered top spot with three games remaining in the minor round. Justin Reid's football department will work overtime to bed down McGovern, Lever and Charlie Cameron.
"They can be rest assured we are doing everything possible to maintain our list. It is a list that currently has the team on top of the ladder and that's served us pretty well," said Fagan.
Adelaide is sensitive to losing gun types with Patrick Dangerfield, Jack Gunston, Phil Davis and Kurt Tippett flying the nest over the past five years.
Fagan criticised the media for reporting unsubstantiated facts, figures and news regarding the futures of Adelaide's off contract young guns.
"What I don't get concerned about are the reports that it in the media. Even in the same network we have differing opinions from so called experts who apparently know what is going on," Fagan said.
"A lot of what they (fans) here is inaccurate in terms of numbers and figures. We can listen to a radio network or listen to a TV and there will be a range of numbers in terms of players ad meetings that may or may not be truthful."
Adelaide's 84 point Showdown win on Sunday was marred by an arena invasion but Fagan said the venue was the envy of the nation for Crows home matches.
"We, 11 times a year, have 50,000 people which is an extraordinary experience. You can't legislate against one idiot," Fagan said.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurt Tippett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CROWS</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fagan</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlie Cameron</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taylor Walker</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Demons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch McGovern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake Lever</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lever, 21</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Dangerfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin Reid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Fagan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGovern</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide's 84</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Travis Boak</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fremantle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phil Davis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon Goodwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Gunston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Showdown 43</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
