<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442636607721961</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/real-estate/queensland/construction-juggernaut-almost-unstoppable-as-home-demand-lifts/news-story/0126ceb9c1165f2cb044083a891db659</url>
  <title>Construction juggernaut almost unstoppable as home demand lifts - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
File photo of sub contractor William Freier working on building a new house in Smithfield, Cairns where about 25 houses were being built last year. Picture: Justin Brierty

AUSTRALIA'S construction juggernaut is showing no signs of slowing down, hitting its strongest pace in over a decade as increased stamp duty concessions for first homebuyers take hold.
Despite talk of home building slowing in some parts of the country including Queensland, the latest Australian Industry Group/ Housing Industry Association Australian Performance of Construction Index (Australian PCI) jumped 4.5 points to 60.5 points in July.
That was "the strongest pace of overall industry growth since the survey's inception in September 2005," the Australian PCI report said.
House building and commercial construction were the major drivers, it said.

Stamp duty reductions which came into effect in NSW and Victoria from July 1 led to an increase in first homebuyer activity.

"House builders reported a high degree of support from ongoing projects while some businesses indicated that stamp duty reductions (which came into effect in NSW and Victoria from 1 July) had led to an increase in first homebuyer activity."
Any reading above 50 points was considered a sign of expansion "with higher numbers indicating a faster pace of expansion".
"The rate of expansion in commercial construction lifted to its highest level in 12 years amid an increase in the number of projects entering the work pipeline.
"House building recorded its fastest pace of growth in three and a half years on the back of a solid backlog of work and ongoing strength in demand."
Engineering construction was also "more robust" while the apartment building sector was back to seeing "modest growth after contracting in June" with new orders especially lifting.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian PCI</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>William Freier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Housing Industry Association Australian Performance of Construction</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smithfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin Brierty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 2005</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Industry Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
