<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442859946024325</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-07/cats-turn-to-dogs-surgeon-to-save-selwoods-season</url>
  <title>Cats turn to Dog's surgeon to save Selwood's season</title>
  <content>
Joel Selwood remains confident he can play finals after ankle surgery

THE SURGEON who saved Tom Liberatore's 2016 season will operate on Geelong captain Joel Selwood as the Cats bid to get their star midfielder back in time for finals. 

Dr David Young was the surgeon who operated on Liberatore following round 19 last season, performing a rarely used operation that saw him return in time for the Bulldogs' elimination final 41 days later. 

The same syndesmosis injury finished Carlton captain Marc Murphy's season after round 12 last year and there has been scepticism that Selwood would be able to return in time for finals, as the Cats hope.

Like the Bulldogs, who had Liberatore's surgery performed the day after his injury, Geelong has acted fast and .

Geelong's decision to operate on Selwood with the aim of getting him back after just three missed matches and after the pre-finals bye came after consultation with specialists in the field. 

The operation performed on Liberatore involved inserting a piece of surgical string into the ankle to hold the tibia and fibula bones in the ankle together, allowing them to heal.

"Obviously I didn't get the scan results I was hoping for on the weekend," Selwood said on the Cats' website.

"The ankle was actually feeling not too bad on Saturday but after catching up with the specialist we decided we'll have surgery.

"It's as simple as a tighten-up of the ankle so I'll go and have that done and miss the remainder of the home-and-away season but be ready for what's next after that."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Liberatore's 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr David Young</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joel Selwood</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marc Murphy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Selwood</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberatore</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldogs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
