<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442731097003877</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Coffs Coast Advocate</source>
  <url>http://www.coffscoastadvocate.com.au/news/forward-battle-key-for-storm-bromwich/3209635/</url>
  <title>Forward battle key for Storm: Bromwich</title>
  <content>
MELBOURNE Storm enforcer Jesse Bromwich says the forward pack must match Sydney Roosters for aggression in Saturday's top-of-the-table blockbuster at AAMI Park. 
Storm could go a long way towards securing the minor premiership with a win over the Roosters, one of three NRL rivals two games behind the ladder leader with four rounds to play.
"I think our forward battle is going to be crucial to getting the two points on the weekend, obviously the Roosters have been going along well this year but they had a slip up last week and I just think it makes it a tougher game this week," Bromwich said. 
"I just think they'll be more fired up, coming off a loss you're always a bit fired up the next week so going into that game you put a little bit more effort into it.
"It's a top-of-the-table clash as well so they're going to come down here trying to prove themselves and we still got to prove ourselves as well."
Roosters firebrands Jared Waerea-Hargreaves and Dylan Napa will take a world of stopping in the middle, but Bromwich is confident the Storm pack can ruffle a few feathers. 
"It was a good battle last week (against North Queensland), I thought our boys that came off the bench did a tremendous job, they played really well and I think they can take a lot of confidence out of that," Bromwich said.
"The Roosters have got a big aggressive pack and they've got a big job this week. 
"For us it's about trying to match them with that (aggression), work as a pack and work as a team, I think that's our strength, we're using each other really well this year."
Storm playmaker Cameron Munster (ankle) could return this week, along with utility Tohu Harris (shoulder).
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jared Waerea-Hargreaves</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAMI Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron Munster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bromwich</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roosters</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Storm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Roosters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jesse Bromwich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dylan Napa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tohu Harris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
