<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442340254974860</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/messenger/east-hills/film-tributes-to-our-canine-friends-in-inaugural-festival/news-story/0b5d9c0ab7e49491f78245cead6f62db</url>
  <title>Top Dog tales on the big screen</title>
  <content>
THE old saying goes every dog has its day and, at the Capri Theatre, that is not too far away.
The Goodwood Rd theatre will host the inaugural Top Dog Film Festival this month to celebrate the bond between man and his best friend.
There will be two hours of short movies about dog-powered sports, the first canine sent in to space and then unconditional love between pooches and their owners.
Adventure Reels director Jemima Robinson, who is behind the national event, saw movie Dog Power, about the world's fastest sled dogs, in Canada, and wanted to bring it to Australian audiences.
She found a further seven films about dogs to show how committed people were to their pets.
"Anyone who has ever had a dog or loved a dog will really enjoy the films," Robinson says.
"While all the films talk about different aspects of dogs, the overriding thing about all the films is the positive impact dogs have on people's lives.
"They bring out the best in people."
Capri volunteer and dog lover Jill Hilbig says her cairn terrier cross Molly "rules her family".
Mrs Hilbig enjoys watching films about dogs because, she says, they show the connection between pets and their owners.
"These types of films show how much dogs respond to you, how clever they are and how faithful they are," Mrs Hilbig, 75, of Belair, says.
The Top Dog Film Festival is at the Capri Theatre, 141 Goodwood Rd, Goodwood, on Wednesday, August 30, 8.30pm-10.30pm. Details: capri.org.au
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goodwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dog Power</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canada</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jill Hilbig</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goodwood Rd</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Hilbig</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jemima Robinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Top Dog Film Festival</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Capri Theatre</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 30, 8.30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Molly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Hilbig, 75, of Belair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
