<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442851356089557</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/real-estate/be-cautious-about-retail-landlords-citi-says-20170807-gxqpgg</url>
  <title>Be cautious about retail landlords, Citi says</title>
  <content>
Listed retail landlords may deliver less rosy earnings outlooks this results season than many in the market expect, according to Citi.
Citi's own forecast for 2018 earnings growth for Australia's major mall owners is 3.5 per cent, significantly less than the market consensus of 5 per cent.
"Aside from more challenging leasing conditions, retail landlords could face cost pressures from increasing electricity prices," analysts Adrian Dark, David Lloyd and Suraj Nebhani wrote in a client note this week.
"The degree and timing of impact will vary, with some of the increase in prices likely mitigated by higher recoveries from tenants, but it does represent a drag.

"Higher electricity costs could also weigh on consumer spending. Consensus forecasts do not appear to reflect these headwinds."

Over the past six months Australia's major retail landlords, including Vicinity Centres, Scentre Group and Westfield,  spooked by the potential impact of online shopping.
Other retail landlords include Charter Hall Retail REIT, Shopping Centres Australasia and BWP Trust, which has a portfolio occupied mostly by Bunnings Warehouse stores.
The, which has signede for its first fulfilment centre, has fuelled those fears.
Some analysts, including CLSA, and representing a buying opportunity.

As scrutiny and concern over mall landlords intensifies, analysts will be focusing closely on their outlook statements and guidance for the coming year.
"Any weakness in either outlook commentary or guidance could drive negative revisions and share price reactions," the Citi team wrote.
BWP Trust, , saw its stock fall by around 2 per cent after its result, even though the landlord had reported above-consensus earnings for fiscal 2017.
However, its 2018 guidance commentary was cautious, given leasing uncertainties, Citi analysts wrote.

Diversified investor and fund manager GPT could buck the retail landlords' trend, according to Citi, with upside in its fiscal 2017 earnings and fiscal 2018 consensus forecast.
Last week, GPT's unlisted Shopping Centre Fund to buy up the 25 per cent in Highpoint shopping centre it doesn't already hold in a $680 million deal with its co-owners, the Besen family.
That deal was struck at a premium and  on its balance sheet in the Melbourne mall.
It should drive some accretion in GPT's earnings, which will also get a tailwind from the office market, according to Citi.

The analysts favour Goodman, Stockland and Investa Office Fund and are more cautious on Mirvac and Westfield, which owns Westfield malls abroad.
"We see upside risk for select stocks with more exposure to active earnings streams (funds management, development) and to office (given the strong growth in Sydney office rents)."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adrian Dark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Besen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shopping Centre Fund</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goodman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CLSA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Investa Office Fund</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Lloyd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suraj Nebhani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Highpoint</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Centres Australasia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mirvac</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BWP Trust</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charter Hall Retail REIT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scentre Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vicinity Centres</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stockland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GPT</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bunnings Warehouse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westfield</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Citi</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
