<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442821291318241</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:42</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/real-estate/victoria/south-east/stamp-duty-boost-spurs-firsttimers-in-outer-bayside-suburbs/news-story/a48c3c2fe2b9ffbde83c9442c65bfce8</url>
  <title>Stamp duty boost spurs first-timers in outer bayside suburbs - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
, sold for $660,000 to first-home buyers.

FIRST-home buyers scored wins in Melbourne's southeast as stamp duty savings boosted their numbers at weekend auctions.
A Parkdale unit and a Frankston house were among homes snapped up by first-time buyers, who are gaining ground in the competitive auction market, according to Advantage Property Consulting director Frank Valentic.
"We have seen a definite come back from first-home buyers," Mr Valentic said.
"They are out and about at a lot of auctions. Investors have ducked for cover with changes from banks and laws."
Mr Valentic said a first-home buyer won the keys to the Parkdale villa unit when it sold for $660,000 under the hammer on August 5.

The Parkdale villa unit has an open-plan kitchen, meals and living area.

He said two bidders, both first-home buyers, contested the auction of with the property was declared on the market by Hocking Stuart, Mentone, at $600,000.
"Villas are the jewel of the apartment market," Mr Valentic said. "They offer a bit of land and single level living."
First-home buyers were also out in force further down the bay when a four-bedroom house at , was sold by O'Brien, Chelsea, for $735,000.

, sold for $735,000.

Mr Valentic said the Frankston market was going from strength to strength, having undergone a 30 per cent lift in house prices this year.
"Houses are going up $10,000 a month," he said.
"It's pretty hard for first-home buyers to save that each month for a deposit."
Interestingly, Mr Valentic said Advantage Property Consulting was offered the property at the start of the year for $680,000, but it didn't have a buyer at the time.

Inside the four-bedroom house at 12 Cecil St, Frankston.

He said the auction result meant the house had grown $55,000 in value in six months.
"The market is moving like a freight train," Mr Valentic said.
"I would encourage first-home buyers to push themselves because it's not going to get any cheaper."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Villa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parkdale</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frankston</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chelsea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>O'Brien</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Advantage Property Consulting</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cecil St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Valentic</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mentone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hocking Stuart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frank Valentic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
