<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442597953015945</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/worst-albums-of-all-time-according-to-critics-2017-8</url>
  <title>The 19 worst albums of all time, according to critics</title>
  <content>
While many are keen to cover their ears when bad music comes on, there exists another group who can approach steaming hot garbage openly, with varying degrees of ironic appreciation.

And then there's that unfortunate, outlying enigma - genuine fans of Limp Bizkit.

With the latter two groups in mind, we turned to review aggregator  to compile this list of the most critically panned albums in history. (Note: The list only includes studio albums with seven or more reviews.)

From the works of Kevin Federline to Limp Bizkit, to multiple entries from Chris Brown, these LPs drew the ire of critics and provoked the repulsion of many.

Here are the 19 worst albums of all time, according to critics:

Maverick

40/100

User score: 2.2/10

What critics said: 'On his new disc the veteran of populist trance shows himself unable to come up with anything remotely innovative or engaging, even for the dance floor.' --

Maverick

40/100

User score: 5.9/10

What critics said: 'Like Mike Oldfield's 'Tubular Bells II' and Meat Loaf's 'Back Into Hell,' it doesn't so much play as fall out of the speakers with a flump: the sound of a towel being thrown in.' --

Warner Bros.

39/100

User score: 1.8/10

What critics said: 'There is Michael Jackson bad, there is Ed Wood bad, and then there is BAYTL, a union so unholy that it cries out for a show on Bravo.' --

Cash Money Records

37/100

User score: 3.0/10

What critics said: 'The songs might have been better as parodies than as imitations, although 'Knockout' -- a Coldplay homage backing a raunchy lyric -- comes close to being both.' --

Interscope

33/100

User score: 4.1/10

What critics said: 'Since the music has no melody, hooks, or energy, all attention is focused on the clown jumping up and down and screaming in front, and long before the record is over, you're left wondering, how the hell did he ever get to put this mess out?' --

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meat Loaf</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warner Bros</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Limp Bizkit</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BAYTL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Jackson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin Federline</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maverick</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Interscope</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bravo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Back Into Hell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tubular Bells II</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ed Wood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coldplay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Money Records</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Like Mike Oldfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
