<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442769751710032</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/comment/why-the-best-age-of-your-entire-life-is--four-years-old-20170807-gxqmjr.html</url>
  <title>Why the best age of your entire life is ... four years old</title>
  <content>
I have been thinking a lot recently about when it is that we lose the desire to move manically, like whirling dervishes and Tasmanian Devils. In part, this is because I spend a lot of time with a four-year-old, telling her to "please, just for a minute, SIT STILL. Sit. Still. S-T-I-L-L. It's not great for Mummy when you wake up in the morning and decide to act as a particularly energetic alarm clock and jump on her for 15 minutes until she gets up, wailing, "I give in, TAKE WHATEVER YOU WANT."
I feel so lethargic in comparison to my daughter, Edie, how much she wants to move, and it's made me wonder if I should stop telling her to sit still; if I should actually be encouraging her to do handstands on the table. Why, in this sedentary, obese world am I trying to get her to move less? Instead, shouldn't I transport myself back 33 years and climb the nearest tree?Photo: Andrew Quilty
I was reminded of this when, in a characteristic moment of laziness, I found myself glued a Channel 4 documentary called Old People's Home for 4-Year-Olds. The premise was simple: a nursery was added to a retirement home, with 10 four-year-olds coexisting happily with 10 pensioners for six weeks, in an experiment to see what happened when the generations mixed. The results were magical.
It was wonderful to watch Hamish, an octogenarian who lost his leg in an accident at the age of 14 and had since led a solitary life with very little contact with children. Within three weeks, he had all but forgotten about his disability and was roaring affectionately at the pre-schoolers in a game of Sleeping Lions.
And as I sat on the sofa taking it all in, I came to the conclusion that the very best age to be a human is four. Three is a fretful time on account of the fact you are still unaware that it is a bad idea to run into roads; by five you're in the system and your parents have got you learning Mandarin during your down-time. But four? Four is perfect. You can have conversations, eat jelly, write your name, count to a reasonable number and ride a bike. You have all the best bits of being an adult, without any of the low self-esteem, the issues, the worries about how you are going to pay the mortgage.
So the next time you find yourself despairing of the world and all the people in it, channel your inner four-year-old instead. Kick off your shoes, dance on the table, demand chocolate ice cream. If what you want from life is more, then for goodness sake, be more four.
Telegraph, London
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>T-I-L-L. It</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian Devils</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sleeping Lions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SIT STILL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Old People's Home</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Telegraph</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Year Olds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TAKE WHATEVER YOU WANT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Quilty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mandarin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
