<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442902895697761</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/wilkshire-ready-to-prove-hes-still-got-it/3209650/</url>
  <title>Wilkshire ready to prove he's still got it</title>
  <content>
FOOTBALL: Sydney FC's new signing, Luke Wilkshire, says he won't take any risks in building up his fitness for the new season, despite coming through exhaustive testing before joining the club.

Wilkshire trained for the first time with the champions on Monday after signing as an injury-replacement for Rhyan Grant, determined to prove that at 35 he can show Australian audiences that his career is not yet over.

The former Socceroo spent last season at Russian clubs Akhmat Grozny and Dinamo Moscow, though he made only six appearances. But having spent four days establishing his fitness with coach Graham Arnold before signing a one-year deal, Wilkshire said he was prepared to take his time acclimatising.

"I'll talk to Arnie but I've had a couple of good sessions already," Wilkshire said.

"We'll build it up slowly, there's plenty of time to get 100%. Touch wood, fitness has never been a problem for me. I'm clearly not at my peak at the moment but I got through (the testing) ok.

"It's strange to hear everyone speaking English, and to be able to understand the coach. But I know a few of the guys from playing with and against them. Everyone speaks about the A-League improving and it has over the years.

"Sydney won the league convincingly last year, and the challenge for me and the team to go back to back is an exciting one. I'm here to help Sydney win the league and have a good run in the Asian Champions League."

With 80 caps for his country, Wilkshire said the opportunity to work with former national team boss Arnold had been a significant factor in rejecting offers elsewhere in Russia in order to play in Australia for the first time in his career.

"With Arnie you know what you'll get," he said.

"He's straight - you can enjoy your football, enjoy your time around, and if you work and do things in the right way you know where you stand."

Night of crashes rounds out weekend of heartbreak on Coast roads
BREAKING: New festival coming to the Sunshine Coast
Major crime spike hits local residents and businesses in small town
Coast's vulnerable better off amid plans to build affordable rentals
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
New celebrity cooking show fails to fire for Seven.
The legendary creator isn't so sure about how Netflix works.
*WARNING this story contains spoilers*
TARA Reid reveals what's coming in the next installment of TV movie.
Farmer's brave decision has cost him the game.
"It didn't seem like they were having a crazy, big night."
Garth Prowd's vision made huge impact on Sunshine Coast community
Home sells in just one day
Winners in Master Builders regional housing and construction awards
Ray and Gert will celebrate 70 years of marrive this week
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garth Prowd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rhyan Grant</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graham Arnold</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dinamo Moscow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tara Reid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arnold</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney FC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asian Champions League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Socceroos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Akhmat Grozny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arnie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Wilkshire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wilkshire</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
