<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442718212101825</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:18</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-07/classocist-mary-beard-speaks-out-about-abuse-of-twitter-after-h/8780634</url>
  <title>Mary Beard: Historian targeted by Twitter trolls in row over race in Roman Britain</title>
  <content>
A debate about ethnic diversity in the Roman Empire boiled over into a bitter dispute which saw classical scholar, author and TV presenter Mary Beard subjected to days of "nasty" attacks on social media.

External Link:

@PrisonPlanet: Thank God the BBC is portraying Roman Britain as ethnically diverse.  I mean, who cares about historical accuracy, right?
It all started with a seemingly harmless BBC cartoon intended to depict a family in Roman Britain.
Alt-right commentator Paul Joseph Watson posted the cartoon and questioned its historical accuracy.
"Thank God the BBC is portraying Roman Britain as ethnically diverse. I mean, who cares about historical accuracy, right?" Mr Watson wrote.
Professor Beard, an expert on Roman history, and others including historian Mike Stuchbery, piped up to say they believed the depiction to be relatively accurate.
Professor Beard cited the case of Quintus Lollius Urbicus, who was born in what is now Algeria and went on to become governor of Britain.
It was then that a barrage of abuse followed, Professor Beard said in a blog post titled .
She said she had been the target of a "torrent of aggressive insults, on everything from my historical competence and elitist ivory tower viewpoint to my age, shape and gender (batty old broad, obese, etc etc)".

External Link:

I wonder how far this "batty old bird" stuff will go
"The cumulative effect was just nasty."

External Link:

@NassimNicholasTaleb: Historians believe their own BS. Where did the subsaharan genes evaporate? NorthAfricans were lightskinned.  Only "Aethiopians", even then
Professor Beard said she had reported some tweets but would not block people on social media.
"It doesn't stop them tweeting, it only means that you don't see it, and it feels to me like leaving the bullies in charge of the playground."
"It's rather too much like what women have been advised to do for centuries. Don't answer back, and just turn away."
Some of the strongest criticisms aimed at Professor Beard came from essayist Nassim Nicholas Taleb who also went beyond Twitter and its 140 character restriction to unpack his perspective on the debate, in a post titled .
Professor Beard said the insults were balanced out by support from others.
"It also feels very sad to me that we cannot have a reasonable discussion on such a topic as the cultural ethnic composition of Roman Britain without resorting to unnecessary insult, abuse, misogyny and language of war not debate (and that includes one senior academic)," she wrote.
"It's a bit of a bleak outlook for how we might talk about modern ethnic diversity."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BBC</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Algeria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Joseph Watson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NorthAfricans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alt Right</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roman Empire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NassimNicholasTaleb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Watson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roman Britain</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mary Beard</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aethiopians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Romans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nassim Nicholas Taleb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thank God</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quintus Lollius Urbicus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PrisonPlanet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>God</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Beard</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mike Stuchbery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
