<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442894305763045</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-07/door-knocking-public-transport-conversationalists-tender-in-sa/8781578</url>
  <title>Tender for doorknocking public transport 'conversationalists' ahead of SA election</title>
  <content>
Thousands of Adelaide households can expect a doorknock from a Transport Department official in the lead up to next year's state election.
South Australia's Liberal Opposition has uncovered tender documents outlining plans for 15 so-called "conversationalists" to visit 18,000 homes to discuss their car use.
The Opposition's Corey Wingard said it appeared taxpayers would foot the bill for work that ought to be carried out by politicians.
"If it's not TV ads, radio ads or newspaper ads, now they have consultant conversationalists," he said.
"It's farcical. It's a joke of a way to spend South Australian taxpayer money, and it's incomprehensible they're doing it just before a state election."
The tender calls for 15 workers to make household visits, and follow-up phone calls, to 18,000 households across 22 weeks beginning in February. Four supervisors would also be recruited.
"The project aims, through holding collaborative conversations with householders, to influence shifts in personal transport behaviour specifically towards a reduction in car use and car reliance," it stated.
"The primary outcome of this project is to ensure safer, greener, more active travel."
But Mr Wingard estimated the doorknocking project would cost hundreds of thousands of dollars, with the real intention of promoting Labor's transport policies.
"Don't go and use thousands and thousands of taxpayer dollars to get people to go out and do your work for you," he said.
In 2015, the Government said there were 66 million trips on Adelaide Metro buses, trams and trains.
The most recent figures from the Federal Government's Bureau of Infrastructure, Transport and Regional Economics showed just 6 per cent of journeys in Adelaide were made via mass transit, compared to 14 per cent in Sydney and 10.8 per cent in Melbourne.
A response has been sought from Transport Minister Stephen Mullighan.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Metro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Transport Minister Stephen Mullighan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Transport Department</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Wingard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia's Liberal Opposition</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Government's Bureau of Infrastructure</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Regional Economics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Opposition's Corey Wingard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
