<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442464809028252</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/sport/i-think-billy-longer-got-on-top-drew-petries-honest-selfassessment-after-west-coasts-loss-to-st-kilda/news-story/90f9811074ce70fd8ec37c1bed6046a1</url>
  <title>"I think Billy Longer got on top"</title>
  <content>
A CANDID Drew Petrie put his hand up to shoulder a large portion of the blame for West Coast's eight-point defeat to St Kilda at Etihad Stadium yesterday after lowering his colours to opposite number Billy Longer.
Petrie has been asked to lead the Eagles' ruck division over the past two weeks, despite making a name for himself predominantly as a key forward during his 316 games at North Melbourne.
The 34-year-old earnt AFL Coaches' Association player of the year votes for his performance against Stefan Martin in West Coast's home win over Brisbane in round 19.
But he was well beaten in the aerial battle by Longer.
The Saints ruckman had 51 hit-outs to Petrie's 15, including a 20-5 advantage at centre bounces, and played a pivotal role in the home side's domination at the stoppages in the final quarter of their 15.13 (103) to 14.11 (95) victory.
St Kilda comprehensively won the clearance (15-6) and contested possession (53-22) counts in the fourth term as they finished full of running.
"I think Billy Longer got on top," Petrie said.
"I wasn't as competitive as I was the week before, so I take responsibility for him getting first hand on the ball and being able to feed his midfielders at ground level.
"I think that turned after half-time.
Disappointed Simpson says Priddis will be back

"We were probably OK up until half-time in clearances and contested ball, but in the second half he got his hand to the footy too often and gave his guys first use."
Petrie has been developing his ruck craft under the tutelage of West Coast great Dean Cox since joining the Eagles at the end of last year and took yesterday's performance personally.
"Last week I was alright, this week I feel like s***," Petrie said.
"I like playing in there (the ruck). What I lack in probably hit-outs and feeding our midfielders, I try and make up for in other areas.
"I let the boys down in allowing Billy to get on top. He's a good ruckman, I'm not taking anything away from him.
"He's a big boy, strong lad and threw me around a bit in the second half especially. He started their momentum."
Petrie had 13 disposals and a team-high eight tackles for West Coast.
Eight Eagles had just one tackle each and four - Jack Darling, Luke Partington, Malcolm Karpany and Will Schofield - did not lay a tackle all day.
St Kilda won the overall tackle count 83-51 in a sign of their greater desperation.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Darling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagles</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Petrie's 15</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Cox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Billy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>11</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Partington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Will Schofield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CANDID Drew Petrie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Coaches' Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saints</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stefan Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Billy Longer</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Priddis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simpsons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Karpany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Petrie</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
