<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442679557395534</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/news/townsvilles-best-performing-school-by-naplan/news-story/f2024095ab4721cdef73247e29d877c1</url>
  <title>Townsville's best performing school</title>
  <content>
STUDENTS at Townsville's top-performing school in the National Assessment Program - Literacy and Numeracy test say the key to success is to remain calm before tests.
Townsville Grammar Year 9 student Emily Price said preparation, including practice tests, had helped.
"We did a lot of work on grammar in English classes," she said.
"We revised it and brushed up on the things we learned."
She advised students to think of it as they would any other test.
"Just go in like it's a practice test and you won't feel pressure," she said.
Director of studies Stephen Monk said the school approached NAPLAN tests by ensuring the students had a well-rounded education.
"We don't 'prepare' per se for NAPLAN," he said.
"We continue to work on literacy and numeracy skills and the test takes care of itself."
Mr Monk said students were told a "good night's sleep" was vital.
"There's no point stressing about it because it's not the thing that's going to have a long-term impact on them," he said. "I think for the students, knowing that they just need to come in and give it their best shot takes the anxiety away. But Year 12 is a different story."
Mr Monk said the school had a community approach to learning and a strong culture of success.
"We have kids that are engaged in learning and teachers who enjoy teaching," he said. "We have very good parental support, which the school encourages.
"We try to keep the communication channels very open between the parents and teachers, to keep them on the right track."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAPLAN</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emily Price</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Monk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville Grammar Year 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Assessment Program</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Monks</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Year 12</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
