<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442464809028237</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4837295/stingrays-to-play-eliminator-after-draw/?cs=302</url>
  <title>Stingrays to play eliminator after draw</title>
  <content>
The Illawarra Stingrays will face a sudden death showdown in the opening round of the finals after drawing 2-2 with North Shore Mariners at JJ Kelly Park on the last day of the season.

ONE SHOT: Stingrays star Erica Halloway shoots on the half volley in the club's 2-2 draw with North Shore Mariners at JJ Kelly Park on Sunday afternoon. Picture: ROBERT PEET
The point consigned the Rays to third spot on the competition ladder, which means they'll meet two-time defending premiers Sydney University in an elimination final next weekend.
Illawarra led twice against the Mariners, but couldn't go on with the job to take maximum points.  
Michelle Heyman and Emma Rolston, who missed a penalty in the second half, both got on the scoresheet but had their strikes cancelled out by Madeleine Bart and Tiffany Paterson.

Stingrays coach Brett Wallin felt his team had enough chances to win the match. 

"We only had ourselves to blame. We needed to execute on Sunday and we didn't," he said.
"With that said, we have had a great six or seven weeks and it is what it is now. We have to win that game against Uni."
The venue for Sunday's final is yet to be determined. 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Shore Mariners</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michelle Heyman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ROBERT PEET</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tiffany Paterson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Madeleine Bart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra Stingrays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brett Wallin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JJ Kelly Park</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Erica Halloway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mariners</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emma Rolston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
