<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442550708375121</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/world/2017/08/07/13/10/is-donald-a-one-term-president</url>
  <title>Will Donald Trump be a one-term president?</title>
  <content>
Donald Trump could be a one-term president, if many senior members in his own Republican party get their way.
Unsurprisingly, after such a disastrous start to his presidency, those Republicans are already thinking about a back-up plan.
By the look of it, that could be the 2020 call up for the competent and steady Vice President, Mike Pence.
The bad news of party rumblings, reported in The New York Times, would have been a rude wake-up call for Mr Trump this morning, who just started a 17-day break from the White House at his private golf course in New Jersey.
He explained his long absence from Washington in a tweet: "Working in Bedminster N.J. as long planned construction is being done at the White House. This is not a vacation-meetings and calls!"
Footage has emerged of Mr Trump on his golf course, as well as of him walking up to a newly married couple and posing for photos.
Knowing what Mr Trump's reaction to the speculation would be, Mr Pence quickly issued a statement denying any backrooms deals and calling The New York Times story "disgraceful and offensive".

Related Articles

Soon after, Mr Trump's advisor Kellyanne Conway appeared on a Sunday morning political show and labelled the speculation a "complete fabrication".
"It is absolutely true that the Vice President is getting ready for 2020, but for re-election as vice president," she said.
However, Republican leaders worry about the President's shockingly low approval rating of just 33 per cent - unprecedented for a President so early in his first term.
Respect for the President is at such a low ebb that Newsweek magazine created a harsh front cover judgement of him.
It shows him sitting in a Lazyboy reclining chair, eating junk food and holding a television remote, with the caption "Lazyboy Donald Trump is bored and tired. Imagine how bad he'd feel if he did any work".
In most cases, The New York Times reports, the Republicans interviewed said they were only preparing a case in the event Trump decides not to run in 2020.
But the ever-widening investigation into the Trump campaign's contacts with the Russians is casting uncertainty over his future as President.
Senator John McCain told the Times: "They see weakness in this President. Look, it's not a nice business we're in."
William Kristol, editor at large of the conservative The Weekly Standard is thinking about creating a "Committee Not to Renominate the President".
And then, with Mr Trump there is the "what he says" compared to "what he does".
During the campaign, he continually excoriated former president Barack Obama for taking holidays with his family.
He promised it would be different when he was in charge. But the figures tell another story.
So far as President, he has spent 58 days of his 197 days in the job at Trump-owned golf courses.
So now he's reminded of what he said before he was elected: "I promise you I will not be taking very long vacations, if I take them at all".
"There is no time for vacations," he said.
"If you are at the White House you have so much work to do. Why would you leave so much? You'd think you'd want to work, work, work."
As one host of a political show noted to laughs from the panel: "That guy needs to speak to President Trump".
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newsweek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>William Kristol</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vice President</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lazyboy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bedminster N.J</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mike Pence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator John McCain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Republicans</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kellyanne Conway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Trump</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump-owned</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York Times</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Committee Not</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Weekly Standard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Pence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Jersey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lazyboy Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barack Obama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
