<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442636607721957</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-07/inner-west-council-unveils-street-art-in-fight-against-graffiti/8781188</url>
  <title>Street art a 'perfect match' for Inner West Council's fight against graffiti</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

Brad Gough and Flavia Deoliveira have had to spend many a weekend in the past few years painting over the graffiti and tags sprayed onto the side of their terrace house in Marrickville.
But that will hopefully now change after they signed up to the Inner West Council's Perfect Match initiative.
On the weekend they unveiled four arresting mural portraits painted on the wall by artist Brad Robson.
"This laneway is really dodgy and it was really boring and grey and it gets tagged a lot - we were really sick of painting it," Mr Gough said.
"We really like the mural. We're not quite sure of the vibe of the neighbourhood yet but we're really happy with it."

The artwork, on the corner of Philpott Street and Stevens Lane, is closely tied to the suburb.
The figures in the mural - drag queen Betty Grumble, athlete Annette Kellerman, poet Henry Lawson and fashion designer Akira Isogawa - all lived or worked in Marrickville at some point.
Robson, who likes to be called a muralist, also lives in the suburb.
"I just wanted to bring across the diversity and the culture that Marrickville brings in Sydney, and these are figures that speak volumes of Marrickville," he said.
"Something on the street like this is for the community so it reminds people of what is around here and what we're part of."
'Community dating service' aimed at reducing graffiti

Perfect Match, now in its fourth year, was initiated to tackle problem graffiti.
The council invited property owners to volunteer their properties and paired them with a street artist in the manner of a "community dating service", Victoria Johnstone, the council's arts and cultural development coordinator, said.

At the weekend locals celebrated 16 new artworks across the inner west including Newtown, Stanmore Petersham, St Peters, Dulwich Hill and Sydenham.
Ms Johnstone told  the council gave artists "a good fee" for their work.
"Obviously councils across the country and the world spend a lot of money on graffiti prevention," she said.
"What is gorgeous about this project is it's not just slapping up a beautiful contemporary artwork, it's the sharing of understanding between artist and the community that you develop.
"Each artwork has a special story."

Ms Johnstone said she had received calls from about 10 other councils interested in designing similar projects.
In March the  without need for council approval.
But Robson said using street art as a method for preventing graffiti was "confusing".
"Graffiti, street art, it's all the same thing," he said.
"If you're spending a bit more time on a mural, everyone seems to respect that and I'm sure a lot of graffiti artists do small jobs and bigger works ... so I think we should just respect each other."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marrickville</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newtown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria Johnstone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stevens Lane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stanmore Petersham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philpott Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Annette Kellerman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Peter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Gough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dulwich Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydenham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad Gough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad Robson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Inner West Council's Perfect Match</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Henry Lawson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Akira Isogawa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Johnstone</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Inner West Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flavia Deoliveira</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Betty Grumble</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
