<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442559298309849</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-07/demons-season-over-but-ok-news-on-knee</url>
  <title>Demon's season over, but no ACL rupture</title>
  <content>
Joel Smith's season is over, but he has avoided an ACL rupture

MELBOURNE defender Joel Smith will miss the rest of the season with a leg injury, but he has escaped a 12-month stint on the sidelines with scans revealing no damage to the anterior cruciate ligament in his knee.

The Demons were fearful the young defender may have ruptured his ACL after sustaining a serious injury while playing for the Casey Demons against Sandringham in the VFL on Saturday.

But Demons football manager Josh Mahoney said the injury was not as bad as first thought, with the 21-year-old to be sidelined for between eight to 10 weeks with a crack in his tibia bone.

"Joel Smith landed awkwardly after a marking contest on the weekend playing for Casey and left the ground on a stretcher," Mahoney told the club website.

"Scans today (Monday) have shown a crack in his tibia bone. A decision will be made this week regarding the need for surgery, nevertheless he will not play again this season.

"This injury generally takes approximately eight to 10 weeks to heal and Joel will be fully recovered at the beginning of pre-season."

More to come
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Mahoney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joel Smith</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Demons</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Casey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Casey Demons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sandringham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mahoneys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
