<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442164161313253</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/lifestyle/why-restaurateur-sam-christie-loves-the-thrill-of-the-hunt-20170731-gxmizz</url>
  <title>Forget Google Maps, this restaurateur loves the thrill of getting lost</title>
  <content>
In an age when the internet has taken some of the fun out of tracking down new spots, restaurateur Sam Christie says he likes the "raw" method - getting lost to see what he can find. He answers our Traveller Q&A.
First, business or economy
Business. It has three things I love: champagne, films and room to sleep.
Most frequented destination

Favourite airport
I love little regional airports. There's just something about them. Last year, I enjoyed touching down on the little Greek island of Milos.
If I ran my own airline I would...
Improve the standard of Bloody Marys, then travel the world chasing the sun.

Where would you go with a million frequent flyer points?
Surfing in Central America, followed by a week of eating in New York...
Worst place you've been lost
New Delhi. I got lost on my first day in India. I was wearing a sleeveless T-shirt and a leper was trying to beg money from me. I kept walking away until he finally rubbed his stump on my bare arm. That was enough to make me hand over most of my cash.

Best trip ever
The two months I spent travelling through Mexico in 1993. I just love Mexico. It's a total assault on the senses.
Most memorable overseas dining
The prawn and fish tacos in La Paz, Mexico. They were from a roadside stall, which had a 50-metre queue from 10am to 4pm every day. They had five types of guacamole and maybe 20 salsas.

In the suitcase
If I am coming back from Japan, Japanese whisky and exercise gear that I haven't worn.
First thing you do in a new city
I like to walk the neighbourhood and suss out good coffee, wine shops and my dining options for that night.

How do you make the most of a spare afternoon in a strange city?
Probably a long lunch, followed by some slightly inebriated shopping, maybe a visit to gallery, then a siesta.
Cure for jet lag
If there's a beach, I like to swim and get a dash of sun. Then I try to stare it down until it's time to sleep.
Other travel tips
I am a big fan of packing as lightly as possible. Picking up some new clothes usually happens anyway and the quality and range is better overseas.
What technology do you use?
My Sennheiser headphones are indispensable on long-haul flights; a currency converter app and Google Translate for the late-night menus in izakayas [bars] in Japan.  

Best overseas purchase
My leather jacket from Undercover, which I found at  in Ginza, Tokyo.
Best travel tale
In 1989, I was caught up in a riot and subsequent curfew while staying on Dal Lake near Srinagar in Kashmir. I was on my way to get a bar of chocolate, cigarettes and bottled water when half a brick landed about two meres in front of me. Suddenly, I saw Indian riot police with wicker shields and bamboo poles in the distance and smelled the tear gas. I knew then it was time to wait out the curfew back on my houseboat.
Best thing about travelling
I absolutely love eating, and for me, it's often about the chase, the hunt to find that special place. These days, the internet has slightly ruined this experience. But I always revert to the raw method of getting lost and discovering things. When I do stumble on something, I also like to go back in the sober light of day and check I wasn't just being romantic.
Top travel gripe
I hate going out for breakfast. In general, breakfast is the meal I miss most when travelling.

lifeandleisure@afr.com.au

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mexico</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tokyo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japanese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bloody Marys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Christie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kashmir</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Traveller Q</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>T-shirts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central America</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Google Map</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>India</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dal Lake</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ginza</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Srinagar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Google Translate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sennheiser</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Delhi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Milo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>La Paz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
