<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442383204648607</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:00</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/07/12/45/dad-films-horror-sea-bugs-that-savaged-boys-legs</url>
  <title>Dad films horror 'sea bugs' that savaged boy's legs</title>
  <content>
A teenager has told of his shock at seeing his feet and ankles bleeding profusely after he went for a dip at a Melbourne beach.
Sam Kanizay, 16, felt sore after football on Saturday and decided to soak his legs at Dendy Street Beach in Brighton. Half-an-hour later, he walked out covered in blood.
Warning: Graphic images

His family believe microscopic sea lice were eating the flesh on his legs, but doctors still haven't confirmed what caused the damage.
"By the time I walked across the sand about 20 metres to put my thongs on, I looked down and noticed that I had blood all over my ankles," Sam told 9NEWS.
"I didn't know what to think of it, it was a bit of a shock and a bit of a random thing to see."
Sam said he wasn't aware of any sensation in his legs when he was cooling them off because the water was so cold and he was talking on the phone.

Related Articles

Following the bizarre incident, Sam's father Jarrod Kanizay returned to the beach on Sunday in a search for answers and captured the creatures he said were responsible.
"What is really clear is these little things really love meat," he said of a video, showing the bugs in a tray of water devouring chunks of meat.
"When he got out, he described having sand on his legs, so he went back in the water," his dad Jarrod Kanizay told AAP.
"He went back to his shoes and what he found was blood on his legs.
"They ate through Sam's skin and made it bleed profusely."
Sam said when the blood was washed off it was easier to see the holes.
"It took a while to get all the blood off and it came back pretty quickly," he told 3AW on Monday.
"It sort of looked like hundreds of little pin holes, or pin type bites, distributed all over my ankle and the top of my foot."
They couldn't stem the bleeding and went to hospital, where staff were at a loss to explain what had happened.
"As soon as we wiped them (his legs) down, they kept bleeding," Mr Kanizay said.
"There was a massive pool of blood on the floor (at the hospital).
"No one knows what the creatures are. They've called a number of people, whether it's toxicity experts or marine exerts and other medics around Melbourne at least... (and) yep, no one (knows)."
Sam is still in Sandringham hospital, but is off antibiotics.
"I was hoping to get out of here today but I might have to go to the specialist," he said.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dendy Street Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarrod Kanizay</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Kanizay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brighton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sandringham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Kanizay, 16</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
