<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442937255436648</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/lifestyle/relationships/young-couple-forced-to-pay-for-wedding-reception-that-never-happened/news-story/dcc7f1d34163b0aca07f86f03ec1825a</url>
  <title>Forced to pay twice for cancelled wedding</title>
  <content>
A YOUNG couple has been forced to pay for their wedding reception twice after they cancelled their first venue over a dispute about the quality of the menu.
Tarryn Sohn and Jason Conway had planned to marry at Maison Melbourne, where they hoped to be served a top class menu with cocktails overseen by head chef Jason Peynenborg.

But the couple cancelled their booking when they were served "cold" food, cheap cocktails and no-name brand soft drinks at their wedding tasting.
--------
MORE MELBOURNE STORIES

--------
They managed to find another venue, the Langham Hotel in Southbank, at short notice and had their dream wedding and reception.
But Maison Melbourne took legal action, claiming the couple did not give them enough time to find a new booking and demanded they pay 75 per cent of their planned $16,000 reception.
The dispute was taken to the Victorian Civil and Administrative Tribunal, which ordered Dr Sohn and Mr Conway to pay $12,500 out of pocket for the wedding and a reception they never had.
The pair had signed a booking agreement in February last year to pay Maison a minimum $16,100 for at least 140 guests and $690 for their ceremony.
The Elsternwick venue claims the couple abandoned the contract after learning at the menu tasting last December that the head chef no longer worked there.
Maison took the pair to the Victorian Civil and Administrative Appeal Tribunal in May when they refused to pay a 75 per cent cancellation fee after the venue failed to find an alternate booking.
In a counter claim, the couple, who eventually married elsewhere on their chosen date and now live in Western Australia, sought the return of $4,219 they had already paid since booking the venue.
Dr Sohn, and Mr Conway, a system engineer, claimed Maison had repudiated the contract because it did not intend to fulfil its obligations and had engaged in misleading and deceptive conduct in breach of consumer laws.
The couple claimed the presentation and quality of food served at the tasting was inferior to that photographed on Maison's Facebook page.
In particular, they complained the food was cold, there was no vegetarian main course option and the desserts were chocolate based, to which both Dr Sohn and Mr Conway were allergic or intolerant.
According to court documents, "Ms Sohn argues that as the function did not take place, Maison did not suffer any real loss.
Maison did not incur any of the costs that are associated with catering and hosting a function such a wait staff, bar staff, cleaning up costs, chef, food ingredients and preparation costs, wedding co-ordinator costs, security costs, beverages (alcoholic and non-alcoholic) costs, setting up costs, hire of items, electricity costs, water and sewage costs and bookkeeping costs."
Dr Sohn argued that Maison could have booked another function after they were notified of the cancellation.
The couple alleged they were also misled about the type of cocktails to be provided during canapes, only learning in December that if they wanted more than champagne-based cocktails served in champagne flutes, or branded soft drinks, they would have to supply these at their own expense.
VCAT Member Tania Petranis found Maison may have used the word 'cocktails' loosely, and Dr Sohn's disappointment was understandable, but there was no misrepresentation and no suggestion branded soft drinks would be offered.
Ms Petranis also found that although Maison used Jason Peyenborg's name in advertising and promotions it had not promised he would be present on the night and she accepted that the new cooks were just as competent and highly regarded.
She found the tasting night was arranged for Dr Sohn and five guests to taste food prepared and served at another function that night, and although this food was not to Dr Sohn's taste or requirements, it was made clear to her that she would get to choose her own menu for her wedding.
"Having looked at the photos (taken at the tasting and from Maison's Facebook page) I find it very difficult to tell the quality of the food or see a huge difference between the photos," she said.
She found the contract ended when Dr Sohn's lawyers formally "reconfirmed that the contract was at an end" in an email sent to Maison on January 27.
Ms Petranis ruled the couple had no legitimate reason to abandon the contract and were therefore liable to pay Maison a further $8,298.50 as demanded.
--------
MORE MELBOURNE STORIES

--------

Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maison</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Peynenborg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Sohn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Langham Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tarryn Sohn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 27</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elsternwick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MELBOURNE STORIES</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Conway</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southbank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maison's Facebook</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maison Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Sohn</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Conway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Administrative Appeals Tribunal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Petranis</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Peyenborg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Civil</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VCAT Member Tania Petranis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Administrative Tribunal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
