<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442993090012617</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:22</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/50-vessels-full-of-artistic-expression/3209660/</url>
  <title>50 Vessels full of artistic expression</title>
  <content>
A NATIONAL exhibition of ceramic art has been launched on the Sunshine Coast.
The exhibition, 50 Vessels, celebrates the creative cauldron of the Sunshine Coast and features 50 nationally recognised artists. Nambour's Old Ambulance Station Gallery is hosting the exhibition, which officially opened on Friday, August 4, as an inspiration to local ceramic art enthusiasts.
From highly decorative to sculptural and classic work, large and small, 50 Vessels showcases a range of Australian and global influences including environmental, sustainability and cultural aspects. Exhibitors, including internationally renowned artist Mitsuo Shoji, have joined the special exhibition by invitation only.
Organiser and Suncoast Clayworkers president Jackie Gasson said the display boasted stunning and diverse works from local and national artists.
"Our artists produce works of an international standard," she said.
"We are proud to welcome award winners to our exhibition such as Greg Daly, who has works on display at more than 80 national and international art galleries and museums."
A glazing specialist, Greg has also displayed his creations across more than 200 national and international exhibitions.
Sunshine Coast master potter and sculptor Ted Seacombe, who has contributed to exhibitions in Japan, Europe, the US and Australia and has works featured permanently across 30 collections worldwide, highlights our local talent.
Known for his beautiful crystalline glazes, as well as his pots of cobalt blue and deep crimson, Ted experiments with and is developing a new range of glazes through an innovative approach to firing - some of which are reminiscent of ancient Chinese glazes.
Contemporary ceramic artist, teacher and best-selling author Janet DeBoos will also join the collective, alongside West Australian clay potter Warrick Palmateer and Gold Coast artisan Megan Puls.
Launched in 2000, Suncoast Clayworkers Association is an umbrella organisation that fosters and promotes all forms of claywork.
The collective hosts its biennial conference and convention Spring Fever to inspire and generate new and quality artwork from members and other interested parties, and also sponsors a showcase of national, international and local exhibitors called Ignition.
The 50 Vessels exhibition continues to August 25.
Night of crashes rounds out weekend of heartbreak on Coast roads
BREAKING: New festival coming to the Sunshine Coast
Major crime spike hits local residents and businesses in small town
Coast's vulnerable better off amid plans to build affordable rentals
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
ONE of Hollywood's most adorable couples is over.
New celebrity cooking show fails to fire for Seven.
The legendary creator isn't so sure about how Netflix works.
*WARNING this story contains spoilers*
TARA Reid reveals what's coming in the next installment of TV movie.
Farmer's brave decision has cost him the game.
Garth Prowd's vision made huge impact on Sunshine Coast community
Home sells in just one day
Winners in Master Builders regional housing and construction awards
Ray and Gert will celebrate 70 years of marrive this week
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spring Fever</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suncoast Clayworkers Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garth Prowd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ted Seacombe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Megan Puls</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tara Reid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suncoast Clayworkers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jackie Gasson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ted</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour's Old Ambulance Station Gallery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warrick Palmateer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Daly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitsuo Shoji</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Janet DeBoos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
