<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442980205110353</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/banking-and-finance/financial-services/zipmoney-shares-spike-on-40m-westpac-investment-20170807-gxqs8z</url>
  <title>ZipMoney shares spike on $40m Westpac investment</title>
  <content>
Shares in ASX-listed ZipMoney jumped to a near-nine month high after Westpac said it would pump $40 million into the payments fintech.
The deal will see Westpac invest $40 million upfront to explore using ZipMoney's products and services across its payments network . A further $8 million was granted to Westpac in the form of performance options.
The equity investment from Westpac at $0.81 per share represented a 14.1 percent premium to ZipMoney's share price.
The shares rose 19.7 per cent to 85c - the highest level since last November - after the deal, which represents one of the largest fintech equity investments in Australia.

"Things are changing so quickly: The rise of millennials, increasing competition and customer demands and the question of what comes after credit cards. Fintech and Zip represent a pathway to the future for the major financial players who are looking to stay ahead," said ZipMoney chief executive Larry Diamond in a statement.

"Zip products are a way to access new markets, new sensibilities and new ways of connecting with users. Zip will benefit from Westpac's expertise, its 200-year history and the power of its distribution capability to help fuel our growth."
As part of the deal ZipMoney will get access to Westpac's customer network and expertise.
ZipMoney is a point-of-sale credit provider that offers customers a "buy now, pay later" proposition with an interest-free period, creating an alternative to using a credit card. Founded in June 2013, it floated in September 2015 at 20¢ a share.
The Westpac investment comes just months after At the time this was the largest debt market deal for an Australian fintech.

As part of the strategic relationship with Westpac, ZipMoney will further develop business-to-business products and services for Westpac. It is understood that ZipMoney's emphasis on AI and big data infrastructure was a key factor in this deal
Fintech is an area that Westpac has been increasingly been playing. Australian Financial Review  (or about 79 per cent on a fully diluted basis) in online mortgage broker Uno Home Loans. It has ploughed almost $28 million into the business in the past 20 months as it steadily built up its stake.
Westpac's investment follows record quarterly results for ZipMoney which saw users reach 665,000 and more than $300 million in transaction volume processed on the platform. 
ZipMoney shares had fallen 5.3 per cent since the start of the year by the close of trading on Friday. 

Last year, ZipMoney  which has 350,000 users and is set to benefit from reforms announced in the federal budget relating to open data.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uno Home Loans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX-listed ZipMoney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Larry Diamond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>zipMoney</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westpac</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 2013</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
