<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443023154784128</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/messenger/east-hills/karate-kept-this-vietnam-vet-on-his-feet-after-almost-losing-his-life-to-a-landmine-blast/news-story/f90b7243cdef16c8fdccbd20c6a29860</url>
  <title>Karate kept this Vietnam vet on his feet</title>
  <content>
ED CZERWINSKI was a young soldier fighting for his country in Vietnam in 1970 when he stepped on the landmine that almost ended his life.
"A mine has shrapnel, like a grenade, and it just blows flesh away," Mr Czerwinski, now 70, of Torrens Park, says.
"I was conscious all the way through until the anaesthetist put the needle in and knocked me out in the operating theatre in Vietnam.
"I have wounds all through the back of my legs and where (shrapnel) was pulled out."
The veteran speaks openly about his war-time ordeal, the years of healing he experienced and the role karate has played in his recovery.
His passion for a Japanese style of karate called seishikan started when he was 45 years old and living on a hobby farm on Kangaroo Island. Still struggling to move in the years after the blast, Mr Czerwinski was told to try the martial art, marking the start of his journey to achieving a black belt.
"When I walked in to my first karate class I was virtually staggering ... but within six months I was far more flexible that I had been in years," he says. "If it wasn't for karate I would probably be using walking sticks, so that is what is keeping me mobile."
He started his own martial arts classes - Adelaide Seishikan in Linden Park - about three years ago to share his love of the art with others.
He says his classes are "no Mickey Mouse Club", rather they are intense to make sure fighters refine their technique.

"You acquire skills and you want to pass them on ... I have trained a lot of people to a black belt standard," Mr Czerwinski says.
Student Anton Piotto, 13, encourages others to join his classes to boost self defence skills.
"It's nice to know how to defend yourself and it is fun," Anton, of Linden Park, says.
Adelaide Seishikan is at Linden Park RSL, Beatty St, Linden Park.
Phone Mr Czerwinski on 0438 895 829 for more information.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beatty St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Linden Park</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japanese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anton, of Linden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kangaroo Island</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mickey Mouse Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vietnam</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Torrens Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ED CZERWINSKI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Seishikan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Linden Park RSL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Czerwinski</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anton Piotto, 13</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
