<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442688147330373</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>SBS</source>
  <url>http://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/2017/08/07/three-killed-baja-california-sur-beach-shootout</url>
  <title>Three killed in Baja California Sur beach shootout</title>
  <content>
Three men have been shot dead on a busy beach in Mexico's popular Los Cabos international tourist area where organised crime has surged in recent months.

20 MINS AGO  UPDATED 11 MINS AGO

Prosecutors in Baja California Sur state said tourists sunning themselves on the beach and stunned locals were on hand when the deadly incident jolted Pamilla beach in San Jose del Cabo.

"At the scene three men were found dead from bullet wounds," prosecutors said in a statement. Two other people were wounded and taken to a local hospital.

Witnesses said tourists frantically started scrambling when shots rang out.

"We heard the shots and just ran to get somewhere safe; it was automatic weapons fire," said a tourist from Mexico City who would identify himself only as Jorge, fearing for his own safety.

Authorities evacuated the beach and started investigating, with the Los Cabos Open tennis tournament underway in town.

More than 230 people have been murdered in Los Cabos alone so far this year.

More than 186,000 people have been murdered and another 30,000 have gone missing in Mexico since 2006, when the government deployed the military to fight organized crime.

Experts say the capture of the top drug cartel leaders has spawned numerous independent criminal groups that have moved beyond drug trafficking into robbery, kidnapping and extortion in areas they control.

Related Reading

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Los Cabos</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mexico</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SAN JOSE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UPDATED 11 MINS AGO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jorge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Los Cabos Open</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MINS AGO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pamilla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cabo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MEXICO CITY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baja California Sur</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
