<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442937255436629</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/news/politics/optus-chairman-paul-osullivan-to-build-new-sydney-airport-20170806-gxqknj</url>
  <title>Optus boss Paul O'Sullivan to build new Sydney airport</title>
  <content>
Optus chairman and former chief executive officer Paul O'Sullivan will chair the corporation charged with overseeing the construction and operation of the second Sydney airport, to be built at Badgerys Creek.
Mr O'Sullivan will chair the newly established Western Sydney Airport Corporation (WSA Co), a statutory body required under law to build the airport which the government will then own and operate.
Joining Mr O'Sullivan as directors will be Airservices Australia board member Fiona Balfour, Tim Eddy and aviation infrastructure and airport operations expert Christine Spring.
In a joint statement, Finance Minister Mathias Cormann and Urban Infrastructure Minister Paul Fletcher, who worked under Mr O'Sullivan at Optus before joining Parliament in 2009, said Mr O'Sullivan's experience in developing Optus as a serious rival to Telstra was a factor in his selection.

"Mr O'Sullivan's business leadership expertise makes him highly credentialled to lead the company delivering Western Sydney Airport," they said.

"His deep experience leading an infrastructure business as it established market share against a long established incumbent will be of great value as Western Sydney Airport is planned and constructed before commencing operations by 2026."
The ministers said more directors will be announced in coming months "with a further focus on construction expertise and experience in Western Sydney".
"The board's early priorities will be to recruit its CEO and senior management and to commence procurement of construction activities," the ministers said.
At the May federal budget, the government confirmed it would build, own and operate the airport, with an injection over a decade of $5.3 billion in so-called good debt.

Construction is scheduled to begin in the second half of 2018, in the run-up to the next federal election, with a completion date of 2026.
The government decided to take on the project itself after after the  because it was too risky.
"Sydney Airport's decision not to accept the [Western Sydney Airport notice of intention] on the terms provided is in the best interests of our investors who represent millions of Australians through their superannuation funds," managing director and chief executive of Sydney Airport Kerrie Mather said in an ASX release in early May.
"Despite the opportunities that WSA will present, the risks associated with the development and operation of WSA are considerable and endure for many decades without commensurate returns for our investors."

On Budget night, May 8, Treasurer Scott Morrison said said the project would create 20,000 jobs by the early 2030s and 60,000 over the long term.
Both the markets and the federal government had anticipated SAC would reject the offer, leaving the government had two options - build it itself, or find another private company to construct it.
But the government reasoned that finding a private builder would take a long time and would blow out the construction timeline.
that governments could build such projects cheaper and more effectively, while managing risk. They were ot under as much pressure as a private company to provide quick returns for investors.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Airport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Urban Infrastructure Minister Paul Fletcher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Finance Minister Mathias Cormann</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Telstra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Sydney Airport</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SAC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WSA Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fiona Balfour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr O'Sullivan</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Airport Kerrie Mather</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treasurer Scott Morrison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul O'Sullivan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Sydney Airport Corporation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Airservices Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christine Spring</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Badgerys Creek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Optus</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Eddy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
