<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443027449751528</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/queensland/man-accused-of-filming-children-in-gold-coast-shopping-centre-bathrooms-20170807-gxqwae.html</url>
  <title>Man accused of filming children in Gold Coast shopping centre bathrooms</title>
  <content>
A man has been charged after allegedly taking pictures and video of children in Gold Coast shopping centre bathrooms during the past two weeks.
It will be alleged a man who worked at a business in a Biggera Waters shopping centre followed a 15-year-old boy into the bathroom and photographed him without consent on Sunday.Photo: Chris Hyde
Police said the boy noticed the phone and told his father, who detained the man allegedly responsible until officers arrived.
It will be further alleged detectives from the Gold Coast Child Protection Investigation Unit found videos of two other children on the man's phone, filmed in a Southport shopping centre bathroom on June 26.
A 27-year-old Southport man was charged with indecent treatment of a child under 16, possessing child exploitation material, making child exploitation material and observations or recordings in breach of privacy. 
He was due to appear in Southport Magistrates Court on Monday, while investigations were continuing.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southport</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Hyde</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast Child Protection Investigation Unit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southport Magistrate Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Biggera Waters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
