<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442164161313245</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/real-estate/south-australia/a-bowden-development-endorsed-by-prince-charles-will-set-new-green-standards/news-story/9abc8a94844c85ebe5bbb4a0ea69b92e</url>
  <title>A Bowden development, endorsed by Prince Charles, will set new green standards. - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
Prince Charles raises a shovel while touring the Bowden development site during a tour in 2015. Picture: Tom Huntley

A BOWDEN development launched by Prince Charles is set for completion in October and is expected to set new standards for environmentally friendly building design.
Named The Prince's Terrace Adelaide, it will comprise 12 homes including eight terraces and four flats, and is the only residential development here to be awarded a 6 Star Green Star design rating from the Green Building Council of Australia.
Each home is predicted to use 50 per cent less energy and 50 per cent less portable water than a typical residential home, cutting power bills by an estimated $1000 a year.
In addition, the project waste contractors are aiming for 95 per cent of all waste on site to be recycled.
The development has been two years in the making - it was launched by Prince Charles during his royal tour in 2015.

Artist's impressions of the finished Prince's Terraces

The project has been developed by Defence Housing Australia (DHA), The Prince's Foundation for Building Community, Prince's Charities Australia, and the State Government's Urban Renewal Authority (Renewal SA).
DHA Managing Director Jan Mason said the concept behind the project was to bring the lessons learnt from the successful Prince's Foundation residential projects in the United Kingdom to the Australian market.
"The Prince's Foundation provided the design and design principles for the Prince's Terraces and worked with local architects to develop layout and design that respects the Adelaide climate and lifestyle," she said.
"DHA will retain some of the dwellings and the Prince is kept informed of the progress of the project."
Ms Mason said the project hoped to set a new standard for residential developments across Australia.

Drone images of the almost completed Prince's Terrace

"The bricks used to build the terraces have been recycled from the original Bowden industrial buildings and are more than 100 years old. In addition, there is a strong emphasis on local, low carbon materials, including locally made concrete with a recycled fly ash content and local granite," Ms Mason said.
"The use of foam block, slurry concrete and double glazed windows means the apartments' insulation levels will be more than double that of normal brick.
"The apartments are also being fitted with roof ventilators, wall grills and ceiling fans to reduce airconditioner and heater use (and) the core filling of the walls has fire ash and slag mixed into the concrete to comply with the environmental ratings.
"In addition, waste at the construction site is being sorted into three industrial bins; for general, concrete and steel waste. The steel and concrete is recycled 100 per cent, and overall the site has been recycling 95 per cent of all waste."
All homes will be retained by DHA and are not currently available for retail sales.
"The dwellings will possibly be allocated into our Sales and Leaseback program at a later date which will afford investors an opportunity to own one of the most unique properties in South Australia," Ms Mason said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Renewal SA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bowden</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Charles</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Kingdom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Huntley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DHA Managing Director Jan Mason</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Defence Housing Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Green Building Council of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince's Terraces</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Building Community</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Star Green Star</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Mason</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government's Urban Renewal Authority</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince's Terrace Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince's Charities Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince's Foundation</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DHA</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
