<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443023154784101</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Radio Australia</source>
  <url>http://www.radioaustralia.net.au/international/2017-08-07/iranian-asylum-seeker-dies-on-manus-island-human-rights-groups-call-for-urgent-review/1691826</url>
  <title>Iranian asylum seeker dies on Manus Island, human rights groups call for urgent review</title>
  <content>
Manus Island authorities have confirmed an Iranian asylum seeker has died at the immigration detention centre.

Key points:

An Iranian ayslum seeker dies in the Lorengau township on Manus Island
Amnesty International refugee co-ordinator says the death is "heartbreaking news"
The death comes following days of protests inside the centre

An Immigration Department spokesman said the Government was aware of the death in the Lorengau township.
Police are investigating the incident and have cordoned off the area where the man was found.
The cause of death is not known.
Amnesty International refugee coordinator Graham Thom said the death was "heartbreaking news".
"It is not yet clear if his death was a result of self-harm or violence," he said.
"This death is yet another bleak tragedy to arise out of the ongoing suffering and tensions on Manus Island.
"There must be an independent, impartial, prompt and effective investigation into his death."
Man's death preceded by protests

The death is the sixth to take place in an Australian offshore detention centre since 2014, according to Monash University's .
It comes following days of protests inside the centre, against attempts to force the asylum seekers to move out.
The Asylum Seeker Resource Centre's a Blucher said tensions were increasing at the immigration centre.
"No matter what the circumstances are around today's reported death, Manus is not safe for refugees," she said in a statement.
"We are deeply concerned for the refugees and people seeking asylum who remain on Manus."
The asylum seekers , refusing to leave the compound.
Most of the 700 refugees on the island are refusing to move because they believe they are not safe in the PNG community.
The refugees on Manus Island are being encouraged to move permanently to the town, as the detention centre closes down.

Photo:(Supplied)
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manus Island</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manus</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graham Thom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amnesty International</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immigration Department</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PNG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monash University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lorengau</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blucher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asylum Seeker Resource Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iranian</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
