<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442937255436692</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/entertainment/stage/sydney-stage/one-flew-over-the-cuckoos-nest-review-sport-for-jove-tackle-us-classic-20170806-gxqlof.html</url>
  <title>Why this play, and why now? Those are questions this production seems unable to answer.</title>
  <content>
One Flew Over The Cuckoo's Nest
Reginald Theatre, Seymour Centre, August 5. Until August 19
★★★
Reading around the subject of One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest, I learned that the Oregon State Hospital, used as a location for Milos Foreman's 1975 movie, is now a museum of mental health. Much the same can be said of Dale Wasserman's stage adaptation of the Ken Kesey novel, which predates the screenplay by a dozen years or so.One Flew Over The Cuckoo's NestPhoto: Supplied
That's not to say this Sport for Jove production doesn't hold some interest. Director Kim Hardwick has a fine track record (her recent staging of another American institution-set play , for example) and she has assembled a promising cast.
Anthony Gooley fills the shoes of Kesey's "gamblin' fool" of a hero, Randle P. McMurphy, more than capably. He's completely convincing as the kind of guy whose idea of fun would be to start a fistfight over the Great American Novel in some dockside dive bar.
Former basketball star Wayne McDaniel has the gravitas, stillness and sheer heft required for the role of Chief Bromden and his voice entrances in the pre-recorded voiceovers. Di Smith's neat-as-a-pin Nurse Ratched wields her power with intriguing subtlety.
The supporting players are good, too, led by Tony Poli (Harding, the ward's honorary president), Travis Jeffrey (the broken, innocent Billy Bibbit), Wendy Strehlow (Cheswick) and Laurence Coy as the bomb-happy Scanlon.

Isabel Hudson's design is strong, raising the level of the stage, tilting the floor slightly, and backing the scene with thick, semi-translucent polythene sheets. Sound design and scoring (Steve Francis) and lighting (Martin Kinnane) serve the play well.
But why this play, and why now? Those are questions this production seems unable to answer. Nor is it able effectively to query the construction of a world populated by variously emasculated men, punishing mother figures, and dizzy good-time girls typified by McMurphy's squeeze Candy Starr (Bishanyia Vincent).
Depicting mental illness in a way that is theatrically appealing as well as credible is always problematic and so it is here. But Hardwick partly solves the problem by demanding restraint from her performers, which spares us the default repertoire of tics and twitches. One fly in the ointment is the miscasting of Johann Walraven as Dr Spivey. His caricature of an addled shrink is too loose-fitting to be effective.
More troubling still is the play's climax, which is stepped through somewhat mechanically and falls well short of the howl of pyrrhic triumph for which Wasserman was presumably aiming.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hardwick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Milos Foreman's 1975</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Poli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wasserman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kim Hardwick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>One Flew Over</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Di Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cheswick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dale Wasserman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nurse Ratched</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ken Kesey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jove</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Francis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Billy Bibbit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Spivey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chief Bromden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Travis Jeffrey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seymour Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Candy Starr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flew Over</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cuckoo's NestPhoto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harding</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Isabel Hudson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wayne McDaniel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wendy Strehlow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cuckoo's Nest</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johann Walraven</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laurence Coy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reginald Theatre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Gooley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin Kinnane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oregon State Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McMurphy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kesey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bishanyia Vincent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Great American Novel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Randle P. McMurphy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scanlon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
