<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442941550404096</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/north/whittleseas-population-booms-as-focus-turns-to-infrastructure/news-story/930e71559b7c15a013895eae1ab4aca3</url>
  <title>Population boom keeps growing</title>
  <content>
WHITTLESEA'S population has surged by more than 60 per cent in a decade and shows no sign of slowing down, recent figures suggest.
Population growth figures released by the Bureau of Statistics reveal Whittlesea was the second fastest growing municipality in the state, behind Wyndham, from 2006-16.
The population jumped from just less than 130,000 in 2006 to more than 207,000 in 2016.
Whittlesea Council estimates the figure will grow to 333,000 in the next 30 years.
What infrastructure projects should be a priority? Have your say below.
The growth was highlighted recently by Northern Hospital in Epping, which had a monthly record of 348 births in July.
Given the continued rise, Mayor Ricky Kirkham said it was vital the council and government kept up with infrastructure, citing the Mernda Rail extension, Plenty Rd upgrades and O'Herns Rd interchange as major wins.
"By working in partnership with our residents and local agencies, council works hard to lobby state and federal governments to fund the essential infrastructure that our community needs and deserves," Cr Kirkham said.
"We will continue to do so until our residents are no longer disadvantaged simply because they live in the outer suburbs."
State Planning Minister Richard Wynne said the growth presented a unique chance to shape the municipality.
"Population growth offers opportunities if we get the planning right and prepare properly," he said.
"We're establishing new communities where people want to live, building world-class schools, roads and hospitals that families deserve and embarking on the big transport projects that get people home safer and sooner."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whittlesea Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mayor Ricky Kirkham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wyndham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>O'Herns Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Kirkham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Epping</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whittlesea</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bureau of Statistics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mernda Rail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Planning Minister Richard Wynne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.75</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
