<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443027449751548</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/afl/st-kilda-footballers-told-to-avoid-melbourne-beaches-amid-gruesome-sea-fleas-threat-20170807-gxqw8u.html</url>
  <title>Saints told to avoid Melbourne beaches amid sea fleas threat</title>
  <content>
WARNING: graphic images below
St Kilda football club have told their players to avoid bathing in Brighton beach after a teenager was left with gruesome and bloody ankles after apparently being bitten by sea fleas after swimming on Saturday.

Up Next

'I came out as gay at 76'

02:00

More National News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Did sea lice attack a teenager's legs?

Experts flummoxed as to what caused Sam Kanizay's legs and feet to bleed after went for a quick swim at a Melbourne beach on Saturday.

Saints midfielder Koby Stevens told reporters that he and his teammate Sam Gilbert were on their way to Brighton beach on Monday as part of recovery from their win over West Coast on Sunday, when the club emailed them to stay away because of the sea fleas threat.
Brighton beach is a popular spot for AFL players who use the icy water to recuperate their sore limbs after a match.

"I've still got my feet today," Stevens joked. "Me and Sammy Gilbert were actually on our way down to the beach and we got the email from Matt Hornsby, our fitness guy, telling us not to go in.
"The whole group got the message of the young bloke who nearly had his feet eaten off down at the beach."

Stevens said the email from the club wasn't the first time he had heard of the phenomenon.
"A couple of weeks back one of my mates was down the water and he came out with blood on his feet as well," he said.Photo: AAP
"You really need your feet for this game, so we were advised not go down there."
On Sunday it came to light that teenager Sam Kanizay had emerged from a dip at Brighton beach with his ankles covered in blood flowing from dozens of wounds on his calves and feet.Photo: Jarrod Kanizay
His father, Jarrod Kanizay, returned to the beach on Sunday night and put a piece of steak into the water.
He then filmed dozens of sea fleas eating the bait, a piece of steak, in the water and swimming into his net.Photo: Scott McNaughton
"We found thousands of little mite-type creatures in our net," Mr Kanizay said. "We put them in an Esky and brought them home and looked at them intently and let them swim in white dishes with red meat.
"Interestingly, overnight they've essentially all clung to the meat and have been busy overnight eating it."Photo: Jarrod Kanizay
His 16-year-old son Sam is still recovering in Dandenong Hospital, who struggled for most of Sunday to control the bleeding.
It is believed that sea fleas are the creatures responsible for biting Sam's legs, although it is still not a definitive belief held by those investigating the incident.
The Environment Protection Authority only does water monitoring in summer and will only become involved if the issue is pollution-related.
The Department of Environment, Land, Water and Planning told Fairfax Media it couldn't become involved as the cause was yet to be identified.
with Ebony Bowden and Carolyn Webb
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Gilbert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Environment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carolyn Webb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steven</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarrod Kanizay</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Kanizay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sammy Gilbert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saints</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Koby Stevens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Kanizay</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dandenong Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Environment Protection Authority</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott McNaughton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Hornsby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brighton</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ebony Bowden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
