<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442937255436621</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-07/venezuela-crisis-how-did-the-country-get-into-this-mess/8780476</url>
  <title>Venezuela crisis: How did the country get into this mess?</title>
  <content>
Venezuela is in crisis. The latest unrest saw a group of anti-government fighters sneaking onto an army base with the apparent intent of starting an uprising.
President Nicolas Maduro says .
"We know where they are headed and all of our military and police force is deployed," he said in a televised address.
It comes as the country's controversial new all-powerful constituent assembly considers creating a law against "hate, intolerance and fascism" that the President says would immediately punish those responsible for the current upheaval.
More than 120 people have died in four months of protests. Here's how the country got into its current mess.
It started with the election of President Nicolas Maduro

Mr Maduro became foreign affairs minister in 2006 and vice-president in 2012 under the late president Hugo Chavez, who died in 2013.
He was elected President in April 2013, but since then his popularity has suffered as a result of a deep recession, inflation, and shortages of food and medicine.
That inflation is now so bad that $1,000 of local currency purchased when Mr Maduro came to power would now be worth just $1.34.
The Supreme Court then tried to get rid of the National Assembly

In the 2015 parliamentary elections, discontent saw the Opposition win control of Venezuela's parliament, the National Assembly.
But in late March this year, .
The court had already shot down most congressional measures since the opposition won control.
It said it was taking over the assembly's role because it was in "contempt" of the law.
But critics say the current Supreme Court justices were named illegally by the ruling Socialist Party and rushed in before the Opposition took over the National Assembly.
The court's order was seen as anti-democratic and although it was quickly annulled, near-daily demonstrations snowballed into a general protest calling for a new presidential election.
Venezuela has since created a new all-powerful legislative body

Last week, Venezuela inaugurated a constituent assembly that was expected to rewrite the constitution and give vast new powers to Mr Maduro's ruling Socialist Party.
Mr Maduro says the new assembly is Venezuela's only hope for restoring peace.
, saying it was a power play aimed at keeping the president in office.
A June survey by polling firm Datanalisis said just 23 per cent of Venezuelans supported the creation of the constituent assembly.
The 545-member assembly has unanimously elected well-known allies of Mr Maduro to its leadership. They could potentially vote to dissolve the opposition-run National Assembly.
Venezuela's chief prosecutor has also been fired

In its first session on the weekend,  and ordered her to stand trial.
Ms Ortega had become Mr Maduro's main challenger from within the ruling socialist movement.
She has accused Mr Maduro of human rights abuses and of fudging the results of the vote which created the new assembly.
Her successor has promised to crack down on the demonstrations, but Ms Ortega has rejected her removal as illegal, saying she still considers herself the country's top prosecutor.
Meanwhile, Venezuela last week jailed two other leading critics of the President, opposition figures Leopoldo Lopez and Antonio Ledezma, both of whom have since been put under house arrest.
The President has also warned Julio Borges, the leader of the National Assembly, that "justice is coming for you and the terrorists you've helped advance".
Crucially, it seems like Mr Maduro still has the military's support

Opposition leaders have urged the military to drop its support for Mr Maduro because he's dragging Venezuela toward dictatorship.
But the President is believed to still have the military's support, which he and his predecessor Mr Chavez worked hard to shore up.
As with the latest uprising, most manifestations of dissent among troops have been small and isolated thus far.
But Venezuela has a long history of instability. Mr Chavez burst onto the national scene by leading a 1992 coup attempt, for which he served time in jail before winning the presidency six years later.
World leaders are piling on the pressure

The White House said Mr Maduro was effectively a dictator after "seizing absolute power" with the vote for a constituent assembly.
The Trump administration announced that financial sanctions would be imposed on the President, including freezing any assets he may have in US jurisdictions and barring Americans from doing business with him.
Meanwhile, Brazilian President Michel Temer said the crisis in his country's neighbour is worrying and his people are "on the side of the Venezuelan people".
He said "there is no more space for non-democratic alternatives in South America".
ABC/wires

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hugo Chavez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Socialist Party</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Nicolas Maduro</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Antonio Ledezma</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Venezuela</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julio Borges</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South America</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Maduro</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms. Ortega</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Datanalisis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Assembly</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Chavez</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazilian President Michel Temer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 2013</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Venezuelan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Supreme Court</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leopoldo Lopez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
