<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443152003804829</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-07/longest-serving-police-woman-wa-marks-40-years/8781552</url>
  <title>'Still a male-dominated profession': WA's longest current serving policewoman marks 40 years</title>
  <content>
As the WA police force marks 100 years since women were allowed to join, the force's first female mounted police officer is still serving today - without the high heels she started out in.
Sergeant Merryn Bojcun joined the force in 1977 with the aim of helping people.
At the time, she had no idea female officers were not permitted to marry or have children.

"Until I joined I wasn't actually aware of all of those things. I had no idea that there were these restrictions on women," she said.
"I was really quite oblivious to this discrimination."
Forty years later, WA Police's longest current serving female officer has seen many changes in her pioneering career.
"When I joined in 1977 there were 36 women in the WA Police. That's the total number ... I think it was about 2 per cent," she said.
Women police constables, or WPCs as they were known, primarily worked with women and children.
As in 1917 when the first women were allowed to join the force, a background in nursing or social welfare was sought after for female officers in the 1970s.
"To actually join the Western Australian police you had to wait until there was a vacancy for a woman because there was this quota kind of system," Sergeant Bojcun said.

Second-wave liberation

Soon after Sergeant Bojcun's training, she was among the first female police officers to be given a uniform and be deployed for regular duties.
The women's uniform was very different to what we see today.
"We had these gorgeous little navy blue ensemble dresses with a double-breasted blazer, and navy blue high heel shoes and stockings and gloves and a handbag, and off we went out on the street," Sergeant Bojcun said.
"Things have changed a lot, but in fact the handbag was quite a useful accoutrement to have at the time.
"In the handbag was police identification, handcuffs, and if necessary we would have a revolver."

Sergeant Bojcun said it was not until the 1980s that things really started to change for women, and today their opportunities were "absolutely unlimited".
"The discrimination has come a long way. It is still a male-dominated profession," she said.

"There are some women who have reached the highest levels in the structure.
"They are to be congratulated because the glass ceiling is triple-glazed as far as I can see in the police force, but every day there are positive moves to reinforce the status of women."
Although at first she did not recognise the significance, Sergeant Bojcun said she realised now that becoming the first female mounted police officer in 1977 was a big achievement.
"I didn't really think so at the time. However, looking back it was one of those things that opened the door for women, to say women can do these things," she said.
The sergeant said her first experiences working with women and children were part of what drove her to move into the family violence sphere in 2003, where she plans to continue working for the foreseeable future.
"I only found out recently that in fact I was the longest-serving female officer. I can't believe that in fact it's been more than 40 years doing this same job," she said.
"But I have to say I don't think I'm the oldest, and I hope to be around for a few more years yet."
Still a way to go: Commissioner

Outgoing WA Police commissioner Karl O'Callaghan said Sergeant Bojcun was one of the many female police officers who had worked to break barriers and transform the role women played in the force.

"Up until the mid-1970s not much had changed [for women in WA Police] since the turn of the century," he said.
"Since then, even what happened in the 1970s seems archaic to what women do now, because women are deployed in just about every area of policing to do just about anything there is, and that's as it should be."
Mr O'Callaghan acknowledged the profession continued to be male-dominated, but said the workforce had grown to be almost one quarter female.
"The biggest challenge for women in the police force today is not so much getting women to join the police force, but being able to keep them into the more senior levels," he said.
"When I say there's 23 per cent of the WA police force that is women, the representation at more senior ranks is a lot smaller than that.
"So working to help women have a family if that's what they want to do, come back to work and continue to ascend through the ranks is still a challenge for our organisation and is for all police forces in Australia."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr O'Callaghan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commissioner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WPCs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sergeant Bojcun</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA Police</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karl O'Callaghan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sergeant Merryn Bojcun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
