<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442851356089582</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:49</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/queensland/brisbane-man-charged-with-raping-a-mother-and-her-daughter-20170807-gxqusx.html</url>
  <title>Brisbane man charged with raping a mother and her daughter</title>
  <content>
A Brisbane man has been charged with raping a mother and her daughter and molesting another of the woman's children.
The 38-year-old landscape gardener, who cannot be named for legal reasons, allegedly raped the woman in March 2015.Photo: Glenn Hunt
He then unlawfully "procured" her teenage daughter at his Brisbane home in June or July 2016, indecently dealt with her in March or May and raped her in September, according to police allegations.
Police allege the man molested the woman's younger daughter, who was under 12 at the time, at his home in October last year.
His case, seven charges in total, was mentioned briefly in the Brisbane Magistrates Court on Monday but the accused was already in custody on other matters and was not required to appear.
Defence solicitor Mark Williams said his client intended to fight the charges, but would not apply for bail in the near future.
"He is waiting to obtain the brief of evidence and determine if there's any forensic evidence that is available or relied upon by the prosecution," he said.
"... The woman's complaint was from two years ago and the child complaints were from early this year and that's something we need to explore and examine.
"It poses questions as to why the mother left it so long to make a complaint."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Magistrates Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 2015.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenn Hunt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
