<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443113349098737</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/chevy-equinox-toyota-rav4-which-is-better-2017-8</url>
  <title>We put the Holden Equinox against the Toyota RAV4 in the battle of popular compact SUVs  --  here's the verdict</title>
  <content>
The Toyota RAV4 is the second best-selling compact SUV in the US (it's Australia's 10th best-selling car overall)

The Chevy Equinox - rebadged in Australia as the Holden Equinox - recently got an upgrade and has boasted record sales ever since.

The RAV4 is competitive when it comes to reliability and safety, but Chevy is catching up on performance and vehicle tech.

We put the two head-to-head to see who wins the battle of the small SUVs.

For the last few months, I have almost exclusively driven compact SUVs.

It's not as sexy of a driving experience as, say, a , but there's still good reason for giving the humble crossover a closer look. Mainly, that this is what most of America is buying nowadays.

Compact and crossover SUVs account for  sold in the US. That's a win for automakers, which secure higher margins on the larger vehicles than passenger sedans.

The Chevy Equinox has boasted reasonable sales, but has conventionally fallen behind frontrunners like the Toyota RAV4, which is the second best-selling compact SUV in the US. Chevy, however, decided to give the Equinox a better shot at cornering the market with a revamped model that's been  since its launch.

We put the Chevy Equinox LT and Toyota RAV4 Platinum head-to-head because both are popular crossovers that match on size. We wanted to see how two crossovers on the larger size stack up when it comes to sheer driving experience.

It's worth noting, however, that we're pitting the Equinox's turbo 4-cylinder engine against the non-turbo, 4-cylinder engine used by the RAV4, which is also larger. That may be a dealbreaker off the bat for some buyers who prefer the power of a classic 4-cylinder engine.

That being said, here's our take on the two:

Business Insider/Danielle Muoio

As a caveat, performance is the same across the Equinox line. We also drove an Equinox LT with two separate packages (the Confidence and Convenience Package and Sun and Infotainment Package) that come standard on the Premier trim.

The biggest disadvantage between the two would come down to some safety tech, such as lane-keep assist, that isn't made available on the LT. There's also slight differences when it comes to more luxe features, like heated steering wheels. We'll be making a note of this throughout the story.

Business Insider/Danielle Muoio

The Equinox Premier starts at $US30,040.

The two SUVs are essentially equals when it comes to price. Unless you commit to the very base model, options that most find necessary will bump the price to the mid-$US35,000 range.

Business Insider/Danielle Muoio

Business Insider/Danielle Muoio

Business Insider/Danielle Muoio

Business Insider/Danielle Muoio

Business Insider/Danielle Muoio

Business Insider/Danielle Muoio

Business Insider/Danielle Muoio

Business Insider/Danielle Muoio

Business Insider/Danielle Muoio

Business Insider/Danielle Muoio

Business Insider/Danielle Muoio

Business Insider/Danielle Muoio

Business Insider/Danielle Muoio

Business Insider/Danielle Muoio

Business Insider/Danielle Muoio

Business Insider/Danielle Muoio

Business Insider/Danielle Muoio

Business Insider/Danielle Muoio

The beauty of the LT is that it feels like a luxe car without breaking the bank. It doesn't look cheap or skimp on comfort, and the 4G LTE hotspot is a nice bonus.

I prefer the Equinox's clean and refined touchscreen over the more complex RAV4 display, which lacks Apple CarPlay and Android Auto. It's a better car to drive, especially if you spring for the 2.0-litre option. Overall, Chevy did a nice job with this upgrade.

Still, the Toyota RAV4 does win in a lot of regards. It comes with a lot more safety features that should be standard in all vehicles at this point. It's also a very no frills, spacious car for an everyday driver trying to cram a lot of people and cargo inside.

You do have to overcome some reservations to go with the Chevy Equinox. The Toyota RAV4 is a stable choice among crossovers and Toyota has a history of reliability that rivals Chevy's.

So in that sense, you would be giving up reliability in favour of in-car Wi-Fi and slightly better driving dynamics.

Still, if I were to put my money where my mouth is, I'd go with a Chevy Equinox LT and seek out the a 2.0-litre engine.

NOW WATCH: Executive Life videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toyota RAV4</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Equinox Premier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia's 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lt</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RAV4</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chevy Equinox LT</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toyota RAV4 Platinum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chevy Equinox</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple CarPlay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$35,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Infotainment Package</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Convenience Package</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SUV</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chevy</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Executive Life</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toyota</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SUVs</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holden Equinox</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Android Auto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Equinox LT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>G LTE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wi-Fi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider/Danielle Muoio</name>
    <count>20</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US30,040</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
