<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443194953478585</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/brand/chanticleer/telco-boss-takes-on-political-hot-potato-20170807-gxqy3u</url>
  <title>Optus chairman Paul O'Sullivan takes on political hot potato with airport</title>
  <content>
Optus chairman Paul O'Sullivan might want to take some advice from his old Vodafone rival Bill Morrow when it comes to taking on a politically contentious piece of government-funded infrastructure.
the body overseeing the second Sydney airport to be built at Badgerys Creek.
O'Sullivan is well-regarded in the telecommunications market for his decade-long stint transforming Optus into a serious rival to market leader Telstra.
Running an airport is a lot different to running a telecommunications company, but O'Sullivan's track record demonstrates he knows something about turning the underdog into a strong No. 2.

In this case, the second airport will be competing against Sydney Airports, which knocked back its first right of refusal to build the second airport because it was uneconomical.

Urban Infrastructure Minister Paul Fletcher knows O'Sullivan well from his life before politics in senior roles at the telecommunications group.
It will be a challenging role given the community backlash against the second airport, the complexities around issues such as transport links and the politics involved.
Telco bosses are suited for these kind of roles, though, because the industry is highly regulated and deeply political.
Morrow knows what this is like after inheriting the National Broadband Network (NBN), which is the country's largest but most unpopular infrastructure project at the moment.

Like Qantas boss Alan Joyce, O'Sullivan also hails from Dublin although he may struggle to convince the airline boss to move his mainline operations from Mascot to Badgerys Creek.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Airport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Morrow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qantas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Urban Infrastructure Minister Paul Fletcher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Broadband Network</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alan Joyce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>O'Sullivan</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Telstra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dublin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vodafone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul O'Sullivan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Badgerys Creek</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Optus</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morrow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
