<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443109054131328</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/markets/buy-hold-sell-a-impact-on-boral-james-hardie-ansell-20170807-gxqn8q</url>
  <title>Buy, hold, sell: $A impact on Boral, James Hardie, Ansell</title>
  <content>
Centennial Asset's Matthew Kidman talks with NAOS Asset's Ben Rundle and Totus Capital's Sam Granger about the impact of the strong Australian dollar on stocks.
Boral

Sam Granger: Sell. It's capital intensive and high price to earnings vs the market. We don't like that business.  
Ben Rundle: It's a hold for me. I think that that acquisition they made of Headwaters gives them good exposure to US infrastructure spend, but it's very expensive.
James Hardie

Ben Rundle: Yeah, it's a buy for me. Some of the peers in the US have reported very strongly only very recently and James Hardie is taking market share in that space.
Sam Granger: It's a hold for us. They've had operational issues, senior management turnover. That concerns us, it's a hold.
Ansell

Sam Granger: We're buying Ansell. There's low negativity about this stock. It's got a great track record, high ROE, it's a buy.

Ben Rundle: Yep, it's a buy for me too. They'll have more visibility on their input costs now post the restructure and there's a buyback to come too, so it's a buy.
Buy stocks?

Ben Rundle: Resmed. I think the Aussie dollar will come back down. Resmed is a good business that's come back on its earnings. Result was a short-term hiccup. It is very well run, high barriers to entry, good return on equity, so I think you can buy it on the dip.
Sam Granger: Hansen Technologies. We think Hansen is a buy. Their founder owns a material part of the stock, he's a great capital allocator, they're following  a model which has worked for Constellation Software in the US, so we think that's a buy.  

Buy Hold Sell is a weekly video series produced by  
Disclaimer: The information contained in this presentation is general in nature and should not be relied upon. Before making any investment of financial planning decisions, you should consult a licensed professional who can advise you whether the decision is appropriate for you. Contributors to this show may have commercial or financial interests in the companies mentioned. 

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boral</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAOS Asset's Ben Rundle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hold Sell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Rundle</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Hardie</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hansen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ROE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Constellation Software</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hansen Technologies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Granger</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Resmed</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Centennial Asset's Matthew Kidman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ansell</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Totus Capital's Sam Granger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
