<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443070399425156</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/lifestyle/health/irish-singer-sinead-oconnor-posts-concerning-video-about-battle-with-mental-illness-sparking-concerns-from-thousands-of-her-fans/news-story/d7bb2a071cb7d4e56dd85a46a4ca2872</url>
  <title>Sad truth behind Sinead's distressing video</title>
  <content>
IRISH singer and songwriter, Sinead O'Connor, has posted a frightening video from the bedroom of a Travel Lodge motel in New Jersey, sparking fears she is suicidal.
, opening up about how alone she is - and that she's "walking alone" and "fighting" every day to "stay alive".
"I'm all by myself, there's absolutely nobody in my life," O'Connor says through tears in the 12 minute clip.
"[No one] except my doctor, my psychiatrist - who is the sweetest man on earth who says I'm his hero - and that's about the only f**king thing keeping me alive at the moment. The fact that I'm his bloody hero ... and that's kind of pathetic."
O'Connor, who says she hasn't been to her homeland in two years, claimed she is being "treated like sh*t" by family members, and that nobody will take care of her.
"It's like a witch hunt, they are pointing the finger saying 'see, see this is why'," she said.
"I'm fighting and fighting and fighting like all the millions of people.
"If it was just for me I'd be gone. Straight away back to my mum ... because I've walked this earth alone for two years now as punishment for being mentally f**king ill and getting angry that no one would f***ing take care of me."
Earlier this year,  after she lost custody of her 13-year-old son, warning them that they would "have a dead celebrity on their hands" if they didn't alter their decision.
In the post on Facebook, she threatened to take her life if matters weren't corrected - and if she didn't receive an unconditional apology from the State.
In her latest plea, O'Connor explains how her mental illness is "like a drug".
"I hope that this video is somehow helpful," she said.
"I give so much love in my life ... I want everyone to see what it's like. Mental illness is a bit like drugs, it doesn't give a s**t who you are. Equally what is worse is that the stigma doesn't give a s**t who you are.
"I have been wanting to go for two fucking years. I'm a 5'4" little f***ing woman wandering the world for two years by myself.
"Nobody in my f***ing life ... It's a crime and it should not be acceptable to any man that knows me or claims to love me."
O'Connor has four children from four different fathers and after losing custody of her 13-year-old son, expressed suicidal thoughts last year.
After promising the agency she will become "the first Irish citizen to take their life in protest" of mental health, she fumed "I would never have become so unwell if I had not been kept from my child. I would not have remained unwell for so long had I been restored to him."
In May last year, the singer sparked a police investigation after she disappeared while out on a bike ride. Those close to her feared she had disappeared to take her life.
In the video, O'Connor says that people in her mental state need to be taken care of by others less vulnerable.
"I'm really sad and I shouldn't be here and I know I'm just one of millions and that's the only thing that keeps me going," she said.
"I'm making this video because I am one of millions.
"You've got to take care of us ... We are doing our best like everybody else.
"Three f***ing illnesses made me suicidal ... My whole life is revolving around just not dying.
"And I'm not going to die, I'm not going to die but still this is no way for people to be living."
O'Connor's post has received more than 1.3K comments from concerned fans, all expressing concern over the 50-year-old's welfare.
"I go to bed every night worried about you," one person posted.
"I wake up and tentatively log onto Facebook because of my worry for you."
"To Sinead's kids get over and help your Mother," another added.
"She is crying out for you all, forget what has happened and forgive ... give her a hug, when she's dead there will be no chance."
O'Connor has struggled with mental illness for years telling The Oprah Winfrey Show in 2007 she had been diagnosed with bipolar disorder in 2003.
The singer was also forced to sell her Irish home in January, 2017 after she reportedly owed $A240,000 in unpaid taxes.
If you or anyone you know needs information or support you can contact Lifeline on 13 11 14 or at lifeline.org.au.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>O'Connor</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Irish</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oprah Winfrey Show</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Travel Lodge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>K</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sinead</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Jersey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sinead O'Connor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
