<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443066104457760</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/messenger/south/hallett-cove-bakery-takes-out-the-top-award-at-hallett-cove-business-association-local-business-awards/news-story/3a8857b064555e7330de40fc2047f672</url>
  <title>Bakery proves its prowess at awards</title>
  <content>
SERVING up delicious treats is a family affair for Hallett Cove Bakery's Shaun and Sandra Brierton.
The couple and their daughter, Bek, 20, are celebrating being named overall winner in the inaugural Hallett Cove Business Association Local Business Awards.
Shaun has been baking for about 35 years and has trained Bek, who specialises in birthday cakes and other sweets, such as doughnuts and caramel slices.
The family hails from England - just like about 15 per cent of Hallett Cove's population - and moved to Adelaide in 2008.
"When we got here we thought, 'It's not really Australia because it's like little Britain'," Sandra says.
She says Hallett Cove Bakery offers a range of products that are particularly popular with expats, including scotch pies, Eccles cakes, quiches and vanilla slices.
Sandra says the key to a perfect vanilla slice is "good, crisp pastry and nice, flavoursome custard".
"You could almost describe the custard as like the flavour of vanilla ice cream."
She says she loves Hallett Cove's "nice, community atmosphere".
"Quite often on the weekend, we'll get three to four regulars who come in and have breakfast and they all have a conversation with one another," she says.
Alongside Business of the Year, the couple took out the Hospitality category in last week's awards, which involved locals nominating and voting for their favourite businesses.
Hallett Cove Business Association chairwoman Marie Soliman says the bakery won the Business of the Year award for its professionalism, community contribution and quality products.
It followed the business's success in the Baking Association of Australia's South Australian Baking Show awards last month, when it took out a prize for its sausage rolls and novelty cake.
At the 2015 Royal Adelaide Show, Shaun came third in the Christmas pudding category, using a recipe from England that's 100 years old.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sandra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hallett Cove</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shaun</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bek, 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian Baking Show</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baking Association of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3.7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hallett Cove Business Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marie Soliman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hallett Cove Bakery's Shaun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Business of the Year</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sandra Brierton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hallett Cove Business Association Local Business Awards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hallett Cove Bakery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eccles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Adelaide Show</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
