<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443152003804813</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Radio Australia</source>
  <url>http://www.radioaustralia.net.au/international/2017-08-07/chinese-media-criticises-us-arrogance-over-north-korea-stresses-limits-of-new-un-sanctions/1691860</url>
  <title>Chinese media criticises US 'arrogance' over North Korea, stresses limits of new UN sanctions</title>
  <content>
Chinese state media has stressed the limits of new United Nations sanctions on North Korea, and also slammed the United States for its "arrogance", saying Washington needs to understand it also has a role in lessening tensions.

Key points:

UN sanctions could cost North Korea a third of its annual export revenue
Trump wrote on Twitter that he spoke with South Korean President Moon Jae-in
The Security Council unanimously approved the sanctions on North Korea

The UN Security Council unanimously  on Saturday that could slash its $3 billion annual export revenue by a third.
The US-drafted resolution bans North Korean exports of coal, iron, iron ore, lead, lead ore and seafood following Pyongyang's two  in July.
It also prohibits countries from increasing the current numbers of North Korean labourers working abroad, bans new joint ventures with North Korea and any new investment in current joint ventures.
US President Donald Trump took to Twitter a day after the council backed the new sanctions to announce that he had spoken with South Korean President Moon Jae-in.

External Link:

Donald Trump on Twitter: Just completed call with President Moon of South Korea. Very happy and impressed with 15-0 United Nations vote on North Korea sanctions.
"Just completed call with President Moon of South Korea. Very happy and impressed with 15-0 United Nations vote on North Korea sanctions," he said.
In a front-page commentary, the overseas edition of the ruling Communist Party's official People's Daily said North Korea's open flouting of UN rules with its missile launches meant that it had to be punished, but sanctions had to be targeted.
"Sanctions to the greatest possible extent must avoid causing negative impacts to ordinary people and to third countries, and avoid bringing disaster to the country in question's normal and legal trade and business exchanges with the outside world, people's normal lives and the humanitarian situation," it wrote.
"A precision blow is the essential part of sanctions."

Video:(ABC News)
China has repeatedly said that while sanctions need to be imposed, they cannot bring a final resolution to the North Korea issue, which has to be addressed by talks.
China has also called for Washington and Seoul to help lower tensions by reining in their military activities and drills on the peninsula, and by withdrawing the Terminal High Altitude Area Defense (THAAD) anti-missile system.
The influential Global Times, published by the People's Daily, said in an editorial that the US needed to curb its "moral arrogance over North Korea".
"The West should be reminded to exercise restraint. If it believes it is only North Korea rather than the US and South Korea as well to blame for the nuclear issue, this ill-fitting mindset will not help solve the crisis," the strongly nationalist publication said.
"The US should aim for peace and co-existence rather than geopolitical dominance."
Reuters
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pyongyang</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UN</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Moon of South</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korea</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>-11</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Nations</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Global Times</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korean</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Korea</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terminal High Altitude Area Defense</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UN Security Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seoul</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Korean President Moon Jae-in</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US-drafted</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>People's Daily</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>THAAD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Communist Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Security Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reuters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Korea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
