<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442731097003884</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/forward-battle-key-for-storm-bromwich/3209635/</url>
  <title>Forward battle key for Storm: Bromwich</title>
  <content>
MELBOURNE Storm enforcer Jesse Bromwich says the forward pack must match Sydney Roosters for aggression in Saturday's top-of-the-table blockbuster at AAMI Park. 
Storm could go a long way towards securing the minor premiership with a win over the Roosters, one of three NRL rivals two games behind the ladder leader with four rounds to play.
"I think our forward battle is going to be crucial to getting the two points on the weekend, obviously the Roosters have been going along well this year but they had a slip up last week and I just think it makes it a tougher game this week," Bromwich said. 
"I just think they'll be more fired up, coming off a loss you're always a bit fired up the next week so going into that game you put a little bit more effort into it.
"It's a top-of-the-table clash as well so they're going to come down here trying to prove themselves and we still got to prove ourselves as well."
Roosters firebrands Jared Waerea-Hargreaves and Dylan Napa will take a world of stopping in the middle, but Bromwich is confident the Storm pack can ruffle a few feathers. 
"It was a good battle last week (against North Queensland), I thought our boys that came off the bench did a tremendous job, they played really well and I think they can take a lot of confidence out of that," Bromwich said.
"The Roosters have got a big aggressive pack and they've got a big job this week. 
"For us it's about trying to match them with that (aggression), work as a pack and work as a team, I think that's our strength, we're using each other really well this year."
Storm playmaker Cameron Munster (ankle) could return this week, along with utility Tohu Harris (shoulder).
Night of crashes rounds out weekend of heartbreak on Coast roads
The plane you need in an emergency
Close call for Coast motorists as debris goes flying on motorway
Planning documents lodged on behalf of site owners
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
The legendary creator isn't so sure about how Netflix works.
*WARNING this story contains spoilers*
TARA Reid reveals what's coming in the next installment of TV movie.
Farmer's brave decision has cost him the game.
"It didn't seem like they were having a crazy, big night."
The news came after the couple attended Splendour in the Grass
Garth Prowd's vision made huge impact on Sunshine Coast community
Home sells in just one day
Winners in Master Builders regional housing and construction awards
Ray and Gert will celebrate 70 years of marrive this week
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jared Waerea-Hargreaves</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garth Prowd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAMI Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tara Reid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron Munster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bromwich</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roosters</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Storm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Roosters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jesse Bromwich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dylan Napa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tohu Harris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
