<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442683852363012</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/these-are-the-young-marines-missing-off-the-cap-co/3209571/</url>
  <title>Osprey crash: These are the young Marines feared dead</title>
  <content>
TRIBUTES are flowing as the names of the three US Marines feared dead off the Capricorn Coast following Saturday afternoon's horror MV-22 Osprey crash begin to emerge.

Two of those Marines still missing have been named as Lt. Benjamin Robert Cross and Corporal Nathan Ordway.

Corporal Ordway, a young man from Wichita, Kansas, was the first to be identified as missing after his sister posted on the 31st Marine Expeditionary Unit's Facebook page.

"Please pray for my brother," Taylor Ordway said.

"We ask that you pray and send love my brother's way."

A family friend, Heidi Peltzer, asked friends to "please pray for his life, his safety, and comfort for the family".

Since Cpl Ordway was identified, social media has been flooded with tributes messages with many people asking the community to keep the Ordway family in their thoughts and prayers.

Lt. Cross, a 26-year-old aviator in the Marines from Maine, has also been identified as one of those missing after the crash.

He was identified by his older brother, Ryan Cross, in an interview with a US based CBS reporter.

"It's something that you hope that you never have to experience. Every military family knows in the back of their mind there's always a possibility. You open it will never happen to you," Mr Cross told CBS.

"Luckily, we have a great support network of family and friends. The community has been amazing just the outpouring of support we received from everyone. Everyone immediately asked what can they do to help."

Mr Cross went to to describe his missing brother as having the "highest moral character" and as someone who was "devoted" to his Marine Corps position. He said Lt. Cross' dream was to be a pilot in the military.

"It probably sounds cliche, but you know, words really can't describe my little brother," Mr Cross said.

"He's the type of person that everybody, the type of friend everybody wishes they had had the type of person everybody wishes they knew.

"The highest moral character - just the most caring, compassionate, empathetic individual I've ever met. He would do anything for anybody that needed it, so selfless.

"My brother, all through high school knew he wanted to be a pilot in the military ... it had been his dream.

"He's always been interested in all things aerial, aeronautical - loved roller coasters and all things math or science so it was kind of a natural fit for him."

While the third missing Marine has not been identified, posts circulating social media indicate he is a young man from the La Puente, California area.

A message on social media from a man close to the family of one of the missing Marines said "To all my Marine brothers and sisters and fellow service members here in the La Puente area, it is with a heavy heart I say that one of these fallen brothers is a local boy. I have spoke to his aunt and I will be posting more info as I get It, until then let's keep his family in our thoughts and prayers".

A recovery mission is ongoing off the Capricorn Coast near Shoalwater Bay today.

Night of crashes rounds out weekend of heartbreak on Coast roads
The plane you need in an emergency
Close call for Coast motorists as debris goes flying on motorway
Planning documents lodged on behalf of site owners
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
The legendary creator isn't so sure about how Netflix works.
*WARNING this story contains spoilers*
TARA Reid reveals what's coming in the next installment of TV movie.
Farmer's brave decision has cost him the game.
"It didn't seem like they were having a crazy, big night."
The news came after the couple attended Splendour in the Grass
Garth Prowd's vision made huge impact on Sunshine Coast community
Home sells in just one day
Winners in Master Builders regional housing and construction awards
Ray and Gert will celebrate 70 years of marrive this week
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Benjamin Robert Cross</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marine Corps</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lt</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taylor Ordway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garth Prowd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marine Expeditionary Unit's Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wichita</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shoalwater Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tara Reid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Marines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>11</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corporal Nathan Ordway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cpl Ordway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ordway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>La Puente</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Capricorn Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MV-22 Osprey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corporal Ordway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan Cross</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kansas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heidi Peltzer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Cross</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ospreys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marine</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
