<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442945845371493</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>http://www.businessinsider.com.au/larsen-c-iceberg-satellite-pictures-2017-8</url>
  <title>Incredible new satellite photos reveal Antarctica's huge iceberg in stunning detail</title>
  <content>
In early July, a rift in Antarctica's Larsen C ice shelf caused the third-largest iceberg ever recorded to  into the Southern Ocean.

The block of ice, dubbed iceberg A-68, may hang around  in the open sea and is . It's roughly the area of Delaware, has the mass of 5.6 Mount Everests, and is voluminous enough to fill Lake Erie more than twice.

However, because it's the middle of winter in Antarctica, scientists have struggled to get good images of the iceberg. So far, they have relied on polar satellites like Sentinel-1, which uses radar to see through thick cloud cover.

A few days of clear weather in late July, however, gave Deimos-1 and Deimos-2 - a pair of satellites that operate as a tag-team - a clear, visible-light view of the scene on the eastern Antarctic Peninsula.

Here are the new photos, released by Deimos Imaging and  in an August 3

An illustration of the two Deimos Imaging satellites.
Deimos-1 (left) takes wider-angle, medium-resolution images while Deimos-2 (right) takes zoomed-in, very-high-resolution pictures.

A zoomed-in view of Antarctica's Larsen C ice shelf, and iceberg A-68, on July 31, 2017.
'Thanks to its wide swath and high revisit time, Deimos-1 spotted where the main developments were going on in the Larsen C Ice Shelf and its surroundings,' Ana Isabel Martinez, a writer for Deimos Imaging, wrote in .

A zoomed-in view of Antarctica's Larsen C ice shelf, and iceberg A-68, on July 28, 2017.

A zoomed-in view of Antarctica's Larsen C ice shelf, and iceberg A-68, on July 28, 2017.

The image above shows the paths other icebergs have taken after breaking off of Antarctica.

Most likely, iceberg A-68 will drift toward the warmer waters of Falkland Islands, though many larger icebergs go farther east to the South Georgia and South Sandwich Islands.

Source:

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deimos Imaging</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Sandwich Islands</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Everest</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Larsen C Ice Shelf</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ana Isabel Martinez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Antarctic Peninsula</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southern Ocean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Delaware</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake Erie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Antarctica's Larsen C</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2.7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Georgia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deimos-2</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deimos-1</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sentinel-1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July/31/2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 28, 2017</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Falkland Islands</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Antarctica</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
