<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443070399425145</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/lifestyle/food/eat/weekly-meal-plan-healthy-eating-has-never-been-so-tasty/news-story/c9b884a43983973ad7305c0bd6985c73</url>
  <title>Weekly meal plan: Healthy eating has never been so tasty</title>
  <content>
This chicken, barley casserole is simple and tasty, perfect for a Monday night.

Share

MONDAY
Hearty  is a winter warmer the whole family will love. This one pot wonder is one you'll have on rotation well into the warmer months. Quick and easy to make, serve this dish still in the pan and let everybody help themselves.
TUESDAY

Jamie Oliver's stuffed zucchinis are perfect as a side or a main. Source: delicious.com.auSource:Supplied
Only Jamie Oliver could turn  into an Italian feast. This recipe is so easy to follow, simply stuff those zucchinis and let the oven do all the hard work as they slowly roast in that rich tomato sugo. Serve with a slice of sourdough to ensure all that sauce gets mopped up.
WEDNESDAY

You don't have to leave the house to get delicious ramen.Source:Taste.com.au

Ramen need not be saved for date night anymore. This recipe makes recreating one of your favourite Japanese dishes at home so easy. Right down to the soft boiled egg. This  is sure to warm you up during the cooler months, and is perfect if you're cooking for friends, your significant other, or even just for yourself.
THURSDAY

You need Jessica Sepel's recipe because pasta should never be a no no.Source:bodyandsoul
You do not, I repeat, do not, have to ditch pasta just because you've decided to eat healthier. It simply needs a slight adaptation. Take  for example. Exempt from cream, and sugary tomato sauces, this recipe uses wholegrain pasta and fresh green vegetables to keep you full and satisfied. And because you're cutting down on sugar and carbs, handfuls of grated parmasen cheese are totally allowed.
FRIDAY

You can tweak this seafood stew to match your taste buds. Source: delicious.com.auSource:Supplied
Fish Fridays are making a comeback in the form of . This recipe is perfect for feeding friends and family you're keen to impress. If you're not a fan of all types of seafood, omit and include whichever type you like. Hot tip: Make extra tomato sugo, you'll thank yourself next week when you're using it to whip up pasta or cooking stuffed zucchini again.
SATURDAY

Healthy, tasty and super quick. Home-made pizzas sound like a winner to us.Source:Taste.com.au
Home-made pizzas are the easiest way to do healthy food at home, especially when there is no dough involved. Make these  if you're entertaining this weekend. They'll be cooked in 20 minutes, leaving you plenty of time to socialise outside the kitchen. The nature of the home-made pizza means it is also the perfect recipe if you're not entertaining and simply spending the night in with your cat. Which is fine, no judgement here.
SUNDAY

Spice up your Sunday roast with a Peruvian twist.Source:bodyandsoul
Ever fancied trying your hand a whole roast chicken? If so, this recipe is for you. This  is delicious and every bit as fancy as it sounds. Give this Sunday roast a go and I very much doubt you'll miss the gravy and soggy peas you're used too.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jessica Sepel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamie Oliver</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japanese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peruvian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>auSource</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
