<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442503463734407</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:28</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/lifestyle/relationships/marriage/man-who-pens-public-tribute-to-his-curvy-wife-faces-backlash-for-objectifying-her/news-story/57050a6d1c3bedb21dcd3f98524ce3aa</url>
  <title>Man who pens public tribute to his 'curvy' wife faces backlash for 'objectifying' her</title>
  <content>
Robbie and Sarah Tripp have found themselves at the centre of a social media storm after his original post about her 'curvy' body went viral.

George HarrisonThe Sun

Share

ONE man's very public tribute to his "curvy" wife ended up dividing opinion after he was slammed for "objectifying" her in the offending post.
American entrepreneur Robbie Tripp to praise his wife, Sarah, in a post where he bigged up his own feminist credentials.
But many other feminists were less than impressed with the post, which featured a shot of Robbie and Sarah sharing a tender moment on a beach.
In his public tribute, Robbie wrote: "I love this woman and her curvy body. As a teenager, I was often teased by my friends for my attraction to girls on the thicker side.
"As I became a man and started to educate myself on issues such as feminism and how the media marginalizes women by portraying a very narrow and very specific standard of beauty (thin, tall, lean), I realised how many men have bought into that lie.
"For me, there is nothing sexier than this woman here: thick thighs, big booty, cute little side roll etc."
At first, the post was widely circulated and praised as an example of touching body-positivity.
But before long, the post had attracted criticism from people who claimed that there's really nothing at all radical about a man loving his wife.

Journalist Julia Pugachevsky wrote on Twitter: "Strong contender for least fave type of male feminist is 'man who thinks liking a curvy woman is revolutionary.'"
The critical comment, which has been retweeted over 26,000 times, sparked a fierce debate around feminism and what it means to be body positive.

strong contender for least fave type of male feminist is "man who thinks liking a curvy woman is revolutionary"
The tweet, alongside the original shot of the couple, taken by photographer , has swept around the internet as part of the ongoing debate.
But many viewers objected completely to Sarah being described as curvy at all.
One unimpressed commenter asked: "Why do you think you're a modern saint because you date a normal-sized woman?"
And another, mocking Robbie's original Instagram post, said: "I'm a feminist, I objectify women for completely different reasons than most of society."
However, not everyone was so critical of Robbie's public love letter.
One commenter on Instagram wrote: "I love this so much. I'm tired of people getting offended by everything and anything.
"This is a beautiful post and we need more men like you in the world."

Tripp often takes to Instagram to share his appreciation of his wife's 'curvy' body.Source:Instagram

But he's been slammed for his public love letter.Source:Instagram
This article was originally published on .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tripp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah Tripp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robbie Tripp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julia Pugachevsky</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George HarrisonThe Sun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robbie</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
