<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443109054131373</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-07/garma-final-forum-addresses-need-for-progress-on-constitution/8781562</url>
  <title>Garma: Indigenous leaders call for progress on constitutional referendum at final forum</title>
  <content>
A campaign to encourage Australians to vote yes on constitutional change for Indigenous people is the next step in enacting the Uluru Statement, the final forum of the Garma Festival has heard.
The forum on Monday focused on the next steps in constitutionally enshrining a body for First Nations people in Parliament as well as a treaty, as stated in the .
"We've got a big job, we've got to educate our countrymen, the rest of the Australian people," Central Australian leader Vincent Forrester said.
"We need to take this argument forward ... they've got to educate Australia, our job is to educate our mob but we need reasoned, eminent people, we've got to get the brains of the working Australian like [lawyer] Geoffrey Robertson and Justice [Michael] Kirby on board."
But  said there were no funds to take those next steps in creating a campaign.
"We don't have any funds for the next step and there is no organisation or body that's organised with funding to take the next steps," she said.
"What everyone can do is set up a meeting with their local member of parliament, write a letter, tell their friends to set up a meeting because it has come through consensus and proper national consultation."

The Federal Government funded the Referendum Council to travel around the country and hold regional dialogues with First Nations people.
Those discussions resulted in the Uluru Statement.
'We have to take the PM on face value'

Many at Garma expected Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull to take action on the report but he only said his Cabinet would consider it.
"We have to take what the Prime Minister said here on face value, that he'll still go to Cabinet and talk to his colleagues and that's why he wasn't able to give us the next steps," she said.
"So in terms of next steps, the referendum council have taken their report to the Prime Minister and Opposition and yes, we are asking them to consider the report and provide a statement to Parliament."
The Kimberly Land Council's Nolan Hunter called for a committee to be created in order to provide more detail on how a First Nations body would work in Parliament.

"If you ask for too much in a referendum proposal, the likelihood of it getting up is difficult," he said.
"People were expecting some kind of commitment at least from the Prime Minister ... but how does he go back to Parliament and get this over the line without the details? It's a bit of a double-edged sword."
Academic Marcia Langton echoed statements across the weekend that the Uluru Statement was the final straw for constitutional change.
"I was in my early 20s when this all started, that was 40-something years ago and I don't want to be dead before a resolution on this issue comes out," she said.
"We are royal commissioned out, we're panelled out, we're experted out. Enough, just do it."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kirby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geoffrey Robertson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Referendum Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vincent Forrester</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garma Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garma</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>First Nations</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marcia Langton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kimberly Land Council's Nolan Hunter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uluru Statement</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
