<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442593658048604</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/rendezview/lena-dunham-should-try-talking-not-reporting/news-story/68cc263029d2111ecb5aa6e9f210a4ce</url>
  <title>Lena Dunham should try talking, not reporting</title>
  <content>
LENA Dunham this weekend took to Twitter to report two flight attendants for having a conversation she deemed, well, reportable.
She alleged the flight attendants were suggesting transgender was a "trend", that they would never accept having a transgender child and found transgender itself "gross".
"At this moment in history we should be teaching our employees about love and inclusivity @AmericanAir." she tweeted.
American Airlines has since provided details which cast doubt on whether it was even their employees, but regardless, it is this kind of policing of people's opinions and speech which lends weight to the tedious cries of "political correctness gone mad".
Well, no, generally speaking, political correctness is just a phrase which means showing some courtesy and respect for your fellow humans, and generally trying to avoid hurting people's feelings if you can.
And if you simply can't help it, well nobody is going to arrest you for it unless you're threatening violence.
But instances like this just provide bullets for the guns wielded by those who like to claim that those on the Left are trying to silence and shame those who hold unapproved opinions.
These flight attendants weren't talking about how they discriminate against transgender people by giving them seats near the toilets. Dunham was absolutely right in thinking that had there been a transgender teen standing behind them as they spoke, that person likely would have felt upset and saddened by what they were hearing. And she is right to think that transgender people already carry an enormous burden, and avoiding piling more hurt and rejection on their shoulders is something all humans should aspire to.
But is this the way to make inclusiveness and tolerance happen?

At this moment in history we should be teaching our employees about love and inclusivity . That was worst part of this night.
We're justifiably outraged at the notion of the government and big business spying on us through our devices and data. We should be equally outraged at the idea that another person can eavesdrop on our conversations and use them to suggest we need re-education.
It raises horrible echoes of East Germany, when neighbours reported on neighbours to curry favour and save themselves.
Dunham didn't take photos or name the flight attendants in question, but by providing as many details as possible to American Airlines, it was clear she felt some kind of action should be taken against them.
If the conversation happened as Dunham described it then sure, it would be beneficial for the world at large if those flight attendants took some time to learn a little about transgender issues, to understand the terrible psychological pain it causes those who feel locked within a body that doesn't match their souls.
But minds can only be changed through conversation - conversations exactly like those flight attendants were apparently having.
Maybe the next time one of them chooses to raise the issue, they'll find someone who isn't in furious agreement with their discomfort. Someone who might explain why they disagree, or speak about the experiences of someone they know.
But every time someone is shamed or shouted down for having an opinion, it becomes less likely their views will ever change.
Being shouted down - or worse - disciplined, for thinking or saying the wrong thing is likely to make people's unpleasant views more intractable, and more invisible.
Grudges and bigotry held in secret are much more dangerous than those which are out in the open where they can be challenged and debated.
It is it worth noting that the origins of laws to protect hate speech in the US are in the civil rights movement. The first laws were not to protect racists, but the likes of Malcolm X and Martin Luther King, who white Southerns claimed might incite a race war with their speeches and writings.
A close family relative of mine was once opposed to same-sex marriage. Couldn't put her finger on why, really. Just had a vague idea it was a bit too radical. Didn't have anything against gay people - would never have marched in the streets against it - just didn't see why they needed to get married.
We never argued about it. It wasn't a big issue in our family, we just disagreed and passed the butter.
She has since changed her mind. And it wasn't because anyone shouted at her, lectured her or reported her for homophobia.
It was because she came to care for a gay person, a person who did kind things for her and made her laugh.
And now she's a little surprised she ever had a problem with it.
This is how people's minds are changed - by experiences, by talking, by being respectfully challenged.

It was a silly reality show, which happened to include a transgender contestant.
How much more effective would Dunham have been if she approached the flight attendants and told them about her experiences with transgender friends?
And what are the odds that instead, those unnamed flight attendants are now feeling angry, resentful and persecuted, instead of inclined to open their minds to another view.
Claire Sutherland is acting RendezView editor.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Claire Sutherland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>American Airlines</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AmericanAir</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm X</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lena Dunham</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East Germany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin Luther King</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RendezView</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dunham</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
