<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443109054131379</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:49</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/western-australia/big-wave-likely-caused-wa-mens-death/news-story/e4bc3a9c25526a6b278e6d54cd8ac9ef</url>
  <title>Wave likely caused WA men's death</title>
  <content>
AN inquest into the disappearance of two fishermen off Coral Bay last year has been told it could not be determined if one of the men was dead or alive when his arm was bitten by sharks.
Experienced fishermen Nigel Kitchen, 50 and Andrew Hinds, 57, failed to return to shore after a fishing trip at the small north-west coastal town on May 29 last year.
The men, who were described as "safety conscious", had two EPIRBS on board their 8.2m boat but they were never activated, leading investigators to conclude it was likely the pair were suddenly "swamped by a wave".
An extensive five-day air, land and sea search failed to locate the men, although an arm belonging to Mr Kitchen was found two days later by a tourist snorkelling in the area.
Counsel assisting the coroner Sergeant Lyle Housiaux said a forensic pathologist concluded that if Mr Kitchen's arm was "traumatically amputated" while he was alive, it was likely he would have died from blood loss without immediate treatment.

Sgt Housiaux said the forensic examination found evidence of predation from more than one shark and more than one species of shark, which he said were likely grey reef and tiger sharks.
Sen. Sgt Andrew Stevens, who investigated the disappearance, said it could not be said "with any certainty" whether Mr Kitchen was "alive or not" when he was injured.
He said it could also not be determined whether a shark caused the injury.
Sen. Sgt Stevens said sharks can behave as both a predator and scavenger and could "carry food for quite a long way without regurgitating or dropping it".
The pair was last seen launching their boat at the Monck Head boat ramp about 11.45am and were reported missing about 6pm that night by friends who became concerned when they had not returned by nightfall.
Various items belonging to the men - including a piece of a seat belonging to the missing boat - were located in the days following their disappearance.
However, neither the men nor their boat have never been found and Sen. Sgt Stevens said it was unlikely they ever will.
Sen. Sgt Stevens said he believed the men were "broadsided" by a wave, which he said must have been "very sudden and very catastrophic".
Deputy State Coroner Evelyn Vicker said she was satisfied that both men had died.
Ms Vicker indicated she would recommend that boat users use water activated EPIRBs and life jackets, instead of the manually activated equipment the men were carrying.
She said she would also recommend that those who go out on the water should tell somebody where they are going and the time they expect to return, noting there was a six-hour window before a search was launched.
Outside court, Mr Kitchen's ex-wife Tracy Whiteside and his daughter Jessica Kitchen said they agreed with Ms Vicker's recommendations.
"Anything you can do to increase safety is something that's worth doing," Ms Kitchen said.
Ms Kitchen described her father as a "family man".
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Kitchen</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sgt Housiaux</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jessica Kitchen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monck Head</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Hinds, 57</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tracy Whiteside</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sen. Sgt Andrew Stevens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Kitchen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sergeant Lyle Housiaux</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deputy State Coroner Evelyn Vicker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EPIRB</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coral Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sen. Sgt Stevens</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nigel Kitchen, 50</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Vicker</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
