<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443066104457793</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-07/relocation-of-seals-from-salmon-farms-angers-north-west-fishers/8780414</url>
  <title>Fishers angry over relocation of 'increasingly aggressive' seals to state's north west</title>
  <content>
There are calls for an inquiry to address Tasmania's rogue seal problem after more than 2,000 were relocated in the past financial year.
Tasmanian Shooters, Fishers and Farmers Party chairman Wayne Turale said seal relocation programs should be stopped immediately, and an inquiry set up to look at how best to deal with the mammals.
"There has been a long-term seal relocation program carried out by DPIPWE [Department of Primary Industries, Parks, Water and Environment]," he said.

"I have been told by a salmon farming operation that in the last approximately six weeks there was approximately 400 seals relocated to the north-west coast."
Mr Turale said relocating seals had a devastating effect on the north-west coast.
"It is now apparent these sea wolves are predating on Tasmania's world-renowned wild brown trout fishery, including our wild sea run browns and other estuarine species such as bream and other native fish," he said.
"These predators have also become increasingly aggressive towards humans with anglers reporting being charged by these pests whilst playing fish and engaging in legal beach netting activities.
"Boating anglers are reporting these aggressive seals following hooked fish right up to and over the gunnels of boats risking capsize.
"They [fishermen] have been landed with a problem that has been caused by a commercial industry.
"If you had some dogs that were killing somebody else's sheep, you wouldn't move them and put them on somebody else's farm."
Tassal investing in 'seal-proof' pens

It is understood Tassal is the only Tasmanian aquaculture company still engaged in seal relocation.
Tassal relocated 2,131 seals to the north-west coast last financial year.
A spokeswoman said the company had "met with multiple stakeholders in recent weeks regarding seal relocations, and understands the frustrations expressed".
"Tassal met with concerned fishermen in the north-west last week, and is committed to addressing their concerns and working together on a solution," she said.
"As part of the solution, Tassal is investing millions into new ocean sanctuary pens and enclosures.
"These pens have so far demonstrated that they are 'seal-proof, with zero breaches to date', and are being rolled out as quickly as they can be constructed across high-seal population locations and all new locations.
"Tassal ... believes that as these pens continue to roll out, there will be a significant reduction in the number of seal relocations."
Culling 'not the answer'

Mr Turale said there should be a government inquiry into the seal program like there was for fallow deer.
"This issue is every bit as big, if not probably bigger," he said.
"We would like to see all the stakeholders have a say."
Mr Turale said some fishermen believed a controlled culling program could be one solution.
"That is for other people to discuss but there certainly needs to be an inquiry," he said.
A DPIPWE spokesman said culling was not the appropriate method for managing the seal population.
"The department does recognise that some circumstances may exist, such as for human health and safety, where the humane destruction of an individual animal may need to be considered," he said.
"This is for individual animals only under certain conditions and is not used for wider management of the species."
The spokesman defended relocation as a legitimate strategy that maintained the welfare of the animals and human safety.
He said to ensure standards were kept to during relocation "the department maintains oversight through processes such as training and accreditation, audits of compliance with the minimum requirements, incident reporting and investigation as required".

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wayne Turale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian Shooters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DPIPWE</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fisher</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turale</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tassal</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Farmers Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Primary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
