<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443066104457736</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-07/wa-runaway-child-drowned-mauled-wild-animals-inquest/8781740</url>
  <title>Teen runaway with FASD ended up drowned, eaten by shark or crocodile</title>
  <content>
A 15-year-old Indigenous boy in state care who drowned and then had his body mauled by a crocodile or shark in Western Australia's top end was suffering foetal alcohol syndrome disorder (FASD), a coronial inquest hears.
Coroner Sarah Linton is this week holding an inquest in Broome into the death the boy, who drowned in 2013 after wandering away from the bush block where he was being looked after.
The courts heard he died from submersion, but his body was then mauled by either a crocodile or a shark, and had his foot chewed off.
The inquest is looking at whether the level of care provided was adequate, particularly in relation to managing the teenager's FASD and habit of inhaling solvents.
The teenager had a history of running away, and on the day he went missing had told another boy he was planning to walk to the town of Derby, 65 kilometres east across the vast King Sound waterway.
Sergeant Jamie Raper said the search was treated as an urgent matter from the moment the teenager was reported missing.
"We were very concerned ... it is a very hostile environment," he said.
"Very thick mangroves, extreme heat, and the tides and the crocodiles ... it was by far the most difficult search that I've done."
He said communications were "a nightmare".
The next morning, after an extensive search involving helicopters, Indigenous rangers and dozens of volunteers, the teenager's body was found in mangroves.
In his opening address, counsel assisting the coroner Toby Bishop described the boy's injuries.
"Forensic pathologists ... formed the opinion that the cause of death was consistent with immersion in a young man, with traumatic amputation of the left foot and multiple soft tissue injuries.
"Experts concluded that these injuries were likely to have been caused by a crocodile or shark."
'We knew he had special needs'

Department of Child Protection was alerted to concerns about the boy's wellbeing when he was a baby, and in 2011 a court order was issued putting him into full-time state care.
Court documents show the teenager was put in the care of several families, before contractor Life Without Barriers became involved, and organised for him to stay at the La Djardarr Bay community with another boy in care and several paid carers.
Life Without Barriers support worker Jack Lane described the difficulties managing the boy's behaviour, which was erratic due to FASD and substance abuse.
"I knew he had run away before ... we knew he had special needs," he said.
"There was a recognition he needed to get out of Broome, because he was getting into trouble ... and he'd be inhaling whenever he could."
In the weeks before his death, the teen had stolen a car, and was "off his head" after sniffing petrol.
Mr Lane, who oversaw the boy's care from Broome, said the bush placement was considered the best way to keep him out of trouble and away from inhalants.
"It was a nice house, they had DVDs, videos, they had everything ... and he had good carers," he said.
Mr Lane said he was shocked when he heard the teenager had run away on foot, as he considered him intelligent enough to understand the risks in walking off in such a remote area in the Wet Season.
While Mr Lane testified he had regular training in relation to managing difficult children, carer Lynton Smith who looked after the teenager full-time at La Djardarr Bay said he did not receive any training in the year he worked for Life Without Barriers.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>DVDs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Without Barriers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King Sound</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Lane</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Lane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coroner Sarah Linton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wet Season</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sergeant Jamie Raper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lynton Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Life Without Barriers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broome</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toby Bishop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Child</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FASD</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>La Djardarr Bay</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
