<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443074694392512</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/south-east/street-watch-police-still-hunting-casey-shopping-centre-pervert-and-five-arrested-in-southeast-antibikie-raids/news-story/bd20450939b094db83caccc28012e647</url>
  <title>Hunt still on for shopping centre pervert</title>
  <content>
CRANBOURNE
Police have reignited a call for information into an alleged shopping centre pervert who has twice exposed himself to female shoppers in Casey. The first incident happened on November 30, 2015, when a woman was followed by a man from a Berwick shopping centre to her car, making comments about her appearance before performing a lewd act. The second reported incident happened on April 19, 2017, when another woman was followed to her car by a man from a Cranbourne shopping centre. He also made comments about her appearance and performed a lewd act. Police believe the two incidents are related, and have released this image of a man they believe may be able to assist in their inquiries. The man is believed to be caucasian, in his early 20s, about 180cm tall, with brown hair. He was said to be wearing tradesmen type clothing.
HAMPTON PARK
Casey Crime Investigation Unit detectives arrested five people and seized drugs and weapons in raids on alleged bikie gang members in the southeast last week. With the help of Echo Taskforce, detectives executed simultaneous warrants about 6am on August 1, arresting a 24-year old Hampton Park man, and known Comancheros Motorcycle Gang associate, and seizing drugs and weapons at a Cranbourne North house. An 18-year-old woman was also arrested at the scene. Two Hampton Park men, aged 20 and 21, were arrested at separate addresses and drugs and weapons seized, while a 26-year-old man is helping police with inquiries following a raid on a Carrum Downs house.
CLYDE NORTH
Firefighters were called to a blaze at a historic homestead on Grices Rd in Clyde North on July 28. Crews were called the blaze at 9.24pm and found a large crowd of people watching. The fire was so large the glow could be seen from some distance away and the flames threatened buildings to its east. About 40 firefighters worked for an hour to bring the fire under control with multiple crews working into the evening. Victoria Police and firefighters are investigating the cause of the fire. Anyone with information is asked to call Crime Stoppers on 1800 333 000.
NARRE WARREN
Police from the Dandenong Divisional Response Unit raided a Jaguar Close Narre Warren North on the afternoon of July 27 afternoon with the help of the Critical Incident Response Team (CIRT) where several residents were taken into custody. Police later located a Narre Warren North man at an address in McCrea St, Dandenong where he was taken into custody by the CIRT. The male (born 1983) was interviewed, charged and bailed on offences including theft of motor vehicle, having a firearm and weapon while prohibited and possessing a drug of dependence (amphetamine), which were items police allege were located at the Jaguar Close address.
PAKENHAM
Police are warning people not to ignore court orders after a Pakenham man had his vehicle impounded for being disqualified and for returning a positive reading to drugs months after the fact. On 16 July 2017, the Dandenong Magistrates Court issued a court order for the man to surrender the vehicle for forfeiture but he failed to do so. On July 28 the Cardinia Highway Patrol went to the owner's home and seized his vehicle.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carrum Downs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pakenham</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dandenong Divisional Response Unit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clyde North</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dandenong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 28</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 27</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Narre Warren North</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grices Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NOVEMBER 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hampton Park</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Casey Crime Investigation Unit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berwick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jaguar Close Narre Warren North</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Critical Incident Response Team</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cranbourne North</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Casey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Narre Warren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cranbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crime Stoppers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cardinia Highway Patrol</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Comancheros Motorcycle Gang</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jaguar Close</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McCrea St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dandenong Magistrates' Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CIRT</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Echo Taskforce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
