<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443152003804832</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/news/epicentre-of-health-and-education-in-townsville/news-story/53ceec8b6682e308eb30d27f3ccecb15</url>
  <title>Ties strengthened in the name of health</title>
  <content>
JAMES Cook University and Townsville Hospital and Health Service have signed a historic Memorandum of Understanding to strengthen ties and work together in delivering health services to the city.
THHS board chair Tony Mooney and JCU vice-chancellor Sandra Harding signed an MOU yesterday in a bid to bolster their homegrown clinical workforce.
Creating a health and knowledge precinct was fundamental to the City Deal which was formalised between the Federal Government and Queensland Governments in December last year.
Mr Mooney said the MOU was only step one of the project which is a key pillar of the Townsville City Deal.
"We already have a close relationship but now that we've signed this document two senior executives will now be given the job of working together and working out how we can achieve things," he said.
"Collaboratively we can improve the opportunity for education, clinicians and professional
research going into the future."
Mr Mooney said the MOU would ensure that the two institutions were the epicentre of medical service and delivery.
"For a straight link between this and that campus - it's not so straight forward," he said.
"The interface is rather haphazard, we want to improve on some research possibilities and stay tuned, we have some announcements going forward.
"I want to build momentum to make sure we're on the radar of government at all levels."
Ms Harding said it was possible for the university to do better and more.
"We thought there were some additional things we want to do," she said.
"Both of us need further development."
Ms Harding said there were talks of closing the road between the back of the hospital and JCU's medical buildings - James Cook Drive - in order to join the campuses.
"The worst possible thing would be if we put our backs against each other," she said.
"This makes sure that we have a regular basis senior executive focus to make sure we are maximising the opportunity."
When asked about the private hospital that was proposed for JCU last year, Ms Harding said the university was still in discussions.
"The idea was and maintains that the private facility wouldn't be competing with the Townsville Hospital," she said.
"We were very mindful of what the hospital's plans were and how it could be complimentary.
"We're still on the journey with that.
"There is a need for it in our community."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MoU</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Cook University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>THHS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville Hospital</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Memorandum of Understanding</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JCU</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Health Service</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville City Deal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Mooney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Harding</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Cook Drive</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Mooney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sandra Harding</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City Deal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
