<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443109054131327</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:49</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/western-australia/wa-verge-collection-how-to-find-kerbside-gold-in-perth/news-story/ec0a3b2e0621a4f5d99053526ad3ae08</url>
  <title>How to find 'kerbside gold'</title>
  <content>
THEY say one person's trash is another's treasure and now it's even easier for Perth fossickers to find what they're looking for in verge cleanups.
Using others people's junk can save you tens of thousands of dollars and Margaret Fort is the person to show us why.
A walk along a kerbside collection with Mrs Fort is a lesson in recycling. Where we see trash she sees "possibility".
It's been estimated each Australian household produces enough landfill to fill a three bedroom house every year... well Mrs Fort can use some of that to furnish a house for next to nothing and she's done just that for friends in need.
"We did everything practically from kerbside, in fact $400 for the whole house, three bedroom, including all the Tupperware you could ask for," Mrs Fort explained.
"What's possible? Everything."
Kerbside collections are becoming increasingly hard to find as many councils move toward skip bins on demand - but a new website, vergeside.com.au has taken the guess work out by listing areas having collections.
"It's at their fingertips and they can then plan what they're doing and peruse and find lots of gold," Mrs Fort said.
But there's even more you can do with recycled materials if you think outside the box.
Leo Flavel turned recycled materials into a Gallery. He scoured kerbsides for building material and salvaged unwanted goods wherever he could... the money he saved was stunning.
"We were quoted between $350,000 and $380,000 by a builder with brand new materials and we did it as owner builder for $160,000," Mr Flavel said.
While saving $200,000 on the construction of his Maylands Art Gallery was a sweetner indeed, it wasn't the driving force in the decision to use recycled materials.
"I guess I wanted to show the community what can be done what can be salvaged how things can be repurposed."
When you see what's been achieved it seems almost criminal to think it was destined for landfill.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Flavel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Fort</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Margaret Fort</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leo Flavel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tupperware</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maylands Art Gallery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
