<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443113349098717</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/law-order/salt-creek-kidnapper-roman-heinzes-appeal-goes-straight-to-full-court-of-the-court-of-criminal-appeal/news-story/f998ba992eff004eb525f2e163ccc948</url>
  <title>Salt Creek kidnapper's appeal sent straight to Full Court</title>
  <content>
THE Salt Creek kidnapper's challenge to his conviction and 22-year prison term has been escalated directly to the state's highest court for determination.
On Monday, Supreme Court Justice David Peek opted not to hear argument on whether Roman Heinze should have permission to go before the Court of Criminal Appeal.
Instead, he said that decision was best made by a three-judge panel of the Full Court - and that those judges would decide the merits of the appeal itself at the same time.
Though neither an unprecedented nor unusual decision, the ruling does mean Heinze's case skips over the first leg of the appeal process entirely.
The three judges of the Full Court will decide not only whether it was right to find him guilty of kidnapping and brutalising two tourists, but also whether his jail term is excessive.

Heinze, 61, is  for crimes including aggravated kidnapping, sexual and physical assault, and endangering life.
All three of his victims were foreign backpackers he contacted on the Gumtree website's ride-sharing section - in defiance of bail conditions banning him from doing so.

The Advertiser's Sean Fewster and Mark Brake retrace the terrain over which the accused Salt Creek backpacker abductor allegedly mowed down one of his victims.

The chase through Salt Creek
In total, Heinze pursued 16 young women through the site.
He indecently assaulted his first victim in September 2014, molested his second three months later, and kidnapped the third and bashed the fourth at the Coorong in February 2016.
The third and fourth victims, from Brazil and Germany,  that included being run down by his four-wheel drive.
A fifth woman avoided harm after posting photos of Heinze online - he cut their trip short but remained obsessed with her afterwards.
During his trial and the initial stages of his appeal, Heinze was represented by barrister Bill Boucaut SC.

The Advertiser's Sean Fewster shows where the Salt Creek backpacker sexual abduction allegedly occurred.

Between the Salt Creek sand dunes
On Monday, former District Court judge Marie Shaw QC told the court she would now be acting for Heinze.
Justice Peek deemed it appropriate to refer both the application for permission to appeal, and the appeal itself, to the Full Court hearings in September.
He ordered Ms Shaw and prosecutor Jim Pearce QC file written outlines of their arguments ahead of those hearings.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gumtree</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Brake</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Advertiser's Sean Fewster</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salt Creek</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jim Pearce QC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Court of Criminal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>District Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roman Heinze</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justice Peek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Full Court</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marie Shaw QC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heinze, 61</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coorong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Boucaut SC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heinze</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Shaw</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Supreme Court Justice David Peek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
