<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442254355627753</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/07/12/15/second-young-woman-admits-to-murdering-adelaide-grandpa-robert-whitwell</url>
  <title>Second young woman admits to murdering Adelaide grandpa Robert Whitwell</title>
  <content>
A young Queensland woman has admitted to murdering her friend's elderly Adelaide grandfather, on the day she was set to face trial.
Eighty-one-year-old Robert Whitwell was killed in his Craigmore home, in Adelaide's north, in August last year.
His teenage granddaughter Britney Dwyer has already confessed to the crime.
Today, in the Adelaide Supreme Court, Dwyer's friend and co-accused Bernadette Burns, 21, entered a plea of guilty to murder, under Section 12A of the Criminal Law Consolidation Act.
That refers to committing an intentional violent act that resulted in a person's death. 
The court has previously heard the motivation behind the killing was a plan to rob Mr Whitwell of thousands of dollars.
Both women live in Queensland and were extradited to South Australia to face the charges in August last year. They have remained in custody since.

Related Articles

Another woman, Shelby Holmes, was given a suspended sentence after admitting to breaking into Mr Whitwell's home in the months before his death.
Mr Whitwell's relatives have described him as caring and devoted to his family.
They have also expressed disbelief that his death was at the hands of someone so close to him.
Burns' parents were in court today, but declined to comment.
Dwyer and Burns will both face court again later this month.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bernadette Burns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Law Consolidation Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dwyer</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craigmore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Whitwell</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shelby Holmes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Section 12A of the Criminal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide's Supreme Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britney Dwyer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Whitwell</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
