<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443074694392525</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/real-estate/queensland/gold-coast/auctions-on-the-gold-coast-continue-with-chills-and-thrills/news-story/bffef6d64325cab574478032b583d2b1</url>
  <title>Auctions on the Gold Coast continue with chills and thrills - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
11 Seashell Ave, Mermaid Beach.

IT might be getting cold outside but auctions are still running hot on the Gold Coast.
The team at Professionals John Henderson Real Estate are taking more than 20 properties to auction on Tuesday, August 8, for their winter auction event, "August Auction Spectacular".
Beachside mansions, riverfront homes, apartments with ocean views and townhouses from Surfers Paradise to Burleigh Heads will be offered to the market.
Among the big list of properties is a Mermaid Beach house within arm's reach of the beach at .
Agent Luke Henderson said the home offered ocean glimpses and seaside luxury.
"The showpiece of the home is the large living and dining areas, which connect through bi-fold doors to the undercover entertaining area overlooking a sparkling pool,'' he said.
CoreLogic data revealed the Gold Coast was the busiest non-capital city region last weekend, with 78 homes going to auction.
Luke Henderson said the winter auction event was inspired by the agency's summer auction event where more than $15 million changed hands in front of a crowd of 250 people in January.
John Henderson Professionals Mermaid Beach principal Andrew Henderson said it was still very much a seller's market and auctions were ideal for vendors.
"There is still strong demand from buyers looking to upgrade to properties in the Mermaid Beach and the Miami area,'' he said.
"The clear majority are Gold Coast or Brisbane buyers, but on the supply side there is limited availability of good quality homes and apartments."
Mr Andrew Henderson said the August 8 event at Mermaid Beach Bowls Club would feature properties to suit everyone. He said his agents were currently registering bidders.
11 Seashell Ave, Mermaid Beach, is going to auction on August 5.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MIAMI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mermaid Beach</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CoreLogic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surfers Paradise</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seashell Ave</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burleigh Heads</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August Auction Spectacular</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Henderson Professionals Mermaid Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Andrew Henderson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mermaid Beach Bowls Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 8</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Henderson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Henderson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professionals John Henderson Real Estate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
