<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443160593739639</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:01</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/entertainment/celebrity/controversial-diana-videotapes-reveal-her-sex-life-with-charles-intimate-secrets/news-story/04e24db9f9d8ebb1fc34d8f7f3032c5c</url>
  <title>The brutal call Diana overheard in the loo</title>
  <content>
PRINCESS Diana claimed she once spied on Prince Charles on the loo having "phone sex talk" with Camilla.
She also said that Camilla was the "raunchier of the two" after listening in on some of her husband's phone calls to his mistress,
Her claims emerged in 12 hours of footage filmed by a handpicked BBC cameraman five months before her death in 1997.
They are separate to the tapes made by her voice coach Peter Settelen, shown this morning on the UK's Channel 4.
The cameraman, who has not been named, was secretly summoned to Kensington Palace by Diana in March 1997.
Over seven recording sessions, she offloaded years of anger with the Royal Family, including how she caught Charles red-handed - or "de flagrante" - talking with his mistress.
The cameraman kept a diary of the sessions in which he wrote: "She caught Charles and Camilla de flagrante after listening in to his phone calls.
"She described how she came to listen to their phone calls. In one, Charles was sitting on the toilet seat when she caught him."
Meanwhile, Diana's most intimate secrets were laid bare before a UK TV audience of millions through videotapes made by Mr Settelen and broadcast on Channel 4.
In the tapes she discussed everything from sex with Prince Charles, her love for a bodyguard, and how the Queen failed to help when she sought advice on Charles' affair with Camilla.
The broadcast of the videotapes for the first time in the UK comes ahead of the 20-year anniversary of Diana's death later this month.
In a sign that the UK people are not ready to let go of Diana's memory, a documentary with her sons Prince William and Prince Harry two weeks ago drew an audience of more than 7.4 million viewers, and this morning's show is expected to attract similar viewing figures.
The videotapes, recorded in Kensington Palace when Diana was undergoing training with Mr Settelen in 1992 and 1993, were never intended for public release, and until now have been too controversial for release in the UK.
In the tapes Diana claims her then-husband was given permission by his father, Prince Philip, to continue his affair with Camilla, who is now Prince Charles' wife.

"My father-in-law said to my husband, 'Uh, if your marriage doesn't work out you can always go back to her (Camilla) after five years','' she tells Settleten.
"Which is exactly, I mean for real I know that it happened after five (years), I knew something was happening before that."
It was these tapes where Diana first revealed Prince Charles's response when she confronted him about his ongoing affair with his lover Camilla Parker Bowles - a line which has been reported thousands of times over more than a decade.
"I remember saying to my husband, you know, 'Why, why is this lady (Camilla) around?' and he said, 'Well I refuse to be the only Prince of Wales who never had a mistress,'' she tells Settleten.
The deeply-unhappy Princess recorded the tapes as her marriage was ending, and revealed:
*She has sex with Prince Charles only about one every three weeks.
*The royal couple's sex life dwindled to nothing after their second son, Prince Harry, was about eight years old.
*She went sobbing to Queen Elizabeth about Charles' infidelity, but the Queen replied: "'I don't know what you should do, Charles is hopeless.''
* "One of the biggest crushes'' of her life was with her bodyguard Barry Mannakee, who later died in the motorcycle accident.

"It got so difficult. People got so jealous and bitchy in this house and eventually he had to go. It was all found out and he was chucked out,'' she recalled.
"I think he was bumped off. But, there we are. We'll never know.''
She also detailed how, the second time she met Prince Charles, she told him he must be lonely following the death of his father figure Lord Mountbatten.
"I said, you know, 'Ghastly, you need someone beside you'. Oh. Wrong word,'' she said.
"Whereupon he leapt upon (me), he started kissing me and everything and I thought, 'Ahh, you know, this is not what people do,' and he was all over me for the rest of the evening, followed me around, everything. A puppy. And, yeah, I was flattered, but it was very puzzling.''
The anniversary of Diana's death on August 31 in a high-speed crash in Paris with her playboy boyfriend Dodi Fayed in 1997 has sparked a fresh round of eulogies and fond memories of the late princess.

The embarrassing revelations come at an awkward time for the royal family, which is in a state of transition.
Prince Philip, 96, retired from public life last week, while Queen Elizabeth, 91, has begun handing some duties and patronages to the younger royals.
Prince Charles has been heir to the throne for 65 years but the public has never quite forgiven him for the affair with Camilla, who seems likely to become Queen Camilla when her husband ascends the throne, despite the royal family stating years ago she would never be Queen, but rather King's Consort.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BBC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen Camilla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Well I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Philip</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Camilla Parker-Bowles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Harry</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Charles</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Settelen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Settleten</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince of Wales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen Elizabeth, 91</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Philip, 96</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Family</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princess Diana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dodi Fayed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kensington Palace</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Camilla</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barry Mannakee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princes William</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Settelen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charles</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 1997</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diana</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK TV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King Consort</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK's Channel 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lord Mountbatten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen Elizabeth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princess</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
