<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442859946024304</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/questnews/logan/logan-included-in-75m-strategy-to-improve-hospital-car-parking/news-story/02154cb4d55b93ceb6935b9b46901bad</url>
  <title>$7.5m hospital car parking strategy</title>
  <content>
LOGAN and Caboolture hospitals have been included in a $7.5 million state government plan to improve parking at hospitals.
The four-year plan, fully revealed this month, was designed to create an extra 100,000 free and discounted car parking spaces at public hospitals each year.
The four-point plan includes developing a car parking concessions policy for all hospital and health services where paid parking applies and increasing concessional car parking spaces.
Health Minister Cameron Dick said the state would continue to develop public hospital car parks including xcoming up with new parking options for Lady Cilento Children's Hospital.
In May, the Albert & Logan News revealed the state would build a $5 million, 500-space car park at Logan Hospital.
The project will almost double space for parking at the hospital and create extra parking for staff. Construction at the Loganlea Rd site was expected to start by August at the adjoining Loganlea TAFE site and finish before the end of the year.
Work has already started at Caboolture Hospital for an extra 200 car parks.
Mr Dick said the government's preferred approach was for multistorey hospital car parks financed by the Queensland Treasury Corporation.
"However, private public partnerships will be retained as an option for circumstances where it can deliver a better outcome, for example, when we are developing a large 'greenfield' hospital site," Mr Dick said.
All hospital and health services will be required to develop and publish their local hospital car parking concessions policy by October 1 and report on them annually.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LOGAN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Treasury Corporation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caboolture Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Loganlea TAFE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caboolture</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Loganlea Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Health Minister Cameron Dick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Logan News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Dick</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Logan Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lady Cilento Children's Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alberts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
