<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442602247983325</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/duo-included-in-state-team-for-senior-sides-tourna/3209615/</url>
  <title>Duo included in state team for senior sides tournament</title>
  <content>
QUEENSLAND senior sides coordinator of selectors Greg Bostock says Sunshine Coasters Louise Witton and Mary Geary add experience to a very strong squad but he's wary of the opposition.
The team - which includes 12 men and women aged 60-and-over - was announced on Monday.
It will compete at the Australian Senior Sides competition at Moonta Memorial Park and Wallaroo Bowling Clubs in South Australia in October.
And Coolum Beach's Witton and Mooloolaba's Geary were again named in the line-up, after being a part of the impressive state side in 2016.
"Louise is a very solid player. She had a very good series last year when the ladies won and she skipped a very good side," Bostock said.
"Louise has always given us a solid performance wherever she plays, bearing in mind she's played seven games in the over-60s and she's had 56 appearances for the open side for Queensland."
Geary has played 20 games for the senior side and 21 games for the state's open team.
"So Mary comes with a wealth of experience and will slot into the team well," Bostock said.
"We've only had one change in the ladies (team) from last year and they will be extremely strong."
But remained cautious of the other state and territory units.
"We should also remember we're going up against a lot of quality bowlers and we'll have to bring our best game," he said.
"We never take what we've achieved last year lightly.
"We never get complacent because Queenslanders don't do that. We go about our business very quietly and we'll give it our best and we'll see how we go from there."
Night of crashes rounds out weekend of heartbreak on Coast roads
Close call for Coast motorists as debris goes flying on motorway
Heavy rain misses most of Coast
Education, student accommodation, bars and music all key to future
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
*WARNING this story contains spoilers*
TARA Reid reveals what's coming in the next installment of TV movie.
Farmer's brave decision has cost him the game.
"It didn't seem like they were having a crazy, big night."
The news came after the couple attended Splendour in the Grass
An intimate safari is on the couple's agenda
Garth Prowd's vision made huge impact on Sunshine Coast community
Home sells in just one day
Winners in Master Builders regional housing and construction awards
Ray and Gert will celebrate 70 years of marrive this week
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garth Prowd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Senior Sides</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moonta Memorial Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mary Geary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tara Reid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mooloolaba's Geary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bostock</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queenslanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wallaroo Bowling Clubs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coasters Louise Witton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Bostock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louise</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coolum Beach's Witton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
