<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443199248445980</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/breaking-news/manus-death-sparks-concerns-for-refugees/news-story/4e73aa86cc33a965d42632fe8ade5e11</url>
  <title>Manus death sparks concerns for refugees</title>
  <content>
The death of a refugee on Manus Island has sparked calls for Australian authorities to intervene after what advocates have described as a preventable tragedy.
The immigration department says it is aware of the man's death, which is being investigated by PNG authorities.
The man is understood to have taken his own life in the township of Lorengau before he was due to move from detention into the Papua New Guinean community.
"More deaths are likely unless the Australian government acts immediately to bring these people, on both Manus Island and Nauru, to safety in Australia," Dr David Berger of Doctors for Refugees said on Monday.
The Turnbull government has consistently said refugees being held on Manus Island and Nauru will never settle in Australia.
Tensions are high on Manus Island, with water and electricity cut off to some compounds at the regional processing centre as authorities try to shuffle detainees around ahead of its October closure.
The dead man is understood to be an Iranian refugee with a history of mental illness.
"He was very sick for (a) long time but Australia did not provide medical treatment for him," Iranian journalist and Manus Island refugee Behrouz Boochani posted to Twitter.
Amnesty International is concerned he was provided inadequate health care and his safety was not paramount.
"This death is yet another bleak tragedy to arise out of the ongoing suffering and tensions on Manus Island," spokesman Graham Thom said.
"There must be an independent, impartial, prompt and effective investigation into his death."
Greens immigration spokesman Nick McKim laid blame for the man's death at the feet of Immigration Minister Peter Dutton.
"This man repeatedly sought Australia's help. The Liberals ignored his pleas and now must bear responsibility for what happened," Senator McKim said.
Readers seeking support and information about suicide prevention can contact Lifeline on 13 11 14.
Suicide Call Back Service 1300 659 467.
MensLine Australia 1300 78 99 78.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manus Island</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graham Thom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amnesty International</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PNG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immigration Minister Peter Dutton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator McKim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Behrouz Boochani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lorengau</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Call Back Service 1300 659 467</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Papua New Guinean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick McKim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nauru</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MensLine Australia 1300 78 99 78</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr David Berger of Doctors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iranian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
