<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443242198119821</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/energy/gas/woodside-petroleum-finds-more-gas-off-myanmar-20170807-gxqt4f</url>
  <title>Woodside Petroleum finds more gas off Myanmar</title>
  <content>
Woodside Petroleum has notched up a third gas discovery off the coast of Myanmar, supporting its ambitions to fast-track the development of a commercial project to supply either the local market or to be piped to Thailand or China
The Pyi Thit-1 well, which was drilled to a total depth of more than 4.5 kilometres, lies close to  in the southern part of Woodside's extensive acreage in the Rakhine Basin.
It "builds on our understanding of the potential resources in the Southern Rakhine Basin and will inform our consideration of development options," chief executive Peter Coleman said.
Analysts mostly remain cautious about the potential for Woodside's emerging position in Myanmar as they await more detail on how the gas may be developed and how profitable it may be. At Woodside's investor briefing in May, the Myanmar business was included in

Woodside,, has outlined a potential plan to develop gas in its "Southern hub" to supply either the local market or for piping to Thailand. It said gas could be developed by connecting into the existing Yadana platform, operated by Total, or as a standalone project.

The French oil major Total also owns a stake in the A-6 block holding Pyi Thit-1, as does Myanmar's MPRL E&P.
The well found gas over a depth of about 65 meters, of which about 36 metres was classified as "net pay", signalling it could yield commercial flows. The gas flowed at a rate of about 50 million cubic feet a day in a test over part of the reservoir.
The nearby Shwe Yee Htun-1 discovery, made in January 2016, found 15 metres of "net gas pay", and is estimated to hold about 900 billion cubic feet of gas.
Shares in Woodside, which owns 40 per cent of Block A-6, were up 0.9 per cent at $29.31 at 2:31pm AEDT.

Woodside has flagged a further two exploration wells in Myanmar that are due to start drilling this quarter.
Its "Northern hub" gas resources could be suitable for piping to China through existing infrastructure, Woodside has said.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woodside Petroleum</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yadana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Myanmar</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pyi Thit-1</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Coleman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Block A-6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rakhine Basin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southern Rakhine Basin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woodside</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thailand</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AEDT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shwe Yee Htun-1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Myanmar's MPRL E</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
