<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443237903152363</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:19</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/south-australia/footy-fan-condemned-for-holocaust-comment-on-facebook-after-adelaide-crows-defeat-the-power-in-showdown/news-story/642cc497ca9439417a6eda5d37e30566</url>
  <title>Idiot fan condemned for 'Holocaust' comment</title>
  <content>
PORT Adelaide Football Club has condemned a social media post mocking the one-sided Showdown as "the Holocaust".
A post on Facebook on Sunday night said "if Port Adelaide FC were Jewish, that was the Holocaust" - a message the club has slammed as "disgraceful".
The post - by an unidentified fan who shared the unofficial supporters group Adelaide Crows Pride's photo shortly after the match - also used the hashtag "#gassing" and heart emojis in Crows colours.
"The AFL and its clubs do a significant amount in the community to educate supporters around the importance of respect and equality regardless of race, religion, gender or sexual orientation," Port Adelaide general manager Matthew Richardson said.
"Social media unfortunately provides a platform at times for people to express views that set out to alarm and gain attention, and this post is clearly an example of that.
"The comments in this post are disgraceful regardless, but to connect them to a game of football is extremely disappointing."
The Adelaide Football Club had been asked for comment.

AFL: Listen in to the Adelaide Crows post match press conference.

Crows press conference
Rabbi Shosana Kaminsky of Beit Shalom Synagogue said such social media behaviour should not be given further attention.
"We are doing ourselves a disservice if we were to give them (anti-semitic comments) oxygen," she said.
"You can find millions of Facebook posts about the Holocaust and imagery that are so far out there, it doesn't do anybody any favours to draw them out."
This is the latest in a series of embarrassing examples of racism in football over the past two seasons, including  and a  about rival players.
In April,  to send a message they will no longer tolerate racial slurs from the terraces.
Meanwhile, a pitch invader had been fined and banned from the Adelaide Oval after his run paused the third quarter for several minutes while security guards escorted him off the field.

AFL: Listen in to the Port Adelaide Power post match press conference.

Power press conference
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holocaust</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shalom Synagogue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CROWS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Crows Pride</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide Power</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rabbi Shosana Kaminsky of Beit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Crows</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jewish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Football Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PORT Adelaide Football Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Richardson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide FC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
