<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443199248446008</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/finance/business/breaking-news/nz-shares-up-on-possible-jacinda-effect/news-story/c5f6a5c3db96b43bbe2a4cb4860f59d2</url>
  <title>NZ shares up on possible 'Jacinda Effect'</title>
  <content>
Sophie BootAustralian Associated Press

Share

New Zealand shares rallied on Monday, with more volume through politically-driven sectors as the September election draws closer.
A2 Milk rallied to another record, while Xero gave back some gains.
The S&P/NZX50 Index rose 25.45 points, or 0.3 per cent, to 7771.57. Within the index, 27 stocks rose, 14 fell and nine were unchanged. Turnover was $160 million.
Jacinda Ardern became leader of the Labour Party on Tuesday, taking over from Andrew Little, and the positive reaction to her ascent has been dubbed the 'Jacinda Effect''
"Everyone's just positioning themselves for the results, you've seen reasonable volumes in the leaders again - perhaps I'm drawing a long bow, but it could be the 'Jacinda Effect'," Rickey Ward, at JBWere said.
"Markets are potentially looking at some sectors - carbon, construction, electricity. A week or so ago, people were dismissing a potential change in government, and perhaps that's changed with Jacinda.
"Fletcher Building is recovering from Friday's sell-off, that's infrastructure spend, and there's good volume going through the electricity sector - all those sorts of things which seem to be big on the agenda for the left," Mr Ward said.
Fletcher Building gained 0.9 per cent to $7.95, while Metro Performance Glass gained 0.7 per cent to $1.44.
A2 Milk was the best performer, up 3 per cent to $4.80, its second consecutive record.

"It just keeps breaking new highs, a lot of analysts upgraded their numbers over the last month. It's a stand-out story, no doubt about it," Mr Ward said.
"Most analysts have come out believing they can extend their Chinese success to other parts of the world, there's a lot of support for it."
Xero was the worst performer, down 1.2 per cent to $27.02.
The stock has gained 56 per cent this year amidst positive earnings, but has fallen back over the past two sessions.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NZ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Metro Performance Glass</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Little</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rickey Ward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P/NZX 50 Index</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Ward</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacinda Ardern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Xero</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sophie BootAustralian Associated Press</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fletcher Building</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacinda Effect</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JBWere</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacinda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
