<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443242198119813</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/real-estate/queensland/millionaires-row-mansion-sells-for-mega-price-after-nearly-two-years-on-the-market/news-story/cb6d116e6a6515a2dfc532adef6dcecb</url>
  <title>'Millionaires' row' mansion sells for mega price after nearly two years on the market - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
This mansion at 109 Herron Rd, Pullenvale, has sold after being on the market for two years.

AN extravagant mansion in the 'millionaires' row' of Brisbane's western suburbs has sold for close to $4.8 million after nearly two years on the market.
The luxury acreage home at 109 Herron Road, Pullenvale, was first advertised for sale in October 2015, but has finally changed hands after lengthy negotiations.
The 1.21ha property, known as "Appassionata", sold to a local Brisbane family looking for the lifestyle Pullenvale offers.

The outlook from the home at 109 Herron Rd, Pullenvale.

It is the third highest sale price for a residential property in the suburb, according to CoreLogic, with the home next door at 105 Herron Road holding the record at $6.7 million.
The suburb is known for its secluded acreage properties and big houses, which often draw seven-figure sale prices.
Selling agent Scott Gemmell of LJ Hooker New Farm recently took over the listing of 109 Herrod Rd from another agency and soon ended up with three offers, before continuing negotiations with the buyer.

The opulent furnishings inside 109 Herron Rd, Pullenvale.

Mr Gemmell said Pullenvale still provided some good buying opportunities.
"There are homes in Pullenvale now that you'd be able to buy for less than you can create, taking into account land value and cost of construction," he said.
Property records show the owners, Demetri and Marina Ghikas, bought the land in 2002 for $175,000.

The rear view of 109 Herron Rd, Pullenvale, and its summer house.

They built the home soon after, drawing inspiration for the European design from fashion designer Oscar de la Renta's famous French provincial villa.
Mrs Ghikas reportedly came upon a picture of de la Renta's property and told her husband; "this is what I want you to build".
The house itself spans 1000 sqm and offers six bedrooms and six bathrooms, surrounded by manicured gardens.

The impressive design inside 109 Herron Rd, Pullenvale.

Every room has been created using the finest granite, limestone and marble with rich antique furnishings.
There's an abundance of crystal chandeliers, including one that lights up an opulent foyer dominated by twin French wrought-iron staircases and lined with blackbutt parquetry flooring.
The property also features a media room, library, wine cellar, open fireplace, airconditioning and ducted vacuum system, and includes a nearby summer house.

"Appassionata" at 109 Herron Rd, Pullenvale, has sold.

Despite their Greek heritage, the owners annually travelled to Italy which, is where they sourced a plaque for "Appassionata".
It's set in one of two stone pillars framing the entrance gates.
Pullenvale is 15km from Brisbane's CBD and has a median house price of $1.1375 million.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herron Rd</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hooker New Farm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marina Ghikas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Appassionata</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herrod Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Demetri</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CoreLogic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Gemmell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herron Road</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Gemmell of LJ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oscar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Ghikas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Renta</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pullenvale</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
