<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443285147793456</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/news/breaking-news/liberals-to-head-off-marriage-bill-push/news-story/34aa0e9e602b1a7c316b2d25265e9c12</url>
  <title>Liberals to head off marriage bill push</title>
  <content>
The federal government is expected to stand by its same-sex marriage plebiscite despite a push by some Liberals for a free vote in parliament.
Liberal MPs were due to meet in Canberra on Monday afternoon ahead of a joint coalition meeting on Tuesday.
Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull has made it clear any decision on government policy is not a matter for the Liberal partyoom alone, but Nationals members as well.
On Monday, senior government members were talking down the prospects of a private member's bill, arguing the coalition promised at the 2016 election no change would be made without Australians having their say.
"If we want to repair this trust deficit that people talk about in Australian politics, one of the first steps must be to allow the government of the day to keep its promises," cabinet minister Arthur Sinodinos said.
It appeared likely the plebiscite bill, which failed in the Senate late last year, would be presented to parliament a second time.
Nationals MP Andrew Broad told his local newspaper, the Sunraysia Daily, if marriage law was changed without a plebiscite it would signal the end of the coalition.
"It won't be me only, the whole show would blow up," he was quoted as saying.
"So suddenly you'd lose 16 lower house members in one bloc. Turnbull's leadership would become untenable and he'd no longer be prime minister."
West Australian senator Dean Smith has released a draft bill which would allow same-sex marriage but allow celebrants and ministers not to preside at ceremonies on religious grounds.
He has the support of at least five other Liberal MPs: Trent Zimmerman, Tim Wilson, Trevor Evans, John Alexander and Warren Entsch.
With the plebiscite bill likely to fail a second time, some senior Liberals are pressing for a postal vote which would not require legislation but fulfil the election promise of a national ballot.
Senator Smith said a postal vote was "useless".
"It's a D-grade response to what is a defining A-grade social issue," Senator Smith said.
Former prime minister Tony Abbott said the postal vote was "certainly better than ramming the thing through the parliament", but he questioned whether it would carry the same authority as a plebiscite.
Advocacy group Australian Marriage Equality has legal advice it says confirms a postal vote would be unconstitutional.
According to the advice, the government does not have the power to spend money on a postal plebiscite without first passing legislation authorising use of taxpayer funds.
Advocates say they would seek an injunction to prevent the postal plebiscite from going ahead until a High Court decision on its constitutionality.
Opposition Leader Bill Shorten said Mr Turnbull had failed to show leadership.
"There is only one reason why this failure to deal with marriage equality has dragged on as long as it has - it is because of the complete failure of leadership and weakness of the prime minister of Australia to deal with this issue," Mr Shorten told a caucus meeting.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arthur Sinodinos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunraysia Daily</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trent Zimmerman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>D-grade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Smith</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leader Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Alexander</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Marriage Equality</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nationals MP Andrew Broad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MPs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>High Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
