<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442808406416044</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/sport/dual-coleman-medallist-josh-kennedy-frustrated-with-lack-of-supply-to-west-coasts-forward-line/news-story/5ac8b7fef07789d61927c9376c8c3fe8</url>
  <title>Eagle frustrated with forward supply</title>
  <content>
JOSH Kennedy concedes he is getting frustrated at the lack of supply to West Coast's forward line as he rubbished claims it would be in the club's interests to miss finals.
The 29-year-old booted five goals in yesterday's eight-point loss to St Kilda at Etihad Stadium, with his effort not enough for the Eagles to salvage a win to keep them in the top eight.
West Coast generated 25 scoring shots against the Saints, with Kennedy, Mark LeCras and Jack Darling combining for 10 majors.
But their inability to get the ball inside their forward 50m arc lethally damaged their chances, with the team generating just 46 inside-50s for the match to the opposition's 62.
Kennedy, who remarkably sits just two goals behind Essendon's Joe Daniher in this year's Coleman Medal race after missing six weeks of football, lamented the lack of scoring opportunities.
"As a forward, obviously you do get a bit frustrated at the lack of supply," Kennedy said.
"But we have been able to make the most of our opportunities with what we've been getting.
"We've been trying to work on ways to obviously get a bit more supply because we've got guys up forward with Jack, Lecca, Crippa (Jamie Cripps), these guys who can kick some goals.
Same old story for the West Coast Eagles

"It's obviously been disappointing that we can't, but you've just got to deal with what you get."
Kennedy dismissed a lack of fitness as the reason behind West Coast's final quarter fadeouts this year.
They again led by 14 points midway through the last term against St Kilda only to be overrun.
Ninth-placed West Coast will need to win at least two, potentially all three, of their remaining home-and-away games to make finals, with Carlton (home), Greater Western Sydney (away) and Adelaide (home) to come.
Kennedy ridiculed claims that it would be a good thing if the Eagles missed finals.
"To be honest, that's absolutely rubbish ... to say that we shouldn't make finals, I don't even know how to answer that," Kennedy said.
"I think it's completely rubbish."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Kennedy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Darling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greater Western Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagles</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lecca</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast Eagles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coleman Medal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crippa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon's Joe Daniher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saints</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark LeCras</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kennedy</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamie Cripps</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
