<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442984500077776</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/news/breaking-news/qld-govt-announces-towing-industry-reforms/news-story/dcaca0c69c42fef5c84d5022bc7ad4a1</url>
  <title>Qld govt announces towing industry reforms</title>
  <content>
Queensland will become the first state to cap towing fees from private carparks as part of wider industry reforms targeting dodgy operators.
Acting Main Roads Minister Steven Miles on Monday said cabinet would introduce all 22 recommendations of an investigation into the tow-truck industry.
"We will now move ahead as fast as we possibly can to get laws drafted and into the parliament," he said.
"Given that this has already been the subject of extensive public consultation, I imagine the committee's work can be done rather quickly."
Fees will be capped at $150 for on-site release, $250 for private property towing and $348 for crash towing, following an investigation by former District Court Judge Michael Forde.
The inquiry, which launched in May, called for harsher penalties, such as increasing fines from $252 to $1513 for unlicensed trucks, with a maximum court imposed penalty of $20,184.
The recommendations also included driver accreditation, conduct requirements for operators and drivers, increased monitoring and enforcement activities and raising awareness among property owners and operators of their rights.
The probe was sparked by a newspaper report which revealed customers were being charged up to $1000 to recover their cars from impound lots.
It also found operators were engaging in predatory behaviour to trick people into getting towed.
Mr Miles said hundreds of calls and complaints had been made to a tow-truck hotline since May 9, with 31 per cent of grievances relating to practices in Fortitude Valley, Albion and Newstead.
The reforms are expected to take effect by the end of the year.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>District Court Judge Michael Forde</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albion</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newstead</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qld</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fortitude Valley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Main Roads Minister Steven Miles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Miles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
