<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442555003342544</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Coffs Coast Advocate</source>
  <url>http://www.coffscoastadvocate.com.au/news/australians-have-a-love-affair-with-diesel-engines/3208810/</url>
  <title>Australians have a love affair with diesel engines</title>
  <content>
WOULD you consider switching from a petrol-powered car to purchasing diesel? Well, according to the latest ABS census report it's exactly what is occurring.
The data, released last week, showed the portion of vehicles fuelled by diesel had grown by 57 per cent in the past five years. Meanwhile, registration of petrol- powered models had dropped from 88.1 per cent of the national fleet in 2012 to 75.7 per cent in 2017.
The nation's apparent love of diesel cars wasn't surprising given the huge increase in the number of people buying SUVs, light commercial utes and four-wheel drives - a sector where diesel tends to dominate. The Ford Ranger and the Toyota HiLux are consistently among the top sellers in the country, after all.
This change in consumer behaviour could be due to more savvy motorists looking for cost savings from fuels like diesel, or due to vehicle manufacturers reducing the number of petrol-powered models in its range.
Our advice is to consider not just the fuel type but all running costs, including depreciation, servicing and purchase costs. Doing research could save you thousands of dollars each year.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ford Ranger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SUVs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toyota Hilux</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
