<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442464809028273</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/entertainment/tv/hawaii-five0-star-daniel-dae-kim-left-show-to-maintain-his-sense-of-selfworth/news-story/b7f7b7b85aebe7b0513acb25071e73ea</url>
  <title>Hawaii Five-0 star Daniel Dae Kim left show to maintain his 'sense of self-worth'</title>
  <content>
Hawaii Five-0 Season 6 - Promo
0:30

Check out Hawaii Five 0 Season 6 - Promo. Courtesy: CBS

February 9th 2016
a year ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment - syndicated/

Daniel Dae Kim. Photo: Art Streiber

Natalie Wolfe

Share

WHEN Daniel Dae Kim and his co-star Grace Park abruptly announced they'd be leaving the hit show Hawaii Five 0, the rumour mill went into overdrive around why the stars decided to leave.
Eventually, it came to light that the two actors had left over contract disputes

Daniel Dae Kim and Grace Park on Hawaii Five 0.Source:Supplied
Kim starred on the CBS reboot for seven years, and despite commenting on his sadness at leaving Hawaii Five-0, the actor had not made a statement on exactly why he decided to leave - until today.
"That was a really important time in my life for seven years. I'm very grateful to CBS and everyone involved in the show for giving me the opportunity,"
And despite Kim being grateful for the opportunity, it was when the show failed to realise the star's "self-worth" that he decided to leave.
"That said, it's possible to be grateful to the opportunity and respectful for the colleagues and the people that I work with, but still maintain a steadfast sense of your self-worth," he added.
Kim starred as Chin Ho Kelly on the crime show but decided to leave after he was offered 10-15 per cent less than his co-stars Alex O'Loughlin and Scott Caan.
"By now many of you have heard the news, and I'm sad to say it is true,"  in early July.
"I will not be returning to Hawaii Five-0 when production starts next week. Though I made myself available to come back, CBS and I weren't able to agree to terms on a new contract, so I made the difficult choice not to continue.

"I'll end by saying that though transitions can be difficult, I encourage us all to look beyond the disappointment of this moment to the bigger picture. The path to equality is rarely easy," he ended.

Daniel Dae-Kim with Hawaii Five-0 co-stars Scott Caan, Alex O'Loughlin and Grace Park.Source:Supplied
Despite Kim saying the show had failed to realise his self-worth, immediately after Kim wrote he was leaving the show, the Hawaii Five-0 boss hit back at the star, writing they had been offered "unprecedented raises" to stay with the show.
"The truth is this: Both actors chose not to extend their contracts," producer Peter M. Lenkov
"CBS was extremely generous and proactive in their renegotiation talks. So much so, the actors were getting unprecedented raises, but in the end they chose to move on. No one wanted to see them go - they are irreplaceable."
Some fans were quick to point out that although the producer said the stars were offered "unprecedented raises", he didn't clarify if they'd been offered the same amount that O'Loughlin and Caan currently get.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Natalie Wolfe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grace Park.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Dae Kim</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Caan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawaii Five-0</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>O'Loughlin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kim</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex O'Loughlin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chin Ho Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Streiber</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawaii Five-0 Season 6</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawaii Five 0.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grace Park</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter M. Lenkov</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBS</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
