<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443328097467348</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/nsw/jean-claude-perrottet-off-the-family-leash-night-of-alleged-sexual-assault-20170807-gxqt3b.html</url>
  <title>Jean Claude Perrottet off the 'family leash' night of alleged sexual assault</title>
  <content>
Jean Claude Perrottet​ comes from a large family that describes themselves as "their own best friends".
But Mr Perrottet, the younger brother of NSW Treasurer Dominic Perrottet, was out of the gaze of his tight-knit, religious family the night he allegedly sexually assaulted a woman at the St John's College formal in 2015.
Crown prosecutor Fiona Gray gave her closing address to the NSW District Court jury on Monday, noting Mr Perrottet's family had given evidence of his good character.
"There was not a family member present that night. It was not a family function," Ms Gray said.
"He was let off that very tight family leash, of what appears to be almost constant scrutiny and high expectations."
Mr Perrottet, 20, has pleaded not guilty to three counts of sexual intercourse without the consent of the 19-year-old University of Sydney student in the early hours of October 18.

Ms Gray said evidence about a dramatic change in the woman's demeanour before and after she met Mr Perrottet at the formal's after-party helped prove what happened.
"This is a woman who was, according to her friends, excitedly running off to the after party. Other friends said she was dancing, she was having a great time."
But CCTV footage later captured the woman walking back to her college dorm room in a very different manner, wearing one shoe, and being followed by Mr Perrottet.
"This is not the woman ... dancing and having a great time. This is not a woman being physically affectionate with the accused. She doesn't look like she's in high spirits."
In the time between the after-party and their return to her dorm room, Mr Perrottet allegedly assaulted the woman under a canopy of trees next to an area of the college known as the Lemon Grove. 
The woman was quiet, shocked, shaking and crying by the time she reached her room, according to her friends' evidence.
"This is not the behaviour of a person who has had consensual intercourse," Ms Gray said.
"She had ended up on her back in a secluded area with a male she didn't know, having sex with her."
Ms Gray told the jury they should dismiss Mr Perrottet's story that their encounter was consensual, and that the woman had initiated some of the sex acts.
"It's completely at odds with every piece of evidence about their interaction. He approached her friends ... he started dancing with her, he suggested they go to a quiet area.
"He has her in the canopy area undoing his belt, undoing his pants. Then when you look again at the CCTV footage, she is not physically interacting with him in any way."
Mr Perrottet's barrister, Alissa Moen​, is due to address the jury on Tuesday.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lemon Grove</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Perrottet</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Perrottet, 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St John's College</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Treasurer Dominic Perrottet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fiona Gray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Grey</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alissa Moen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCTV</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jean Claude Perrottet</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW District Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
