<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442902895697756</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/business/property/lendlease-puts-finishing-touches-on-new-sydney-sofitel-hotel-20170807-gxqsv9.html</url>
  <title>Finishing touches going on Sydney's first new luxury hotel in 17 years</title>
  <content>
The finishing touches are being applied to the 5-star Sofitel Sydney Darling Harbour - the first luxury hotel to be developed in Sydney since the 2000 Olympics.
It will beat the opening of James Packer's integrated resort at Barangaroo and bookings are under way for 2018 to cater for the events at the adjoining International Convention Centre.

Up Next

ASX winners and losers - a snapshot

00:43

More BusinessDay Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Inside Sofitel Sydney Darling Harbour

A peek inside Sydney's first 5-star luxury hotel to open in almost 20 years.

Developed by Lendlease, the hotel is part of the $3.4 billion, 20 hectare transformation of Darling Harbour. It was designed by Sydney architect Richard Francis-Jones, from Francis-Jones Morehen Thorp (FJMT).
Neil Arckless, project director, Lendlease, Sofitel Sydney Darling Harbour, said it had come in ahead of time with practical completion due in two weeks.

The owner of the property is hotel developer Jerry Schwartz and AccorHotels will be the operator under the Sofitel brand.
Mr Arckless said the 35-storey building, dressed in a curtainwall facade of glass, had "panoramic harbour and city views" from a range of large luxury rooms.

Guests will be able to use a rooftop club lounge, meeting rooms, ballroom and outdoor infinity pool deck, as well as bars and restaurants with views of Darling Harbour and across the water to the CBD skyline.

You will now receive updates from

Business AM Newsletter

Business AM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

At ground level, there is a bar, restaurant and ballroom. Photo: Dallas Kilponen
"Darling Harbour is an area that Lendlease has worked in for over 20 years, and this hotel has given our team a once-in-a-career opportunity to help shape one of Australia's favourite places," Mr Arckless said.
"It will have a 4.5-star NABERS rating [a national rating system that measures the environmental performance of Australian buildings] and great care has gone into making it a very sustainable building."Photo: Brook Mitchell
Since the first pouring of concrete in July 2015, more than 2500 workers have contributed over 1.1 million hours to get the building to practical completion.
Mr Arckless said the vision for the precinct had been the catalyst for a resurgence in the local hotel industry. Around 1500 hotel rooms have been added to the Sydney market, including the W Hotel's 402 rooms on the site of the former IMAX Theatre, the Ritz Carlton's 220 rooms at The Star and the Hyatt Regency, formerly the Four Points Sheraton.Photo: Brook Mitchell
According to Dr Schwartz, the Sofitel will a crucial role in winning major conferences and events for Sydney.
He said there had been growing calls for new, 5-star accommodation to help Sydney compete with destinations in Asia and elsewhere, and "I believe that when the Sofitel opens it will become a landmark, setting new standards for luxury hotels in the city".
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sofitel</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neil Arckless</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AccorHotels</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sofitel Sydney Darling Harbour</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>International Convention Center</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Francis-Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ritz Carlton's 220</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>W Hotel's 402</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NABERS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darling Harbour</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jerry Schwartz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hyatt Regency</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Packer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Arckless</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BROOK MITCHELL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Four Points Sheraton.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barangaroo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BusinessDay Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IMAX Theatre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Schwartz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FJMT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dallas Kilponen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lendlease</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Francis-Jones Morehen Thorp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
