<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443293737728344</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:32</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/world/breaking-news/deadline-set-for-us-response-to-expulsions/news-story/39cf0e05f7339b197bf61129a9f4f0c9</url>
  <title>Deadline set for US response to expulsions</title>
  <content>
Associated Press

Share

The Trump administration has yet to decide how to respond to Russia's move to expel hundreds of American diplomats, but will deliver a response to Moscow by September 1, US Secretary of State Rex Tillerson says.
A day after sitting down in the Philippines with Russia's top diplomat, Tillerson said he'd asked "clarifying questions" about the Kremlin's retaliation announced last month following new sanctions passed by Congress and signed by US President Donald Trump.
The Trump administration has struggled to determine how the move will affect the US diplomatic presence in Russia.
Despite the Russian move, which seemed to plunge the two countries even further into acrimony, Russian Foreign Minister Sergey Lavrov emerged from the meeting declaring a readiness for more engagement with the US on North Korea, Syria and Ukraine, among other issues.
Tillerson broadly echoed that sentiment, saying the two countries had critical national security issues to discuss despite deep disagreements on some matters.
"I don't think it is useful to just cut everything off on one single issue," he said following his first meeting with Lavrov since the new sanctions were imposed.
"These are two very large countries and we should find places that we can work together, let's try to work together. Places we have our differences, we're going to have to continue to find a way to address those."
Tillerson also said Russia has been showing "some willingness" to start talking about a resolution to the crisis in Ukraine, devoid of real progress for years. That assessment came as Lavrov announced that the Trump administration had committed to sending its new special envoy for Ukraine negotiations, Kurt Volker, to Moscow to discuss next steps.
Yet several obstacles hang over any attempt to pursue a more functional US-Russia relationship: the new US sanctions, Russia's retaliatory move to expel diplomats, and the ongoing US Justice Department investigation into Russia's election meddling and potential Trump campaign collusion.

Fearing Trump might move inappropriately to ease sanctions on Russia, Congress last month passed new legislation that both added more sanctions and made it harder for the president to lift them. Trump and Tillerson opposed the legislation, but facing a likely veto override, Trump begrudgingly signed the bill.
Moscow's response to the sanctions was to announce it would force the US to cut its embassy and consulate staff in Russia by 755 people.
Lavrov, describing his meeting with Tillerson, said Russia and the US had agreed to resume a high-level diplomatic channel that Moscow had suspended after a previous US move to tighten existing Russia sanctions.
"We felt that our American counterparts need to keep the dialogue open," Lavrov said. "There's no alternative to that."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moscow</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Associated Press</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian Foreign Minister Sergey Lavrov</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philippines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurt Volker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Secretary of State</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tillerson</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ukraine</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lavrov</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US-Russia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Justice Department</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kremlin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rex Tillerson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
