<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442808406416096</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/sport/bryce-cotton-got-me-to-perth-wildcats-says-new-import-devondrick-walker/news-story/b84225c60df18fb19663b1e7d9213dd7</url>
  <title>"I have never seen Bryce so happy"</title>
  <content>
PERTH Wildcats import Devondrick Walker has revealed watching and hearing about Bryce Cotton's extreme enjoyment playing in the NBL played a significant part in him signing for the club.
Walker and Derek Cooke junior arrived in Australia during the weekend and started training with their new teammates today.
While Cotton won't fly back to Perth until later this month, he played with Walker in America and they remained close friends. Walker said he had followed Cotton's career closely and had seen a clear difference with how he'd enjoyed his time in Perth.
"It persuaded me to come," he said.
"I mentioned to the coaches before - I have never seen Bryce so happy. I've never seen him so alive and so animated about the game and how passionate he was when he came here.
"I've seen him over the years at other places and he didn't have anywhere near as much energy as he had here. It was definitely helpful to see him feel that way."
Wildcats coach Trevor Gleeson was thrilled with Cotton's endorsement.
Walker's addition gives the club another outstanding three-point shooter and Gleeson wants to use that ammunition to full effect during the chase for a three-peat of titles.
"With our roster, we needed a bit of scoring power from the perimeter," Gleeson said.
"With Bryce coming back, he's able to beat his man and create a rotation. Now we've just got to get our team to find him in the right spot and run the right plays and get him in the right position for the ball.
"They've got some history together and some chemistry on the court. I can't wait to see how they play out there and how they fit into the Wildcats."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gleeson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cotton</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Derek Cooke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Devondrick Walker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bryce</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bryce Cotton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth Wildcats</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wildcats</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Gleeson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walker</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
