<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442988795045248</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Ipswich Queensland Times</source>
  <url>http://www.qt.com.au/news/i-was-threatened-with-a-spear-gun-and-the-robbers-/3209643/</url>
  <title>'I was threatened with a spear gun and the robbers took off with my husband'</title>
  <content>
A MACKAY couple has told of a terrifying home invasion, where a woman was threatened with a spear gun and forced to wait in her bathroom while three robbers ransacked her West Mackay home.

Around 4pm on Friday, Lana Rosenblatt was alone at her Holland St home when three men allegedly entered her house.

Around the same time, her husband Stephen Rosenblatt had just arrived home from work when he saw a car parked in his driveway.

He called Mrs Rosenblatt to see if they could move their car, but she didn't answer.

After a couple of dials, she finally answered and told her husband they were being robbed.

Mr Rosenblatt "bailed out of the car" leaving the engine of his Madza BT50, a car he had owned for just seven days, running.

He chased the men "over the back fence" and back around to Holland St, before they jumped into his car.

"I've opened up the door," Mr Rosenblatt recalled. "They backed over the top of me, knocked me to the ground, I've gotten back up grabbed on to the bull-bar running with the car across the road.

"They've (driven) forward, and rather than get run over I jumped on the bonnet and held on."

He couldn't be sure how fast they were going, but said it was at speed.

Police search West Mackay after a home invasion on Friday.Jacob Miley

Mr Rosenblatt claimed he stayed on the bonnet from Holland St all the way to Jackson St, crossing the busy Bridge Rd.

"They came to a screeching halt, trying to throw me off the bonnet again, pointing the speargun at me through the windscreen - another bloke had a steel bar," he said.

When they pulled up, Mr Rosenblatt said he went for the guy least armed, but said he was too quick for him.

Again they took off, and he grabbed hold of the rail behind the rear window of the car and got dragged along the road, he said.

"They went to swerve into another car that was parked there (along Jackson St) and I thought bugger that and I let go because otherwise I would have got crushed," Mr Rosenblatt said.

Despite being dragged for some time, he only received cuts to his body and was taken to hospital in a stable condition.

The third robber involved fled on foot and was last seen through Mackay West State School.  but came up empty handed.

Mackay CIB officer in charge Detective Senior Sergeant David Tucker said yesterday investigators had identified a number of people they wanted to talk to and were making inquiries.

Det Snr Sgt Tucker said at this stage they were looking at every possibility of the robbery.

"It was a very dangerous situation... and we just don't want things like this, this type of crime occurring in our community," he said.

"Our detectives worked very hard on the weekend and are continuing to work very hard to identify the persons responsible."

The stolen car was later located at East Mackay's Illawong beach - and the victims of the robbery were able to recover some stolen items.

If you have information for police, contact Policelink on 131 444 or provide information using the online form 24hrs per day.
You can report information about crime anonymously to Crime Stoppers, a registered charity and community volunteer organisation, by calling 1800 333 000 or via crimestoppersqld.com.au 24hrs per day.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Detective Senior Sergeant David Tucker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East Mackay's Illawong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jackson St</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Rosenblatt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holland St</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Policelink</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Mackay</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackay CIB</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Det Snr Sgt Tucker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Rosenblatt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crime Stoppers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday.Jacob Miley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lana Rosenblatt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Rosenblatt</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Madza BT50</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackay West State School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bridge Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
