<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443152003804876</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/act-news/canberra-airport-security-workers-want-pay-parity-with-sydney-guards-20170807-gxqsp2.html</url>
  <title>'Not good enough': Canberra Airport security workers want pay parity </title>
  <content>
Security guards at Canberra Airport have called for pay parity with their Sydney colleagues, as long running bargaining negotiations with the contractor continue.  
Workers employed to screen passengers after check-in and provide other airport screening by contractor SNP Security are calling on the company to sign off on a new enterprise bargaining agreement, increasing their award pay from the current base rate of $21.13 per hour to $22.96 an hour, the amount paid to guards of the same level at Sydney Airport. Photo: Karleen Minney
Last year SNP agreed to bargain with employees represented by union United Voice, who are calling on the company to pay staff doing the equivalent work in Sydney and Canberra the same hourly rate.
The Fair Work Commission is now overseeing the negotiations after an agreement could not be reached. 
The union is seeking more training and delegates rights for the Canberra workers, while the company has offered to pay rates in line with the award, without back pay for workers and any any overtime pay to be at the award rate.
Overtime for part-time employees would not apply until they had worked more than 37.75 hours in a single week or shifts longer than 12 hours.
One security worker, who The Canberra Times has agreed not to name, said the travelling public would be surprised to learn how little security workers were paid. 

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"The wages is the most important thing for us. In Sydney they are paid more money, even though we have the same responsibility and same standards to keep," the worker said. 
"We asked them to explain why this unfair situation can stay in place, one company with different payroll. They said the reason was the two places were different operations. 
"Regular travellers know we are doing a good job. Aviation security screening staff have more responsibility than ever and it's not a normal security job."
United Voice ACT branch organiser Erryn Cresshull​ said the Canberra workers were making reasonable demands. 
"The guards at the Canberra Airport are low paid workers - their boss won't even pay them what they pay the Sydney Airport guards," she said.  
"This leaves guards feeling undervalued and frustrated. They work hard to keep everyone safe at the Canberra Airport with pressure increasing all the time. 
"They perform an essential role and need to be adequately paid for it."
In a statement, a spokeswoman said SNP was a family-owned business which "highly values our employees and takes pride in how we care for them."
"SNP Security has long-standing relationships with the unions and has always worked openly with them, in good faith, in order to meet our statutory obligations to our workers.
"SNP is delighted that the Fair Work Commission will be coming to the table to assist with the negotiation with our Canberra-based airport workers as we know this will bring benefits to the workers, the unions and our business." 
Follow Tom McIlroy on  and 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>SNP Security</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Airport</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Erryn Cresshull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Voice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra Airport</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karleen Minney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SNP</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Voice ACT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra Times</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom McIlroy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fair Work Commission</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
