<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442688147330339</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:11</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Life Hacker</source>
  <url>https://www.lifehacker.com.au/2017/08/now-alexa-will-play-music-to-fit-your-mood/</url>
  <title>Alexa Now Plays Music To Match Your Mood (Including 'Baby Making')</title>
  <content>
Alexa still hasn't been officially released in Australia. (Hurry up Amazon!) But for those who , the original and arguably best smart home assistant just added a neat new feature - you can now ask it to set the mood for you.

Amazon rolled out 500 new voice commands this week that allow you to ask Alexa to play music that caters to a number of different moods and activities. For instance, you can ask Alexa to play music for a dinner party or nap time. You can also ask for things like "hooking up music" or "baby-making music."

Each request can be further narrowed down by genre. For instance, you could ask for classical music to nap to, or hip-hop music for a workout.

Mood commands only works for customers that have Prime Music (it comes free with every Prime membership) or Amazon Music Unlimited, so you're going to have to employ a VPN to use this feature in Australia.

While I imagine asking Alexa to play "baby making music" is the fast track to not doing any baby making, I can see how asking for tunes for dinner parties, or a regular party for that matter, could actually be pretty useful.

I know I labour over playlists for pretty music every social event I'm the DJ for, passing the buck to Alexa could be a decent time saver. At the very least, it's a quick way to pull up some appropriate tunes when you're cooking, trying to relax for a few, or need a little pick me up.

Alexa already allowed you to make music requests by genre, artist, and specific song.

WATCH MORE: Home Ideas & Life Hacks

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>DJ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Home Ideas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Music</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexa</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon Music Unlimited</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexa Now Plays Music To Match Your Mood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATCH MORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VPN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baby Making</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Life Hacks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
