<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443027449751536</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/news/donna-louise-steele-murder-police-say-motheroftwo-knew-her-killer/news-story/366ebdc43ddd272ff32770f03cf3e59f</url>
  <title>Murdered mum knew her killer</title>
  <content>
A MOTHER-of-two found dead in crocodile-infested waters in far north Queensland was likely murdered by someone she knew.
Donna Louise Steele's body was discovered in a remote creek early on Sunday, four days after the 42-year-old was reported missing by her partner.
She was last seen alive on Wednesday at an IGA supermarket in Cooktown. Detective Inspector Geoff Marsh told media today the body found in Isabella Creek hadn't yet been positively identified, but investigators believed it was Ms Steele.
When asked if there were any suspects he said police had a "number of lines of inquiry" - and ruled out the killing as a random act.
"We are confident that [the killer] was a person known to her."
Inspector Marsh said inquiries in relation to her belongings, and in particular at her home, led police to suspect it was a targeted attack.
He would not confirm reports the body was found wrapped in some sort of material.
A number of Cooktown locals had already come forward with information, something Inspector Marsh hoped would continue.
Initially there had been "great alarm" when Ms Steele vanished and there was now "absolute shock" her body had been found.
"It has devastated that small community."
Inspector Marsh said he was hoping the discovery of her body would "embolden" people to come forward with information.
"The fact she was missing they might have kept it to themselves, but now a body has been found it might trigger them to come forward."
Police were supporting Ms Steele's two young children, two boys aged 8 and 10, as much as they could. The children are now in the care of their father.
Specialist homicide and scientific officers from Brisbane were being flown in to assist Cairns and Cooktown investigators as they examined multiple crime scenes.
The creek where the body was found and Ms Steele's home are among the areas police are searching carefully for clues. There is a distance of about 20km between the two locations.
Anyone with information is asked to contact police or anonymously via Crimestoppers.

Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cooktown</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crimestoppers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iGA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Isabella Creek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donna Louise Steele</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Steele</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Inspector Marsh</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Detective Inspector Geoff Marsh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
