<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443156298772260</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/breaking-news/qld-man-charged-over-dodgy-caravan-sales/news-story/ae0e5adb171655eff2172894e40260c5</url>
  <title>Qld man charged over dodgy caravan sales</title>
  <content>
A Brisbane man who allegedly sold written-off caravans will face court later this month charged with 81 separate offences.
The 65-year-old is accused of buying caravans, mostly from NSW, that had been irreparably damaged by crashes, hail and floods.
The vehicles were legally written off and unable to be registered in Australia, but the man from Manly West allegedly brought them to Queensland and put new registration plates on them.
Police claim the vehicles were then sold online to "unsuspecting" buyers.
Queensland's Drug and Serious Crime Group led the investigation.
Detective Inspector Lance Vercoe said these types of crimes were particularly costly to the community.
"Not only are a large number of people substantially out of pocket through the purchase of these caravans, but there was a significant risk with these caravans being registered without the usual testing processes and driven on Queensland roads, despite being previously written off," he said in a statement on Monday.
Insp Vercoe said people who had bought one of the written-off caravans could apply for compensation through the Office of Fair Trading.
The 65-year-old will face Brisbane Magistrates Court on August 22.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Detective Inspector Lance Vercoe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Office of Fair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland's Drug</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qld</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insp Vercoe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Magistrates Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUGUST 22</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manly West</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Serious Crime Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
