<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443328097467376</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/news/bloody-fight-erupts-in-the-stands-at-a-preseason-nfl-scrimmage/news-story/348fa9a4124e74f096f9d2f0cb9e88a2</url>
  <title>Blood pours from fan's mouth after vicious shot</title>
  <content>
FIGHTS between fans in the stands at sporting events are always stupid but this one just might be the dumbest of the lot.
In the red corner - which is fitting because his face ends up covered in blood - is a man wearing one of those corny "Keep Calm" shirts that he clearly failed to adhere to when tempers escalate.
And in the blue corner is Bruce Wayne himself. Gotham City's finest. Enemy of the Penguin, Joker and the Riddler. Your hero and mine, Batman.
It all went down at Nissan Stadium in Tennessee on Sunday (AEST) at a, wait for it, preseason training session for the NFL's Titans.
That's right, this was a scrimmage, not a game, and with only one team on the field there's a decent chance these two archrivals are actually on the same side. But that didn't stop them throwing down like they were Conor McGregor and Nate Diaz inside the Octagon.
From what a brave videographer told the the brawl started when the man who couldn't keep calm stole the phone of the Dark Knight. We can forgive him for his attempt to swipe the batphone (who wouldn't want control of Commissioner Gordon's secure line) but we can't condone what happened next.
WARNING: It gets a little graphic partway through the video.
Thankfully, a random punter was on hand to apply a headlock to the aggressor, who we have to say threw his punches like an AFL footballer pretending to handball the pill so he wasn't pinged for holding the ball.
With technique like that, we're only sending Robin to take care of you next time.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commissioner Gordon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Conor McGregor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nate Diaz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruce Wayne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Penguin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gotham City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riddler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tennessee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dark Knight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Batman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AEST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NFL's Titans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nissan Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
