<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443194953478604</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/afl/afl-news/jack-steeles-luke-shuey-shutdown-crucial-in-st-kildas-win-over-west-coast-20170807-gxqr71.html</url>
  <title>Jack Steele's Luke Shuey shutdown crucial in St Kilda's win over West Coast</title>
  <content>
Not only did St Kilda's Jack Steele play the best statistical game of his career on Sunday - gathering 26 disposals, 10 clearances, 11 tackles and booting two goals - he simultaneously held West Coast's Luke Shuey to his lowest disposal count since 2015.
Steele was superb in the Saints thrilling eight-point win over the Eagles, a victory that kept alive their chances of a first finals appearance since 2011.

Up Next

Dockers end their losing streak

01:30

More AFL Real Footy Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

AFL plays of round 20

It's all about the six pointers; Hannebery through traffic kicks a ripper, Coniglio has a claim to GOTY in Canberra, McDonald-Tipungwuti nutmegs Petrevski-Seton at the G, Billings clutch kick against West Coast and Eddie Betts is back from surgery to work his usual magic from the pocket.

The 21-year-old was exhausted post game sporting "a few knocks and bruises", and said he was pleased the Saints held onto a close game the week after they inexplicably let a late lead slip against Port Adelaide at Adelaide Oval.
"It did affect us a lot [the Port Adelaide loss]," Steele said. "If we got last week's win we would be in the eight right now.

"But it's how you look at it - yes it was devastating but we reviewed the game, knew what we had to do in the last quarter today and were able to execute that and get the win."
The Saints play a virtual elimination final next Sunday against Melbourne. Both teams are on 40 premiership points, with the Demons (10th on the ladder) ahead of the Saints (11th) by little more than 7 per cent. 

St Kilda trailed the Eagles by two-goals early in the fourth quarter but surged to lead by just over a goal for most of the term. West Coast then got within one point with minutes to go, but a Jack Billings goal with 30 seconds remaining sealed the victory.  

You will now receive updates from

Realfooty Newsletter

Realfooty Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"It was good, exactly what I wanted last week to be honest. We changed the game plan a bit, especially in the last quarter," he said.Photo: AAP Image
"There were a few structural things we changed. Especially for the last five minutes, just more players knowing where to go and knowing their role better.
"We just knew too that the season was on the line, so we did everything to make sure our season is alive."Photo: AAP Image
Steele went head-to-head with gun midfielder Shuey and not only nullified him, but hurt him and the Eagles going the other way.
"I don't know if he [Shuey] led me to the ball or what but that's definitely my best game," Steele said.
"I had a focus on Shuey around the stoppage, because he is a very good clearance player so I just played on him and was able to find the ball so I am happy."
St Kilda recruited Steele from GWS at the end of the 2016 season for a future second-round pick, and if his performances continue at Sunday's level that bit of business will look a bargain.
The Saints relied on strong showings from many of their lesser-lauded players to beat the Eagles, including Blake Acres, Koby Stevens, Jimmy Webster and Shane Savage, but coach Alan Richardson was most pleased with Steele's efforts.
"That was a really impressive game by Jack Steele today," Richardson said on Sunday.
"Shuey is an outstanding player. To be able to control him for big parts of the game and get the numbers; he kicked a couple of goals and got big clearance numbers.
"He'll always get big tackle numbers, he likes getting after the opposition. He had a really positive performance."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Petrevski-Seton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richardson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Realfooty Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagles</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eddie Betts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda's Jack Steele</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast's Luke Shuey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Steele's Luke Shuey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Real Footy Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coniglio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDonald-Tipungwuti</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jimmy Webster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saints (11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saints</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blake Acres</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Koby Stevens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane Savage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steele</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>G</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Demons (10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shuey</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GWS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP Image</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dockers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alan Richardson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Steele</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hannebery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Billings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
