<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442679557395589</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/brand/chanticleer/sims-metals-fails-investors-with-dismissive-ceo-change-20170807-gxqmrp</url>
  <title>Sims Metals fails investors with "dismissive" CEO change </title>
  <content>
The abrupt departure of the two top executives at ASX-listed metals recycler Sims Metal has alarmed the company's investors and drawn criticism from the analyst community about the way the management change was handled.
It now appears had legitimate reasons for installing a new chief executive as the company enters a new chapter following the end of a five-year transformation strategy.
But the way the management change was executed late last week has baffled the market and wiped 12 per cent off the company's share price.
Sims will not attract the same kind of attention as but it provides an important lesson for all boards when handling difficult decisions around management changes.

Brunsdon took the market by surprise on Friday by issuing a short ASX statement announcing chief executive Galdino Claro and chief financial officer Fred Knechtel were leaving the company immediately. Claro was being replaced permanently by former Asciano and Rio Tinto executive Alistair Field.

There was no explanation for the sudden departures, even after the company's shares went into freefall. Usually when a company announces a leadership change, it will organise a conference call to brief investors and analysts.
The situation was so unusual that analysts were openly critical about the way it was handled in notes to clients. Citi's Simon Thackray raised concerns about the "timing and lack of clarity".
Credit Suisse analysts were also clearly unimpressed, describing the announcement as "perfunctory," "anonymous" and "dismissive."
"Being conditioned by precedent that such significant announcements are normally chairman delivered and supported by conference call, we are surprised by the dismissive treatment of the news, although typical of SGM (Sims)."

It appears Brunsdon had to make a tough decision to dispense with Claro, who had made progress during his four-year tenure by cutting costs and getting the company back on track.
However, the company was entering a new phase and the board believed it was time to inject fresh blood into the senior ranks. This did not go down well with the chief executive, who left immediately, and Knechtel, who followed him out the door.
Brunsdon told The Australian Financial Review he was surprised by the market's savage reaction to the management change and has defended what he said was a "tough" decision.
The challenge for Brunsdon was balancing what he and the board felt was in the company's best long-term interests with the short-term disruption caused by a messy management transition.

It also highlights the pressure boards are under when they feel it is time for a management change but the CEO is reluctant to leave.
Still, Sims ultimately failed its investors by not properly communicating the reasons for the management change and negotiating a smoother transition.
Sims does not have the best reputation in this area. Credit Suisse notes that removing the chief executive also potentially avoids a second strike against the company"s remuneration report at the next annual general meeting. Last year, 31.7 per cent of shareholders voted against the remuneration report.
There have been a number of companies, including Bellamy's and Ardent Leisure, that have badly handled senior management changes this year so Sims is not alone.  its CEO change last week either as the new boss, Dig Howitt, was not around to brief the market on the day his appointment was announced.

michael.smith@fairfaxmedia.com.au

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brunsdon</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bellamy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dig Howitt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suisse</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Galdino Claro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asciano</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Tinto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fred Knechtel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SGM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SIM</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Knechtel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ardent Leisure</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX-listed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sims Metal</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ALISTAIR FIELD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Claros</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Citi's Simon Thackray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
