<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443366752173617</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/sport/football/barcelona-set-to-raid-liverpool-with-neymar-millions/news-story/4d91d9181514bbf6054d86a752bd7638</url>
  <title>Barcelona set to raid Liverpool with Neymar millions</title>
  <content>
Liverpool's Philippe Coutinho celebrates after scoring.

Alec ShiltonThe Sun

Share

BARCELONA believe they have Philippe Coutinho in the bag.
The Catalan giants are confident of landing the Liverpool playmaker in a $148 million deal this week.
Jurgen Klopp's Reds are determined to keep hold of the Brazilian and rejected an opening $118m approach.
But Barca are flush with cash following the $325m sale of Neymar to Paris Saint-Germain and are now preparing a fresh five-year deal.
Kop boss Klopp has insisted Coutinho, 25, is not for sale.
The German now faces a battle to keep hold of the 27-cap South American.

Liverpool's Philippe Coutinho controls the ball during the final of the Premier League Asia Trophy.Source:AFP
The transfer could become the joint second biggest in history and match the $148m deal that Manchester United struck with Everton to sign Romelu Lukaku - of which they paid $123m upfront.
Coutinho was absent from the Reds' 2-1 friendly win over Athletic Bilbao in Dublin on Saturday with a back complaint.
Klopp said: "Phil had back problems so there was no reason for any risks."

Barca are also closing in on a $148m deal to sign Ousmane Dembele from Dortmund.
The France winger, 20, turned down a move from Rennes last summer because he did not want to sit on the bench.
NEYMAR WILL MAKE PSG BEST

Paris Saint-Germain's Brazilian forward Neymar.Source:AFP
Paris Saint-Germain midfielder Javier Pastore has pledged Neymar that his new club will help him become the best player on the planet.
Neymar became the most expensive player in history when the Ligue 1 giants snatched the 25-year-old Brazilian from Barcelona after paying the 222 million euros ($264m) release clause.
Neymar was joyously welcomed at Parc des Princes on Saturday night at his official unveiling before PSG's opening Ligue 1 win over Amiens.
"He's one of the best players in the world. He's a decisive player, who scores goals. The whole team are going to help him become the best player in the world," vowed Pastore.
"For us it's fantastic, we're thrilled that he's come here," added Pastore, who has relinquished his No. 10 shirt to the Brazilian star.
"We're waiting now for him to play to start to help us win everything this season." Red tape forced Neymar to skip his hoped for debut in Saturday's 2-0 win as his international transfer certificate wasn't lodged in time with the French league, meaning he had to watch Pastore and his new teammates from the stands.

Brazilian forward Neymar waves to the crowd.Source:AFP
The Argentinian suggested Neymar will feel at home at the Paris club. "Our style won't change with him, we have a possession-based game like Barcelona, with lots of movement." Pastore said it had been an easy decision to give him his jersey. "I knew that he wanted to have the No. 10. I know that for the club it's important to have a No. 10 like Neymar for all that that represents.
"For me to return to No. 27 isn't a problem, I really like that number. I'm happy to have worn the No. 10 between 'Ibra' (Zlatan Ibrahimovic) and before Neymar." Despite all the drama and intrigue surrounding his departure from Barcelona Pastore described Neymar as "laid-back and reserved".
One of his other new teammates Adrien Rabiot said Neymar was "a cool guy, balanced, who has the right spirit, joyful".
The French midfielder disclosed: "On Friday we got him to sing. He was up for it straight away. You can see he's really happy to be here.
"That's what he's told us in any case, I reckon he means it." Neymar's compatriot Dani Alves said his role in Neymar's arrival had been minimal.
"I didn't interfere. The only thing I said to him was 'Be happy and make the right decision, whether that's staying at Barca or coming here'."

Paris Saint-Germain's Brazilian forward Neymar gestures as his arrives during his presentation.Source:AFP
Alves, who played with Neymar at Barcelona, said that rather than persuading Neymar to move to PSG, it had been Neymar who had advised him to move to Paris from Juventus this summer.
"Contrary to what people think, it was he who advised me to sign for PSG," said Alves after Saturday's game. "It wasn't me who was telling him to come here." He added: "We hadn't arranged to both come here. There was no plan, but when he suggested I join PSG, it was supposedly because he was going to come too."
with - AAP

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parc</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jurgen Klopp's Reds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Romelu Lukaku</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pastore</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barcelona Pastore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Juventus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neymar.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adrien Rabiot</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South American</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coutinho</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Athletic Bilbao</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris Saint-Germain</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NEYMAR WILL MAKE PSG BEST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liverpool</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PSG</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dani Alves</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dublin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ousmane Dembele</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alves</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazilian</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Argentinian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philippe Coutinho</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris Saint-Germain's Brazilian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Everton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amiens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Klopp</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manchester United</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zlatan Ibrahimovic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barca</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ibra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier League Asia Trophy.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alec ShiltonThe Sun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dortmund</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liverpool's Philippe Coutinho</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neymar</name>
    <count>18</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catalans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rennes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barcelona</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ligue 1</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Javier Pastore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
