<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443250788054469</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:22</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-07/burgoyne-feeling-positive-about-playing-on</url>
  <title>Burgoyne 'feeling positive' about playing on</title>
  <content>
Shaun Burgoyne is keen to play on in 2018

SHAUN Burgoyne wants to take his outstanding career into a 17th season, saying he has the enthusiasm and form to continue.

The 34-year-old Hawthorn utility said the plan remains to wait until the end of the season and then sit down with the club to discuss his playing future.

The four-time premiership player - one at Port Adelaide and three with the Hawks - has played every game this season for a career total of 338.

"I'm feeling quite positive about potentially playing on next year," he said.

"You have to stay injury-free at my age, you have to get a kick and I've been able to play (a lot of) positions - that's definitely helped my career."

While Burgoyne is one of Hawthorn's most senior players, he is free of any formal leadership duties.

The utility nicknamed 'Silk' for his sublime skills said not being a part of the leadership group was helping in the latter stages of his career.

"I just rock up, come to training, get out and if I want to talk to Clarko (coach Alastair Clarkson), I will go into his office and I will sit down and say 'mate, I want to chat to you about something'," Burgoyne said.

"I'm very confident in myself that I can talk to any of the coaching group or the players - and I don't like being in those meetings.

"So mentally, I'm pretty good.

"When I get out of here I go home, talk to my kids about footy and Auskick and school and I watch a lot of NRL, so I don't get bogged down by the constant AFL hammering."

Burgoyne is acutely aware that the end is coming - teammate Luke Hodge will retire at the end of this season, as will former Hawk Sam Mitchell.

He was in the same 2000 draft as St Kilda legend Nick Riewoldt, who also announced last week that this season will be his last.

"You have a little bit of a bond, because you are of the same age and you're fighting the same things - time, age, the game, younger players coming through," he said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shaun Burgoyne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Silk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Riewoldt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burgoyne</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawk Sam Mitchell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Auskick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alastair Clarkson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Hodge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
