<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442602247983293</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/entertainment/confidential/shock-end-to-episode-4-of-got-who-has-been-killed/news-story/a40249603d058605e56c8527ae9ca20b</url>
  <title>Who is dead in Game Of Thrones?</title>
  <content>
IT'S the shortest episode of the season but Spoils Of War packed a tonne of events in and was more of a blast than a burst of fire from an angry dragon.
Get set for some huge spoilers as we look through what happened.
There were some great reunions, including a double Stark meeting, Jon and Theon getting angry, Brienne and Arya and what was billed as a battle but was pretty much a massacre of the Lannister army. They are toast. Literally, after the dragons finished with them.
And have we seen the death of one of the series most popular characters in Jaime? Let's discuss.
First of all we see Jaime, Bronn and the Tarlys returning from Highgarden with the spoils of conquest, including a fat bag of gold for Bronn. Our favourite Sellsword is back and this time he wants Highgarden as his home. Jaime, however, is still feeling the effects of his chat with Lady Olenna, so isn't in the mood for frivolity.
"Oh aye, Cersei's reign will be quiet and peaceful," Bronn tells him, much to everyone's amusement except Jaime. And Cersei, who'd probably have The Mountain skin him alive for that.
Talking of Cersei, she's handing over the Highgarden gold to the Iron Bank and in return will get even more cash to spend on mercenaries and more ships. She'll need to watch out for that honeymoon rate though. The banks always get you with that one...
More interestingly, Littlefinger gives Bran the catspaw dagger. Now this is very strange. Surely Littlefinger knows that Bran can see everything? So why hand him the dagger that "started the war of the five kings"? If not, he does now, given that Bran quoted him the "Chaos is a ladder" line.
We also see that the National Disability Insurance Scheme has come to Winterfell, with Bran enjoying a nice new wheelchair. Surely Littlefinger will need something similar soon, when Bran reveals what Lord Baelish has been up to.
Then it's time to find out that Bran has about as much compassion as a White Walker when Meera comes to bid him farewell. Only he's not really Bran: "I remember what it feels like to be Brandon Stark". That's colder than a long winter. Anyway, Meera is off to see her family. Maybe she'll chat with her dad, the only other living person who knows the truth about Jon Snow's parentage ...
Then it's time for Arya to arrive at Winterfell, although not before meeting the stupidest guards in the entire north. If Jon Snow is counting on these morons to turn back the Night King, it's going to be a very short final battle because these two couldn't find their own backsides, even if they could use both hands and a list of instructions.
Still, it means Sansa and Arya can meet in from of Ned Stark's tomb. It's an emotional meeting place but you wouldn't guess it from their reactions. In fact it's about as warm and fuzzy as an ice dagger. Still, the proper Stark Reunion, when they go and see Bran is a little better. Bran's even a bit happier to see Arya than he was to see Sansa. So happy that he gives her the catspaw dagger and hopefully we can get to see her use it on Littlefinger later.
Even though there weren't any tears, it's still a lovely moment and it keeps them coming when we see Jon putting the moves on Daenerys.
"Come up to my hotel room and check out my etchings," he tells her. "They're on dragon glass."
Well, sort of. It's actually a great big cave full of the stuff, with plenty of drawings in it left by the Children Of The Forest. Would have been nice if they had left some instructions on best ways to kill the Night King but it's a start. It reveals men and COTF fighting together against White Walkers, which Jon then uses to make a point about alliances to Dany.
But she's too smart to fall for a simple line.
"I will fight for you ... when you bend the knee," she tells him. "Isn't their survival more important than your pride?"
She's too quick for him, because he's working too hard on looking brooding and moody. It slows your reaction time. Anyway, the Unresolved Sexual Tension is strong enough to cut dragon glass, even if she is his aunt. (Ewwww!)
Before Ser Davos can say: "Get a room!", Tyrion turns up with more bad news. His plan has stuffed up again.
"I'm done with clever plans," says Dany, deciding to order one of those snazzy T-shirts with Lady Olenna's slogan: "You're a dragon. Be a dragon".
Jon stops brooding long enough to point out that if she blows up King's Landing with dragons, then she's no better than Cersei and might as well sleep with her own relations. Maybe even a nephew! Ooops...
While Dany thinks about that, we're back to Winterfell where Brienne is kicking Pod's arse in a fight. Then Arya turns up and shows she's like some crazy GoT ninja, if Westeros had ninjas. The only person more surprised than Sansa is Littlefinger, who's feeling very glad he wore the brown leather trousers that day.
Then it's back to Dragonstone, where Ser Davos is making a move on Missandei. Little does he know about Grey Worm but it does appear that he's trying to show Missandei that there's more than one cunning linguist on this island.
Theon arrives and Jon shakes him warmly by the throat. Theon wants help to save Yara and redeem himself. Again. Only Dany is elsewhere. And we're about to find out where ...
Jaime, the Lannisters and Tarlys are heading back to King's Landing with the Highgarden goodies, minus the gold, which went on ahead. As always, it's more important to pay the bank than feed the people and it's good Jaime has realised this.
However, he's about to learn an even better lesson - don't take on an angry dragon.
This was billed as a big battle but it's more of a big massacre. A Dothraki charge forces the Lannister and Tarly soldiers to cluster up close, where Drogon can incinerate more of them. Then the Dothraki chop what's left to bits.
Jaime acts - well he thinks heroically but really it's massively stupid - and is saved by Dickon Tarly at first, while Bronn tries to take on the dragon with one of Qyburn's crossbows. Dany helps out by thoughtfully flying Drogon right at the giant crossbow, rather than attacking from the side or rear LIKE A SENSIBLE PERSON MIGHT DO. Drogon cops a spear in the shoulder and Jaime sees his chance to charge at Dany and the dragon.
Tyrion, who is watching the slaughter in horror, has time to call: "You f***ing idiot!" at his big brother, who is about to get toasted, until Bronn (who has miraculously escaped being toasted himself when Drogon blew up the crossbow) tackles him off the horse and the pair fall into the lake.
Now, they are both wearing armour and should certainly drown, especially as Jaime only has one hand and can't get out of all that heavy steel but the narrative doesn't call for Jaime to die yet, so I suspect there will be some miraculous escape next week.
Still, the stage is set for everyone, like the First Men and COTF, to unite to fight the White Walkers. Cersei has no army, so she has to talk, if only to make enough time to hire some Sellsword companies. Could we have a three-way meeting next week? Time will tell...
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tarlys</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>COTF</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>STARK REUNION</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ooops</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qyburn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ned Stark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bran</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Night King</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jon</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Disability Insurance Scheme</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Highgarden</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>First Men</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Winterfell</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>T-shirts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lady Olenna</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spoils of War</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Game of Thrones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daenerys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ser Davos</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dany</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arya</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Missandei</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jaime</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Children of the Forest</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iron Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grey Worm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dragonstone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dickon Tarly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dothraki</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lannister</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meera</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Littlefinger</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brienne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jon Snow</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tyrion</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sansa</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LIKE A SENSIBLE PERSON MIGHT DO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brandon Stark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Drogon</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cersei</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lord Baelish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westeros</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Unresolved Sexual Tension</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bronn</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theon</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White Walkers</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King's Landing</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
