<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443375342108373</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/afl/more-news/match-review-panel-hands-down-penalties-for-brodie-grundy-tom-hawkins-zach-merrett-shane-mumford/news-story/867a02b6008044ca2fc718617d1a0d14</url>
  <title>Hawkins faces two week ban by MRP</title>
  <content>
BRODIE Grundy has received a three-match suspension for his tackle on Kangaroo Ben Brown.
And Tom Hawkins can accept a fortnight-long ban for his jumper-punch.
Grundy can have the ban reduced to two weeks if he elects to submit an early guilty plea.
The Magpie's tackle was assessed as "careless with high impact to the head".
"Based on the available video evidence and a medical report from North Melbourne Football Club, the incident was assessed as careless conduct with high impact to the head," the panel said.
AFL DAILY:
ROBBO:
"The incident was classified as a three-match sanction. The player has no applicable record with impacts the penalty. An early plea enables the player to accept a two-match sanction."
Grundy's tackle divided opinion, with past players agreeing with Collingwood coach Nathan Buckley's assessment that the Magpies ruckman laid "the perfect tackle".
"That is how the modern player is taught to tackle. Pin an arm, pin a lever and take to ground so the player can't get involved in the next play," former Port Adelaide star Kane Cornes said.
"He's got the ball. Accidents do happen."
Collingwood premiership captain Nick Maxwell says Grundy's intent was to stop Brown from disposing of the ball and not to hurt the Kangaroos spearhead.
Brown still doesn't remember anything from Saturday night, after being tackled from behind, but said it is a "vulnerable" feeling when the arms are pinned.
Brown said today that he "kind of feels bad" for Grundy.
Brown is at Arden Street today after spending most of Saturday night in the Epworth hospital following the tackle that is certain to be scrutinised by the panel today.
A determination on Grundy's fate is expected before 5pm.
Brown said he is "feeling really good" but admitted he is sympathetic toward the Magpie.
"He sent me a text and that was really nice to see from him," Brown said at the club today.
"And I think he was really remorseful afterwards.
"I've seen a little bit of the vision of what he had to say (on Channel 7 after the game) and I kind of feel bad for him as well because these kind of decisions are really split-second ones in games, so I hope he's feeling all right as well.
"I've looked back at it and it didn't look like Brodie was trying to hurt me in any way. It's always difficult when you're in those situations because we are taught to tackle to pin the arms and to try to get a guy to ground.
"So I can appreciate that it was a really split-second decision and I obviously don't have any hard feelings towards him."
Brown said he had a headache for a lot of yesterday that has since subsided, and has had CT scans that have returned positive results.
He will face further concussion tests tomorrow and will be given as much time as possible before a call is made on whether he will face Hawthorn in Launceston this weekend.
"It has to try and come down to their intent because sometimes that tackle will happen 20 times and once someone will get knocked out, the other 19 times could be exactly the same and they don't get knocked out," Maxwell said on Channel 7.
"You can't ask a player to make that decision in half a second, he's just trying to lay the tackle, if his intent is to pick him up and smash him into the ground, you can clearly see that.
"His intent there wasn't to grab him and smash him into the ground. I think we're making it so hard for the players to try and come up with a decision in that half a second."
Tribunal guidelines state that a tackle is considered dangerous if it consists of more than one action, is of an "inherently dangerous kind" like a spear tackle, if the player being tackled is in a vulnerable position - with specific mention of arms being pinned - or if "an opponent is slung, driven or rotated into the ground with excessive force".
JON RALPH:
OPINION:
Hawkins was charged with striking Dane Rampe but due to his previous poor record, his two-match sanction was increased to three games with a one-game discount on offer if he pleads guilty.
"Based on the available video evidence and a medical report from the Sydney Swans Football Club, the incident was assessed as intentional contact with low impact to the face," the panel determined.
Hawkins came under scrutiny for two incidents in Geelong's disastrous loss to Sydney on Friday night: a punch to Callum Mills' chest and a jumper punch to Dane Rampe's throat.
Hawkins was the first victim of the MRP's tough stance on jumper punches when he was banned for a week for a clash with Adelaide's Matt Crouch.
He also copped a week for punching GWS co-captain Phil Davis last year.
"We know there's a crackdown, he's done it again, he's a recidivist, this is the fourth time he's done it in 18 months," former tribunal member Daniel Harford said today on RSN927.
"He'll get two weeks for that. It's an absolute shambles for Geelong.
"They (the Cats) should be rightly as annoyed as possible with Tom Hawkins for what he did on Friday night. It was just the stupidest thing."
Hawkins' teammate Mitch Duncan was also charged with striking for his chest whack on Swan Tom Papley, with the incident assessed as "intentional conduct with medium impact to the body".
Shane Mumford was offered a one-match ban for rough conduct on Max Gawn, while Bombers Brownlow hope Zach Merrett was charged with striking Carlton's Lachie Plowman and offered a one-match suspension after it was deemed to be intentional conduct with medium impact to the body.
Joe Daniher was offered a $1500 fine for striking Blaine Boekhorst, with Josh Jenkins fined $1000 for wrestling, with Jackson Trengove also charged with a third wrestling offence against the Crow and hit with a $2500 fine.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dane Rampe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MRP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Buckley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CROWS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JON RALPH</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arden Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maxwell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swan Tom Papley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jackson Trengove</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Daniher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Jenkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grundy</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magpies</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL DAILY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blaine Boekhorst</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Launceston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch Duncan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide's Matt Crouch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton's Lachie Plowman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Epworth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane Mumford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 7</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ROBBO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brodie Grundy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kangaroo Ben Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Max Gawn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phil Davis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GWS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawkins</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brodie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bombers Brownlow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Harford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RSN927</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Callum Mills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brown</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zach Merrett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kane Cornes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Hawkins</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Swans Football Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Maxwell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Melbourne Football Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
