<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442902895697731</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:01</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/10000-people-set-to-flock-to-new-coast-festival/3209648/</url>
  <title>10,000 people set to flock to new Coast festival</title>
  <content>
A MASSIVE, two-day festival of sports, live music, food trucks and drinks are coming to the Coast.

Event People director Scott Hollow said the Beach Carnivale music, sports and food festival was confirmed to head to Cotton Tree on October 21-22.

Amusement rides, a beer, cider and wine hall, live music and 15-20 food trucks, a mixture of local and external, will be the support acts to a weekend of fast-paced, fun, social sport.

Dodgeball, skateboarding, three-on-three basketball and half-court netball will all be played at the popular Coast suburb in what Mr Hollow hoped would become a family-friendly annual event.

He expected more than 10,000 people to attend the new festival.

"It's about being fun and family-friendly," he said.

He said the sporting events would be run by local sporting organisations who could share in the entry fee takings and hopefully boost their memberships in the process with the exposure, with his company taking care of the marketing.

"One hundred per cent (we hope to make it an annual event)," Mr Hollow said.

"The target market is families to come down."

Mr Hollow said the Sunshine Coast Council had been keen to get the event up here, and he said there was also scope for the Australian Beach Games, a more extensive beach sports festival, to also be established on the Coast.

The website is being finalised and registrations are set to open soon for the event, which is open to punters to form a team and get involved.

Night of crashes rounds out weekend of heartbreak on Coast roads
Major crime spike hits local residents and businesses in small town
The plane you need in an emergency
Coast's vulnerable better off amid plans to build affordable rentals
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
New celebrity cooking show fails to fire for Seven.
The legendary creator isn't so sure about how Netflix works.
*WARNING this story contains spoilers*
TARA Reid reveals what's coming in the next installment of TV movie.
Farmer's brave decision has cost him the game.
"It didn't seem like they were having a crazy, big night."
Garth Prowd's vision made huge impact on Sunshine Coast community
Home sells in just one day
Winners in Master Builders regional housing and construction awards
Ray and Gert will celebrate 70 years of marrive this week
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garth Prowd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hollow</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beach Carnivale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Hollow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tara Reid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Beach Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cotton Tree</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
