<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442426154322144</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/aussie-cafe-charges-men-18-gender-gap-surcharge/3209585/</url>
  <title>Aussie cafe charges men 18% 'gender gap' surcharge</title>
  <content>
A MELBOURNE cafe that caused a social media storm after charging men a tax and seating women first insists it has had a stack of support.

And not just from the girls.

Handsome Her, a vegan cafe in Brunswick, said it was charging men 18 per cent more in a bid to address the gender pay gap.

The cafe, which clearly advertises its rules on a chalk board, explained men will be charged the premium - and the gap donated to women's services.

However co-owner Alex O'Brien told Seven News the surcharge, which is in place one week out of every month, wasn't compulsory.

She also said none had so far refused to pay it and in a Facebook post overnight said the idea has been well supported overall.
"If people aren't comfortable paying it or if men don't want to pay it, we're not going to kick them out the door," she said.

"It's just a good opportunity to do some good."
The idea has caused a mixed reaction on social media, with some supporting the concept.

Writing on its Facebook page overnight, the cafe insisted it was jam-packed with customers over the past few days who have supported the cause.

It also insisted it wasn't just women who were backing the idea.

"We've had men travel across town to visit us and pay 'the man tax' and throw some extra in the donation jar - guys, you're pretty neat," the post read.

The cafe also thanked its staff who have taken it all in its stride.

"It's not every day that your boss pulls you into her fire-pit of feminism and you have to quickly become warriors and defend where you work and what you do on a level that others never do," the post continued.

"You have not only been incredibly strong, proud and supportive, but nurturing and protective as well."

Close call for Coast motorists as debris goes flying on motorway
Heavy rain misses most of Coast
Planning documents lodged on behalf of site owners
Five dates through August for community to have its say on rock wall
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
TARA Reid reveals what's coming in the next installment of TV movie.
Farmer's brave decision has cost him the game.
"It didn't seem like they were having a crazy, big night."
The news came after the couple attended Splendour in the Grass
An intimate safari is on the couple's agenda
Blue Murder was the original true crime blockbuster.
Garth Prowd's vision made huge impact on Sunshine Coast community
Home sells in just one day
Winners in Master Builders regional housing and construction awards
Ray and Gert will celebrate 70 years of marrive this week
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brunswick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garth Prowd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blue Murder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tara Reid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex O'Brien</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seven News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
