<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443152003804850</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:59</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/federal-politics/political-news/breakthrough-hiv-drug-authorities-reconsider-decision-to-block-cheap-access-20170807-gxqrhq.html</url>
  <title>Breakthrough HIV drug: Authorities reconsider decision to block cheap access </title>
  <content>
People at high risk of HIV could soon get cheap access to a breakthrough preventative drug as federal health authorities revisit their decision to refuse a taxpayer subsidy.
More than 30,000 Australians could benefit if the pharmaceutical benefits advisory committee approves the listing of Truvada and a generic version of the drug next week.

Up Next

'I came out as gay at 76'

02:00

More National News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Sexual transmission of HIV can be stopped

A University of NSW Kirby Institute surveyed 343 couples, one with HIV and the other without and the findings have been described as "revolutionary".

HIV advocates say the antiretroviral drug is so popular among gay men - the people most likely to contract the virus - it could slash the number of transmissions across the country. It is believed to be up to 95 per cent effective in preventing HIV infection.
But at the moment the drug is prohibitively expensive - about $1200 a month - for those who are not part of government-funded trials. It can be imported from overseas for a fraction of that but the difficult process deters many potential users.

The drug was approved for use as a pre-exposure prophylaxis (PrEP) last year but the advisory committee subsequently announced it had rejected a proposal to list it on the benefits scheme, deciding the price set by the drug's sponsor, Gilead Sciences, was too high.
Gilead and generic producer Mylan Australia have since submitted fresh applications, which were considered by the advisory committee last month. A decision will be announced on August 18.

The Australian Federation of AIDS Organisations chief executive Darryl O'Donnell​ believes a positive decision is likely.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"We think that PrEP is absolutely central to ending HIV transmission in Australia and we're very hopeful - and reasonably confident - that the [advisory committee] will find these are cost-effective," he said. "With two sponsors coming with applications the government is in a much better position to be able to negotiate a fair price for these drugs."Photo: Jeff Chiu
With the drug already approved for people who have HIV, the panel's decision will be based largely on cost. If the advisory committee approves the drug it will still need to go through formal price negotiations - and quality and availability checks - before being approved by the Turnbull government.
That process would take several months, however, Health Minister Greg Hunt has promised the government will sign off on recommendations of the advisory committee "without fear or favour".
Greens leader Richard Di Natale said it was "absolutely clear" that affordable access to the drug was a key step in eliminating HIV in Australia.
"Until this critical medication is listed it will remain out of reach for many at-risk Australians, needlessly putting them at risk of contracting HIV at a time when we should be doing all we can to end HIV transmission in Australia," he told Fairfax Media.
Mr O'Donnell says while PrEP is a major piece of the puzzle it is not the "magic bullet".
It is just one element of a new "HIV blueprint" that he says would effectively end HIV transmission and cost the government only $32.5 million a year - not including the cost of PrEP subsidies. Mr O'Donnell says the plan would prevent thousands of people contracting the virus and eventually deliver $2 billion of federal budget savings.
The blueprint - which focuses on better prevention, testing and treatment programs, new advocacy campaigns and more workplace support - will be presented to federal MPs this week. 
Mr Hunt is expected to meet with Mr O'Donnell next month. "I look forward to reviewing the plan and meeting with the group to discuss their ideas," the minister said.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gilead Sciences</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darryl O'Donnell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HIV</name>
    <count>13</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeff Chiu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Di Natale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kirby Institute</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Health Minister Greg Hunt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gilead</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUGUST 18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hunt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Federation of AIDS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr O'Donnell</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Truvada</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mylan Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
