<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443199248446037</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/entertainment/celebrity/hilary-duff-gets-ultimate-revenge-against-body-shamers-after-posting-impassioned-speech-on-instagram/news-story/63aaf83c4acd265fc430f72869b96f5b</url>
  <title>Hilary Duff's ultimate revenge against body shamers</title>
  <content>
SHE clapped back at body shamers, and now Hilary Duff has got the ultimate revenge by revealing more.
After the 29-year-old of herself in a one-piece swimsuit - telling critics to "kiss my ass" - Duff has gone one step further to silence the haters by rocking an even skimpier two-piece bikini while on Holiday in Hawaii.
The mum-of-one looked tanned and toned as she proudly walked up the Maui beach - proving she wasn't going to let anything ruin her holiday.

Earlier, on people who criticise women's bodies.
The Younger star is holidaying in Hawaii where she has been getting in some quality time with her son. But her trip was interrupted when trolls began picking apart her "flaws" after bathing suit pictures shot by paparazzi emerged.
Clapping back, Duff posted one photo taken by a pap which showed her from behind in a one-piece swimsuit as she carried her son.
Alongside the snap, she told fans she was revealing her "flaws" and posted it "on behalf of young girls, women, and mothers of all ages".
"I'm enjoying a vacation with my son after a long season of shooting and being away from him for weeks at a time over those months.
"Since websites and magazines love to share 'celeb flaws' - well I have them!
"My body has given me the greatest gift of my life: Luca, 5 years ago.
"I'm turning 30 in September and my body is healthy and gets me where I need to go.
"Ladies, lets be proud of what we've got and stop wasting precious time in the day wishing we were different, better, and unflawed.
"You guys (you know who you are!) already know how to ruin a good time, and now you are body shamers as well. #kissmyass."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>DUFF</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MAUI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luca, 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawaii</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hilary Duff</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
