<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443203543413369</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/real-estate/queensland/south-east/crowd-gathers-to-watch-bidders-drive-price-of-home-with-man-cave/news-story/a2bee72444f6ad095dbbfa5c07b593de</url>
  <title>Crowd gathers to watch bidders drive price of home with man cave - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
15 Justin Street, Holland Park West.

A four-bedroom, two-bathroom home with anat Holland Park West has sold for $1.07 million at auction.
The property at , went to auction on Saturday.
Professionals Style Real Estate - Brisbane selling agent Peter Elisseos said the Art Deco home had a fantastic modern twist, bringing the outdoors in for year-round entertaining.

Check out the man cave at 15 Justin Street, Holland Park West.

The property features a security system, polished timber floors, pedestrian gate and solar hot water. Mr Elisseos said the buyers were an older couple who were keen to move in as part of the next chapter of their lives.
"They loved the feel of the area and the place in general," he said.
"The property is low maintenance and there is a nice old world charm about it."

15 Justin Street, Holland Park West.

The auction attracted a crowd of about 50 to 60 people, with five registered bidders.
Mr Elisseos said about 30 bids were made throughout the auction battle.
The property is close to child care centres, Catholic primary schools, Garden City Shopping Centre and local cafes.
Public transport is just a stone's throw away.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Elisseos</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holland Park West</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Deco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catholic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin Street</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garden City Shopping Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Elisseos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Style Real Estate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
