<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442555003342541</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/australians-have-a-love-affair-with-diesel-engines/3208810/</url>
  <title>Australians have a love affair with diesel engines</title>
  <content>
WOULD you consider switching from a petrol-powered car to purchasing diesel? Well, according to the latest ABS census report it's exactly what is occurring.
The data, released last week, showed the portion of vehicles fuelled by diesel had grown by 57 per cent in the past five years. Meanwhile, registration of petrol- powered models had dropped from 88.1 per cent of the national fleet in 2012 to 75.7 per cent in 2017.
The nation's apparent love of diesel cars wasn't surprising given the huge increase in the number of people buying SUVs, light commercial utes and four-wheel drives - a sector where diesel tends to dominate. The Ford Ranger and the Toyota HiLux are consistently among the top sellers in the country, after all.
This change in consumer behaviour could be due to more savvy motorists looking for cost savings from fuels like diesel, or due to vehicle manufacturers reducing the number of petrol-powered models in its range.
Our advice is to consider not just the fuel type but all running costs, including depreciation, servicing and purchase costs. Doing research could save you thousands of dollars each year.
Night of crashes rounds out weekend of heartbreak on Coast roads
Close call for Coast motorists as debris goes flying on motorway
Heavy rain misses most of Coast
Education, student accommodation, bars and music all key to future
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
*WARNING this story contains spoilers*
TARA Reid reveals what's coming in the next installment of TV movie.
Farmer's brave decision has cost him the game.
"It didn't seem like they were having a crazy, big night."
The news came after the couple attended Splendour in the Grass
An intimate safari is on the couple's agenda
Garth Prowd's vision made huge impact on Sunshine Coast community
Home sells in just one day
Winners in Master Builders regional housing and construction awards
Ray and Gert will celebrate 70 years of marrive this week
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garth Prowd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ford Ranger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tara Reid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SUVs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toyota Hilux</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
