<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443027449751533</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/sport/sports-life/us-sports-star-noah-syndergaard-made-a-really-cool-game-of-thrones-cameo/news-story/e0dc8bc6c620c1506eaf6905630a95dc</url>
  <title>US sports star Noah Syndergaard made a really cool Game of Thrones cameo</title>
  <content>
Top 5 Game of Thrones Sex Scenes
1:08

Now in its seventh season, Game of Thrones has filled your television with swords, dragons and lots and lots of sex scenes. We've collected the five best.

July 31st 2017
7 days ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment - syndicated/Television/

Noah Syndergaard realised his GoT dream.

Share

WARNING: This story contains spoilers about the latest Game of Thrones episode. If your idea of peak happiness involves sitting on the edge of the couch with a spear in one hand and a severed human head in the other while watching the hour-long nudefest and you haven't seen tonight's show, continue at your own peril.
NOAH Syndergaard: 1, Ed Sheeran: 0.
It took a single four-second cameo in the latest Game of Thrones episode to air to help to us arrive at that scorecard.
The pop star was widely ridiculed for his appearance in the opening show of season seven where he ate rabbit by a campfire, sang about a woman's hands and generally reinforced to viewers he chose wisely by pursuing music rather than acting.
But we're betting New York Mets star Syndergaard will receive a much warmer reception for his cameo in episode four.
He was given fewer lines than Sheeran. In fact, he didn't say a single word. But actions speak louder than words.
The 24-year-old pitcher used his throwing arm to good effect as a Lannister soldier during an action sequence we're assuming involved lots of blood and gore. We came to this wildly speculative conclusion because, well, doesn't every GoT episode have lots of blood and gore?
Syndergaard swapped a baseball for a spear, launching the weapon and knocking a Dothraki soldier clean off his horse.
. with the sweet spear toss on GoT
Take that you mean Dothraki
Syndergaard is a huge GoT fan, calling it the "greatest TV show of all time" in  and was introduced to the show by his mother. If you don't want to have the awkward sex chat with your child, why not make them watch Game of Thrones until they get the gist, right?

He was only on set in Spain for one day and while he wanted to bring a couple of swords back home as souvenirs, he thought getting them through customs would have been too tough an ask, even for a Lannister soldier.
"It was a dream come true," Syndergaard said. "To be able to say I was in Game of Thrones is an unbelievable feeling.
"I couldn't be more happy to get the opportunity to go over there."
There were rumours UFC star Conor McGregor would be making an appearance in the most popular program on the planet, while a host of famous faces have popped up in GoT episodes over the seasons.
Coldplay drummer Will Champion scored a gig at season three's Red Wedding while Icelandic music groups Sigur Ros and Of Monsters and Men have also found themselves on screen.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ed Sheeran: 0</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Conor McGregor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York Mets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NOAH Syndergaard: 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noah Syndergaard</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UFC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sex Scenes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Game of Thrones</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Will Champion</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dothraki</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lannister</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sigur Ros</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coldplay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Red Wedding</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sheeran</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syndergaard</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Icelandic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
