<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442168456280593</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/personal-finance/shares/healthcare-sector-may-not-be-so-healthy-20170802-gxo9r3</url>
  <title>Do you think healthcare is a healthy investment? You need a second opinion.</title>
  <content>
by
Stirling Larkin

Representing a staggering one-fifth of the entire US economy,  matters more than any other to the fate of the entire global economy. Given the prospect of higher US interest rates and the rise of China, close scrutiny of this sector is more important than ever before.
To put it into context, US national healthcare expenditure ran at more than $US3 trillion in 2016, which is more than double Australia's entire 2016 GDP of $1.67 trillion.
The sector has done particularly well, with US healthcare stocks outperforming all other sectors on an equally weighted basis year-to-date.
Australian ultra high net worth investors have taken a greater interest in the sector than other investors because it is well recognised that innovation, not price increases, is the key driver of earnings growth, and ultra high net worth investors enjoy a penchant for innovation and tech.

Yet ultra high net worth investors, most of whom have US dollar denominated accounts in Hong Kong, Singapore or New York, find it difficult to obtain enough information on the US healthcare sector. They are being told by analysts that there is too much uncertainty in the industry because of the uncertainty over healthcare reform under US President Donald Trump.

Global investors need to watch this space carefully. If healthcare falters, that would have knock-on effects for the broader US economy, which would send shockwaves around the world.
Beyond financial market forces, US political rancour, Trumponomics and increased foreign competition present a new threat to US pharmaceutical and service sub-sectors.
China, in particular has begun ramping up its biomedical footprint globally and in fewer than 20 years, China's annual health spending has risen from $US21 per capita to $US420 ($529).
This has given Beijing the opportunity to support export potential.

Too big to ignore

It has become a conundrum too big to ignore for US and indeed Australian investors, given that the "Trump trade" has seen the S&P500, NASDAQ and other US risk assets rally since November last year, thanks to fiscal stimuli, healthcare "repeal and replace" and tax reform, which are now stalling.
Further, US giants such as Amazon have made no secret that they intend to expand directly into the Australian market next year and specifically target its pharmacy sector.
Global healthcare investments have been heavily promoted to Australian investors in recent months, including the iShares Global Healthcare, BetaShares Global Healthcare and Health Care Select Sector SPDR exchange traded funds.

It is not surprising that these are being taken seriously by local investors who have witnessed both the Australian ASX200 Healthcare index return 18.5 per cent a year over five years, against 15.7 per cent for America's S&P500 Healthcare index.
The US healthcare sector remains complex and in its current form is unsustainable, demonstrated by the fact that medical costs are growing at more than twice the pace of nominal US GDP.
Trumponomics not only stimulated the broader US sharemarkets, but provided an insulin injection for US healthcare, which had been expecting Hillary Clinton to win and bring a new wave of price controls and regulation for the sector.
It is important to remember that US healthcare historically has outperformed in the 12 months following presidential elections.

Bucking the trend

Healthcare shares in seven of the past nine presidential elections since 1980 have outperformed the S&P500 by an average of 2.3 per cent a year.
The two exceptions were in 1992, during Hillary Clinton's unsuccessful attempt to introduce universal care and limit drug pricing, and in 2008, during the introduction of Obamacare and before the five-year patent cliff, starting in 2009, when numerous blockbuster drugs went off patent.
US healthcare remains one of the few sectors that have both sales and earnings growth, bucking the negative earnings trend of the broader market over the past five quarters.

Outside of consumer staples, healthcare has experienced the fewest negative adjustments to earnings growth since 2015 and this above-average growth momentum continues to be driven by drug volume and launches, particularly in oncology, rather than price increases in the US domestic market.
The threat of higher interest rates circles healthcare as it does other US sectors, primarily because many healthcare constituents are now considered high price/earnings stocks. But whether they are considered healthy is for you to decide.
Stirling Larkin is chief investment officer of Australian Standfirst www.australianstandfirst.com

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iShares Global Healthcare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Health Care Select Sector SPDR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BetaShares Global Healthcare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>America's S</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hong Kong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hillary Clinton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trumponomics</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US GDP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SINGAPORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Standfirst</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P 500</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$ 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stirling Larkin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BEIJING</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P500 Healthcare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NASDAQ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US420 ($529</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian ASX200 Healthcare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GDP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Obamacare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$21</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
