<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443160593739677</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/entertainment/movies/upcoming-movies/elizabeth-olsen-reveals-the-cast-of-avengers-infinity-war-were-only-given-sections-of-the-script/news-story/c010bfb506836280189e1c61c0edcf94</url>
  <title>Elizabeth Olsen reveals the cast of Avengers: Infinity War were only given sections of the script</title>
  <content>
Marvel Releases Gag Reel for Avengers: Age of Ultron
1:11

To promote the upcoming release of the Avengers: Age of Ultron home video release, Marvel Studios has released a new minute-long snippet of the movie's gag reel. Like any good batch out outtakes, the video includes gaffed lines, poop jokes and an array of actors pretending to kiss one another. What sets Avengers: Age of Ultron's gag reel apart, though, is the addition of CGI mistakes that made it into the movie-making process.

September 29th 2015
2 years ago
/video/video.news.com.au/Lifestyle/

The entire Avengers cast are kept very much in the dark. Picture: Jay Maidment

Natalie Wolfe

Share

IN THE age of social media, internet hackers and chatty celebrities, it's no surprise that movie studios are continually amping up security on their biggest movies.
Marvel Cinematic Universe, the studio behind most of the world's biggest superhero flicks, seem to have taken things to a whole new level to keep the upcoming Avengers: Infinity War a secret.
Actress Elizabeth Olsen, who plays the Scarlet Witch in the superhero franchise, recently appeared on revealing that none of the cast are allowed to see the entire script.
It was when the late night host pushed the 28-year-old actress for spoilers for the 2018 movie that she revealed the film's directors Joe and Anthony Russo had censored her script.
"This time they actually decided to not give us scripts," she said, adding they only gave her the pages with her own dialogue and gave her context by "explaining other things that are happening".

Elizabeth Olsen will be as much in the dark as the movie's fans when Avengers: Infinity War comes out. Picture: Jay MaidmentSource:Supplied
The directors' script censorship means that, when Olsen goes to see the movie, she's going to be in the same boat as everyone else.
"I'll be so shocked and surprised. I'll be like 'Oh I see, that's what was happening to the world at that time'," she told Colbert.

And, while Olsen definitely won't be dropping any spoilers about the upcoming movie, the studio's biggest worry wasn't the actress - it was Spider-Man: Homecoming star Tom Holland.
The young actor became so notorious for running his mouth and accidentally revealing plot lines that the studio resorted to keeping Holland completely in the dark - not even telling the actor who he was fighting.
"Yeah, there is one moment in Avengers where I don't know who that person is. And I'm fighting him, and there's nothing more embarrassing than pretending to fight a 'monster' in front of 200 people, in Spandex. You know, literally like dodging stuff and trying to web him. They're all like, 'That's Great Tom, more energy. More Energy. Jump. Jump,"

No actor in the Avengers franchise is more in the dark than Tom Holland.Source:Supplied
The actor worked with so much CGI, or "tennis balls" as he calls them, that it wasn't until the red carpet for Captain America: Civil War that he met all of the other avengers.
Avengers: Infinity War won't hit cinemas until May, 2018 which means Marvel still have 10 months of trying to keep everything under wraps.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Natalie Wolfe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spider-Man</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Russo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Captain America</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marvel Studios</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oh I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marvel Releases Gag Reel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Civil War</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colbert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scarlet Witch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jay MaidmentSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olsen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Holland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Great Tom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 2018</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elizabeth Olsen</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SEPTEMBER 29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jay Maidment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Holland.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Infinity War</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marvel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ultron</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Age of Ultron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marvel Cinematic Universe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CGI</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Avengers</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
