<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442589363081257</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:48</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Radio Australia</source>
  <url>http://www.radioaustralia.net.au/international/2017-08-07/osprey-mishap-second-marine-identified-after-us-military-aircraft-crash/1691668</url>
  <title>Osprey mishap: Second marine identified after US military aircraft crash</title>
  <content>
A second Marine missing in the US military aircraft crash off Queensland's coast has been identified by his brother, who says he was the type of person everybody wishes they knew.
Lt. Benjamin Robert Cross was named by his older brother Ryan Cross, in an interview with a CBS reporter in the United States.
He said his brother had the "highest moral character" and was "devoted" to the Marine Corps.
"It's something that you hope that you never have to experience," he said of the Saturday accident.
"Every military family knows in the back of their mind there's always a possibility.
"You hope it will never happen to you.
"It probably sounds cliche, but you know, words really can't describe my little brother.
"He's the type of friend everybody wishes they had, the type of person everybody wishes they knew."
The  during a training exercise on Saturday afternoon.

, and moved to a recovery and salvage phase expected to take several months.
Alongside Lt. Cross, Corporal Nathan Ordway has also been identified by family as a victim of the crash.
Corporal Ordway's family and friends have taken to social media to call for prayers.
"Please pray for his life, his safety, and comfort for the family," family friend Heidi Peltzer wrote on Facebook.
One more of the 26 personnel who were onboard remains missing, presumed dead, but is yet to be identified.
Another is recovering in a Brisbane hospital with a leg injury.
A number of Australian Defence Force (ADF) assets were involved in supporting the US-led recovery operation, including HMAS Melville and a Navy clearance diving team.
The commander of Townsville's 3rd Brigade, Brigadier Chris Field, said Army helicopters will be called in to help with the search.
"We hosted marines out of Darwin for about three months," he said.
"They became part of our family so in any family circumstances, we feel the sadness, we feel the sorrow and we'll work together to make sure we continue to support people.
"We're absolutely steadfast beside our allies, whatever they need will be provided."
Defence Minister Marise Payne said the Australian Government stood ready to support the US further, adding it would be a complex recovery operation affected by a range of factors including water depth and conditions, debris and water current.
"Australian Army aviation assets are at short-notice readiness to support any further requirements."
US military training exercises are regularly conducted in the region, and Rockhampton Acting Mayor Cherie Rutherford said the marines were considered part of their community.
"It's devastating news and our prayers and thoughts are with the families and friends of those marines who lost their lives," Councillor Rutherford said.
"It must be extremely difficult for them and of course our community feels that pain with them."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Benjamin Robert Cross</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marine Corps</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lt</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Defence Force</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rockhampton Acting Mayor Cherie Rutherford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Councillor Rutherford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US-led</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corporal Nathan Ordway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville's 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brigadier Chris Field</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Defence Minister Marise Payne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HMAS Melville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Army</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Navy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brigade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corporal Ordway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan Cross</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ADF</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heidi Peltzer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ospreys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
