<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442421859354777</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/sport/crusaders-super-rugby-coach-scott-robertons-impressive-moves/news-story/e44592ec343bee6867efed971e637648</url>
  <title>Super Rugby coach's impressive moves</title>
  <content>
SCOTT Robertson couldn't help himself when it dawned on him what his Crusaders had achieved at Ellis Park.
After his team's 25-17 victory over the Lions in the Super Rugby final, first-year coach Robertson finally relented and broke out some trademark break dancing moves on the famous turf.
The colourful celebration mirrored that which followed his three NPC titles as coach of Canterbury.
Earlier in the season, former Crusaders and All Blacks flanker Robertson was adamant the dance moves wouldn't be seen on the loftier Super Rugby stage.
That was until the urging of his victorious players ramped up on Saturday.
"The boys start singing and you start to get a tingle in the old toes and off you go," Robertson said.
"It's a great way to finish the campaign."
Together with assistant Leon MacDonald, Robertson become the first title-winning Super Rugby player to repeat the deed as a coach.
In fact, the 42-year-old won four titles as a player and revealed in the wake of Saturday's triumph that he had always regretted signing with French club Perpignan in 2003.
"Leon is the same. For us to hand on and do what we've done with the players, it's a special moment," Robertson said.
"Now to come back as a coach. The questions were there in my head and I've answered a couple of them."
After eight title-less campaigns under Todd Blackadder, Robertson can't explain why he instantly hit on the winning formula at a franchise historically brimming with All Blacks.
Adding to the achievement, his side became the first to win a championship after traversing the Indian Ocean during the play-offs.
A loss to the British and Irish Lions and then to Hurricanes were the only setbacks in a season which revived memories of previous dominant Crusaders campaigns.
"It's hugely satisfying, like I coach because I just love the environment and want to come in on a Monday to meet with the boys," Robertson said.
"That's what coaches do, they teach people to be the best they can at their profession.
"For me to do that and get the opportunity from great coaches like Wayne Smith, Robbie Deans, Steve Hansen, now I get to turn that on to other players."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canterbury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Hansen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>All Blacks</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NPC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Super Rugby</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robbie Deans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leon MacDonald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ellis Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Todd Blackadder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Robertson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robertson</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wayne Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perpignan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indian Ocean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Irish Lions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
