<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442550708375140</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/lifestyle/fashion/pull-out-your-shoulder-pads-midnight-glam-is-one-of-the-top-trends-for-summer-20170731-gxm6ev.html</url>
  <title>Trend school: the four key looks for spring</title>
  <content>
In fashion circles, we call this weekend the calm before the storm.
After hibernating for most of June and July (unless you were one of the people ), the industry officially welcomes summer in early August, when the department stores showcase their summer ranges.

Ruffle up ... Jesinta Franklin perfects the new romantic trend in Macgraw. Photo: David Jones

Despite retail having more struggles than , the major department stores are both going bigger than Ben Hur, with David Jones hosting a  on Wednesday (which ties to its sponsorship of the upcoming  at Melbourne's National Gallery of Victoria), and Myer following on August 17 with a two-part extravaganza on Sydney's eastern beaches.
According to David Jones' head womenswear buyer, Teneille Ferguson, there are four dominant trends for summer: Midnight Glam, New Romantic, Artesian Boho and Club Tropicana. Yes, the '80s are still back.
So pour yourself a Midori, dust off your shoulder pads and pay attention to what's big for summer.

Golden glam ... Jada Pinkett Smith. Photo: Willy Sanjuan/AP

1980s glamour

If you had to describe this trend in a person, it's Jennifer Beals in Flashdance. Think one-shouldered jumpsuits. In fact, think one-shouldered anything as the dominant up-top silhouette for summer.
"There's a luxurious element to this trend, lots of silks, satins and metallics," Ferguson says. 
Jumpsuits were big last summer but they were more casual, more 1970s; this summer is about evening wear.
But don't despair, you can easily have both in your wardrobe. Try updating your 2016 jumpsuit with a coloured velvet blazer for spring if you've already met your onesie quota.

Camilla and Marc, $699

Victoriana 2.0

Lace has been big for several seasons but this summer expect to see skirts and dresses with more tiers than a royal family wedding cake.
"It's a little softer than it's been previously. Victoriana is more structured but now it has a softer romantic flow to it," Ferguson says.
One of the key pieces is a ruffled blouse, with great examples from  or , which practically has a mortgage on this trend in Australia ().
"You can wear it with jeans, a pencil skirt, something a little easier than wearing head to toe [lace]," Ferguson says.

Zimmermann, $650.

Loud and proud

If there's one trend that screams spring racing and summer party, it's this: landscape prints, bright oranges, pinks and yellows and oversized florals.
There's a distinct Dolce & Gabbana vibe to this trend: think fruit, flamingoes and palm trees and you won't go wrong.
This trend is also set to be huge for swimwear. One word of advice: check the layout of the print before you buy to avoid any awkward placed pineapples or bananas.
If you're not a fan of prints, Ferguson has a solution: the non-print print, which labels such as David Jones newbie  does oh so well.
"A two-coloured print is a nice way to wear a print that ties back with the rest of your black pieces."
 With shoes, invest in a great quality nude mid-heel for the races and leave the black or white for Derby Day.

by johnny, $350.

Swept away

If all the structured dresses and exaggerated shoulders have you wanting to hide in your walk-in until February, we've saved the best for last. 
If you want to dress at work like you're off to a music festival, this summer's take on luxe boho will be on your shopping list.
Ferguson says keep it current by investing in a wrap dress, or a piece with paisley print or embellishment.
It's a high summer trend and can look uber-casual, so styling it for the office can take some skill.
"It's harder with dresses, they tend to be more casual. You can dress them up with a boot but if you go towards the floaty blouses you can team with pants or skirt to wear to work," Ferguson says.

Thurley, $499.

Need more inspiration? Shop our editor's picks

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marc, $699</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Willy Sanjuan/AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne's National Gallery of Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zimmermann, $650</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Golden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Teneille Ferguson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gabbana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Jones</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Club Tropicana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dolce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Myers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thurley, $499</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ferguson</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Artesian Boho</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jesinta Franklin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Camilla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Hur</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoriana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Derby Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jennifer Beals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Midori</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jada Pinkett Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Romantic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoriana 2.0</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
