<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442159866345829</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/world/2017/08/07/11/55/princess-diana-spied-on-charles-during-sex-talk-with-camilla</url>
  <title>Princess Diana spied on Charles during 'sex talk'  with Camilla</title>
  <content>
Princess Diana once spied on Prince Charles while he had "phone sex talk" with his mistress on the toilet, a documentary has revealed.
The revelations come from 12 hours of footage filmed by a hand-picked BBC cameraman before her death in 1997,  reports.
The unnamed cameraman was secretly called to Kensington Palace by Diana in 1997, and kept a diary of their sessions.
"She described how she came to listen to their phone calls. In one, Charles was sitting on the toilet seat when she caught him," the cameraman reportedly said.

It comes after the airing of Channel 4's documentary Diana: In Her Own Words  in Britain on Sunday to mixed reaction.
The documentary revealed Princess Diana developed bulimia from the stress of her marriage and had only met Charles 13 times before their wedding day.
Friends of the late princess have slammed the British broadcaster's decision to air the private recordings, in which Diana speaks frankly about her unhappy marriage to Prince Charles, describing details of their sex life, her fury at her husband's mistress and her love for another man.

Related Articles

However, one of Diana's former bodyguards said she would "love it" that her innermost thoughts were being shared.
In the explosive recordings, made between 1992 and mid-1993 with voice coach Peter Settelen, Princess Diana revealed Charles was "all over her like a rash" and wasn't "very consistent in his courtship".
Intimate details about her marriage to Charles are revealed including their lack of intimacy after the birth of Harry in 1984.
In one recording, Diana explains the couple's sex life: "Once every three weeks and then it fizzled out."
Portions of the tapes were broadcast by US network NBC in 2004 but they have never been shown in Britain until Sunday on Britain's Channel 4 when Diana: In Her Own Words went to air.
The tapes were made to help Diana practice public speaking as she struck out on her own in a career devoted to charity work. On camera, she seems relaxed and keen to tell her side of the story.
Diana also discusses her battle with bulimia, which came on around the stresses of appealing for advice on her husband's affair saying: "I didn't think I was good enough for this family, so I took it out on myself."
She said the illness was a "discreet" way to do so.
The couple divorced in 1996, and Charles married his longtime paramour Camilla Parker Bowles in 2005.
Diana also talks about falling "deeply in love" in the 1980s with her bodyguard Barry Mannakee, who later died in a motorcycle accident.
"That was the biggest blow in my life," Diana says.
She also describes confronting her husband and his mistress Camilla Parker Bowles at a party - a moment that former bodyguard Ken Wharfe said marked "the real beginning of the end" of the royal marriage.
"She realized there was no chance of reconciliation," he said. "There was only one direction and that was divorce."
Diana went to the Queen for advice on her distress at her husband's affair, but said she received no support.
"I went to the top lady, and I was sobbing, and I said what do I do?" Princess Diana said. "And she [the Queen] said, 'I don't know what you should do, Charles is hopeless', and that was it."
Channel 4 said the tapes are "important historical source" and the subjects covered "a matter of public record" in their defence of choosing to air them.
The videotapes have had a twisting journey to public view. They were seized by British police during a 2001 raid on the home of Diana's former butler, Paul Burrell, who was accused of stealing from the princess.
The case against Burrell was later abandoned. Diana's family made a legal claim to the recordings but they were eventually returned to Settelen.
This month marks 20 years since the death of the princess in a car crash in Paris on August 31.
With Associated Press.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BBC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charles 13</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Associated Press</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Camilla Parker-Bowles</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Settelen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Charles</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Settelen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princess Diana</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kensington Palace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Camilla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barry Mannakee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Burrell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charles</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 4</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burrell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diana</name>
    <count>13</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain's Channel 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ken Wharfe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
