<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442722507069205</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/real-estate/south-australia/even-the-selling-agent-was-surprised-at-the-result-this-popular-prospect-home-fetched-at-auction/news-story/24f6bf92fc015cfef8a97249f52faca9</url>
  <title>Even the selling agent was surprised at the result this popular Prospect home fetched at auction. - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
With a unique verge garden, four bedrooms and character features, this home at 46 Johns St, Prospect sold well above its reserve for $955,000 at auction on the weekend.

A CHARACTER villa in Prospect, which was advertised with a price guide of $780,000, sold for $955,000 at auction on the weekend.
The four-bedroom home with a feature garden that extended out to the front verge proved very popular with the househunters, attracting about 200 groups to its open inspections and about 15 registered bidders on the day.
Selling agent Margie Saint said there was a "massive crowd" of spectators at the auction despite cold weather.
"It's lucky I don't get stage fright - it (the crowd) was overflowing into both sides of the street and there was a single line to allow cars to go through," she said.

The home had high ceilings and character features, which were popular with buyers.

"There were five strong bidders competing for it- it just sailed past the reserve very quickly.
"At the end of the day there were two people fighting it out."
Ms Saint said the vendors, who had bought the home from her 20 years earlier, were "very pragmatic and realistic" about its likely sale price and "thrilled to bits" at the end result.
Prospect's median house price is $655,000 according to CoreLogic data and Ms Saint said her feedback indicated this one would sell somewhere in the low $800,000s - so the reserve was set around that level.
The end result, more than $100,000 higher, exceeded even her expectations, she said.
"It couldn't have happened to nicer people and bravo to them (the vendors) - they really did a lot of hard work in terms of extensions," she said.

The home had established gardens out the front and back, as well as a verge garden.

Ms Saint advertised the house online and in The Advertiser Realestate Magazine in The Messenger and online. Its unusual verge garden was also the subject of an Advertiser story. .
She said the four-bedroom home appealed to a mix of downsizers and families, who were attracted by its character features and zoning for city high schools.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>John St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Margie Saint</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Advertiser Realestate Magazine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CoreLogic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Messengers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Saint</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
