<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442426154322131</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:10</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/iron-ore-futures-are-flying-as-chinese-steel-prices-surge-again-2017-8</url>
  <title>Iron ore futures are flying as Chinese steel prices surge again</title>
  <content>
Iron ore futures in China have started the new week as they ended the last: screeching higher upon the resumption of trade on Monday.

Here's the scoreboard around 90 minutes into today's session.

SHFE Rebar		¥4,041	,	5.43%
DCE Iron Ore		¥600.50	,	4.62%
DCE Coking Coal		¥1,266.50	,	-1.78%
DCE Coke		¥2,068.00	,	1.60%

The most actively traded September 2017 iron ore contract in Dalian is now up 4.62%, having climbed to as high as 619 yuan per tonne earlier in the session.

It currently sits at the highest level since March 22, extending its rally from June 14 to over 46%.

The strength in iron ore mirrors another jaw-dropping surge in rebar futures traded separately on the Shanghai Futures Exchange.

The October 2017 contract is currently up 5.43% at 4,041 yuan, rising above the 4,000 yuan per tonne level since February 2013. It briefly touched a high of 4,101 yuan in early trade.

Strength in Chinese steel prices, driven by low inventory levels and strong demand, has seen Chinese steel mill margins balloon in recent months, encouraging firms to raise output levels to take advantage of strong operating conditions.

That in turn helped to bolster iron ore demand, explaining the large gains seen in recent months.

According to , the price for benchmark 62% fines soared 1.6% to $74.12 a tonne last Friday, leaving it sitting at the highest level since April 11 this year.

Last week it surged 7.8%, extending its rally from mid-June to 38.9%.

Given the scale of the gains in futures markets today, it looks like that strength will continue when Metal Bulletin releases its daily iron ore index later in the session.

NOW WATCH: Money & Markets videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Metal Bulletin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shanghai Futures Exchange</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 2013</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dalian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 22</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SHFE Rebar		¥4,041	,	5.43</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DCE Coke		¥2,068.00	,	1.60</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DCE Coking Coal		¥1,266.50	,	-1.78</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 14</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DCE Iron Ore		¥600.50	,	4.62</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
