<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442816996350872</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Coffs Coast Advocate</source>
  <url>http://www.coffscoastadvocate.com.au/news/chris-pratt-and-anna-faris-split/3209629/</url>
  <title>Chris Pratt and Anna Faris split</title>
  <content>
LONG considered one of Hollywood's most adorable couples, Chris Pratt and Anna Faris today announced their separation.

News of the shock split came via a joint announcement on  in which the pair state that they "tried hard for a long time."

"Anna and I are sad to announce we are legally separating. We tried hard for a long time, and we're really disappointed. Our son has two parents who love him very much and for his sake we want to keep this situation as private as possible moving forward. We still have love for each other, will always cherish our time together and continue to have the deepest respect for one another," says the announcement, signed "Chris Pratt and Anna Faris."

Pratt, 40 and Faris, 40, met in 2007 on the set of the film Take Me Home Tonight, getting engaged a year later and marrying in Bali in July 2009. They have one son, Jack, born in 2012.

Pratt's career has skyrocketed in recent years, with the actor going from supporting sitcom player in P arks and Recreation to one of Hollywood's most in-demand leading men, with starring roles in Jurassic World, Guardians of the Galaxy and Passengers. Faris is an in-demand actor in her own right, with comic turns in films like Scary Movie and T he House Bunny and a leading role in sitcom Mom.

In a 2015 interview, Faris responded to persistent rumours Pratt was cheating on her, calling the tabloid speculation "stinging".

The cheating rumours had him hooking up with his Passengers co-star Jennifer Lawrence.

"[That] stung a little bit harder than I thought it would," Faris told Us Weekly. "I had always kind of believed that part of the rumours of celebrity couples were sort of true because they had never been part of my life. I was like, 'Oh, maybe there's a kernel of truth to that.' It's been a little devastating because for us, it's like, 'What the heck?'. This has been blindsiding to us. We have an incredible relationship. It has been weirdly stinging."

At the time, Faris said she and her husband shared similar values and had simple goals for the future.

"I am very lucky that I am with a man [who] values family," she said. "We're so lucky that we have the same sense of humour. We dream about having a little bit of a farm one day."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anna Faris</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Guardians Of The Galaxy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Pratt</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Faris, 40</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jurassic World</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scary Movie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Us Weekly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Take Me Home Tonight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pratt, 40</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bali</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JENNIFER LAWRENCE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>House Bunny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 2009</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pratt</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FARIS</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
