<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443121939033437</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:52</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/panthers-keen-to-keep-hold-of-rookie/3209685/</url>
  <title>Panthers keen to keep hold of rookie</title>
  <content>
PENRITH has hatched a plan to sign rookie fullback Dylan Edwards on a long-term deal.
Edwards has been a sensation for the Panthers this season, starring in his 11 games thus far.
As a successful product of Penrith's junior system, the club wants to extend his contract that expires at the end of 2018.
Panthers chairman Brian Fletcher confirmed Edwards was part of the club's plans for the future.
The 21-year-old delivered was at his best in Penrith's win over the Wests Tigers on Sunday - scoring a try and running for a game-high 206 metres.
"Dylan is long-term for sure," Fletcher said.
"Phil Gould would be swirling something around in his head - because we have no intention in letting him go anywhere."
Fletcher also confirmed Penrith were edging closer to extending coach Anthony Griffin, who still has a season to run on his current deal.
"We've always looked at him as a long-term coach and in a month we'll be talking to him for sure," he said.
"We won't be waiting until the middle of next year to talk to him put it that way.
"I'm hoping it will be looked at prior to the end of this year."
Night of crashes rounds out weekend of heartbreak on Coast roads
BREAKING: New festival coming to the Sunshine Coast
Major crime spike hits local residents and businesses in small town
Coast's vulnerable better off amid plans to build affordable rentals
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
A NATIONAL exhibition of ceramic art has been launched on the Coast
ONE of Hollywood's most adorable couples is over.
New celebrity cooking show fails to fire for Seven.
The legendary creator isn't so sure about how Netflix works.
*WARNING this story contains spoilers*
TARA Reid reveals what's coming in the next installment of TV movie.
Garth Prowd's vision made huge impact on Sunshine Coast community
Home sells in just one day
Winners in Master Builders regional housing and construction awards
Ray and Gert will celebrate 70 years of marrive this week
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dylan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fletcher</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garth Prowd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brian Fletcher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tara Reid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phil Gould</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edwards</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Panther</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wests Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dylan Edwards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Penrith</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Griffin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
