<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443371047141057</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/the-worst-style-mistakes-a-man-can-make-2017-8</url>
  <title>The 10 worst style mistakes a man can make, according to women -- and how to avoid them</title>
  <content>
Style mistakes are something a man generally wants to avoid.

And style mistakes that the opposite sex has voted as the most egregious? Well, you'd better listen up.

Female commenters on Reddit's  were asked to vote on what they consider to be the worst style blunders they see on men.

We've rounded up the 10 most upvoted sins and coupled them with advice on how to best avoid them.

J. Crew
A pair of chino shorts is much more flattering.
'Jean shorts.' --

Jean shorts, affectionately known as 'jorts,' are a bit of a scourge during warmer months. They have unsightly hemlines and janky appearance.

Instead wear: A nice slim pair of .

A good fit is key.
'Baggy/'relaxed fit' jeans in general.' --

Baggy jeans remind us of the '90s. We've come pretty far since then, and baggy jeans should be relegated to the same bin as Furbies and frosted tips.

Instead wear:  or even skinny side.

Getty/Jason Kempin
You don't need to wear anything on your head.
'Fedoras. Just stop with them. It's not 1935.' --

Hats -- especially fedoras and other dressy hats -- are passe in 2016. They look very out of place today, and will always make it look like you're trying too hard.

Instead wear: Absolutely nothing on your head.

Getty/John Phillips
No one likes an unkempt beard.
'Just ... not grooming. Not trimming beards ... that sort of thing.' --

Grooming is important, guys. When a guy is unkempt, others will start to notice.

Instead wear: A , , or .

Giorgio Fochesato / Getty Images
The only people who should wear glasses are those who need them.
'My ex used to wear glasses even though he didn't need them and it was really obvious that he didn't and he looked like an idiot.' --

It goes like this: If you're not wearing those glasses to see, you're not doing yourself any favours. And if you do wear nonprescription glasses, absolutely do not talk about it.

Instead wear: Prescription glasses or nothing at all.

Not everything needs to be tucked in.
'Tucking your non-dress shirt into your non-dress pants.' --

There's an easy test for this. If your shirt has long tails, it's meant to be tucked in. If it has no tails, it's not meant to be tucked in. If it has short tails, it's your call.

Go forth and tuck correctly.

Instead wear: Your tailed shirts tucked, and your nontailed shirts untucked.

Slim-fit chinos are a better choice.
'Stay away from those god awful khaki old man pants with the pleats in the front.' --

Pleats are generally considered unflattering and should be avoided. The extra fold of fabric creates an odd, billowing silhouette that is best avoided if you're on the average to skinny side of pant sizes.

Instead wear: Flat-front, slim-fit chinos.

Getty/Frazer Harrison
Fit is the most important thing to consider.
'Wearing clothes that are waay too big for them!' --

Over and over again, we at Business Insider have emphasised fit over everything else when it comes to clothing. We're not kidding. Well-fitting clothing is more flattering no matter what your body type is.

Instead wear: Clothes that fit well. (For suits,  is a good place to start.)

Keep it simple.
'Those shirts with the flames on them, oh lordy ... ' --

This should go without saying, but apparently it needs to be said. Anything with graphics, flames, witty sayings, or logos on it needs to be turned into trash immediately.

They're not clever. They're not cute, and they're a serious turn-off.

Instead wear: Literally any other shirt.

NOW WATCH: Executive Life videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Giorgio Fochesato</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getty Images</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getty/Frazer Harrison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pleats</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getty/Jason Kempin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>J. Crew</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getty/John Phillips</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jean</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Furbies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Executive Life</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Business Insider</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reddit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flat-front</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
