<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443066104457749</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/news/asean-needs-to-play-bigger-global-role-former-indonesian-minister-says-20170806-gxqkwl</url>
  <title>ASEAN needs to play bigger global role, former Indonesian minister says</title>
  <content>
The Association of Southeast Asian Nations needs to assume a bigger leadership role in global affairs in the face of China's rise, the vacuum in US leadership under Donald Trump, and European fragmentation, a former senior Indonesian minister and public servant says.
With the 10-member bloc celebrating its 50th anniversary on Tuesday, former vice minister for trade and finance, Mahendra Siregar, told The Australian Financial Review that ASEAN should also seek to be China's equal amid tensions over competing territorial claims in the South China Sea.
Mr Siregar said that, while a planned free trade agreement between Australia and Indonesia would strengthen ties between the two countries, both sides had to ensure it was a "convincing" deal and implemented properly so that it met expectations.
Originally established in 1967 by Singapore, Indonesia, Malaysia, the Philippines and Thailand to be a bulwark against communism and promote economic development in Asia, ASEAN has since grown to include Vietnam, Cambodia, Laos, Myanmar and Brunei with an emphasis on economic integration among members.

The . After a deadlock on the weekend, ASEAN foreign ministers released a joint communique calling for non-militarisation and self-restraint in the South China Sea and adopted a framework for negotiating a code of conduct with China to govern behaviour.

Mr Siregar, though, said that ASEANto wield influence, particularly given the uncertainty emanating from the US under Mr Trump and in the European Union as Brexit unfolds.
"ASEAN should not just take care of itself but has a bigger responsibility to look after the region," he said.
"I think obviously that is not just an opportunity but a responsibility for doing so because the position the US President is taking would need counter-balance from others to assume bigger responsibility and leadership.
."

Mr Siregar said ASEAN should not seek to be a check against China but become a "more equal partner".
"I don't think China is interested to see a weak ASEAN and its respective members," he said.
"It would be beneficial for both sides to grow strongly, and of course with that potentially building a stronger partnership over a large area."
Mr Siregar has close ties to Australia, receiving a Masters in economics at Monash University in 1991. A former diplomat and public servant, he served as a vice minister between 2009 and 2013 before being appointed chair of the Investment Coordinating Board by President Susilo Bambang Yudhoyono.

Mr Siregar, who is regarded as one of Jakarta's top policy minds, is in Australia as a guest of the Andrews government and Lowy Institute to promote greater engagement between Victoria and Indonesia.
He said Australia and Indonesia were eager to complete a free trade agreement as soon as possible and such as deal would be a good platform for trade, investment, services and worker mobility between the two countries.
He struck a note of caution, though, saying that an FTA should not be seen as an end in itself but just another building block in forging better relations between Canberra and Jakarta.
"We should not look at that as something that will give us euphoria for strong relations without focussing harder on the opportunities and the work that we need to carry on afterwards," he said.

"I've seen many FTAs in the past that failed to deliver as expected simply because we don't work as hard on the implementing stage as we do on the negotiating side."
Mr Siregar was optimistic that Australia and Indonesia would continue to grow closer over time, saying the relationship had matured past the point where one incident would ruin it.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asean</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indonesian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Myanmar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philippines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Association of Southeast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cambodia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asian Nations</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indonesia</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Masters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Siregar</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SINGAPORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vietnam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brexit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FTAs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monash University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>European Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thailand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lowy Institute</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brunei</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jakarta</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mahendra Siregar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASEANto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Investment Coordinating Board</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FTA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Susilo Bambang Yudhoyono</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malaysia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South China Sea</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
