<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442207110986889</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/street-talk/pas-group-coliseum-capital-at-an-impasse-ahead-of-offer-close-20170807-gxqn06</url>
  <title>PAS Group, Coliseum Capital at an impasse ahead of offer close</title>
  <content>
While Downer EDI has been battling for control of Spotless Group, a similar situation is playing out in small caps. 
US-based investment manager Coliseum Capital is in the market with a 51¢ a share bid for ASX-listed retail brands owner The PAS Group. 
Coliseum had a 48.6 per cent stake before making the on-market bid in June, and The PAS Group board told shareholders to reject the bid. 
Despite the rejection, Minter Ellison-advised Coliseum has had some success picking up shares via its broker Canaccord Genuity.

While slow, the buying has seen Coliseum move to a 54 per cent stake and it took control of the board last week, when the fund manager's Adam Gray was appointed chairman replacing Rod Walker. 

The question for all parties now is how far up the register Coliseum can go before the bid closes on Thursday. 
Having gained control, Coliseum can lay claim to meeting its objective. Surely, though, it would like to move up towards 90 per cent and full control, where it could take the company private and run the business away from prying eyes. 
The problem for Coliseum is that liquidity has dried up and it is prohibited from raising the 51¢ a share tender offer unless a competing bid surfaces, which seems highly unlikely given the situation.
Coliseum could always make a new bid in the future to try and mop up the minorities -  - however it is said to have no intention of doing so. It's been through the process twice in two years already. 

The PAS Group shareholders also have an important decision to make.
The company has flagged a tough operating environment, telling investors in May that sales of its Black Pepper and Review brands were below expectation and it was on track for $18.5 million to $20 million EBITDA for the 2017 financial year. That compares to $23.9 million EBITDA last financial year and $20.5 million one year earlier. 
No shares changed hands on Monday morning, which suggests the situation is at an impasse. PAS Group shareholders are staring at life as minority owners to Coliseum, while Coliseum will have to run the business in full view of the public. 

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rod Walker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PA Group</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Downer EDI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spotless Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Gray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EBITDA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canaccord Genuity</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coliseum Capital</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Black Pepper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX-listed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minter Ellison-advised Coliseum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coliseum</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
