<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442937255436736</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/adelaide-united-has-launched-supreme-court-action-against-football-federation-sa/news-story/68b9b5131a78c8fc2ed9050527932505</url>
  <title>Reds take Supreme Court action</title>
  <content>
ADELAIDE United is taking Supreme Court action against Football Federation SA.
The dispute centres around FFSA docking the club's NPL side three points and fining Adelaide $1500 last month.
Adelaide chairman Greg Griffin said the club had planned to appeal the points deduction to Football Federation Australia but rules block that possibility because the fine is less than $3000.
, made by its self-appointed independent disciplinary committee which decided a suspended three-point deduction and fine was suffice, and later winning the appeal, saw United lose the points.
"The (FFSA) appeals committee decision is void and has no effect,'' Griffin said.
"The declaration that the appeals committee decision breaches clause 10.2 (under FFA's national disciplinary regulations) of the defendant's own grievance and disciplinary regulations.
"The decision is ultra vires (beyond the powers) of jurisdiction of the appeals committee.
The case is to be listed for an urgent trial next week after FFSA was served court documents yesterday.
Adelaide has also put an interim injunction restraining FFSA from relegating the Reds.
Adelaide was punished for playing a FIFA-registered player according to FFSA regulations "who had not been placed on their player roster in accordance with the competition operating regulation 7h" on May 27 after a 5-3 win over Olympic.
Adelaide's NPL side is three points clear of relegation with Blue Eagles in the box seat to join relegated Cumberland with two matches remaining.
Adelaide faces Birkalla at Angle Park today.
FFSA chief executive Michael Carter said there could be ramification for the NPL competition during its final two rounds.
"We're disappointed, but not surprised," he said.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Football Federation Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Birkalla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NPL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide's NPL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFSA</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide $1500</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Football Federation SA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cumberland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blue Eagles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FIFA-registered</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Angle Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Griffin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide United</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Carter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 27</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Griffin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Supreme Court</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
