<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442679557395552</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/world/take-a-powderkeg-kenya-election-and-add-fake-news-20170807-gxqss1.html</url>
  <title>Take a powder-keg Kenya election and add fake news</title>
  <content>
Eldoret, Kenya: Fake news. Odd plot twists. Tit-for-tat accusations. One candidate calling another "crooked".
Those political phenomena, familiar to voters in the United States and Europe, have surfaced in Kenya before a tightly contested presidential election on Tuesday. But in a country with a history of election violence, the addition of such toxic behavior has further fanned fears about whether the country can pull off a credible and peaceful vote.Photo: AP
Two previous elections were marred by violence amid widespread claims that they had been rigged; in 2007, the disputed vote plunged Kenya into bloodshed that left at least 1,300 people dead and 600,000 displaced from their homes.
Just in the past week, there was a break-in at the country estate of the Vice President, which ended after an 18-hour siege. Then, a senior election official in charge of crucial voting technology was found dead. His body, disposed of in a forest outside Nairobi, the capital, showed signs of torture.Photo: AP
In addition, the military confirmed the existence of a document that the opposition party claimed revealed plans to rig the vote in favour of President Uhuru Kenyatta. But the military then backtracked, saying that the document was being "quoted out of context" and that the military was "apolitical."
In the latest development, just two days before election day, the main opposition coalition, the National Super Alliance, accused President Kenyatta of ordering an armed raid on one of its tallying centres. The accusation was reported by some media outlets but dismissed by others as false.

The details of all those events remain hazy and unconfirmed, spawning fears and conspiracy theories among Kenyans already nervous about Tuesday's vote. Whether those reports are false or simply shoddy journalism, 90 per cent of Kenyans surveyed in a report in July said they had seen or heard deliberately fake news, according to GeoPoll, a polling service. This included stories said to have been produced by the BBC and CNN. One news article had the headline "Crooked Raila," referring to Raila Odinga, who is running against Kenyatta.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

The President's team is reported to have enlisted Cambridge Analytica, the big-data company that worked on President Donald Trump's campaign.
"There is an ecosystem of fake news around this election," said Alphonce Shiundu, editor of Africa Check, a fact-checking organisation. "Kenyans really don't know what the truth is."
In a contest that will cost at least $1 billion, according to Kenya's treasury, more than 19.6 million registered voters will choose hundreds of legislative candidates across the country, in addition to the President and Vice President.
"Quite a lot is at stake," said Justin Willis, professor of history at Durham University in England and an expert on Kenyan politics. "Everyone is working hard to win. People have invested so much, and so much money, that they need to recoup their losses, right up to the president."
President Kenyatta, 55, who leads the Jubilee Party, will face off against Mr Odinga, 72, a former prime minister who leads the National Super Alliance.
New York Times
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BBC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cambridge Analytica</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Durham University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raila Odinga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vice President</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Super Alliance</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Kenyatta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin Willis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raila</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kenyatta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York Times</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Africa Check</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Kenyatta, 55</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jubilee Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alphonce Shiundu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Odinga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Uhuru Kenyatta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kenyans</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eldoret</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geopoll</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kenya</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CNN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nairobi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
