<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442207110986837</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/real-estate/commercial/hotels-and-leisure/1000-rooms-mantra-buys-art-series-hotel-rights-for-525m-20170807-gxqmlh</url>
  <title>1000 rooms: Mantra buys Art Series hotel rights for $52.5m</title>
  <content>
Mantra Group has snapped up the operating rights to the Art Series boutique hotel chain, including over 1000 room keys, for $52.5 million in a deal with the family-owned Deague Group.
The major acquisition, which comes ahead of Mantra releasing its full-year results on August 18, will see Mantra replace ASX-listed EVENT Hospitality & Entertainment as the operator of seven art-inspired hotels by the end of the year.
Five of the hotels are dotted around Melbourne and are The Cullen in Prahran, The Larwill Studio at Melbourne's Royal Childrens Hospital in Flemington, The Olsen in South Yarra, The Blackman on St Kilda Road and The Chen in Box Hill, which due to open in November.
The other two are The Johnson in Spring Hill on the Brisbane city fringe and The Watson in Adelaide.

"This acquisition enhances our existing portfolio and presents a unique opportunity for Mantra Group to increase its footprint across three key locations (Melbourne, Brisbane and Adelaide) in a single transaction," said Mantra Group CEO Bob East.

"This is a rare opportunity to acquire a collection of exceptional hotels and one which is expected to make a significant contribution to Mantra Group's business." 
The deal will grow Mantra's portfolio to about 135 properties and about 22,500 rooms, the second largest in the country behind French giant AccorHotels.
The Deague Group, previously called Asian Pacific Group, began developing its Art Series Hotels in 2008. The Cullen was the first to open in Prahran in 2009. It has progressively sold down the underlying real estate  for a combined $146 million in 2015.
The latest deal with Mantra takes the total value of  Art Series property and business rights sold to $570 million.

The Deague Group will retain ownership of its next Art Series Hotel under Brisbane's Storey Bridge being developed as part of the $110 million redevelopment of Brisbane's Howard Smith Wharves, and due for completion next year. The project recently .
CEO Will Deague said the family was selling its Art Series Hotels "with mixed emotions" but that it was  time to re-cycle the funds into other areas of the property industry including multi-unit residential, office complexes and further hotel development.
"We've had great success with our hotels, but we're property developers at heart," he told The Australian Financial Review.
He said Mantra had approached the Deague Group with an offer to take over the hotels from EVENT, which has operated them since they opened. EVENT, which operates hotes like QT Sydney and Melbourne and the Rydges hotels, will be paid an early termination fee, Mr Deague said.

The purchase price of approximately $52.5 million (excluding transaction costs) is for the leasehold and management letting rights to the four and five-star hotels as well as freehold title to key commercial lots, reception areas and offices.
The deal will be funded via available cash and existing debt facilities and is expected to settle at the end of the year. It is expected to contribute approximately $7 million in underlying earnings (EBITDA) its first full year of ownership and then lift to between $8.5 -$9 million in the following year once the The Chen swings in profitability.
Mantra is forecasting full-year earnings of $101 million-$107 million. Last week , with one of the concerns being a lack of major acquisition announcements. 

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne's Royal Childrens Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Watson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Series</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spring Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AccorHotels</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blackman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane's Howard Smith Wharves</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX-listed EVENT Hospitality</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cullen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Box Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Larwill Studio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Series Hotels</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asian Pacific Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EBITDA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane's Storey Bridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO Will Deague</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rydges</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flemington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prahran</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olsen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Deague</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Yarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QT Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUGUST 18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deague Group</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mantra Group CEO Bob East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mantra Group</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
