<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442679557395560</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/comment/that-thinking-feeling/reality-gives-hollywood-a-run-for-its-money-20170806-gxjdy4.html</url>
  <title>Reality gives Hollywood a run for its money</title>
  <content>
The world has gone mad. Just consider the events of the last couple of weeks.
The world's third-most senior Catholic fronts an Australian court yesterday to answer sex charges.Photo: Justin McManus
The nation's most popular politician suffers a nervous breakdown, pending serious extortion and criminal charges.
Another politician - a state minister no less - claims he doesn't remember using the word "f---tard" in an abusive rant over the Premier's department.Photo: Tammy Law
A rising star in the Turnbull ministry doesn't know his Mum has signed him up as an Italian citizen.
As a movie, it would be a cracker.

Imagine Jack Nicholson in the role of Cardinal George Pell, and Richard Gere as Paul Pisasale. Johnny Depp could sign up as the foul-mouthed State MP Bill Byrne, or perhaps he'll want to have one more go at mocking Barnaby Joyce by taking the role of Matt Canavan. 
The plot could go on, and on.Photo: Bradley Kanaris
Perhaps the state's chief scientist is stood aside, on full pay, over fraud claims. And Donald Trump, playing himself of course, wants a talk-radio host, with no experience in science, to become the Agriculture Department's chief scientist!
Throw in a crime element, with primary school children being caught with drugs at school.
And an international angle, with an Australian woman, with a heart of gold, being gunned down by police, after she reports an alleged sex assault.
Some of the script could be set on the beautiful rolling campuses of our universities; those charged with empowering the minds of our talented students.
But in a twist, they could be preparing for an onslaught of accusations over on-campus sex assaults!
The story line could take all sorts of ridiculous turns, but the morale movie-goers leave with is linear: the reputation of some of our institutions is reaching breaking point.
And the consequence? We are turning our back on tradition, whether it's politics or religion, and finding our own personal way forward.
Our trust in big business, such as the banks, has been broken, along with the daily promises of our politicians. Telling your teenager that organised religion deserves their support sounds hollow.
Perhaps it's just society turning a corner, where we back ourselves over those held up as pillars of our community.
This week, one farmer, whose internet speed was too slow, decided to build his own private 53 metre tower. 
It's just one story, but it throws up dozens of other examples.
Losing faith in our institutions might even be making us more personally responsible. Like Ninja Warriors, we are getting life-fit, and steering our own course.
We are diagnosing ourselves online. Moving our political support away from the big parties. Working out childhood bullying episodes between parents, without involving the school.
There's one organisation that has risen above the onslaught of public cynicism. The Ekka. Where the modern and traditional mix as easily as the city and the country. Where a boutique beer can wash down the dagwood dog. Where knitting and sewing and cake decorating force long queues, and take pride of place.
Where teens sit with their grandparents barracking at the wood chop.
It's an institution that still serves us well. And one worth supporting.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tammy Law</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barnaby Joyce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Pisasale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catholic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin McManus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnny Depp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State MP Bill Byrne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ekka</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Gere</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ninja Warrior</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Canavan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bradley Kanaris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Nicholson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cardinal George Pell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Agriculture Department</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
