<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442469103995649</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/game-of-thrones-cave-paintings-joke-jon-snow-drew-them-2017-8</url>
  <title>'Game of Thrones' fans are all making the same joke about Jon Snow</title>
  <content>
Warning: Minor spoiler alert if you have not seen "Game of Thrones" season seven, episode four.
On the latest episode of "Game of Thrones," Jon Snow shows Daenerys the dragonglass mine beneath Dragonstone.

Much to Daenerys' surprise, Jon has found what appear to be ancient cave paintings in the mine. The paintings seem to depict a war between the allied Children of the Forest and First Men, and the White Walkers.

Jon explains to Daenerys that in the past everyone fought the same enemy: White Walkers. Jon tries to convince Daenerys to join the North's cause once more, but Daenerys says she will only fight for the North when Jon bends the knee, and again Jon resists (though it seems like he could be caving).

"Game of Thrones" fans have had some hilarious reactions to this scene on Twitter, joking that Jon drew the cave paintings himself to sway Daenerys into providing him with her assistance in fighting the White Walkers.

Here are some of the best responses to the scene:

Inside the episode: Jon actually painted those cave painting himself to convince Dany
- Jen Bunny (@jennnarellla)

So Jon drew that cave painting of the white walkers to convince Dany right?
- salam rida (@_salamrida)

Anyone else think Jon Snow spent the last week drawing those White Walker cave paintings to woo Dany?
- Chris Boggus (@ChrisBoggus1)

Jon probs drew the cave paintings to prove his point. He was down there a suspiciously long time w/o mining dragon glass
- Elizabeth H (@_EHolla)

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jen Bunny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ChrisBoggus1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Boggus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jon</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>First Men</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daenerys</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elizabeth H</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dany</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Children of the Forest</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dragonstone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jon Snow</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White Walkers</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
