<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442808406416088</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/sport/athletics/world-athletics-championships-2017-kurtis-marschall-vaults-to-final-morgan-mitchell-bereft-20170806-gxqiu7.html</url>
  <title>Powerful emotions as Marschall vaults to final, Mitchell left bereft </title>
  <content>
Australia's rising young star Kurtis Marschall has made it through to the pole vault final at the world championships, the first Australian man to do so since Steve Hooker retired.
Marschall advanced on countback after confidently clearing 5.60 metres with his first jump but missing out three times at 5.70m - a height he has been regularly clearing in other competitions and training.

Up Next

Bolt defeated by Gatlin in final 100m race

00:23

More Sports HQ Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Olympic champion Betty Cuthbert dies aged 79

Australian Olympic athletics champion Betty Cuthbert has died after a long battle with multiple sclerosis.

It left him with a nervous wait, relying on the performances of others to be able to get through. Eventually the cards - or the bar - fell his way. His successful first attempt at 5.60 was the difference.
"I cleared the same bar [5.60] that I cleared in Rio but I cleared it at the first attempt this time and I'm really happy with that," he said "I missed the first bar [at 5.70] which was very close and I was like, 'I've got this no worries at all'. And then the second attempt was a headwind and I just lost my confidence. That was a shocking jump.

Photo: AP
"I was stressing hard and always looking over to my coach, thinking, 'Am I going to sneak in, is 5.60 going to be enough?' It's always going to be a nervous wait when you miss the qualifying height or the height that is definitely going to get you in."

World and Olympic champion Hooker was the last Australian to make the pole vault final of major championship when he advanced in 2012 in London but did not clear a height in the final.

Australian runner Morgan Mitchell, for a while at least, could separate what was happening at the track from what was going on in her head. She could wipe away the tears that rolled down her cheeks as she cuddled under her doona not wanting to get out of bed. She would force herself up, go to the track and run. She could flick from person to athlete. 

You will now receive updates from

Sport Newsletter

Sport Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

On Sunday morning in London, she could not flick that switch. She was run out in her 400m in 52.22s to be fifth in her heat, and was bereft. Photo: Daniel Pockett
"It is a shit feeling, it's like I have brought it all back to the track, I just don't know, I'm so f---ing lost at the moment," she said tearfully.
In Rio last year at the Olympics she ran well to make the semi-final, but missed out on a final spot. She has battled post-Rio with the high and low of how she performed there, but other factors complicate the picture.
"That [Rio] definitely haunted me, it definitely wasn't supposed to go that way last year," the 22-year-old said.
"I think to be honest, I didn't want to care anymore, I fell into a heap of sad emotions, depression, didn't want to get out of bed, was crying at training. I'm not an excuse person, I told Fitz [coach Peter Fitzgerald] I might be sad but doesn't mean I am going to bring that to the track."
Mitchell speaks candidly of the depth of emotion and mental problems that have been plaguing her.
"It's the hardest sport," she said. "I don't think people understand how hard you work, for it to all fall to pieces in 52 seconds is just crap, it feels like last year all over again but I am a different person, a different athlete.
"I just don't know what's going on, we just have to sit down and re-evaluate and fix what went wrong. It's just hard separating yourself from athlete to person, particularly when you are suffering on the sidelines and people don't get that.
"I just don't get it, I really don't get it. I want to make that semi, I want to grow, I want to make a final. Stuff sucks at the moment."
Meanwhile, Australian hurdler Nick Hough knocked down five hurdles on his way to fifth in his heat in 13.61s which was not quick enough to advance to the semi-finals.
American Allyson Felix jogged over the line to win the heat of the 400m. The veteran, who is a nine-time world championships gold medallist and six time Olympic gold winner, has the quickest time in the world this year. Reigning Olympic champion Shaunae Miller-Ouibo was very comfortable in winning her heat in 50.97s.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morgan Mitchell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Hough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sports HQ Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Hooker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Betty Cuthbert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marschall</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Fitzgerald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitchell</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gatlin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shaunae Miller-Ouibo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>13</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurtis Marschall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fitz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Pockett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>American Allyson Felix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>14</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Olympic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
