<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443246493087135</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:21</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/greens-lose-coast-candidates/3209714/</url>
  <title>Greens lose Coast candidates</title>
  <content>
THE Greens bid to boost its support on the Sunshine Coast is in disarray with the party losing two key endorsed candidates months before an election day is set.
The party's high-profile candidate for Noosa, Joe Shlegeris, who in 2015 recorded its highest primary vote in the state has pulled out due to personal issues.
And Aaron White, who stood against Mr Shlegeris for Noosa and subsequently won pre-selection for Nicklin has announced he is quitting his candidacy, his position on the Greens' policy committee and the party.
Neither Mr White nor Mr Shlegeris responded to calls yesterday.
Noosa branch convenor Steve Haines said the party had been really disappointed to lose Mr Shlegeris who he said the party had been confident could wrest Noosa from the LNP's Glen Elmes.
The pre-selection process would begin again in two weeks with the party willing to look outside its membership ranks if a nomination was received from a suitable person.
Mr Haines said Mr Shlegeris' reasons for withdrawing had not been for "reasons related to the political process".
Mr White announced his intentions via a Facebook post expressing disillusionment with the state of the Queensland and Australia's political party system and saying he considered representatives often put the interests of their respective parties before the community's interest.
"My concern is the Greens are endeavouring to become mainstream right when business as usual politics are going out of fashion," he wrote.
"People are screaming out for uncompromising, genuine representatives who put the community's interests first and foremost."
Night of crashes rounds out weekend of heartbreak on Coast roads
Anger over being thrown out of Coast venue
BREAKING: New festival coming to the Sunshine Coast
Coast's vulnerable better off amid plans to build affordable rentals
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
A NATIONAL exhibition of ceramic art has been launched on the Coast
ONE of Hollywood's most adorable couples is over.
New celebrity cooking show fails to fire for Seven.
The legendary creator isn't so sure about how Netflix works.
*WARNING this story contains spoilers*
TARA Reid reveals what's coming in the next installment of TV movie.
Garth Prowd's vision made huge impact on Sunshine Coast community
Home sells in just one day
Winners in Master Builders regional housing and construction awards
Ray and Gert will celebrate 70 years of marrive this week
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garth Prowd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Haines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Shlegeris</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LNP's Glen Elmes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tara Reid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr White</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicklin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aaron White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Shlegeris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Haines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
