<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442593658048577</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/entertainment/tv/reality-tv/kim-kardashian-reveals-her-biggest-instagram-regret/news-story/56530b450980573fafb248fc991cdd09</url>
  <title>Kim Kardashian reveals her biggest Instagram regret</title>
  <content>
Kim Kardashian's Best Looks of 2016
1:24

Kim Kardashian had a busy 2016, so we decided to put together her best looks from the year for your viewing pleasure. So sit back, enjoy, and try to keep your tongue off the floor.

December 31st 2016
7 months ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment - syndicated/

Kim Kardashian reveals the Instagram photo she regrets most.

Share

IF YOU thought Kim Kardashian's biggest regret would be related to her sex tape or even the release of her 2011 single Jam (Turn it up), you're wrong.
Well, she probably regrets those too. But over the weekend, she's admitted her biggest Instagram regret.
After much reflection, the 36-year-old has revealed she loses sleep at night thinking about the engagement snap she posted after Kanye proposed to her on October 23, 2013.
The black and white photo features Kim's hand - with the sparkly diamond engagement ring displayed prominently on her finger. The grandstands at AT&T Park - the San Francisco baseball stadium where Kanye popped the question - looms in the background.

A post shared by Kim Kardashian West (@kimkardashian) on

So what's the big regret about? It has nothing to do with flaunting the $2 million 15-carat Lorraine Schwartz sparkler or the fact the man who's supposed to know her best decided to propose at a sporting facility.
She regrets her nails, obviously.
"One of my biggest photo regrets is when I got engaged and I had the shortest nails when I showed my picture. It would have looked so much better with long nails," she told beauty vlogger Patrick Starrr on his YouTube channel recently.
She pointed out she doesn't really like long nails and can't do her day-to-day business with them on. But, if it looks good on the 'gram, that's all that matters.
So, short nails on Instagram. It's an embarrassing life lesson we all must learn.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kim Kardashian West</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>San Francisco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kim Kardashian</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>YouTube</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Starrr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lorraine Schwartz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kim Kardashian's Best Looks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>T Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kanye</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
