<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443332392434713</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/air-force-one-history-america-president-airplane-photo-2017-8</url>
  <title>With a new Air Force One on the way, here's a look back at its incredible history</title>
  <content>
On Wednesday,  for two Boeing 747-8 Intercontinental commercial airliners that will be converted over to serve as the nation's next generation presidential transports.

The two brand-new jumbo jets were abandoned after Russia's Transaero airline bust in 2015. At the time, Boeing had already built two of the four 747s Transaero had on order. So instead of delivering the planes, Boeing completed flight testing and sent them to the California desert where they have been waiting for a new buyer. Now it seems the planes are now destined to take on the call sign, Air Force One.

Air Force One is instantly recognisable - both as the aeroplane of the President of the United States and as a flying symbol of American military and economic might. With its hand-polished blue, white, and silver livery, it boldly proclaims the arrival of the powerful man in the world.

What many people don't know is that there isn't one, but two nearly identical Boeing jets that serve as the official transport of the president. Normally, the planes are referred to by their tail numbers - 28000 and 29000 - but when the Commander and Chief steps on board, they take on the call sign "Air Force One." In fact, presidential aeroplanes didn't begin using the .

The president's pair of Boeing VC-25A jets are operated by the Presidential Airlift Group out of Joint Base Andrews in Maryland. While the current Boeing 747-based planes have been in service for more than two decades, they're simply the latest in a long-line of flying White Houses.

Here's a look back at the history America's presidential aeroplanes.

NOW WATCH: Executive Life videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boeing VC-25A</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Intercontinental</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joint Base Andrews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Transaero</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boeing</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Executive Life</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maryland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President of the United</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Air Force One</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Presidential Airlift Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia's Transaero</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
