<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442421859354803</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/world/2017/08/07/12/32/isis-predicts-brutal-bloodbath-in-raqqa-but-concedes-mosul-defeat-in-propaganda-magazine</url>
  <title>ISIS predicts brutal bloodbath in Raqqa but concedes Mosul defeat in propaganda magazine</title>
  <content>
The latest edition of Islamic State's propaganda magazine promises the  will be "no picnic", warning deadly booby trapped buildings and a wave of car and truck bombs await the anti-ISIS coalition.

Rumiyah, Issue 12, released today, features an interview with Islamic State's military commander of Syrian city Raqqa, the group's de facto capital.

Elsewhere, though, the magazine is devoid of much of the regular insights and content that analysts and ISIS supporters track inside each multi-language online edition.

There is no mention of the recent arrests of alleged plane bomb plotters in Sydney, and a counter-terror analyst spoken to by nine.com.au ranked issue 12 something of "a disappointment".

Notably, there was still no official confirmation whether the group's leader Abu Bakr al-Baghdadi is dead or alive, following recent speculation he had been killed in Syria.

Rumiyah's regular feature on terror tactics, where in the past the group has highlighted how-to guides to violent actions like kidnapping and truck-ramming, was also conspicuously absent.

Instead, issue 12 of the slickly produced magazine could be viewed as a "we're still here" statement, Raphael Gluck, a Washington DC-based counter-terror analyst, told nine.com.au.

Related Articles

Gluck said one of the key themes in issue 12 was Islamic State framing its recent , a former key strategic stronghold, as "part of the prophecy".

"ISIS now appears to concede Mosul, lauding the brave fight its soldiers mounted," the lead analyst for jihadOscope said.

Islamic State's rhetoric has recently focused on mocking the , as well as the involvement of a global coalition battling one determined ISIS army, Gluck added.

In the magazine, the military commander of Raqqa set the stage for what US-backed coalition forces will face as they tighten the noose around Islamic State's most important bastion in Syria.

Heavily booby trapped buildings, VBIEDs and strategically positioned sniper units are proliferated throughout the remaining parts of the city under ISIS control, according to the interview.

"The Battle of Raqqa will not be a picnic for the murtaddin and their supporters," the unnamed commander was quoted as saying.

An Australian fighter, Tareq Kamleh, also known as Dr Jihad, is believed to be in Raqqa. It is unclear how many other Australians jihadists could be with him.

The paediatric doctor who defected to the so-called caliphate appeared in an  last month, supposedly in a tunnel under Raqqa.

Gluck said today's issue of Rumiyah showed, despite losses and the crumbling of the self-styled caliphate, the group is still able to get its prized monthly propaganda magazine out.

(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tareq Kamleh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baghdadi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rumiyah</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syrian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raqqa</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Issue 12</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington DC-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raphael Gluck</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mosul</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gluck</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Battle of Raqqa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abu Bakr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ISIS</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Jihad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamic State</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VBIED</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>jihadOscope</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syria</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US-backed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
