<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443371047141012</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/national/man-was-charged-after-allegedly-filming-children-in-toilets-of-two-major-gold-coast-shopping-centres/news-story/075d0dce73d967dc94de90348d62d146</url>
  <title>Coast man charged with child exploitation</title>
  <content>
A MAN was charged with indecent treatment of a child after allegedly photographing and filming children at two Gold Coast major shopping centres.
It will be alleged that on August 6 a man who worked in a store at Harbour Town followed a 15-year-old boy into a public toilet and photographed him without consent.
The teen who noticed the phone under the door then told his father of the incident.
The father tracked down the alleged offender and detained him until police arrived.
It will be further alleged that once taken into custody, police found an additional video of two children on the man's phone believed to have been filmed in the toilets at Australia Fair in June.
Detectives from the Gold Coast Child Protection Investigation Unit have charged a 27-year-old Southport man with indecent treatment of a child under 16.
He was also charged with possessing child exploitation material, making child exploitation material and observations or recordings in breach of privacy.
He appeared in Southport Magistrates Court today and was granted conditional bail.
He will appear in court again on August 22.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast Child Protection Investigation Unit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southport Magistrate Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harbour Town</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia Fair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUGUST 22</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
