<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442297305301264</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/tasmania/state-government-drops-unattractive-plan-for-fibre-optic-cable-from-sydney-to-hobart/news-story/3d0b5ff441766aeeab8edbd72098cf2d</url>
  <title>Government drops fibre optic cable plan</title>
  <content>
A US$15 million ($A18.9 million) fibre optic line from Sydney to Hobart has been called an unattractive proposition for the state.
State Innovation Minister Michael Ferguson said the capacity provided by the line was not needed.
Mr Ferguson said the latest proposal offered by a SubPartners consortium was not the same as an original proposal, which had been "thrilling".

"Three years ago there was an opportunity announced and shared for plans for a fibre line called APX-Central, which was a fibre line which ran four pairs from Sydney to Perth, and that would continue to Singapore, which would be known as APX-West," he said.
"The opportunity dangled in front of Tasmania was that Tasmania take a spur line, an extension out of that line from Sydney to Perth."

Mr Ferguson said the State Government had been very interested in the possibility and had appointed a bargaining agent on behalf of the Government.
"Unfortunately in the time elapsed since then, the consortium has not agreed to that being an option and has offered an altogether separate line out of Sydney into Tasmania," he said.
Mr Ferguson said Tasmania already had sufficient capacity.
"For $US15 million [and] Tasmania to not have any rights on it, would not have been an attractive proposition," he said.

The Mercury has sought comment from the SubPartners consortium.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hobart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>APX-West</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SubPartners</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SINGAPORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>APX-Central</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Ferguson</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Innovation Minister Michael Ferguson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US15</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
