<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442808406416160</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/afl/afl-news/comment-west-coast-might-have-a-pulse-but-the-buzzards-are-circling-20170807-gxqua6.html</url>
  <title>West Coast might have a 'pulse' but the buzzards are circling</title>
  <content>
West Coast coach Adam Simpson boldly claimed the Eagles still have a "pulse" after coughing up another three-quarter lead to St Kilda on Sunday.
But in reality the defibrillators have been packed away, the machines have been turned off and a priest has been called in to give the Eagles their last rites.Photo: West Coast Eagles
West Coast can still make the top 8, but with two out of its three remaining games against sides currently sitting on top of the ladder it would require a Jon Snow-style resurrection from the dead for the Eagles to take part in September.
But there is no Red Witch lingering in the shadows to breathe life back into West Coast.

Adam Simpson joked after the game he was a "glass half full" kind of guy.
The only problem is he is dealing in an unimaginative game plan that smacks of a glass half empty when the game is on the line.

"That was a big one, but there's still a pulse," Simpson told reporters after the game.
"The boys are pretty tight at the moment. They're pretty galvanised and despite all the outside noise they're still having a go.Photo: AAP
"We'll go in with a real positive mindset this week."
The Saints smashed the Eagles in all departments in the last quarter winning the contested possession by 34. They had nine more clearances and laid 12 tackles more than West Coast. 
St Kilda belted the Eagles around the contest and the final tackle count of 81-50 in favour of the Saints paints a bleak picture.
What is more damning is the Eagles laid only four tackles in their forward 50 for the whole game.
Power forward Jack Darling, who had a serviceable game with two goals, didn't lay one tackle and neither did young goal sneak Malcolm Karpany.
Tagger Mark Hutchings only put the gripe on one Saint for the whole four-quarters and the man who replaced tackling-machine Matt Priddis, Chris Masten, had one.
I was critical two weeks ago of the Eagles giving Priddis a one-year extension (before he announced his retirement) but the 32-year-old should have played against the Saints.
The last time the Brownlow Medallist played against the Pies he had a game-high 12 tackles.
I'm not suggesting Priddis' presence would have helped the Eagles get over the line, but his physicality near the ball wouldn't have hurt West Coast's chances.
I think Luke Partington is an exciting prospect but a number of times he appeared to panic when the heat was on. Ironically the youngster didn't lay a tackle for the entire game.
Simpson gave a strong indication Priddis would be back for the Eagles' crucial clash with Carlton this Saturday.
But Priddis' omission for whatever reason the club wants to throw up was a glaring one.
"We 'managed' him (Priddis), a bit like we did with (Sam) Mitchell a few weeks ago (against Collingwood)," Simpson said.
"Pridda's fine. He's all in as well. That's a non-issue for us. He came over and was in the (coaches') box doing the role that Sam did a few weeks ago.
"We missed him at stages today but we need to continue to grow,  and he'll get an opportunity this week."
Eagles supporters have become accustomed to West Coast's last quarter capitulation, but giving up another lead against the Saints when the game was up for grabs is difficult to swallow.
Like I mentioned previously, it has lurched from an ugly problem to an epidemic and the fault has to come back to the coaching staff.
The Eagles' glass jaw was exposed again and it didn't even take a haymaker from the Saints to knock West Coast to the canvas, just a series of well-placed rabbit punches.
I was crucified by Eagles fans and accused of creating "hysteria" by some sections of the media by  should go at the end of the season.
Despite the barrage of abuse I stand by the statement and while Simpson might be safe for now, if he continues to deliver the same substance next year his job could quickly become untenable.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Darling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Masten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagles</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Red Witch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Partington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast Eagles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Priddis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Simpson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitchell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Hutchings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saints</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow Medallist</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jon Snow-style</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Priddis</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pridda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simpsons</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Karpany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
