<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442421859354753</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4838290/south-coast-line-airport-trains-back-to-normal/?cs=12</url>
  <title>South Coast line, Airport trains back to normal</title>
  <content>
Rail services are back to normal after the Airport Line was shut down after a crane toppled into an apartment complex at Wolli Creek on Sunday. Picture: Michele Mossop

Evening peak services on the South Coast line and trips to Sydney Airport will not be affected by Sunday's crane collapse at Wolli Creek.
On Sunday morning a large crane collapsed into an apartment complex at Wolli Creek.
The complex was evacuated, with up to 200 residents having to find temporary accommodation.
Trains on a section of the Airport Line were cancelled and Sydney Trains was concerned about possible delays on Monday.

"There may not be rail services to both the international and domestic airports [on Monday] morning,""CEO Howard Collins said.
However the crane was secured late on Sunday night and the airport line reopened.
A TrainLink NSW spokesman said the South Coast line commuters were not affected on Monday.
"There are no impacts on South Coast Line services today from the crane incident at Wolli Creek yesterday," the spokesman said.

"Trains are running as normal on the T2 Airport Line for our South Coast customers who plan to travel to Sydney Airport."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Airport</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>T2 Airport Line</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Airport Line</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wolli Creek</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Coast</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TrainLink NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO Howard Collins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Coast Line</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MICHELE MOSSOP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Trains</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
