<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442851356089561</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-07/police-say-racist-motive-to-car-acid-attacks-in-sydneys-north/8780742</url>
  <title>Acid attacks on Sydney cars could be racially motivated, NSW Police say</title>
  <content>
New South Wales police are investigating race as a possible motive after 16 vehicles, including luxury cars, had an acid-like substance poured on them in Sydney's north.
A 53-year-old bus driver has been charged with allegedly pouring a paint-eroding chemical on parked cars at shopping centres in Ryde and at Macquarie University between February and June this year.
Its understood all of the cars had ornaments or stickers on them that identified the vehicle's owner as being from an Asian background.
Superintendent Stephen Egginton said police were investigating if the attacks were racially motivated.

"We look at all motivation," he said.
"If it is determined that it is a racial motive that underpins these offences, then we will be seeking the court to actually look at that during any subsequent sentencing that might occur."
Police said they were concerned there may be more victims who had not come forward.
"We are concerned that a number of people may have had these offences occur against them but they haven't reported them to police," Superintendent Egginton said.
"It's important that members of the community feel that they can report these matters to us.
"Early indications were that there was a reluctance from some of the members from the community to come forward and report these matters."

University a hot spot

The man has been charged with 16 counts of malicious damage to property.
He has been released on strict conditional bail and will face Burwood local court later this month.
A statement from Macquarie University said that several cars parked in the university's W4 car park were vandalised earlier this year.
"The university security team regularly patrols all areas of the campus, including the car parks," the statement said.
"Once advised of the vandalism these patrols were further increased.
"The university has a very low rate of crime and takes all incidents of this nature very seriously.
"Police regularly visit the campus thanks to the Cops on Campus initiative, a collaboration between the university and NSW Police that sees a positive police presence on campus."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>New South Wales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryde</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>W4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macquarie University</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Superintendent Egginton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Superintendent Stephen Egginton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Police</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
