<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443113349098742</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:50</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/politics/taswater-chief-miles-hampton-labels-government-a-schoolyard-bully-over-its-planned-takeover/news-story/b53bc9d5462d0390cec559ef19c3f466</url>
  <title>TasWater takes aim at 'schoolyard bully'</title>
  <content>
THE head of TasWater has fired the first shot ahead of a final session of State Parliament set to be dominated by the Liberals' TasWater takeover bid.
The State Government will table legislation this week to take TasWater away from councils, creating a new government business enterprise responsible for water and sewerage services in Tasmania.
The Government says the new entity will deliver infrastructure upgrades faster than TasWater can while keeping a lid on price rises.
TasWater chairman Miles Hampton accused the State Government of acting like a "schoolyard bully" over the takeover.
Mr Hampton said TasWater had reviewed the draft legislation and sought a second round of legal advice which again says the takeover is illegal and unconstitutional.
He said the legislation was designed so neither TasWater nor its current owners, the 29 Tasmanian councils, could initiate a legal action to challenge the takeover.
It also gave the Government power to instruct the entity on how it should prioritise its infrastructure upgrades, as opposed to the program being guided by consultation with the Health Department and the EPA, Mr Hampton said.
"Under this scenario, nothing will prevent future projects from being prioritised to suit political agendas and election cycles," he said.
"The Treasurer and Government will be able to build up debt, require certain projects to be done ahead of other projects, and look after the big end of town."

Labor has already said it will vote against the legislation, meaning the Government will need the votes of at least six independent MLCs to achieve the takeover, meant to apply from mid-2018.
Opposition leader Rebecca White said the takeover bid and the legislation contained "a number of shortcomings".
Ms White said the Government had released a draft two weeks before a final Bill was to be tabled and did not seek submissions, indicating the Liberals were not serious about consulting in an effort to get the Bill through.
State Parliament resumes tomorrow, giving the Government until November to finalise promised changes before a state election is held by March.
Big-ticket items on the Government's agenda include the TasWater takeover, lowering the school starting age and land acquisition legislation to clear the way for a kunanyi/Mt Wellington cable car.
The Legislative Council has eight sitting weeks left this year and the House of Assembly has seven.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treasurer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberals' TasWater</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Parliament</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TasWater</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rebecca White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Miles Hampton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Legislative Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Wellington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>House of Assembly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Health Department</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EPA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hampton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MLCs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-10</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
