<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442765456742660</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/rugby-league/league-news/melbourne-storms-jesse-bromwich-wants-star-teammates-back-as-finals-approach-20170807-gxqre1.html</url>
  <title>Melbourne Storm's Jesse Bromwich wants star teammates back as finals approach</title>
  <content>
Melbourne Storm prop Jesse Bromwich has backed star teammates Cameron Munster and Tohu Harris to return from injury and make an impact.
Munster is considered a chance to return from an ankle injury in the Storm's clash with Sydney Roosters at AAMI Park on Saturday night while Harris is continuing to work on his return from a shoulder injury.Photo: Jesse Marlow
The Storm are on top of the ladder and a win over the Roosters would leave them three games clear with three games to go.
Ryley Jacks stood up when called in to replace Munster at five-eighth last round while the Storm's younger forwards such as Joe Stimson are also doing well in place of Harris.
But Bromwich would love to see both stars back leading into the finals, although the Storm won't risk either player until they have proven their fitness.
For either player to play against the Roosters they will need to be named in the Storm's extended squad on Tuesday.

"I'm probably expecting Munster to play but I haven't seen him out training yet," Bromwich said on Monday.
"I'm not too sure how he will go, we will see how tough he is."

You will now receive updates from

League HQ Newsletter

League HQ Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Harris has had multiple injury issues this year, which has been a surprise as in previous years he has been among the club's most durable players.
With the Kiwi star heading home to the New Zealand Warriors next season, Bromwich said Harris wanted to end his tenure at the Storm on the field.
"I feel for T at the moment," Bromwich said.
"He is moving on next year and he wants to be out there playing with the boys and finishing the year strong.
"He is another one who has had a bumpy season. He was injured for a long period at the start of the year and he played a handful of games and got injured again.
"He is busting his backside at training but I'm not sure how much it is improving. He will find out more this week and hopefully he is back soon."
With only three games until the finals after the Roosters clash, Bromwich has backed Harris to bounce back once fit.
"Definitely. He is someone who is very experienced," Bromwich said.
"He has played in a lot of big games, he is a big-game player and someone who has been there and done that.
"Having everyone back in the forward pack would be a great end to the year and with him moving on I'd love to send him out as best I could."
There is another looming issue for select Storm players as whoever ends the season without a try has to do a nudie run.
Bromwich and Munster top the list entering the last four games.
"It's been spoken about quite a lot over the last two weeks," Bromwich said.
"I'm trying to get onto anything but it's not coming my way. I'm finally giving in to the thought I might have to do it for the first time in my career."
The Storm play the Rooters at AAMI Park on Saturday at 5.30pm.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jesse Marlow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Stimson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAMI Park</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harris</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand Warriors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron Munster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>League HQ Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bromwich</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roosters</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Storm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Storm's Jesse Bromwich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Roosters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Munster</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryley Jacks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jesse Bromwich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kiwi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tohu Harris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
