<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442980205110317</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-07/end-of-ice-cream-tradition-as-mr-whippy-told-to-move-on/8781596</url>
  <title>End of 35-year tradition as Charlton Esplanade's Mr Whippy told to move on by Fraser Coast council</title>
  <content>
Whether it is the sound of Green Sleeves or the quick dunk into a waiting tub of molten chocolate, there is something special about visiting an ice cream truck at the beach on a holiday afternoon.
But there are problems on the Fraser Coast for Mr Whippy, who is finding it increasingly difficult to find a proper location.

The ice cream van owned by Robbie Staff has been tinkling and dunking on Charlton Esplanade at Hervey Bay for 35 years.
Now Mr Staff's livelihood is under threat and his business is fighting to survive due to council regulations.
"The [council] has legislation that severely restricts where we can operate. It's blatantly unfair and involves protecting other businesses from mobile businesses," he said.
"A lot of my trade is esplanade-based, people expect to find us on the esplanade here at Hervey Bay. It's not just us, it can also affect mobile coffee businesses."
Section 6(3) of the Fraser Coast Regional Council Local Law number 1 describes conditions for approval as a mobile food vendor, including:
Not sell, or offer for sale, any food within 200 metres of a retail shop selling the same or similar items of food.
Charlton Esplanade is a 10 kilometre stretch of beach-front road, looking out onto the calm waters off Hervey Bay, protected by the sand dunes of Fraser Island looming in the distance.
On this long stretch of road, it would be fair to assume there are locations where Mr Staff can do business, but he said it comes down to one thing: people.
"Like any business, we need to be where there are people. The council might say 'he's got all of Hervey Bay' but it's not of any use being able to trade in locations where there aren't people," he said.
"There would be very few places that we can actually trade that would be more than 200 metres from other places selling ice cream," he said.

External Link:

Ice cream runs through his veins
"Generally, the busier locations like here at Scarness are going to have other retail outlets that are selling different types of ice cream."
Mr Staff said he contacted the Fraser Coast Regional Council to work through the problem but they have yet to come to an agreement.
"We've had a lot of discussions with the council and explained that we wouldn't be able to survive without trading in these locations," Mr Staff said.
The Council provided a statement to the ABC regarding the ice cream vendor suggesting it make a submission to a local laws review scheduled for 2018:
While Council has been working with Mr Staff to find a solution, Council and Mr Staff have to work within the provisions of existing Local Laws and state legislation.
Council is ready to assist Mr Staff find ways to operate within the parameters of his permits and complete outstanding application requirements.
We encourage Mr Staff to make a submission outlining how he would like to change the local laws during the local law review which is planned for next year.
Between now and then, the sound of Green Sleeves may be heard much less on the esplanade or at local caravan parks.
"We've been trading in the local caravan parks for probably around 35 years," Mr Staff said.
"A lot of people look forward to coming here for the holidays and enjoying the tradition of coming out to the van. It's a big part of our business, definitely.
"We're going to find it very difficult to survive. Otherwise we would have to relocate. We don't want to relocate, we're happy here. All we need is a fair go."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fraser Coast Regional Council Local Law</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scarness</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlton Esplanade's Mr Whippy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlton Esplanade</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robbie Staff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Staff</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Whippy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fraser Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fraser Coast Regional Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hervey Bay</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Green Sleeves</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fraser Island</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Local Laws</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
