<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442907190665133</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:02</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Coffs Coast Advocate</source>
  <url>http://www.coffscoastadvocate.com.au/news/business-as-usual-for-winx-in-tuesday-trial/3209644/</url>
  <title>Business as usual for Winx in Tuesday trial</title>
  <content>
TRAINER Chris Waller couldn't be happier with the people's champion Winx ahead of her second barrier trial at Randwick on Tuesday morning.

But don't expect any fireworks as Waller said he wants to see her come through the 1000m gallop before "getting serious'' on her work with her season return in the Group 2 Warwick Stakes just 12 days away.

"She's well, it's just another exercise for her,'' Waller said. "After Tuesday we will get into the serious part of her training to see what she needs to fit for the Warwick Stakes.

"She's come up terrifically well, she's exactly where we need her to be.''

In her first trial back on July 24 jockey Hugh Bowman only let Winx out of idling mode for about 100m and she ran into third place.

It's likely the same will be asked of her on Tuesday in a heat which also includes potential spring stars Antonio Giuseppe, Daysee Doom, Invader and Pariah.

The latter trio will probably have a say in Winx keeping her maiden status in barrier trials intact - she's yet to win a trial in 15 attempts despite being undefeated in her last 17 races.

But as Waller says a trial is just a tool for preparing for a race.

"It will be a similar trial to the other day,'' he said. "We have to make sure she gets through the trial well but everything has gone to plan so far.''

In previous preparations Winx has been given a race day exhibition gallop prior to resuming but Waller said unless he feels she needs it racegoers will have to wait until August 19 to see her in action.

If he does, then she could be a surprise addition to this Saturday's Rosehill card.

"I don't think she will need a hard gallop, she looks picture perfect,'' he said.

Winx, the best racehorse in the world on turf, has won here last 17 starts on end and Waller is preparation her for a historic third straight Cox Plate in October.

Sydneysiders will be spoiled in the lead up to the Plate though as Waller is expected to run her in the Chelmsford Stakes and George Main in September and Craven Plate on Everest day on October 14 before heading to Melbourne.

Tuesday's trials could well shape the spring as most of Sydney's top line or emerging gallopers continue their build ups.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craven Plate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydneysiders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Randwick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Everest</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waller</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 24</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chelmsford Stakes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Waller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hugh Bowman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warwick Stakes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Group 2 Warwick Stakes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Antonio Giuseppe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Winx</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday's Rosehill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 14</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George Main</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cox Plate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daysee Doom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
