<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442855651056989</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/national/missing-woman-off-gold-coast-beach-after-clothes-left-on-shoreline/news-story/404664bc2a7ae4466862e8f9972186d4</url>
  <title>Missing Vic woman could be on Coast</title>
  <content>
POLICE are recoordinating efforts to search for a woman originally thought to have been missing off a Gold Coast beach this morning.
Earlier, clothes found about 300 metres north of Kurrawa Beach around 6.15am this morning sparked a wide ranging search by surf-life savers and water police.
Three council life guards, jet skis and a Surf Life Saving helicopter had been deployed in a bid to find 40-year-old Gail Elizabeth Oliver whose ID was found in a backpack containing women's clothing.
But a few hours later police called off the water search in the belief she had not gone into the water and could still be in the area.
Ms Oliver is a reported missing person from Victoria.
Members of the public have come forward to advise police they had seen a woman matching her description walking off from the area overnight.
Police are concerned for her welfare and are urging her to make contact with police straight away.
Anyone who has seen Ms Oliver is also urged to contact PoliceLink on 131 444 immediately.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>ID</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Oliver</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gail Elizabeth Oliver</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Policelink</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surf Life Saving</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurrawa Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
