<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442984500077874</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:20</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/queensland/crime-and-justice/fourth-arson-attack-in-a-week-on-north-rockhampton-home/news-story/ecd2932e052596303614a0ae5cde6ab4</url>
  <title>Fourth arson attack in a week</title>
  <content>
TEENAGER and her grandmother were forced to flee their home in the middle of the night, following the fourth arson attack on the house in a week.
Authorities arrived about midnight on Monday to find the Berserker St, North Rockhampton, home engulfed in flames.
Significant damage was done to the back of the property with a rear bedroom destroyed.
Two people inside the home, a 17-year-old girl and her grandmother, fled the house before it became engulfed.
The duo have now been forced to move out of the house, which police have declared a crime scene and are guarding around the clock.
Specialist scientific officers are working to determine the accelerant used in Monday night's attack.
Two teenagers are being interviewed by police as "persons of interest".
Rockhampton Police CIB officer-in-charge Detective Senior-Sergeant Luke Peachey said the home's residents and adjoining neighbours were on high alert about the escalating nature of the attacks.
A boy, 15, was charged with two acts of wilful damage placed by fire last week in relation to the first two attacks. He was remanded in custody. Since then two more arson attempts have been made.
"We have persons of interest who we are speaking to," Det Snr-Sgt Peachey said.
He wouldn't detail a motive for the ongoing attacks, other than to say police were "keeping an open mind" and investigating "a number of leads".
Det Snr-Sgt Peachey said arson attacks could easily become murder investigations.
"We need to be very vigilant," he said.
"On each occasion the fire is getting worse."
He said anyone with information should call Crime Stoppers on 1800 333 000.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Det Snr Sgt Peachey</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rockhampton Police CIB</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Rockhampton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berserker St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Detective Senior Sergeant Luke Peachey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crime Stoppers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
