<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442859946024314</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:51</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/business-and-homes-fall-victim-to-coast-crime-spik/3209646/</url>
  <title>Business and homes fall victim to Coast crime spike</title>
  <content>
A MAJOR crime spike has hit residents and businesses in a small Coast town.
Over the past two weeks Nambour has experienced a notable increase in break-ins and thefts prompting police warnings.
On the night of August 3, discount store Price Busters on Howard St was robbed of $300 including the till and a real estate agent suffered an attempted break-in.
Police suspect the two offences are linked.
During the same night a man entered the store Crystal Realm on Queen St which hadn't been locked.
The owner was in the store at the time and when she challenged the man he said he was security and warned her to keep the door locked.
Police confirmed the man was not a security guard.
On August 4, a man was charged with robbery after he stole a wallet from someone on Mill Lane about 7pm and the next day in an unrelated incident a mobile phone was stolen from someone on Curry St at 11.45am.
Break-ins have also been reported at homes in Image Flat, Yandina, Mapleton and Nambour with police suspicious of who may be committing some of the offences.
Residents are urged to lock their homes and cars as most of the offences were the result of people not securing their property.
Anyone with information about these crimes should contact Crime Stoppers on 1800 333 000 or Policelink on 13 14 44.
Night of crashes rounds out weekend of heartbreak on Coast roads
The plane you need in an emergency
Close call for Coast motorists as debris goes flying on motorway
Planning documents lodged on behalf of site owners
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
New celebrity cooking show fails to fire for Seven.
The legendary creator isn't so sure about how Netflix works.
*WARNING this story contains spoilers*
TARA Reid reveals what's coming in the next installment of TV movie.
Farmer's brave decision has cost him the game.
"It didn't seem like they were having a crazy, big night."
Garth Prowd's vision made huge impact on Sunshine Coast community
Home sells in just one day
Winners in Master Builders regional housing and construction awards
Ray and Gert will celebrate 70 years of marrive this week
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crystal Realm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mapleton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garth Prowd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Policelink</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Image Flat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tara Reid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Curry St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Howard St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Price Busters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crime Stoppers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yandina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mill Lane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
