<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442464809028245</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/tasmania/shooters-fishers-and-farmers-party-joins-fishers-calls-for-seal-relocations-to-stop/news-story/7f942c91eb7abf2433c315a2742837db</url>
  <title>Party calls for seal relocations to stop</title>
  <content>
FRUSTRATED fishermen have received backing in their calls for an end to seal relocations from southern fish farms to northern fishing grounds.
The Mercury reported last month that increasingly aggressive seals were charging at fishing boats, destroying nets and taking the catch of fisherman along the coastal strip from Rocky Cape to Devonport.

Tassal is the only salmon producer which still relocates seals and more than 1640 animals were moved into the North-West last financial year.
The company said it was in the process of installing better nets to protect their stock from seal incursions and seals were only relocated as a last resort.
The Shooters, Fishers and Farmers Party said there was "widespread community concerns" over the issue.
"SFFP Tas is aware from consultation with both commercial and recreational anglers that these predators, up to approximately 15 years ago, were in low numbers and few established seal colonies were established on the North-West Coast," party chair Wayne Turale said.
"It is now apparent these 'sea wolves' are now, after depleting the saltwater marine fishery, predating on Tasmania's world-renowned wild brown trout fishery, including our wild sea run browns and other estuarine species such as bream and other native fish.
"As incredible as it sounds these predators have been sighted as far inland as 17km near Mawbanna and also Sisters Beach by farmers who own property on, or near, waterways.
"These predators have also become increasingly aggressive towards humans with anglers reporting being 'charged'."
Boating anglers have told the party that seals - which weight about 150kg - were following hooked fish right up to and over the side of boats, creating a risk that the vessel may capsize.
"Local commercial fishers have been demanding action on this matter for some years now from Department of Primary Industry, Parks, Water and Environment and seeking support from Minister [Jeremy] Rockliff," Mr Turale said.
"As any experienced Tasmania outdoorsman knows, it is totally illogical to introduce large numbers of efficient predators into any environment that has limited and restricted prey. It goes totally against the basic rules of nature.
"Fishers now have grave fears for the local calamari fishery, which is one of the last species currently available in reasonable numbers."
SFFP Tas said the relocation program needed to stop until an independent assessment and impact study was conducted in consultation with commercial fishers.
The Mercury has contacted DPIPWE for comment.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wayne Turale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rocky Cape</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DPIPWE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SFFP Tas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Devonport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mawbanna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fisher</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeremy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North-West Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sisters Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tassal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Farmers Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Primary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rockliff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North West</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
