<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442980205110408</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4839122/there-will-be-blood-review-mso-brings-hard-edged-grace-to-greenwood-score/?cs=2372</url>
  <title>There Will Be Blood review: MSO brings hard-edged grace to Greenwood score</title>
  <content>
MELBOURNE INTERNATIONAL FILM FESTIVAL
THERE WILL BE BLOOD ????????????
Jonny Greenwood, Melbourne Symphony Orchestra
Hamer Hall
August 5

As part of the Melbourne International Film Festival, the Melbourne Symphony Orchestra rendered live Jonny Greenwood's sparse and terrifying score for There Will Be Blood, PT Anderson's 2007 epic chronicling the rise and fall of California oil man Henry Plainview???.
Conductor Hugh Brunt from the London Contemporary Orchestra - who has worked closely with Greenwood on films including arrangements for his band Radiohead - was flown in for the occasion.
Set against the desolate, cold and silent southern California desert, Greenwood's score spoke to that notion: bare, dry, lonely, remote and immense.
It opened with the sparse Henry Plainview, which started slightly anaemic but lifted powerfully as we descended into the dark silver mine. The cellists and other bass strings were outstanding, and bedded an otherwise chaotic score.
Proven Lands, manic and scary, navigated the film's anxiety with a hard-edged grace, the orchestra rarely faltering amid the violence of Greenwood's score.
But the true triumph was in the softer arrangements. Eat Him by His Own Light, Oil and Prospectors Arrive were all magnified by Brunt's restraint.
The thing about a film score is that it can be a thankless job: do it well and most people don't notice, do it poorly and it ruins the film. But the immense power of Greenwood's arrangements was evident as the MSO stalked Plainview over hills in the California desert. Almost subconsciously, the strings snaked their way into a scene and worked their ways over the murky contours of Plainview's face.
Johannes Brahms'??? Violin Concerto in D Major, Op. 77: III, a triumphant and unwieldy tune that ends the film, was wrestled into place by violinist Riley Skevington, who though he was sometimes drowned out by the orchestra and occasionally rushed among the more complex arrangements, ably reiterated the joyous irony of Anderson's masterpiece.
The story  first appeared on .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MSO</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Will Be Blood</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>D Major</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anderson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London Contemporary Orchestra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Radiohead</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johannes Brahms</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>III</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riley Skevington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamer Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hugh Brunt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Henry Plainview</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Symphony Orchestra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Concerto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greenwood</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prospectors Arrive</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PLAINVIEW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne International Film Festival</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PT Anderson's 2007</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonny Greenwood</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
