<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443237903152397</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/entertainment/television/kyle-sandilands-shock-confession-to-eddie-mcguire-im-135-kilos-eddie-help-me/news-story/bdcac8aaf347b146a8e43d7d0150fd2b</url>
  <title>Kyle begs Eddie for diet tips: 'I'm 135 kilos, help'</title>
  <content>
KIIS FM shock jock Kyle Sandilands has revealed he has tipped the scales at 135 kilograms before asking media personality Eddie McGuire for help.
McGuire  after revealing he had shed a whopping 20kg in a matter of weeks following an extreme diet.
The intensive 12-week program is based on Chinese herbs and involves not eating or drinking anything other than three cups of herb tonic a day for the first two weeks.

During an on-air interview on the Kyle and Jackie O Show, Sandilands, 46, told McGuire: "I'm 135 kilos Eddie - help me."
"It does take a bit of mental strength to get through but I found it relatively easy going," McGuire told the hosts, detailing his diet.
"You have the herbs but also you go and get the acupuncture and a massage for the first couple of weeks and also get weighed in everyday so that gets you a bit honest."

"You're probably the same Kyle, you've probably put on a kilo-and-a-half or two kilos every year."
Sandilands is shown holding up five fingers to his co-host Jackie O.
"You reckon I put on five (kilos) a year Jackie?" he was heard asking, which she nods in agreement. "Jesus."
McGuire responded by complimenting Sandilands, describing him as a "strong-minded bloke."
"You get belligerent like I did and when everyone starts pushing food in front of you, offering you drinks or saying you weren't working and then when it's all done they say, 'You're a plonk of fat'," he added.
Sandilands quipped "I'm in" when McGuire said people were allowed to smoke during the diet.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sandilands</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kyle</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jackie O Show</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jackie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eddie McGuire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sandilands, 46</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eddie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGuire</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jesus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kyle Sandilands</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KIIS FM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jackie O</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
