<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442937255436641</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/07/14/52/matt-wright-outback-wrangler-crocodile-duct-tape</url>
  <title>Aussie outback wrangler uses duct tape to shut giant jaws of monster crocodile</title>
  <content>
A monster crocodile the "size of 10 men" has been caught in Australia's Northern Territory, but it's not just the size of the reptile that has people talking.
On Saturday, Outback Wrangler Matt Wright posted a photo on Facebook of himself alongside the salt water crocodile, with its head appearing to be heavily wrapped in duct tape.
Some people commenting on the post, which has now gone viral with nearly 5000 likes and more than 700 shares, pointed out the thick layers of duct tape around the animal's head.
"Did you get enough tape on him hope that's not staying on for too long poor boy," one person said.
"Yes he is huge but time to take the tape off and let him go," another said.
However, one person argued that the duct tape helps keep the animal calm during relocation.
"Having spent quite (sic) at bit of time in and around Kakadu the tape is used for 2 reasons, to protect the people relocating the croc and as it covers the eyes the croc is not stressed and kept calm. The tail is still a forcible weapon as are the claws. Large salties like this are highly territorial and can become problematic for the locals."

Related Articles

Mr Wright is a helicopter pilot and animal expert who has made a name for himself posting photos and videos of his outback animal encounters on the internet.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia's Northern Territory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Outback Wrangler Matt Wright</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kakadu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Wright</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
