<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442950140338864</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/federal-politics/political-news/politics-live-liberal-party-meets-to-decide-position-on-gay-marriage-in-australia-20170807-gxqoow.html</url>
  <title>LIVE: Liberal Party meets to decide position on gay marriage in Australia</title>
  <content>
Let's take a look at what the meeting will discuss.

Five reformers - Dean Smith, Trent Zimmerman, Tim Wilson, Trevor Evans and Warren Entsch - are pushing for a free vote.

They have put their names to a private members' bill circulated to all government MPs at the weekend. The bill includes religious protections which they hope will help persuade voters to support their cause.

The Liberal party room meets at 4 pm.

The Labor caucus just had a quick together to show how great and unified everything is in its ranks.

Leader Bill Shorten said the reason why same-sex marriage hasn't been dealt with is clear and that's because of the "complete failure of leadership and weakness" of the Prime Minister.
More and more holes have appeared in the plebiscite policy.

It was supposed to be held in February this year - but Parliament had other ideas.

Many MPs have said they would not vote in Parliament according to the outcome of the plebiscite - leaving people to scratch their heads about the point of having their say.

Now, of course, we have the prospect of a postal plebiscite - which might be legally dodgy not to mention there's a whole generation of people who don't really use the postal system anymore.
It was a pretty hot-to-trot affair by all accounts - five-and-a-half-hours long - and it was less than a month later that Mr Abbott was gone as prime minister.

After the meeting Mr Abbott said there were two options for the party to take to the 2016 election - a parliamentary vote or a vote of the people.

Which is how we ended up with the idea of a plebiscite.
Tony Abbott is one reason and leadership is the other.

It is nearly two years exactly since the Coalition party room debated the issue - prompted, in part, by a cross-party private member's bill that would have legalised same-sex marriage.

That meeting ran for several hours and ended with MPs voting against a free vote on the issue.
And so we find ourselves here. Again. Waiting for the Liberal party room to have a super special meeting about something it says it is not that much of an issue for everyday people.

Same-sex marriage is the issue that will not go away for the Turnbull government.

So how did we get here?
Hello and welcome to the day (well, afternoon), in politics with me, Alex Ellinghausen and Andrew Meares.

It's a pleasure to have your company.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trent Zimmerman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Meares</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Abbott</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hello</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Ellinghausen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
