<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442559298309877</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Life Hacker</source>
  <url>https://www.lifehacker.com.au/2017/08/ask-lh-are-carport-entrances-classed-as-public-driveways/</url>
  <title>Ask LH: Are Carport Entrances Classed As Public Driveways?</title>
  <content>
Dear Lifehacker, I live in the Ipswich area of Queensland and am wondering if a driveway for a multi block of units is classed as a public driveway? The units each have a carport but there is only one driveway which is obviously shared by all residents. I am asking because a policeman has tried to tell me that as the units have a carport the driveway then becomes a public one. Is this right? Thanks, Margaret

The driveway to a block of units is simply an access area that allows motorists to enter. Whether public or private, nobody should be using the driveway as a parking space. As we have explained in the past, it is  to block a driveway in a way that prevents or hampers access to the connecting property. This includes parking in your own driveway outside of the property boundary.

In Queensland, motorists are prohibited from parking in driveways except in the following circumstances:

you drive a bus and are dropping off or picking up passengers

you are dropping off or picking up passengers within 2 minutes of stopping

you do not leave the vehicle unattended

In other words, if non-residents (or annoying neighbours) are using the driveway to park there car, you are entitled to notify your local council. A few fines from parking inspectors should see the problem cleared up in no time.

Cheers
Lifehacker

Got your own question you want to put to Lifehacker? Send it using our .

WATCH MORE: Travel Ideas

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>LH</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dear Lifehacker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lifehacker</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATCH MORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carport Entrances Classed As Public Driveways</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Travel Ideas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Margaret</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ipswich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
