<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443023154784200</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/north-west/consultation-starts-on-future-of-kyneton-primary-school-site/news-story/21aed21c09f4728d11b4389a06227882</url>
  <title>Fate of Kyneton school site in focus</title>
  <content>
A NEW masterplan and community consultation process will determine the future of the Kyneton Primary School site on Baynton St.
The primary school, built in 1855, will be superseded by an $11.5 million new school site on Edgecombe St, drawing into question the fate of the historic home.
But an announcement at Kyneton Mechanics Institute last Wednesday confirmed a period of review in which public suggestions for ongoing use would be open for public comment.

The State Government is tipping in $55,000 to the process, with $25,000 from Macedon Ranges Council, $15,000 of it in-kind support.
Macedon state Labor MP Mary-Anne Thomas said she was "very excited by this very significant investment in health and educational facilities".
Ms Thomas encouraged those with ideas to come forward, describing the masterplan process as "a once-in-a-lifetime opportunity".
"People have been gathering together and coming up with fabulous ideas," she said.
"It's clear recognition of how this site is important and primary schools are nothing if not the heart of community."
The process will begin imminently with the completion of the community consultation set for the end of this year, ahead of the school relocation.
West Ward councillor Roger Jukes said finding a future use for the site would be the start of a town revitalisation
"The government is clearly keen for the site to be continue to be occupied and education and training outcomes are clearly big possibilities here," he said.
Cr Jukes said the price of inaction with important public buildings was highlighted by the old Kyneton Hospital site.
"That's an example of the outcome if a proactive process is not initiated," he said.
Among suggestions to this point have been an autistic school or a lost trades hub.
The masterplan process will look at providing public open space in the town centre; explore mixed use (community services and commercial); explore of flexible and multiuse community spaces; and look at enhancing Kyneton's bluestone heritage buildings.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kyneton Mechanics Institute</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kyneton Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kyneton Primary School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labor MP Mary-Anne Thomas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Ward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edgecombe St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baynton St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kyneton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roger Jukes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Jukes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Thomas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macedon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MACEDON RANGES Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
