<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442168456280607</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:10</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/heaviest-rain-in-more-than-a-month-hits-and-misses/3209555/</url>
  <title>Heaviest rain in more than a month hits and misses</title>
  <content>
THE heaviest rainfall in more than a month was recorded in some places on the Sunshine Coast overnight but that according to the Bureau of Meteorology may be it for the rest of the week at least.
Things will really heat up Friday which is expected to hit 27 degrees and on Saturday when a 26 degree maximum is expected.
To the region's south Caboolture and Bribie Island felt the impact of a severe storm overnight Sunday which delivered falls between 25-28 mm good totals also reported north of Gympie.
On the Sunshine Coast 29mm at Diamond Valley in the hinterland topped the region's rainfall totals with Ewen Maddock Dam also receiving 22mm overnight.
Eudlo with 18mm, Pelican Waters with 17mm and Palmview with 12mm all received more rain than the 2mm recorded at Sunshine Coast Airport and along most of the coastal strip.
Forecaster David Croft said the weather would be fine now for the rest of the week with cool mornings particularly on Wednesday and Thursday with overnight temperatures dropping into single digits.
The Sunshine Coast can expect a sunny Monday afternoon following a cloudy morning with the temperature reaching 26 degrees after failing to drop below 14.9 degrees overnight.
Tuesday will be cooler with a nine degree minimum ahead of a 23 degree maximum on a sunny day with light winds gathering strength from the south west at 15-25kmh before dropping out in the afternoon.
Wednesday and Thursday are both expected to see temperatures drop to eight degrees overnight on sunny days which will reach 23 degrees with winds light early and then shift east on Wednesday and then north east Thursday reaching up to 25kmh.
Planning documents lodged on behalf of site owners
A breakthrough victory at the CrossFit Games.
In some ways SunCentral is like the Coast's version of the NBN
Five dates through August for community to have its say on rock wall
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
Farmer's brave decision has cost him the game.
"It didn't seem like they were having a crazy, big night."
The news came after the couple attended Splendour in the Grass
An intimate safari is on the couple's agenda
Blue Murder was the original true crime blockbuster.
Fiery larrikin Peter FitzSimons had the audience in stitches.
Garth Prowd's vision made huge impact on Sunshine Coast community
Home sells in just one day
Winners in Master Builders regional housing and construction awards
Ray and Gert will celebrate 70 years of marrive this week
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garth Prowd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bribie Island</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blue Murder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pelican Waters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamond Valley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Airport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gympie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SunCentral</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eudlo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast 29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caboolture</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ewen Maddock Dam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter FitzSimons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Croft</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CrossFit Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bureau of Meteorology</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palmview</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
