<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442937255436697</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/entertainment/tv/flashback/nbc-boss-reveals-his-revival-wishlist-includes-the-office-the-west-wing-and-30-rock/news-story/49be4367885090cc96a80d9652b64c1c</url>
  <title>NBC boss reveals his revival wishlist includes The Office, The West Wing and 30 Rock</title>
  <content>
The humour behind 30 Rock
2:05

Geoff Elliott and Jeff Immelt talk about the reality of TV show '30 Rock' and why selling down NBC helped GE get more focused.

March 20th 2013
4 years ago

The offer is open for Tina Fey to create new episodes of 30 Rock. Picture: Ali Goldstein

Natalie Wolfe

Share

IF YOU hadn't realised it yet, Hollywood is totally loving revivals right now.
Whether it's Disney adapting literally all of their cartoons into live-action remakes or streaming services buying up the rights to basically every series we've ever seen, the most obvious trend in the industry right now seems to be drawing on old success stories.
NBC's Entertainment Chairman Bob Greenblatt recently revealed  that since Will & Grace was given the green light to come back, he's been dreaming big about reviving some of the network's greatest shows.

The excitement around Will & Grace's return has opened the floodgates.Source:Instagram
In recent years, there have been a number of revivals that no doubt should've stayed on the shelf but, if Greenblatt's wishlist is anything to go by, we could be in for some exciting reboots.
The chairman revealed The Office, helmed by Greg Daniels, has been at the top of his list for a while ever since it finished its hugely successful nine season run back in 2013.
"We often talk about The Office, I've talked to Greg four times over the past few years. It's always, 'maybe some day but not now'," he told Deadline.
"There is certainly an open invitation but we don't have anything happening right now. If he wants to do it, I would do it," he added.

Steve Carrell mightn't be done with Michael Scott yet.Source:News Limited
And, also hopefully on the horizon is a 30 Rock revival.
The show, which starred Tina Fey and Alec Baldwin, ran for seven seasons until 2013 and was nominated for over 100 Primetime Emmy Awards.

"I'd say to Tina 'Hey, you think some more 30 Rock makes any sense?' She'd say, I don't know maybe.'"

Tina Fey, the writer behind 30 Rock, has shut down Greenblatt on numerous occasions. Picture: Ali GoldsteinSource:AP
And the optimistic Greenblatt also revealed he's been regularly shut down by Aaron Sorkin, the man behind the critically-acclaimed political drama The West Wing.
"I keep saying to him, 'Do you want to do The West Wing again, wouldn't it be great to do it?' He says, 'You know I love that show and some day I'd love to revisit it, but it's not going to happen right now'," he told
But despite Greenblatt's push for a number of future revivals, the chairman also admitted he's nervous about bringing popular shows back for a second time.
"It's not an easy think to crack [a revival], expectations are so high and you've got to get it just right," he said.
"If Tina called and said 'I'd do 30 Rock,' I'd do it in a heartbeat, even for a limited run. The same about The Office."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Natalie Wolfe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alec Baldwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tina</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Daniels</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeff Immelt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Goldstein</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Disney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali GoldsteinSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aaron Sorkin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Carrell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Primetime Emmy Awards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Wing</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geoff Elliott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Limited</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Scott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBC Entertainment Chairman Bob Greenblatt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greenblatt</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tina Fey</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
