<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442937255436636</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4838989/the-internet-isnt-handling-this-hollywood-split-well/?cs=2372</url>
  <title>The internet isn't handling this Hollywood split well</title>
  <content>
One of Hollywood's favourite pairs, Chris Pratt and Anna Faris, have announced they are "legally separating" after eight-years of marriage.

In a joint statement released on their social media accounts the actor couple, who married in 2009, said they have "tried hard for a long time," before asking for privacy for the sake of their four-year-old son Jack.
"Anna and I are sad to announce we are legally separating," the statement on reads.
"We tried hard for a long time, and we're really disappointed. Our son has two parents who love him very much and for his sake we want to keep this situation as private as possible moving forward. We still have love for each other, will always cherish our time together and continue to have the deepest respect for one another."

According toPeople , the Guardian of the Galaxy Star Pratt, 38, and Mom star, Faris, 40, have both been spotted without their wedding rings in recent times, including Faris noticeably not wearing it at the premiere of her Emoji movie. This is Faris' second marriage, having split with actor Ben Indra after four years in 2008.
With the couple frequently crowned #relationshipgoals on social media, fans have not taken the news well, with many going into a frenzy across all platforms with emojis and words of support to express their sadness and dismay for the "perfect couple."
"I know it's ridiculous to care about a relationship involving two people you've never met. I know it's crazy how much society today value celebrities and their lives. But I am honestly saddened to hear this just because they seemed so perfect together," wrote one fan on Pratt's Facebook.

You've gotta do what's healthiest for you and Anna. You're setting a great example for your son. Families come in many forms. Love to yours??????? Amber | ??????????????????? (@AmberKinion)

I'm really sorry to hear this. We all have your back and will support you throughout this difficult time. I'm so so sorry. ??????? brooke (@dianaofasgard)

The pair first met in 2007 when they co-starred in Take me Home, before getting married in Bali in 2009. Earlier this year their son Jack stole hearts when he joined his parents at Pratt's Hollywood Walk of Fame unveiling. At the event, Faris thanked the actor for being her "anchor" through everything including the premature birth of their son.
"This is actually a thank-you speech," she said according toPeople. "I'm the beneficiary of all this because I get to spend every day with this wonderful man. I know that if our circumstances were different and we weren't as fortunate to be standing here and living our Hollywood life, we would be happy in the woods together, I think."
Pratt also took to the stage with kind words for his wife, "I want to thank my wife Anna, I love you. You've given me so much. You gave me the greatest star in the galaxy in my little boy, I love him and I love you...For your dedication and your heart. I will do my best to protect it, and in return I will give you all of those things as well. You have my heart, my dedication, my trust."

Cue the internet's tears.

The story  first appeared on .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anna Faris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Pratt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Faris, 40</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Indra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amber</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Guardian of the Galaxy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>toPeople</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anna</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bali</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Star Pratt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AmberKinion</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pratt's Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pratt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pratt's Hollywood Walk of Fame</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FARIS</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
