<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443246493087149</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-07/don-zach-merrett-joins-danger-on-brownlow-sidelines</url>
  <title>Don Zach Merrett joins Danger on Brownlow sidelines</title>
  <content>
Zach Merrett has been offered a one-game ban for his strike on Lachie Plowman

ESSENDON'S Zach Merrett has joined the ranks of Brownlow Medal fancies ruled ineligible after he was offered a one-game ban for striking Carlton's Lachie Plowman.

Merrett struck Plowman in the midriff with a swinging left arm during the second quarter of Essendon's eight-point win at the MCG.

The incident was assessed as intentional conduct with medium impact to the body, resulting in a two-game suspension, which can be reduced with an early guilty plea.

Merrett, who is projected to poll 15 votes after 20 rounds on the AFL.com.au Brownlow predictor, would have to successfully challenge the charge at the Tribunal on Tuesday night if he were to have any chance of winning the award.

•

With reigning Brownlow medallist Patrick Dangerfield already ruled out of taking a second 'Charlie' home after his tackle on Carlton ruckman Matthew Kreuzer in round 19, Merrett's ineligibility makes it two of the competition's most in-form players now set to spectate on the Monday night of Grand Final week.

Richmond superstar Dustin Martin is the raging favourite to have the medal draped around his neck but even that is in danger. He has twice been fined for low-level offences this season and if it happens a third time, he will automatically be struck out for a game and won't win the Brownlow.

According to the AFL.com.au predictor, Josh Kelly (21 votes), Tom Mitchell (19) and Marcus Bontempelli and Rory Sloane (each 18) would be the main contenders if that happened.

Lachie Plowman went to ground following this incident involving Zach Merrett.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MCG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow Medal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rory Sloane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Mitchell (19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Plowman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Dangerfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton's Lachie Plowman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Kreuzer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Final</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon's Zach Merrett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dustin Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Kelly (21</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lachie Plowman</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zach Merrett</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marcus Bontempelli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Merrett</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
