<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442765456742649</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/entertainment/music/tours/sydney-adele-fan-speaks-about-having-a-heart-attack-at-the-singers-concert/news-story/59e5719b90a7ecdd7a45740ffe87aa19</url>
  <title>Sydney Adele fan speaks about having a heart attack at the singer's concert</title>
  <content>
Adele may never go on tour ever again
0:56

Adele may be done touring for life. The singer announces that she may never perform in another live show, in a heartfelt handwritten note, after ending her tour in London.

June 30th 2017
a month ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment - syndicated/

Adele performed in front of huge crowds in Australia earlier this year. Picture: Cameron Spencer

Natalie Wolfe

Share

WHEN Adele hit Australian shores earlier this year to bring her world tour down under, it seemed like nothing could stop the British powerhouse.
The singer was  left, right and centre and performed for her biggest crowd to date at Sydney's ANZ Stadium in March.

Adele performing at ANZ Stadium on the night a fan collapsed. Picture: Cameron SpencerSource:Getty Images
But,  the singer caused in every city she played at, there was one event that stopped Adele in her tracks - when one of her Aussie fans collapsed to the ground mid-show.
Ambulances were called to ANZ Stadium halfway through Adele's first Sydney show on March 10and had to be taken to Westmead Hospital for treatment.
The super-fan has since been identified as 47-year-old Sydney woman Megan Nicholson who recently  about her near-death experience.
"I was dead. My family almost lost me," Ms Nicholson told the magazine.
Megan, whose husband Andrew bought her VIP tickets to the show as an early birthday present, went into cardiac arrest right after she threw a bracelet on stage for the singer.
"Once I got to the stage and saw her [Adele] coming towards me I felt an adrenaline rush, and then I felt clammy and nauseous," she said.
Ms Nicholson has since fully recovered, telling the magazine the doctors believe it was excitement that caused her collapse.

"The only explanation the doctors could come up with is the adrenaline rush sent me into cardiac arrest," she said.

Megan Nicholson with her husband Andrew.Source:Facebook
Adele was instrumental in making sure Ms Nicholson was taken care of at the concert after she saw the paramedics walking towards the collapsed concertgoers.
"She stopped the show after about a dozen paramedics came into the front area of the stadium,' news.com.au
"She could see them [paramedics] so she quickly told everyone to get out of the aisles.
"Then the next song started, which was Set Fire to the Rain, and the light show started. Adele yelled out 'STOP WAIT' and the lights came back on."
It is understood Adele became quite emotional as the woman was treated on the scene.
"The lights came back on, and Adele burst into tears," news.com.au reported at the time.
"Adele said 'I'm sorry, I can't, someone's not well and I'm worried. There's fireworks in this song and I don't want to scare them.'"
It is understood Adele started the song again when she was given the all clear and the woman was escorted from the stadium on a stretcher.
At Adele's second Sydney show on March 11, the singer dedicated Take It All to the then-hospitalised Megan and wished her a speedy recovered
"At this point in the show last night, there was a lady, she got really ill down there and I sang this song and with my back to what was going on," she told the crowd.
"I knew what was going on but I was really scared and it was at this point I stopped the show to check if she was okay. I don't know if she's okay yet but I'd like to sing this song for her tonight," she added.

Adele played in front of nearly 100,000 fans at her second Sydney concert on March 11, 2017.Source:Supplied
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Natalie Wolfe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westmead Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getty Images</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Take It All</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adele</name>
    <count>16</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron SpencerSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VIP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 11</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney's ANZ Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>STOP WAIT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Adele</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Megan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Set Fire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Megan Nicholson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANZ Stadium</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CAMERON SPENCER</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Nicholson</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
