<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442980205110428</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/07/14/55/perth-dad-rescued-after-three-nights-lost-in-the-desert</url>
  <title>Perth man who spent three nights lost in the desert doesn't want police help to retrieve car</title>
  <content>
A Perth man who spent three nights lost in the Pilbara desert intends to retrieve his car without the help of police.

Anthony Collis was flown to Newman Hospital yesterday to be treated for severe dehydration and sunburn, but was discharged last night.

The 32-year-old's ordeal began on Thursday, when he and his girlfriend planned to travel from Perth to Darwin, but became bogged on the Canning stock route.

His partner, Debbie Blomfield, managed to stumble to a nearby campsite and raise the alarm.

A major search involving the tactical response group and Aboriginal trackers was launched, but it took three days to find the missing Perth father.

Emergency crews discovered foot tracks on Sunday morning, which led to his rescue.

Mr Collis' feet were badly torn up after walking around the remote Pilbara barefoot.

Related Articles

He is recovering in Newman with his partner.

It is understood the pair intends to hire a car to return to the Canning stock route to collect their own car and drive it back to Perth.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newman Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Collis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pilbara</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Collis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Debbie Blomfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aboriginal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canning</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
