<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443237903152429</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/sport/boxing/paulie-malinaggi-discusses-sparring-session-with-conor-mcgregor/news-story/6a2107971d5a50c0825cd32bfa5ef7aa</url>
  <title>Paulie Malinaggi discusses sparring session with Conor McGregor</title>
  <content>
Conor McGregor speaks during the Floyd Mayweather Jr. v Conor McGregor World Press Tour.

John Hutchinson and Stuart AtkinsThe Sun

Share

CONOR MCGREGOR 'whimpers like a girl' when he is punched in the body, according to former sparring partner Paulie Malignaggi.
The pair are continuing their war of words on social media, after Malignaggi stormed out of McGregor's training camp after claiming he was "set up".
It came after a photo was doing the rounds showing the American on the floor after being 'knocked down' by McGregor.
Malignaggi insists it was the result of a push, and was seething at how he was "used" by the McGregor camp.

Paulie Malignaggi following his fight with Danny Garcia.Source:Getty Images
And now the retired Brooklyn boxer has again taken to social media to criticise the Irishman's boxing durability.
He wrote on Twitter: "He whimpers like a girl when he gets ripped to body lol".
Yea but this coming week I'll actually start to discuss a bit what happened Tuesday, he whimpers like a girl when he gets ripped to body lol
When asked does he regret helping out McGregor, Malignaggi replied: "Absolutely".
He added: "When I look back at the experience as a whole, not just sparring but as a whole, yes there was definitely an agenda beyond shadow of a doubt."
"I didn't get paid, I'm not worried about it though. I paid him with the ass beating he received from me on Tuesday".

McGregor opened up on the controversial sparring session with Malignaggi and insisted the former boxer "got his ass whooped".
Speaking on Showtime's All Access, McGregor was adamant there was only one aggressor when the two sparred.

Paulie Malignaggi is a two-time boxing world champion.Source:Getty Images
The Notorious said: "He stayed in there - you've got to give him respect for that.
"But that was it - he came, he got his a** whooped and that was it."
McGregor went on to explain why he brought former welterweight world champ Malignaggi in for the training sessions.
He added: "I was just watching this guy speak, like 'who the f*** is he?'.
"I looked at his stance, looked at his approach. There are some similarities to Floyd.
"I don't really give a f*ck if there were similarities or not.
"He was speaking a hell of a game. I said, 'bring this boy in here and let's fight!'"

Conor McGregor during the Floyd Mayweather Jr. v Conor McGregor World Press Tour.Source:Getty Images
Malignaggi at first was very complimentary of the Irish MMA star turned boxer, saying that the UFC lightweight champion had good power.
But after one too many photos of the sparring sessions were leaked online, Malignaggi feels enough is enough and he has demanded that McGregor releases the sparring session video.
Writing on Twitter, the retired Brooklyn boxer said: "Its not nice to paint a picture that isn't true.
"This was a pushdown in sparring, post the whole video rounds 1 through 12 unedited".
"I came to help this camp out, not to be exploited, now your gonna get the truth though.

Paul Malignaggi will work as an analyst on the McGregor-Mayweather fight.Source:Getty Images
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Floyd Mayweather Jr</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Conor McGregor</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getty Images</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGregor</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGregor-Mayweather</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BROOKLYN</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malignaggi</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Malignaggi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Conor McGregor World Press Tour.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UFC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Hutchinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paulie Malinaggi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paulie Malignaggi</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Showtime's All Access</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Irishman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Floyd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Conor McGregor World Press Tour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stuart AtkinsThe Sun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Danny Garcia.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Irish MMA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
