<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442464809028217</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/07/12/55/cost-of-melbourne-north-east-link-could-soar-to-23-billion</url>
  <title>Cost of Melbourne's North East Link could soar to $23 billion</title>
  <content>
The cost of building Melbourne's North East Link toll road could soar above $23 billion, under alignment options outlined by the authority in charge of the project.
The North East Link Authority (NELA) has presented four proposed corridors for the project, varying in length from 11km to 40km.
Option A is the shortest, and links the Ring Road at Greensborough with the Eastern Freeway at Bulleen Road, with a tunnel between Lower Plenty Road and Manningham Road.
Option B is a 24km corridor between Greensborough and Eastlink at Ringwood, up to 70 per cent of which would be underground.
Option C is slightly longer at 26km and pushes the alignment further east, past Ryans Road.
Finally, Option D would take the tollway outside the city's Urban Growth Boundary, with a 40km road crossing the Yarra River near Kangaroo Ground.
Premier Daniel Andrews said the government would nominate its preferred alignment by the end of the year.

Related Articles

"We are about getting this right, and getting it done," he said.
"We said we would share all the options, and that's what we've done."
The NELA has warned all four options would likely require the acquisition of properties.
It said it's too early to discuss cost, but a rough estimate suggests Option A would be the cheapest at about $6.3 billion, while Option D could come in at more than $23 billion.
Ivanhoe MP Anthony Carbines said the toll road would help reduce traffic on Rosanna Road, which acts as a "de-facto Berlin Wall", but wouldn't commit to any option.
"I will support the corridor option that has the community support", he said.
Documents provided by the NELA show Option A to be the most beneficial route, due to its direct connection between the Eastern Freeway and Ring Road, as well as a likely reduction in trucks on residential streets, and potential improvements to travel times and local bus services.
The state opposition has voiced its support for the North East Link, but Liberal Leader Matthew Guy said the government should also resurrect the scrapped East West Link.
"Without the East West Link the government will be building the North East carpark", he said.
A number of local councils and residents' groups are concerned about the possible impact on local amenity.
The Greens oppose the project, and have called for the government to scrap its plans.
Greens MP Samantha Dunn said building more roads would simply create more congestion
"If the government actually asked the voters, they'd say invest in public transport, like the Doncaster rail line," she said.
The government said it expects to sign contracts in 2019.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne's North East Link</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rosanna Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulleen Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ringwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East-West Link</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greens MP Samantha Dunn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryans Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yarra River</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ring Road</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manningham Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Option D</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Option A</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lower Plenty Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eastern Freeway</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EastLink</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kangaroo Ground</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Daniel Andrews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Leader Matthew Guy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ivanhoe MP Anthony Carbines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doncaster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North East Link</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berlin Wall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NELA</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GREENSBOROUGH</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North East Link Authority</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Urban Growth Boundary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
