<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443237903152390</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:19</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/news/homemade-balloon-bomb-starts-fire/news-story/3caeed7341817029fa344ece3bb4756a</url>
  <title>Homemade 'bomb' terrifies mother</title>
  <content>
A HOMEMADE "balloon bomb" is being blamed for starting a fire on the roof of a Townsville home last night.
Jazzmine Gregory was in her Heatley home last night about 10pm when she heard a loud bang near her daughter's bedroom.
She yelled out to what she thought were intruders but received no response.
"They just kept smashing on my door and windows. It sounded like they were trying to break in so I called the police," she said.
"At this time I felt safe turning the lights on to look outside when I spotted my neighbour in my yard who said there was a fire on my roof.
"I went down to see a fire on my roof and was still on phone to the police who asked if we were okay."
Firefighters soon turned up and climbed on the roof to find what Ms Gregory described as a "metal thing with melted electrical wire and tape".
"On inspecting it this morning I found it had a chemical smell and wired white stuff on it," she said.
Ms Gregory said her neighbour had seen the device land on the roof and described it as a balloon that was on fire.
"Someone is making homemade balloon bombs," she said.
Ms Gregory said she was concerned those responsible for causing the fire would return.
And she has no idea who could be responsible for the sinister prank.
"I keep to myself," she said.
"I think it's just kids going around randomly targeting houses."
A spokeswoman for the Queensland Police Service confirmed officers attended the home last night.
Police do not believe the incident is related to an explosion in Flinders St on Thursday night.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms. Gregory</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Police Service</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heatley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jazzmine Gregory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flinders St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
