<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442387499615977</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/rising-star-re-signs-for-titans/3209581/</url>
  <title>Rising star re-signs for Titans</title>
  <content>
THE Titans have scored a retention coup by signing rising star Morgan Boyle for a further three seasons, locking the hulking forward up until the end of 2020.
Boyle, who joined the Gold Coast from Canberra last year as part of their under-20 program, made his NRL debut in Round 6 against his old club and has played 12 games this year despite being on a second-tier deal.
The 197cm, 100kg second-rower's improvement has been exponential and the Titans were desperate to extend his contract.
They had to fight significant interest from several clubs though, including the Wests Tigers, who were understood to have been chasing the 21-year-old as late as last week before he signed with the Titans.
Boyle is understood to have signed a significantly upgraded three-year deal.
Boyle is the latest part of the puzzle for the Titans, who have several members of their pack locked up until at least 2019, including Ryan James, Jarrod Wallace, Kevin Proctor and Nathan Peats.
Fellow young gun Max King extended his deal with the Titans to the end of 2019.
The Titans are also expected to announce the signatures of forwards Jai Arrow and Brenton Lawrence in the coming days.
Close call for Coast motorists as debris goes flying on motorway
Heavy rain misses most of Coast
Planning documents lodged on behalf of site owners
Five dates through August for community to have its say on rock wall
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
TARA Reid reveals what's coming in the next installment of TV movie.
Farmer's brave decision has cost him the game.
"It didn't seem like they were having a crazy, big night."
The news came after the couple attended Splendour in the Grass
An intimate safari is on the couple's agenda
Blue Murder was the original true crime blockbuster.
Garth Prowd's vision made huge impact on Sunshine Coast community
Home sells in just one day
Winners in Master Builders regional housing and construction awards
Ray and Gert will celebrate 70 years of marrive this week
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boyle</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garth Prowd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blue Murder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jai Arrow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tara Reid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Max King</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wests Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan James</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Peats</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brenton Lawrence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Titans</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarrod Wallace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morgan Boyle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin Proctor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Round 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
