<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443289442760920</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/blogs/rita-panahi/bill-shorten-and-the-politics-of-envy/news-story/49f623eb7d1aae0ba57787abda76fb07</url>
  <title>Bill Shorten and the politics of envy</title>
  <content>
of Australia if he remembers that one must "never interfere with an enemy while he's in the process of destroying himself".
Lately, Shorten has had a great deal to say about the great divide between the haves and have-nots.
The Opposition Leader's habit of indulging in class warfare would be fraught with danger if the Coalition weren't so hopelessly inept at prosecuting an argument.
Shorten's stirring speech on inequality was at a luncheon of Labor luminaries, academics and public servants dining on beef tenderloin and desserts adorned with gold leaf.
The irony was delicious.
"The system as it stands is accelerating inequality rather than addressing it," Shorten thundered. "It is entrenching unfairness rather than alleviating it."
Labor is set to push the "inequality" message heavily in the coming months, complete with a vow to make the rich pay their "fair share" of tax.
The notion that the rich don't carry their fair share of the tax burden is popular with the Left globally and is being pushed heavily by Shorten.
But the reality is that the top 10 per cent of income earners pay close to 50 per cent of all personal income tax collected in Australia - that's after all the "generous tax concessions" that Shorten whines about including negative gearing.
Meanwhile, the bottom 30 per cent of income earners pay only about 5 per cent of income tax collected. That figure is even less when you factor in government handouts that taxpayers on lower incomes receive.
Australians are aspirational and want equality of opportunity.
Trying to engineer equality of outcome is neither fair nor prudent.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shorten</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Opposition Leader</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
