<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443242198119780</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/tasmania/antidiscrimination-commission-to-hear-complaint-over-hobart-preacher-campbell-markhams-blogs/news-story/faf220e76fb3281419182fd1892df5a1</url>
  <title>Pastor to answer for anti-gay blogs</title>
  <content>
A HOBART pastor will face Tasmania's Anti-Discrimination Commission over online blogs referring to the gay lifestyle as "distressingly dangerous" and having "appalling health risks".
Presbyterian preacher Campbell Markham is subject to a complaint over the blogs written during Tasmania's heated gay marriage debate in 2011.
He has called for the Anti-Discrimination Act to be scrapped because it threatened the ability of Christians to teach the Bible and hamstrings debate among the wider community.
But gay rights activist Rodney Croome has defended the laws, which prohibit offending someone on the basis of things such as sexuality, saying they protect the LGBTI community from "hateful" language.
The complaint has been accepted by Anti-Discrimination Commissioner Sarah Bolt.
Mr Markham and fellow Cornerstone Hobart Church member David Gee, head to conciliation on Friday. Mr Gee faces complaints over his street preaching in Hobart Mall.
The complaint also refers to a blog Mr Markham wrote about school posters that discussed same-sex parented families.

The blog quotes the Bible: "If anyone causes one of these little ones who believe in me to sin, it would be better for them to have a large millstone hung around their neck and to be drowned in the depths of the sea."
Mr Markham said it was a quote from Jesus relayed by a first century rabbi who used "very pointed language to seize the attention of listeners".
"All of Jesus' teachings have that kind of quality and perhaps people in the Church are more used to hearing and understanding the context of that language."
In no way was he condoning capital punishment, Mr Markham said.
He said debates around these issues should be played out in the community and not restrained.
"I believe Tasmanians ought to have the right to speak their minds," he said.
Tasmanian Gay and Lesbian Rights Group spokesman Rodney Croome said the case highlighted the importance of "strong laws against hateful and offensive language speech".
"Freedom of speech is a fundamental right but it is not absolute, and when free speech crosses into hate speech a line has to be drawn," he told the Mercury yesterday.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Markham</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian Gay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Gee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bible</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anti-Discrimination Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hobart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rodney Croome</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Gee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anti-Discrimination Commissioner Sarah Bolt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LGBTI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Presbyterian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Campbell Markham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cornerstone Hobart Church</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania's Anti-Discrimination Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jesus</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hobart Mall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lesbian Rights Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
