<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442902895697749</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-07/kennedy-frustrated-by-lack-of-forward-supply</url>
  <title>Kennedy frustrated by lack of forward supply</title>
  <content>
Josh Kennedy is frustrated by the Eagles' lack of forward supply

DUAL Coleman medallist Josh Kennedy is getting frustrated by the lack of supply into West Coast's forward line after helplessly watching another final-quarter fadeout against St Kilda.

The star Eagles spearhead bagged another five goals on Sunday and is back into the race to win the League's goalkicking for a third-straight season, now only two goals behind leader Joe Daniher who has booted 56.

Kennedy has slotted 20 goals in four games since his return from a calf strain and is doing everything in his power to keep the Eagles in the finals hunt, despite feeding off limited supply.

West Coast had just 46 inside 50s against the Saints and is ranked equal-13th for taking the ball into attack this season.

"As a forward you do get a bit frustrated at the lack of supply, but we have been able to make the most of our opportunities with what we've been getting," Kennedy said.

"We've been trying to work on ways to get a bit more supply because we've got guys up forward - Jack (Darling), Lecca (Mark LeCras), Crippa (Jamie Cripps) - who can kick some goals.

"It's obviously been disappointing that we can't (get enough supply) but you've just got to deal with what you get."

More to come.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coleman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Kennedy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagles</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lecca</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Daniher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crippa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saints</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark LeCras</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kennedy</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamie Cripps</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
