<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442335960007420</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/messenger/north-northeast/adelaide-soccer-team-northern-wolves-fined-500-over-allin-brawl-during-match/news-story/633fff16121f2e7a7b3b02ffde45a32b</url>
  <title>Giant soccer brawl - but only a $500 fine</title>
  <content>
TWO soccer clubs have escaped serious penalties following an investigation into an all-in brawl involving up to 45 players and supporters.
The June 24 match between Northern Wolves and One Tree Hill was abandoned in the 65th minute, after a fight started between the teams following an argument between players.
The SA Amateur Soccer League last month fined Northern Wolves $500 for its involvement in the incident and placed the club on a $500 good behaviour bond.
One Tree Hill was given a warning, but no fines.
The league has not suspended any players involved in the brawl.
Police and an ambulance were called to the match, at the corner of Uley Rd and Hanson Rd, Elizabeth.
A police spokesman said no one was charged because people were not willing to provide a statement.
Witnesses told the Northern Weekly a One Tree Hill player was allegedly "coward punched" from behind by a Northern Wolves player and was kicked while on the ground.
After the hit, One Tree Hill players rushed to the side of the fallen player and began fighting with their opponents.
More than 20 supporters had taken to the field as well, according to one witness.
A One Tree Hill club spokesman, who did not want to be named, said he was shocked by his opponents' behaviour.
"I was just running in there to break it up, but I personally copped a couple of hits," he said.
"I turned around to see around 20 of their supporters running onto the pitch who started throwing kicks, punches, the lot. This is the first time anything on this scale has ever happened.
"The disappointing thing for me is such little action has been taken - it is a slap on the wrist."
Northern Wolves president Agostino Bivone said the club had dealt with the incident.
"The matter has been before the South Australian Amateur Soccer League and has been resolved for over six weeks," Mr Bivone said.
"As a club, we do not condone such behaviour and have enforced the club's processes and procedures that are in place to assist in educating our members so these events don't happen again."
Amateur Soccer League secretary Alex Cichanowski said there was no place for violence in the sport.
Last month, Elizabeth South club Eleven Adult FC was banned indefinitely by the league after players threatened and chased a referee off the field during a match against Polonia Soccer Club.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Wolves</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uley Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Soccer League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Wolves $500</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eleven Adult FC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA Amateur Soccer League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elizabeth South</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Agostino Bivone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tree Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Cichanowski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hanson Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Weekly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Polonia Soccer Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elizabeth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian Amateur Soccer League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 24</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Bivone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>One Tree Hill</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
