<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443280852826085</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4838210/comedians-on-show-at-wollongongs-anywhere-theatre-festival/?cs=300</url>
  <title>Comedians on show at Wollongong's Anywhere Theatre Festival</title>
  <content>
FUNNY PAIR: Kiki and Pascal will entertain with Kiama Kabaret - a show of comedy, burlesque and circus at the Arts Precinct from August 24 to 26. Picture: Supplied

SIBLING RIVALRY: Lachlan Brooks and sister Hayley will be looking for laughs as part of He Said She Said, August 18 and 19 at The Stane Manor, 10 Porter Street in North Wollongong. Picture: Supplied
Some of the Illawarra's finest comedians will come out to play for the inaugural Anywhere Theatre Festival kicking off next week.
The festival celebrate comedy, theatre, street performance and cabaret with dozens of shows at a raft of venues across Wollongong from August 17 to 27.
Of the shows to hit a funnybone is He Said She Said, pulling together comedy couples from around the Illawarra.

These include romantic couples, business partners, a dad and daughter, siblings and each will give their version of events of the one story.
As the saying goes, there's two sides to every story.
Thirroul siblings - and housemates - Hayley Brooks, 28, and brother Lachlan, 24, will be taking part and discussing what life was like growing up in an overtly religious household.

Lachlan - a chef by day and serious comedian by night - said the pair's Pentecostal upbringing was "full on" but proved entertaining to others.
"People don't really believe us when we tell them," added Hayley.
- Hayley Brooks
"We'll be doing a bit about how our mum was growing up and some of the stuff that went on and the way that church influenced some of her ridiculous behaviour."
Both were excited to be included in Wollongong's newest festival which uses various venues around town, including a North Wollongong backyard for this particular event on August 18 and 19.
"I think it's really good especially an area like Illawarra where there's a lot of people moving down and it's good to encourage the arts and creative culture," Hayley said.

"It'd be interesting to see how it goes, this will be the first year so you ... will see what works and what doesn't."
Other comic relief on show will be a RAW Comedy 2016 finalist, Joseph Green, with his stand-up show Death of a Ladies' Man, Kiama Kabaret, plus some of the funniest females in town for WomanGong Comedy.

Organiser of the latter Shane Moon said the show follows a sold-out debut to celebrate International Women's Day which proved there is an abundance of female talent in the Illawarra.
"I think in general women work better in a bit as a community, a bit of a village, so if we're all encouraging each other to get up there more people will do it," Ms Moon said.
She said the comedy scene in general is "growing" across the Illawarra with more open mic nights for comics popping up as well more venues hosting regular comedy nights.

For ticket information visit:  
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>RAW Comedy 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Moon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lachlan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Wollongong</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lachlan Brooks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hayley Brooks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pentecostal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>International Women's Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane Moon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arts Precinct</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stane Manor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thirroul</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anywhere Theatre Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WomanGong Comedy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joseph Green</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pascal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hayley</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ladies' Man</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lachlan, 24</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Porter Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUGUST 18</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 24</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Said She Said</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kiama Kabaret</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hayley Brooks, 28</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong's Anywhere Theatre Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kiki</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
