<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442937255436664</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/north-west/sunbury-pokie-machines-grab-185-million-in-financial-year/news-story/58ec150878687262ab23b594b4a13fca</url>
  <title>Sunbury punters spend up big on pokies</title>
  <content>
THE amount of money poured into pokie machines in Sunbury in the past financial year could have paid for the soon-to-be-built global learning centre.
Punters plunged $18,582,731 - or $50,911 a day on average - into Sunbury pokies in the 2016-17 financial year, according to new Victorian Commission for Gambling Regulation statistics.
Sunbury has 230 electronic gaming machines at five venues, with the two operations not attached to clubs taking almost a third of the expenditure.
Thirty-one machines at the Royal Hotel yielded $5,667,863, while the Olive Tree Hotel, where there are 43 pokies, collected $5,372,084.
The other venues' figures were the Sunbury Bowling Club, $3,898,810; Sunbury Football Social Club, $1,884,696; and the Sunbury United Sporting Club, $1,759,276.
Sunbury Community Health's building healthier communities manager Bernadette Hetherington said the figures were alarming.
"As an organisation, we are formulating a response which will focus on community awareness," she said.
"We need people to be aware of the size of the losses, what opportunities from an economic or social point of view we might be missing and trying to advocate for more equity in ensuring venues invest meaningfully in their communities."
Ms Hetherington said it was difficult as a community health provider to actively respond to the gambling addiction.
"It's a hidden shame - people are just not going to come forward and tell you straight out how much they have lost," she said.
"The type of people attending pokie venues may not be the most adapt in socialising.
"You can lose hours and lose money and socially isolate yourself, despite being around others."
Ms Hetherington said it was not about pulling pokies out, but putting a limit on them and encouraging sporting clubs to hunt for other ways to revenue raise.
Jacksons Creek Ward councillor Jack Medcraft said Sunbury had enough pokies.
"They do provide a social outlet for people, but they are also taking pensions in some instances," he said.
"I'd like to see more accountability from venues, proving what they have done to improve the community with reinvesting."
Across Hume, punters spent $105.7 million on the machines during the past financial year. The city was the seventh highest area for gambling losses in Victoria, with two venues in the top 20.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bernadette Hetherington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Hotels</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunbury Community Health</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunbury</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thirty-one</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gambling Regulation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunbury United Sporting Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunbury Bowling Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Medcraft</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hume</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olive Tree Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacksons Creek Ward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Hetherington</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunbury Football Social Club, $1,884,696</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
