<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442602247983301</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/coast-to-receive-71m-affordable-housing-injection/3209612/</url>
  <title>Coast to receive $71m affordable housing injection</title>
  <content>
MORE than 200 of the Sunshine Coast's most vulnerable could be better off amid plans to build more affordable rentals in the region.
The State Government will invest $71 million for 243 new homes on the Coast which can also cater for seniors and pensioners thanks to the proposed construction's high accessibility standards.
This development is part of a $1.8 billion Housing Strategy announced in June aimed at creating building and construction jobs while providing 5,000 secure homes across Queensland.
Premier Annastacia Palaszczuk said the strategy would see Queensland take the lead in delivering social and affordable housing in Australia.
"Secure housing enables young people to finish their education," she said.
"It provides the stability that keeps families together. And it gives people the secure base they need to get and keep a job."
One Sunshine Coast pensioner feeling the sting of the housing market is Val Wilson who has called the Military Jetty Caravan Park in Golden Beach home for the past six years.

Ms Wilson claimed she was unable to find a rental for less than $335 per week and was told by the Department of Housing a home more than $300 was out of her reach.
A departmental spokesperson said a local Housing Service Centre had been working with Ms Wilson to find "a suitable, affordable place to live in either the private rental market or in social housing" which should be finalised soon.
"The department understands that it can be difficult for seniors to find affordable rental properties, especially for those on fixed incomes," the spokesperson said.
The 10-year plan will see 4,522 social homes and 1,034 affordable homes built across the state equating to 450 full-time construction jobs a year.
Minister for Housing and Public Works Mick de Brenni said the Queensland Housing Strategy construction program would be complemented by comprehensive reforms to improve housing outcomes.
"Government will use underutilised government land and this new funding to leverage new private and community sector investment in affordable housing," Mr de Brenni said.
"And this strategy is a big win for local builders and tradies in the residential sector across the state.
"Because we have refused to privatise housing we are now able to target job opportunities to locally based builders."
The Department of Housing has been asked where the affordable homes on the Coast will be built, but are yet to respond.
Night of crashes rounds out weekend of heartbreak on Coast roads
The plane you need in an emergency
Close call for Coast motorists as debris goes flying on motorway
Education, student accommodation, bars and music all key to future
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
*WARNING this story contains spoilers*
TARA Reid reveals what's coming in the next installment of TV movie.
Farmer's brave decision has cost him the game.
"It didn't seem like they were having a crazy, big night."
The news came after the couple attended Splendour in the Grass
An intimate safari is on the couple's agenda
Garth Prowd's vision made huge impact on Sunshine Coast community
Home sells in just one day
Winners in Master Builders regional housing and construction awards
Ray and Gert will celebrate 70 years of marrive this week
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Golden Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Housing</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garth Prowd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brenni</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tara Reid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Housing Strategy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Military Jetty Caravan Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Wilson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Annastacia Palaszczuk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Housing Service Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Val Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Public Works Mick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Housing Strategy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
