<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442597953015983</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:50</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/medical-evacuation-jet-first-for-coast-airport/3209620/</url>
  <title>Medical evacuation jet first for Coast airport</title>
  <content>
THE Sunshine Coast's first medical evacuation jet to be based at the region's airport has arrived from Tokyo.
The Cessna Citation CJ2 will be used to conduct medical repatriation flights throughout Australia, PNG and the South Pacific regions.
The aircraft can fly direct from the Sunshine Coast to places like Papua New Guinea and Vanuatu and will have medical retrieval teams constantly on call.
The McDermott Aviation Group based at the airport is Australia's largest privately-owned aviation company and also Australia's largest employer of aviation apprentices and employees with around 150 staff.
The group's fixed-wing division, Machjet, would operate the newly-purchased jet.
The Cessna Citation Jet CJ2 is one of the most versatile light private jets available in Australia.
It seats six passengers in comfort, but can carry up to seven passengers with a single-pilot.
Not only does the CJ2 enable speed and comfort at an affordable price, but it also offers the convenience of operating into airstrips most other jets cannot.
It has the ability to land at places like Lord Howe Island and Lizard Island which both have less than 950m of available runway and can also land on narrow airfields.
The aircraft has a maximum range of 2900kms, can travel at 667kmh reaching a maximum altitude of 45,000 feet.
It is equipped with a toilet and galley.
Night of crashes rounds out weekend of heartbreak on Coast roads
Close call for Coast motorists as debris goes flying on motorway
Coast's vulnerable better off amid plans to build affordable rentals
Education, student accommodation, bars and music all key to future
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
*WARNING this story contains spoilers*
TARA Reid reveals what's coming in the next installment of TV movie.
Farmer's brave decision has cost him the game.
"It didn't seem like they were having a crazy, big night."
The news came after the couple attended Splendour in the Grass
An intimate safari is on the couple's agenda
Garth Prowd's vision made huge impact on Sunshine Coast community
Home sells in just one day
Winners in Master Builders regional housing and construction awards
Ray and Gert will celebrate 70 years of marrive this week
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garth Prowd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tokyo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Machjet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vanuatu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tara Reid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cessna Citation Jet CJ2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lizard Island</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cessna Citation CJ2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PNG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lord Howe Island</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDermott Aviation Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Papua New Guinea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Pacific</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CJ2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
