<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442851356089639</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:49</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/politics/opposition-leader-rebecca-white-rejigs-her-team-ahead-of-the-next-state-election/news-story/8771bcd2eff3ba3ac729846cfe020270</url>
  <title>Labor maintains focus on health</title>
  <content>
MENTAL health has been given special emphasis under a State Opposition reshuffle that splits the shadow health portfolio.
Labor's most recently elected member - Rumney MLC Sarah Lovell - has been given the newly created mental health portfolio along with workplace relations and small business under a pre-election reshuffle announced today by leader Rebecca White.
Ms Lovell said she was thrilled to hold the new portfolio.
"We are seeing more and more, particularly over the last week or so, that the crisis in our health system has spread to mental health. We have had mental health patients waiting in the emergency department for 80 hours to access treatment," she said.

Ms White said she was dedicated to the shadow health role which she has held since the 2014 election.
"People want leadership in health, it's the number one issue they are talking to us about, and we are here to demonstrate that," she said.
Braddon MP Shane Broad, who was elected on a recount in April, will retain primary industries and water and take on infrastructure and mining.
Retiring MPs David Llewellyn (police and forestry) and Lara Giddings (Attorney-General, justice and corrections) have kept their portfolios.
Leader of Government Business in the House of Assembly Michael Ferguson said Labor's third shadow ministry in six months showed the party was "riven with disunity".
"Tellingly, Madeleine Ogilvie has been punished in response to speaking out against the union bosses by having responsibility for small business taken off her, and given to the unionist Sarah Lovell," Mr Ferguson said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Attorney-General</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs David Llewellyn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Braddon MP Shane Broad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Opposition</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Government Business</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Ferguson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rebecca White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah Lovell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Lovell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>House of Assembly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Madeleine Ogilvie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Ferguson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lara Giddings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rumney MLC Sarah Lovell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
