<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442211405954252</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Coffs Coast Advocate</source>
  <url>http://www.coffscoastadvocate.com.au/news/recap-game-thrones-s7-e4-spoils-war/3209513/</url>
  <title>RECAP: Game of Thrones s7 e4 - The Spoils of War</title>
  <content>
AFTER weeks of talking and strategising, Daenerys Targaryen finally put her dragons to good use.

In today's new episode of Game of Thrones, titled The Spoils of War, the Mother of Dragons went to plan B after learning of the Lannisters' victories at Highgarden and against her navy (helmed by the Yara and Theon Greyjoy).

Despite advice against using her dragons from her hand Tyrion and Jon Snow, Daenerys took one of her dragons and the Dothraki forces to ambush Jaime Lannister and his forces on their way back to King's Landing.

It made for the most epic battle scene of the season so far. With his soldiers being burnt alive, Jaime sent Bronn (back for the first time this season) to use the new weapon on the dragon. While it did pierce the dragon's flesh, it wasn't enough to bring the beast or Daenerys down.

Jaime's future is now uncertain, as he was last seen sinking to the bottom of a waterway at the end of the epic battle.

There was also another Stark family reunion in today's episode, with Arya returning home to Winterfell.

She was reunited with her siblings Sansa and Bran, as well as her would-be rescuer Brienne of Tarth - showing the lady knight what she'd in the years since they'd last seen each other.

Daniel Portman and Gwendoline Christie in a scene from season 7 episode 4 of Game of Thrones. Foxtel

Here are the key scenes from today's episode:

Winterfell
Sophie Turner in a scene from season 7 episode 4 of Game of Thrones.Helen Sloane

The youngest Stark woman returned home but found herself stopped by two gruff guards who wanted nothing to do with her.

There were a few moments where you felt she would just up and leave, but she convinced the pair to let her in. Either that, or suffer the consequences when she told Sansa access was denied.

While the guards bickered, she glanced at a wolf sigil on their banner, and disappeared.

The guards went to Sansa sharing details of Arya's comments and disappearance, but Lady Stark knew where to find the assassin.

The reunion occurred in the Stark crypts, where the stark contrast between the two was made more evident.

While they both had long, unpleasant journeys back to Winterfell, Sansa's path was notably different to that of Arya's.

But it was Sansa's reaction to Arya's list that was key, at least: She laughed at the mention of Arya's list of people to kill.

When you thought there couldn't be another reunion, Sansa revealed Bran had also returned.

Arya and Bran embraced for the first time since season one as he sat in a new wheelchair beside Winterfell's weirwood tree.

Bran knew of her list, which further unsettled Sansa, who thought it was a joke, but then handed her the weapon intended for his death in the first season.

Petr Baelish gave Bran the weapon at the start of the episode, claiming not to know to whom it belonged.

Dragonstone: I will fight for the North
Conleth Hill, Peter Dinklage, Nathalie Emmanuel, Emilia Clarke, Liam Cunningham and Kit Harington in a scene from season 7 episode 4 of Game of Thrones.Foxtel

Jon Snow continued his mission of trying to win Daenerys Targaryen's support.

While she granted the King in the North's request to mine Dragonstone for obsidian, which can produce valerian weapons - one of the only weapons that can defeat white walkers - she hasn't yet said she would join his fight.

It is during Jon's search for obsidian that he makes a discovery that could win Daenerys' support.

Among the walls under Dragonstone's surface, were old drawings carved into the rock, which charted some of the world's history.

While some may have been indecipherable to viewers, nothing could mistake the appearance of the white walkers.

It was there Jon could better sell his case. With evidence in those stories, he convinced Daenerys it was a valid and real threat.

She said the words he wanted to hear, "I will fight for the North", but there is a catch: only if he bends the knee.

Before he could decide one way or the other, bad news arrived from the battlefields.

Casterly Rock was won, but the rest of her forces have been decimated.

A clearly irate Daenerys lambasted Tyrion's strategy - everything he planned to date had fallen apart, every battle he outlined just weeks ago was lost - and it was time for her to take on Olenna Tyrell's advice.

When Olenna was at Dragonstone, she told Daenerys to "be a dragon".

Daenerys had held off, thought the losses proved it was time for her to take actions into her own hands.

She did ask Jon for his advice first, which could be another step towards the two working closer together.

King's Landing
Nikolaj Coster-Waldau and Jerome Flynn in a scene from season 7 episode 4 of Game of Thrones. Foxtel

Bronn, Jaime Lannister, and House Tarly's forces had combined to destroy the remnants of House Tyrell at Highgarden at the end of the last episode.

Bronn started the episode requesting Highgarden - Jaime had offered him a castle after all, and Bronn wanted the former home of the Tyrells.

Jaime gave him his gold but promised his castle for when the war was won.

Nothing could quite prepare them for what came next.

Jaime sourced the gold for King's Landing in order to repay the Lannister's debt to the Iron Bank.

That was just the legwork for what was to come.

For the first time in this series, the Dothraki rode on Westeros, and Daenerys rode Drogon into battle from the sky.

Emilia Clarke in a scene from season 7 episode 4 of Game of Thrones.Foxtel

They terrorised the combined force - it was, after all, the first time a dragon had been seen in Westeros since the Mad King rode into King's Landing all those years ago.

Midway through the battle, Jaime sent Bronn to Qyburn's new dragon-piercing weapon (a giant ballista), which he demonstrated in the King's Landing crypt.

The weapon worked.

While Drogon tore through the forces, the ballista found its mark about the dragon's right shoulder.

Grounded, Daenerys tried to pull it out, which is when Jaime made his move.

Tyrion watched his brother charge at the Mother of Dragons from the top of a nearby hill, but as it seemed he would take out the Targaryen Drogon reared his head.

A storm of fire spewed from the dragon's mouth, but a late, diving ally, who we assume to be Bronn, saved Jaime from the fire at the last moment.

Our last frame left Jaime's fate uncertain: did the Lannister drown as he sunk to the bottom of the waterway?

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liam Cunningham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jaime Lannister</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Portman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>House Tyrell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mad King</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qyburn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jerome Flynn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Casterly Rock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kit Harington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Dinklage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bran</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olenna Tyrell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jon</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theon Greyjoy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Highgarden</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Conleth Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Winterfell</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Petr Baelish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>House Tarly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tyrells</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spoils of War</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Game of Thrones</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daenerys</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Helen Sloane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Game of Thrones</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arya</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jaime</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iron Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxtel</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dragonstone</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emilia Clarke</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dothraki</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lannister</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nikolaj Coster-Waldau</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daenerys Targaryen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mother of Dragons</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jon Snow</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tyrion</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sansa</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brienne of Tarth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Drogon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gwendoline Christie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olenna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westeros</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lady Stark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bronn</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Targaryen Drogon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King's Landing</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sophie Turner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathalie Emmanuel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
