<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442679557395616</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/questnews/north/oneofakind-pandoras-box-trapped-in-a-style-time-warp/news-story/eafe1d46dbf300f5c89a879e0d13a477</url>
  <title>Brisbane home trapped in time warp</title>
  <content>
ON first inspection this Brisbane home is the picture of pleasant suburban living.
Behind the carved white front door, however, is a world time has forgotten.
An Aladdin's Cave of vintage treasure decorates almost every table, wall and corner in the 1970s home. And every last thing is for sale.
In keeping with its history of going against the grain, the home at 22 Dargie St, Everton Park is up for sale with its contents included.
The flamboyant art pieces, the ornate furniture, and even the living room water feature will go as part of a rare real estate package deal.
Madeline Hicks Real Estate agent Mary Di Marco said the sale of the two-storey, three-bedroom home was as uncommon as its history.
Ms Di Marco said the home, a "Pandora's box" perched on an 812sq m block, was built in 1970.
It forms part of the elegant Trouts Estate - a pocket of homes so focused on presentation that powerlines were run underground and residents could not build front fences.
"This was the cream of the estate, Dargie St," she said.
She said the brick home was born from the design skill of the present owner, who had designed the home and much of its decor for her parents.
For more than four decades the home has remained a 1970s time capsule.
"It's a family home that's still in its original state.
"Everything about it would have been state-of-the-art when it was built," Ms Di Marco said.
"Every time I come here, I just see something else that takes my breath away.
"It speaks of a bygone era."
The home is listed without a price.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Everton Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mary Di Marco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pandora</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trouts Estate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dargie St</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Di Marco</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Madeline Hicks Real Estate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aladdin's Cave</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
