<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443452651520704</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/sport/the-advertiser-footy-podcast-dissects-showdown-43-and-what-the-flogging-might-mean-for-port-adelaide-and-its-season/news-story/c9b67c90b66f38d73e9d7bb9cc36746f</url>
  <title>The fallout from Port's flogging</title>
  <content>
THE fallout from Showdown 43 is the focus of this week's The Advertiser Footy Podcast, with both our experts Michelangelo Rucci and Chris McDermott holding nothing back when it comes to Port Adelaide's effort.
Rucci says there is no need to look at the stats - the scale of the flogging is evident in the scoreline.
"Forty scores, not scoring shots because there were some on the fulls. Port only 11. They were destroyed," he says.
McDermott says the Crows beat Port were beaten all over the park.
"Destroyed from the centre bounce, to defence to forward line and everywhere in between. It was a ferocious display from Adelaide. Their key forwards stood up, their midfield did what we thought they could do, and their defence was outstanding. Port was always going to have trouble scoring but I didn't know they weren't going to get the ball. Their midfield did not come to play."
The experts also say the game has helped the All-Australian selectors, with the rucking contest that delivered Sam Jacobs a third Showdown Medal a good pointer to who wins the honour.
"There is no decision now - it is Sam Jacobs All-Australian ruckman if they are the two contenders," Rucci says.
"I thought Ryder was in front," McDermott offers. "He's not in front after that weekend. I've never seen Jacobs hit the scoreboard like that, cover the ground and his dominance at stoppages was enormous. That was a thrashing."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>CROWS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rucci</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Showdown Medal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacobs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MICHELANGELO RUCCI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDermott</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris McDermott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Advertiser Footy Podcast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Jacobs All-Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>All-Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Jacobs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Showdown 43</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
