<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442340254974931</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:50</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/south-australia/former-prime-minister-tony-abbott-attacks-defence-industry-minister-christopher-pyne-ahead-of-liberal-meeting-on-marriage-equality/news-story/f7f281f66c8eef8ab8c8781ee6ef8f0b</url>
  <title>Abbott attacks Pyne over same-sex marriage</title>
  <content>
FORMER prime minister Tony Abbott has criticised Defence Industry Minister Christopher Pyne's behind-the-scenes advocacy for same-sex marriage and says the Government should keep lobbying the Senate for a plebiscite.
A group of Liberal backbenchers will push for a conscience vote on same-sex marriage at a  on Monday but a majority of their colleagues want the party to maintain its policy of holding a national plebiscite on the issue.
In July, Mr Pyne  for suggesting at a private Liberal Party function that same-sex marriage could be legalised in Australia before the next election.
In an interview on Sydney radio 2GB, Mr Abbott took a swipe at Mr Pyne over his comments and support for marriage equality.
"Plainly there has been talk behind the scenes by the same-sex marriage lobby for a long time,'' Mr Abbott said.
"Pretty obviously, Christopher Pyne was a key part of that. It was a shocking thing for Christopher Pyne to say - even at a private gathering.
"And look I guess this is why people have been so unhappy with all of this - because it looks to be a device to get around our clear commitment.''
Mr Pyne is not a member of the group of five MPs who have been pushing for a same-sex marriage bill to be introduced into Parliament as soon as this week.
Mr Abbott said the Government should keep trying to persuade the Senate to allow a plebiscite to go ahead on same-sex marriage.
"The Howard Government tried 40 times to change unfair dismissal laws in the Senate. We've put the plebiscite up once - that's all," he aid.
"We should have another go and if that fails, let's have another go.''
Marriage equality advocates have confirmed that they will launch a High Court challenge if the Government tries to hold a national plebiscite on same-sex marriage without the approval of Parliament.

Co-Chair for Australian Marriage Equality Alex Greenwich says a postal vote plebiscite for same-sex marriage is a 'bloody stupid idea', and if announced today the challenge to it will begin.

Postal vote plebiscite is a 'bloody stupid idea'
Liberal Senator Dean Smith has drafted his own marriage equality bill and together with Liberal MPs Trent Zimmerman, Tim Wilson, Trevor Evans and Warren Entsch, will push for a parliamentary vote on the bill after circulating it to members over the weekend.
There's also speculation a postal plebiscite proposal will be put to cabinet on Monday and taken to the party room for approval.
Mr Zimmerman says that is possible, but he's hopeful the rogue MPs can persuade their colleagues.
"I'm always an optimist," he told ABC radio.
Senator Smith says a postal plebiscite is "useless", insisting Mr Turnbull is wrong to continue to support a plebiscite.
"The plebiscite is a D-grade response to a defining A-grade social issue," he told the Nine Network.
Mr Wilson says his electorate of Goldstein has been revealed in numerous polls as having the highest support for marriage equality.
But he pledged to represent the views of those in favour and the 20 per cent who oppose same-sex marriage.
"People who feel strongly against a change in the law, they want their say through a vote and I will communicate that position to the party room because that's what a good representative should do," he told ABC TV.
Senator Smith's bill, expected to be supported by Labor, allows for two people to marry regardless of their gender, while enshrining protections and exemptions for religious communities.
That includes religious ministers, civil celebrants, and businesses linked to a religious body who refuse to cater for same-sex couples.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GB</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Defence Industry Minister Christopher Pyne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>D-grade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Howard Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Network</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Smith</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pyne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Abbott</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christopher Pyne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MPs Trent Zimmerman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goldstein</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Zimmerman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>High Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Senator Dean Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Marriage Equality Alex Greenwich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Co-chair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Pyne</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC TV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
