<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443491306227041</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:18</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/inner-south/tree-vandal-sam-cohen-who-left-trail-of-destruction-over-several-months-walks-free-from-court/news-story/c7154284467ff6920e315e21c5b2b4b8</url>
  <title>Serial tree vandal walks from court</title>
  <content>
A  MACHETE-wielding tree hacker who left a trail of destruction in several suburbs and a damage bill in the tens of thousands has walked free from court.

Sam Cohen fronted Moorabbin Magistrates' Court for a sentencing hearing on August 3 after he hacked at 20 trees along Heatherton's Henry Street Trail Reserve and four in Clayton South, Cheltenham and Mordialloc.
Cohen, 21, from Heatherton, pleaded guilty to those charges, as well as to vandalising red gums and wattles in Braeside Park.
But sentencing was deferred to allow him to comply with an unrelated corrections order previously issued over an attempted- armed robbery.
Magistrate Timothy Gattuso deferred the matter until October 5, but warned Cohen he could "find yourself in custody if you don't comply with the current community corrections order," he said.
"When it comes back before- me, I'll hopefully have a progress report ... if you're doing well I will give you the opportunity of a further corrections order."
The court heard how Cohen was seen wielding a machete and an axe, which he used to threaten a witness on October 20.
His tree-hacking rampage - between August and November last year - came to an end- after his arrest on December 1, when he came home in a stolen car an hour after police found a stolen numberplate under his bed.
Magistrate Gattuso described his conduct as concerning behaviour that "clearly needs punishment".
But defence lawyer Bernie Balmer said punishment should be deferred while Cohen proved he could comply with the previous order.
Mr Balmer said Cohen had been exposed to family violence as a child and to drug abuse from a young age.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heatherton's Henry Street Trail Reserve</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bernie Balmer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clayton South</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cohen, 21</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moorabbin Magistrates' Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magistrate Gattuso</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cohen</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magistrate Timothy Gattuso</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cheltenham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Braeside Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heatherton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mordialloc</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Balmer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MACHETE-wielding</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Cohen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
