<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442636607721965</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/technology/commonwealth-banks-money-laundering-woes-are-a-slip-in-a-bank-tech-race-it-is-used-to-winning-20170804-gxpfvd</url>
  <title>CBA's money laundering woes are an embarrassing slip in a bank tech race it is used to winning</title>
  <content>
For years the Commonwealth Bank of Australia has basked in the glory of a reputation of being Australia's foremost banking tech innovator ... the ongoing money laundering crisis engulfing it is an example of what can happen if you fall off the bleeding edge.
The bank is reeling after being pulled up by financial intelligence agency AUSTRAC for failing or delaying reports on suspicious cash deposits in its market leading "intelligent deposit machines" on more than 50,000 occasions.
There is no conclusion to draw other than that the bank decided to run before it could walk with the ATMs, in order to cash in on its massive investment to get a tech lead.
The new ATMs made their debut in October 2012 as part of a nationwide refresh of its fleet, with 40 new deposit ATMs enabling the deposit of cash to be registered in accounts in real time.

James Elsby

According to bank insiders, at the time none of its Big Four rivals were in a position to offer the same functions in their own ATMs, as their systems couldn't cope with the demands of real-time banking.

The smart ATMs represented a public crystallisation of the largely intangible benefits of its billion-dollar, multi-year core banking systems overhaul, which had just come to an end.
Talking up systems

At an investor briefing in May of that year,  - including its high-profile and widely lauded chief information officer Michael Harte - who talked up its systems as "world class", and positioned CBA as "streets ahead" of its rivals.
"If you don't open channels, if you don't have rich relationship data and real-time services you cannot lead the market and you cannot change the game," Harte enthused.

Tamara Voninski

"With real-time banking at the core, we have enabled instant transfer of value between parties. We aren't holding money for days; we know our customers don't want this. We know banks and others are disliked for this."
In its 2012 media release announcing the ATMs, CBA's executive general manager retail products and customers Michael Cant (who is still with the bank as its EGM of corporate financial services) crowed that the machines sat alongside its mobile banking apps and online options in meaning it offered its customers high levels of convenience.
"Our investment in core banking is designed to give Australians more control over their money, and the ATM refresh is the latest testament to this," Cant said.
The bank execs were not wrong in their sense for what their customers wanted, and over the next three years CBA pressed home its flying start by installing 507 of its intelligent deposit machines, reaping the benefits of large deposits and fees from small business customers eager to get their cash on the books post haste.

Ben Rushton

Moving too fast

Yet it seems it failed to correctly answer the conundrum of whether it should do something just because it could. The fact that money launderers were seemingly able to take advantage of gaps in its systems to the tune of $77 million indicate it simply moved too fast for its processes to keep up.
It is a dilemma that technology companies face all the time; should they release the next iteration of a product ahead of rivals and cross their fingers that the bugs don't bite? Or should they tick all the boxes and risk looking like a laggard when someone else jumps first?
Perhaps unsurprisingly given its earlier hubris, CBA has . They will be privately enjoying the fall from grace and the frantic hunt for answers from a peer that has lorded it over them.

CBA has already  in part for its failure to recognise and report dodgy transactions. But while you might look to cut a disruptive start-up some slack in this regard, it is the kind of excuse that will have CBA's highly resourced and highly respected techies shrinking back into their beanbags.
The bank's current tech chief David Whiteing should be safe from any hunt for a corporate head to put on a spike, with .
Whiteing only ascended to the role in 2014 when Harte left for Barclays in Britain, and at worst could stand accused of failing to fix things quick enough. But really the key failings here should not be blamed on "the tech guy".
Vibrant innovation

CBA led the bank tech race and its execs publicly enjoyed the plaudits, and no area of tech innovation is more vibrant at present than the thriving fintech scene. It would seem unwise for the bank to retreat from the battle right as it is heating up.
It has continued to seek the tech lead under Whiteing in areas such as blockchain and quantum computing, and by and large it would be harsh to condemn an organisation for looking to push things forward from a tech innovation perspective.
But when you gamble, sometimes you lose ... and it remains to be seen what the long-term ramifications of this calamity are.
Fines and potential executive resignations are one thing, but we may see a more conservative tech approach emerge in future from CBA, and that would seem to be the most damaging result of all.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whiteing</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Rushton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big Four</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUSTRAC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ATMs</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Ca</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 2012</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tamara Voninski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barclays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harte</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Bank of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Harte</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EGM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Whiteing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ATM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Elsby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBA</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
