<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443452651520716</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/nsw/government-promises-hornsby-council-fix-after-toxic-mayor-dumped-20170806-gxqm8q.html</url>
  <title>Government promises Hornsby council fix after 'toxic' mayor dumped</title>
  <content>
The NSW government has promised to deliver a fix for Hornsby council, which was left financially depleted and with reduced territory as a result of the government's backflip on its signature council merger policy.
The policy backflip scrapped any remaining hope the council had of securing the vaunted $70 million of benefits of merging with Ku-ring -gai after the NSW Court of Appeal ruled the merger invalid in March. Photo: James Alcock
The council is now lobbying the government for the return of the territory it surrendered to the new City of Parramatta Council on the promise of the financial benefits of merging with Ku-ring-gai.
Financially modelling, released by Hornsby Council in June,over the next decade because of the boundary changes. 
In a bid to rectify the situation, Hornsby MP Matt Kean said the government was now considering a "a range of options".
"Despite amalgamations being taken off the table, the NSW Government will ensure Hornsby residents will not be financially worse off," he said. 

It comes as Liberal mayor Steve Russell claims he was shafted by party factional bosses ahead of next month's council elections over his support for the now-abandoned policy.
The mayor said he was now considering resigning from the Liberal Party.
"I was fully intending to run again. I was told I was toxic, my brand was toxic out there because I supported council amalgamations and I was unelectable.
"Because it was inconvenient for me to be there, they've just recycled Philip Ruddock."
Mr Ruddock, a former long-serving federal MP for Berowra, .
In a formal proposal submitted to the state government last month, Hornsby council requested that the original pre-merger boundaries be restored, which would see the lucrative area south of the M2, including Epping and Carlingford, returned to Hornsby Council. 
Alternatively, it proposed the boundaries be redrawn so as to hand Hornsby Council all of the Epping town centre, allowing Parramatta to retain Carlingford. 
It is understood that financial compensation, rather than boundary restoration, is also among the range of options being considered by the state government.
Cr Russell said he was "strongly against" this approach, claiming the money would be used at the "discretion of future councillors to spend on pet projects".
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Russell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>M.2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Ruddock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hornsby Council</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hornsby MP Matt Kean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hornsby</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Alcock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berowra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Russell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parramatta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Epping</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlingford</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Court of Appeal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philip Ruddock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City of Parramatta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ku-ring</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
