<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442984500077761</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-07/teachers-struggling-with-students-sexual-behaviour-in-schools/8781018</url>
  <title>Teachers struggle to deal with primary schoolers exhibiting inappropriate sexual behaviour: study</title>
  <content>
There are calls for more training for teachers to help them deal with reports of children as young as five showing signs of highly inappropriate sexual behaviour at school.

Key points:

40pc of surveyed teachers said they had observed problematic sexual behaviour
Teachers could identify cases of 'age-appropriate' sexual curiosity
Teachers expressed a wish for more training in managing sexual behaviour

In a , teachers reported witnessing students threatening to rape other students, simulating intercourse and coercing others to engage in sexual behaviour.
The research has raised concerns about teachers' ability to differentiate between victims of abuse and children who mimic what they see in the media.
A sample of 107 primary school teachers who taught children aged 5-13 were surveyed, with 40 per cent saying they had observed problematic sexual behaviour.
Lead researcher Lesley-Anne Ey, a lecturer in child development and education at the University of South Australia, said those teachers expressed feeling that they needed more training in the area.
Dr Ey said the reported behaviour included severe cases, such as children threatening to rape other children and touching one and another
"Trying to coerce each other - a lot of these incidents happened in the toilets," she said.
The research found teachers could identify cases of "age-appropriate" sexual curiosity.
But Dr Ey said some teachers felt ill-equipped to deal with those more serious.
"Some of the teachers were responding that they weren't expecting the type of behaviour that they were seeing," she said.
"Their key concern was that they don't know how to actually manage that behaviour.
"They don't know what's causing that behaviour and they don't know how to support children engaged in this type of behaviour."
In all states and territories of Australia it is compulsory for educators to notify child protection authorities if they suspect abuse is occurring.
But Dr Ey said training for teachers varied in scope, quality and consistency and that needed to change overall.
"We do have a national curriculum, so I personally think that we also should have national training and national documentation so that we have consistency across states and territories," she said.
"And all teachers are educated the same and respond the same across the nation."
The difference between sexual abuse and imitation

The difficulty lies in determining if children are imitating what they see on the internet, or if students are victims of sexual abuse.
"Teachers need to find out, are these children victims of sexual abuse, or are they imitating this behaviour?" Dr Ey said.
"Regardless of which way that goes, it's still concerning and it's still problematic, and these children still need support."
Pam Kent, South Australian president of the Primary Principals Association, said the high incidence of problematic sexual behaviour in schools was not surprising.
"Sadly much more often than many probably realise, it's not specific to socio-economic background, it's disturbingly much more frequent than we realise," she said.
Ms Kent said the rise of social media and exposure of adult behaviour through TV and the internet could make it hard for teachers to discern between sexual abuse and behaviour imitation.
But she said she believed teachers in primary schools knew their students "fairly well" and were well trained to identify serious problems and report them.
"And they know generally when it's an inappropriate social behaviour or verbal harassment in a sexual form and they can pick up on that," she said.
"But the problem is ... that the teacher feels they have to do [something] when several years ago this was something that would have been dealt with in the home."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of South</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Kent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Primary Principals Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pam Kent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lesley-anne Ey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Ey</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
