<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442426154322152</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Coffs Coast Advocate</source>
  <url>http://www.coffscoastadvocate.com.au/news/nuturing-our-local-small-businesses/3209584/</url>
  <title>Nuturing our local small businesses</title>
  <content>
SMALL businesses have often been described as 'the backbone of our economy" as they employ close to 5 million Australians.
They are also the cornerstone of our local communities as it is likely that each and every one of us deals with at least one small business on a daily basis.
They are your local cafe, your local convenience store, dentist, chemist, fruiterer and butcher.
There are some interesting facts about our small businesses that may surprise you - the information was passed to me from the Office of NSW Small Business Commissioner:

60% of small businesses have no staff (i.e. they run the business themselves with no employees or employ only contract staff)
20% of small businesses have less than 5 staff
3% of small businesses have 5-20 staff
The role of small businesses in the wider economy is often underestimated and undervalued. While a small start-up might not generate as many jobs as larger more established businesses, they are nevertheless a driving force behind our economy.
The ETC Business Services Team delivers the Australian Small Business Advisory Service, which provides small business operators and those who intend to start a business with access to a range of services, including:

Ongoing guidance and mentoring
General business advice and support
Business and marketing plans, including digital marketing
Budgeting
Training and Workshops
The team covers the Local Government Areas of Coffs Harbour, Bellingen, Nambucca, Kempsey and Port Macquarie.
Your initial assessment is likely to be complimentary but there may be a small charge for ongoing services. Phone the ETC Business Services Team today on 1800 007 400.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAMBUCCA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ETC Business Services Team</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bellingen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Macquarie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kempsey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Small Business Commissioner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Office of NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Local Government Areas of Coffs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harbor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Small Business Advisory Service</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nuturing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
