<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442722507069200</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/sport/afl/afl-wrap-ports-pathetic-failure-piesroos-horror-show-issue-afl-cant-ignore/news-story/bc039d9c4c799292b4ee408da7e5bbc7</url>
  <title>'Pathetic' stain exposes failed con job</title>
  <content>
THE jig is up, Port Adelaide.
The worst con job in footy is now more evident than ever as even the most optimistic Power fans would have to concede their team is virtually no chance of doing any damage in September.
Barring a complete meltdown Port will play finals, but surviving more than a week or two is a long shot.
The theory isn't a new one, but it's gained even more legs after the Power's capitulation to the Crows in Sunday's Showdown. Before the match Port coach Ken Hinkley said he didn't care his side had lost the past four Adelaide derbies, but he'll definitely care about how it lost the fifth.
Port was never in the contest as Adelaide romped to an 18.22 (130) to 7.4 (46) win in the city of churches. It was carnage from start to finish.
Only one of Port's 11 wins in 2017 has come against a side currently sitting in the top eight. West Coast has been accused all year of being a flat track bully for its inability to win in Melbourne, but the Power is now challenging the Eagles to become the AFL's favourite punching bag.
Melbourne legend Garry Lyon and Power great Kane Cornes both put the gloves on after Sunday's shocker.
"It says plenty about them (the Crows) and it says plenty about Port Adelaide too. A side that's had a real inability to deal with top eight sides and it extrapolates it against the very best in the competition. That was pathetic," Lyon told .
Cornes labelled the effort "embarrassing" and questioned his old club's understanding of the Showdown's significance.
"It was an embarrassing performance," Cornes told SEN Breakfast. "I really expected a response, they had lost their last four against Adelaide. The lack of physical pressure really disappointed me.
"You just question whether the modern Port Adelaide players understand what the Showdown is about. That was an 84-point margin, a record in the Showdown. Adelaide has won the last five, and a lot of them have been easy.
"I saw (ex-Port coach) Mark Williams at the game yesterday, and I looked over to him and thought, 'What is he thinking?' because no man has done more to build the rivalry. My brother (Port legend Chad Cornes) was down there running for Port, he would have been embarrassed.
"Does the modern Port player realise what the Showdown is all about?"
Port is fifth on the ladder, level on points with Sydney and the Western Bulldogs. It miraculously escaped with a last-gasp win over St Kilda (11th) two weekends ago, but the latest lowlight ensures the cracks that were papered over with that victory are now back in plain sight.
Hinkley's men will be relieved to know they take on a side not in the top eight next week when they come up against Collingwood, but it looms as a danger game for the men in teal considering the Pies are fresh from a 54-point drubbing of North Melbourne.
'WORST I'VE SEEN IN 10 YEARS'
Speaking of Collingwood, even though the club recovered from a demoralising draw against Adelaide in Round 19 after leading by 50 points, it wasn't all rosy for coach Nathan Buckley and Co.
The Magpies eventually coasted to a 16.15 (111) to 7.15 (57) win over the Kangaroos but the first half was full of woefully inaccurate kicking as both sides combined to kick six goals and 20 behinds.
Former Western Bulldogs and Richmond coach Terry Wallace said the show in the opening stanza was as bad as he's seen at AFL level in a decade.
"It was really hard to sit through," Wallace said on SEN's Hungry For Sport.
"It was the worst game I've called this year, no doubt whatsoever. The first half, I said five years, it could be the worst I've seen in 10. It was turnover city.
"Only six goals were scored, North scored just one. From one half forward area to the other, it was turnover city. No one could hold two possessions in a row. It was terrible. It was awful."
ISSUE THE AFL CAN'T IGNORE
The policing of dangerous tackles will again be in the spotlight when the AFL match review panel meets.
A week after Geelong superstar Patrick Dangerfield copped a one-game ban for his challenge on Matthew Kreuzer, a similar fate awaits Collingwood's Brodie Grundy. The Magpies ruckman is certain to face MRP scrutiny on Monday for a tackle on Ben Brown during Saturday night's game at Etihad Stadium which left the Kangaroos spearhead concussed.
Brown was sent to hospital for observation after his head hit the turf in a tackle similar to Dangerfield's challenge on Carlton big man Kreuzer. The 24-year-old Brown took to social media on Sunday saying he was feeling good and resting at home, but it's unclear whether he'll be available for next week's game against Hawthorn.
Grundy was paid a free kick for holding the ball in what coach Nathan Buckley described as a "perfect tackle".
But like Dangerfield, Grundy is expected to pay the price for pinning his opponent's arms and denying him the opportunity to protect his head. An emotional Grundy said he had no intention to hurt Brown, but AFL legend Leigh Matthews had no doubt it would lead to a suspension.
"The fact is if Dangerfield gets a week, Grundy has to get a week," he said on the Seven Network's AFL Game Day. "It's the same - pinned the arms, head hits the ground - and I agree with that, to be honest.
"The big picture is trying to make the game safer, and I'm for that."
- AAP
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MRP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Buckley</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CROWS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ken Hinkley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda (11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kreuzer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leigh Matthews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday's Showdown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grundy</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lyon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magpies</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Bulldogs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seven Network's AFL Game Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garry Lyon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terry Wallace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chad Cornes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Dangerfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wallace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Kreuzer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL CAN'T IGNORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SEEN IN 10 YEARS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hinkley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood's Brodie Grundy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SEN's Hungry For Sport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dangerfield</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Does</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cornes</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Round 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port's 11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brown</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kane Cornes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SEN Breakfast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
