<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442683852362981</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/cuphead-xbox-one-photos-video-2017-8</url>
  <title>The next major Xbox One game looks like nothing else on modern game consoles</title>
  <content>
Few video games are as gorgeous as "Cuphead," an upcoming Xbox One and PC game.

Just look at this:

That winking, sinister-looking cigar you see above is one of the game's many bosses. And that frustrated-looking guy with a cup for a head? That's actually not the eponymous "Cuphead," but instead is his trusty partner "Mugman." 

The game is so gorgeous because it's hand-drawn - something few games pull off, and no games pull off as well as "Cuphead." But what's the game about? What do you do in "Cuphead"? Let's dive in.

Studio MDHR

Studio MDHR

There's a lot going on here, I realise, so allow me to break it down:

-Both Cuphead and Mugman are playing through this level, moving from left to right -- you can see Cuphead walking along the ceiling, while Mugman is hopping around on the ground.
-Usually, both Cuphead and Mugman (or just one of them) is walking along the ground.
-Cars are moving along from right to left, both on the bottom of the screen and along the ceiling.
-A crazy duck with wheels appears to be a type of boss or enemy character.
-There's a twinkling playing card in the middle of the screen -- maybe a power-up of some type? That's unclear.

Studio MDHR

Studio MDHR

Studio MDHR

Studio MDHR

While there are many boss fights in 'Cuphead,' the game has a 'Super Mario World'-esque overworld map that allows you to choose where you want to go. Some levels are focused on a boss fight, while others require more standard platforming.

Also of note: Mugman is air-dashing in the image above, which looks like another move you're able to execute.

Studio MDHR

Studio MDHR

Studio MDHR

Studio MDHR

Studio MDHR

NOW WATCH: Tech Insider videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mugman</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MDHR</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Super Mario World</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tech Insider</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cuphead</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Xbox One</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
