<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651442593658048633</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/sport/afl/teams/gws/nick-maxwell-slams-matthew-lloyd-for-saying-josh-kelly-has-withdrawn-from-the-gws-giants/news-story/03058073b8de64cf291b6fe8c83aa7d0</url>
  <title>'Absolute rubbish': Maxwell slams Kelly claims</title>
  <content>
GWS GIANTS development coach Nick Maxwell has slammed Essendon great Matthew Lloyd over his comments that Josh Kelly is "withdrawing himself" from the Giants.
Lloyd had said that he believed people at the Giants felt that Kelly was "out the door" and that it was showing in his interactions at the club.
"I think that people at the Giants believe that by the day and by the week, they're losing touch with Kelly and that he is in a sense, withdrawing himself from that football club and that he's still playing okay but they don't feel like he looks them in the eyes like he used to," Lloyd said on 3AW radio.
"So maybe they feel like he's out the door."
LISTEN TO THE ROUND 20 REVIEW FOX FOOTY PODCAST BELOW, OR
But Maxwell - who works at the Giants in a leadership/development role, along with being the club's matchday runner - said Lloyd's comments were "absolute rubbish", citing the level of investment he'd seen from the in-demand Kelly.
"I've got no idea if he's going or if he's staying, no idea at all - all I know is that is absolute rubbish," Maxwell said on Channel 7's Game Day.
"Because I am with him for five or six hours every weekend for the game, before the game, after the game, I'm with him on review days and he's in our leadership group and he could not be more invested."
Kelly has been heavily linked to a return home to Victoria, with North Melbourne, Carlton and St Kilda among his reported suitors.
The gun midfielder has enjoyed a stellar season at the Giants, averaging 29.1 disposals, 412 metres-gained, 7.3 score involvements, 4.9 clearances and 6.4 tackles per game.
Against Melbourne on Saturday, the 22-year-old recorded 27 disposals, booted three goals, had eight score involvements and 538 metres-gained.
Maxwell said Kelly's investment in the club couldn't be questioned.
"He's always texting, wanting to ask 'what can we be doing more? How can we help these young players? How can we bring someone along?'" Maxwell said.
"His investment in the group right now - as I said, I don't know what goes on beyond September - but all I know right now is his investment in the football club and how much he loves his teammates and wants to be around them, wants success - I could not ask any more of him, of someone who works in leadership.
"So I don't know where that information's come from but he is so invested in the football club and we've got no issue with him - there's no way that he's withdrawing in any possible way."
Maxwell said he believed Lloyd had received incorrect information.
"He's obviously speaking to someone or getting information from someone who doesn't know what they're talking about," he said.
"Because as I said, I'm with him (Kelly).
"So I don't know - maybe there's two or three days when I'm not with him every week where he might be (withdrawn) - but I couldn't see him changing his personality that much because as I said, when I'm with him, he's so invested in the group and we're loving what he's doing."
LIVE stream every game of every round of the 2017 Toyota AFL Premiership Season on FOX SPORTS. Get your free 2-week Foxtel Now trial and start watching in minutes.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Game Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Lloyd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maxwell</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toyota AFL Premiership Season</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lloyd</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FOX SPORTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelly</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxtel Now</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ROUND 20 REVIEW FOX FOOTY PODCAST BELOW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GWS Giants</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Maxwell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
