<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443448356553300</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/federal-politics/political-news/politics-live-liberal-party-meets-to-decide-position-on-gay-marriage-in-australia-20170726-gxqoow.html</url>
  <title>LIVE: Liberal Party meets to decide position on gay marriage in Australia</title>
  <content>
If you've just joined me, here's a quick update.

Liberal Party MPs have been discussing same-sex marriage for just over an hour.

There's roughly three camps - the reformers, the pragmatists and the hardline conservatives.

Cabinet met earlier today and resolved to, once again, put the plebiscite to the Parliament. If that fails, then a postal vote would be put. If that fails, a free vote might be offered.
Reporter Michael Koziol says the leadership of the government is telling the party room a free vote will happen by the end of the year if the plebiscite and postal vote are unsuccessful (when I saw unsuccessful I mean fails to get through the Parliament).

From a Liberal MP: Party room told cabinet position is: 1) Try plebiscite again 2) If Senate blocks, postal vote 3) Free vote by year's end

The Labor caucus has finished its meeting.

Shadow attorney-general, Mark Dreyfus, told the meeting Liberal senator Dean Smith's same-sex marriage private member's bill was "an acceptable compromise".
It's interesting to go back to what the then communications minister Malcolm Turnbull had to say after the previous marriage discussion in August 2015.

"There is a huge number of big issues, so one of the attractions of a free vote is that it would have meant the matter would have been resolved in this parliament one way or another in a couple of weeks," Mr Turnbull said the day after the meeting.

"The reason I haven't advocated a plebiscite after the next election is that it would mean, it will mean, that this issue is a live issue all the way up to the next election and, indeed, at the next election and, if we are returned to office, it will be a very live issue in the lead-up to the plebiscite itself."
Political reporter Matthew Knott has been walking the corridors.

"The media are being blocked from the corridors around the Liberal party room with a group of security guards and some Parliament House officials telling any journalists to go away," he says.

"But I spoke to some MPs on the way in and there is no expectation that a conscience vote will succeed. Moderate MPs who support same-sex marriage are already talking of today's party room as a necessary defeat before an eventual victory."
 
Veterans' Affairs Minister Dan Tehan spoke to Sky News just before the meeting began.

"My view is we should honour that election commitment," Mr Tehan said.

Mr Tehan said he had already told his constituents he would vote according to the plebiscite's outcome.
Coalition ministers were saying last week they didn't try hard enough to swing the crossbench in the plebiscite's favour the first time it was debated in Parliament.

"It would be good for the government to re-put this to the Senate," Assistant Minister Alex Hawke.

"There are reasonable crossbench senators who will know that a majority of people would like a plebiscite, and the plebiscite is the best way to resolve this issue. I think that negotiation can't happen unless we put it together and I would urge the crossbench to look at it again."
The meeting is now underway.

It is understood MPs will be told the leadership's position is to take the plebiscite legislation to Parliament - again - with a postal ballot vote as a back-up option if that it is rejected again.

We know it is going to be rejected because all the MPs who voted against it the first time around have already they haven't changed their minds.
Okay - so the meeting will start in about 20 minutes' time.

Andrew Meares asked for permission for reporters, photographers and cameramen to film the arrivals in the corridor.

But the presiding officers - Speaker of the House of Representatives Tony Smith and Senate President Stephen Parry - said no.

A further example of politicians liking to conduct business under the cover of darkness.

There's a lot of threats being thrown around at this point and all of them come down to whether or not someone is prepared to bring down the government.

National MP Andrew Broad, who represents the seat of Mallee, has said he would withdraw his support for the Coalition if it changed its policy.

Mr BroadThe Sunraysia Daily.

Mr Broad said he would not be the only member to quit the government's ranks.

"It won't be me only, the whole show would blow up," he said.
It is pretty hard to find anyone outside the Coalition who thinks a postal vote is a brilliant idea.

.

Let's be straight here - it's a compromise option designed the keep a government with a one seat majority together.
So - there are three camps:

the reformers who want to change the Coalition's policy to a free vote;

the pragmatists who want resolution via a postal plebiscite; and

the hardline conservatives who want the existing policy no matter what.

Then there is the plan by Malcolm Turnbull and his senior ministers - including Peter Dutton and Mathias Cormann - to try and resolve the matter by using a postal vote.

Tony Abbott has said he will argue against that this afternoon.

The Duttons and Cormanns of the world just want this issue dealt with. They can see the way it is dragging down the government.

But Mr Abbott said: "There has to be a plebiscite....We should have another go and if that fails, we should have another go."
Let's take a look at what the meeting will discuss.

Five reformers - Dean Smith, Trent Zimmerman, Tim Wilson, Trevor Evans and Warren Entsch - are pushing for a free vote.

They have put their names to a private members' bill circulated to all government MPs at the weekend. The bill includes religious protections which they hope will help persuade voters to support their cause.

The Liberal party room meets at 4 pm.

The Labor caucus just had a quick together to show how great and unified everything is in its ranks.

Leader Bill Shorten said the reason why same-sex marriage hasn't been dealt with is clear and that's because of the "complete failure of leadership and weakness" of the Prime Minister.
More and more holes have appeared in the plebiscite policy.

It was supposed to be held in February this year - but Parliament had other ideas.

Many MPs have said they would not vote in Parliament according to the outcome of the plebiscite - leaving people to scratch their heads about the point of having their say.

Now, of course, we have the prospect of a postal plebiscite - which might be legally dodgy not to mention there's a whole generation of people who don't really use the postal system anymore.
It was a pretty hot-to-trot affair by all accounts - five-and-a-half-hours long - and it was less than a month later that Mr Abbott was gone as prime minister.

After the meeting Mr Abbott said there were two options for the party to take to the 2016 election - a parliamentary vote or a vote of the people.

Which is how we ended up with the idea of a plebiscite.
Tony Abbott is one reason and leadership is the other.

It is nearly two years exactly since the Coalition party room debated the issue - prompted, in part, by a cross-party private member's bill that would have legalised same-sex marriage.

That meeting ran for several hours and ended with MPs voting against a free vote on the issue.
And so we find ourselves here. Again. Waiting for the Liberal party room to have a super special meeting about something it says it is not that much of an issue for everyday people.

Same-sex marriage is the issue that will not go away for the Turnbull government.

So how did we get here?
Hello and welcome to the day (well, afternoon), in politics with me, Alex Ellinghausen and Andrew Meares.

It's a pleasure to have your company.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Assistant Minister Alex Hawke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trent Zimmerman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Affairs Minister Dan Tehan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Dutton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Party MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Meares</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Abbott</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Representatives Tony Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dutton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Speaker of the House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Knott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Broad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nationals MP Andrew Broad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hello</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mathias Cormann</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Abbott</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sky News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Koziol</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Tehan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr BroadThe Sunraysia Daily</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Dreyfus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mallee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate President Stephen Parry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Smith</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cormann</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Ellinghausen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parliament House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
