<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443285147793525</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/nrl/ben-ikin-says-its-time-gold-coast-titans-asked-coach-neil-henry-the-tough-questions/news-story/abfd91e799be2604421ec075d5c66742</url>
  <title>Ikin: Time to ask Henry the tough questions</title>
  <content>
OUT of finals contention and out of sorts, Gold Coast coach Neil Henry must come up with answers fast if he is to retain his job, according to Ben Ikin.
The Titans have suffered back-to-back NRL humiliations - the most recent a club-worst 54-0 hammering to Brisbane on Saturday - that's brought into question Henry's future at the club.
Reports of a rift between players and coach have emerged, while former Titans owner Darryl Kelly is reportedly also having second thoughts about buying the club back off the NRL such was the meekness of the Broncos defeat.
Ikin, who started his playing career at the now-defunct Gold Coast Seagulls, believes Henry should be forced to explain why he is the right man for the job.
"Everyone is open for criticism on the back of what's happened," Ikin told AAP on Monday.
"If I'm on the board I'm asking him how things are going to change in the next few weeks and what his answers are for the future, because at the start of this year I had them as a finals side."
Henry piloted the Titans to the finals last season and is contracted until the end of 2018.
The NRL, who currently own the club, would probably be reluctant to take action given a large severance package they would need to pay Henry if he was axed before the end of his deal.
But new private owners, in partnership with the club's board, may soon be in charge of the club's finances.
Tians prop Jarrod Wallace apologised on behalf of the team's performance following Monday's recovery session, admitting the team's game review had been "confronting".
Denying any notion of a player revolt, the Queensland Origin rookie endorsed Henry and stressed they would work to show Kelly and other interested parties the club was worth investing in.
"After a loss like that there's always going to be people trying to get heads rolled, but we're trying to stick together and we're all behind him," the 26-year-old said.

NRL: Penrith have moved into the top 8 for the first time this season and they believe they can challenge for a premiership.

Finals looming for Panthers
"And we love Darryl and want him to stick around. We are very sorry for how we've played, not just to him but our fans."
But Ikin argued the damage had already been done before the dismal showings against the Broncos and Wests Tigers in the last two weeks that have left fans fuming.
"I tend to base my opinion on a team's culture in the first three quarters of a season, not the last few games (once finals are out of the equation)," he said.
"The preseason was a good chance for them to build on a promising campaign in 2016, but now hard questions should be asked of whether Henry is getting it right.
"Right now, the gap between their best and worst is far too great."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ikin</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neil Henry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darryl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darryl Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Origin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast Seagulls</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Panther</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wests Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broncos</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Henry</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Penrith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Ikin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Titans</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>19</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarrod Wallace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
