<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443280852826076</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/national/breaking-news/nsw-police-back-officers-in-fatal-shooting/news-story/68761505a014a46e5266ee8d28a6d127</url>
  <title>NSW Police back officers in fatal shooting</title>
  <content>
Jamie McKinnellAustralian Associated Press

Share

The response of officers who fatally shot a knife-wielding man in northern NSW followed "textbook" procedure, police say.
Three officers found Christopher McGrail armed with a knife after responding to reports of a disturbance at a Grafton unit on Sunday afternoon.
"Both Taser and OC spray were deployed prior to police having to shoot the individual," NSW Police Assistant Commissioner for the Northern Region Max Mitchell said on Monday.
Residents nearby the Turf Street unit heard police yelling for Mr McGrail to "drop the knife".
Two constables and a sergeant first used a Taser and OC spray, before he was eventually shot.
He was treated at the scene and flown to Gold Coast hospital in a critical condition but died overnight.
Mr Mitchell said the suspect was known to police.
"It's an unfortunate situation and from what I've been briefed on, police have undertaken their tactical options textbook," he told reporters in Newcastle.
One resident said he heard the drama unfolding before seeing an officer pointing his gun.

"There was another one over the road with his gun pointed straight at me and the culprit right in between us," the resident, who didn't want to be named, told AAP.
"I leapt up, shut the door and got my head down.
"A gun can go where it's not supposed to go, so I put two walls between me and the police."
The officers were still yelling for the man to drop the weapon after two shots rang out, the resident said.
Mr Mitchell said he was unaware whether residents could have been at risk, but a critical incident investigation would examine all aspects of the shooting.
"They're the type of issues that police will call upon," he said.
"If there were any witnesses who are able to come forward and provide a statement, it's most important," he said.
The officers involved were in shock, Mr Mitchell said.
"My understanding is they are as well as what could be expected," he said.
"No police officer wants to shoot an individual.
"It is traumatic."
The investigation is being overseen by the Law Enforcement Conduct Commission.
"This will provide assurance to the public and the next of kin that the investigation is conducted in a competent, thorough and objective manner," a spokeswoman said in a statement.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christopher McGrail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taser</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamie McKinnellAustralian Associated Press</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Region Max Mitchell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turf Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Police Assistant Commissioner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr McGrail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Mitchell</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grafton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Law Enforcement Conduct Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
