<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443753299236576</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/sport/afl/west-coast-should-cull-eight-to-10-players-from-its-list-at-seasons-end-says-robert-walls/news-story/f522f97eb78cd7b51c9ff2c83f9d7d34</url>
  <title>'Insipid display': Walls' ruthless list cull call</title>
  <content>
CARLTON premiership great Robert Walls has blasted the West Coast's "insipid display" and workrate against St Kilda, calling for the club to cull eight to 10 senior players at season's end.
The Eagles suffered an eight-point defeat at the hands of the Saints on Sunday in a loss that has put a major dent in their finals' aspirations.
Walls, who watched the game first-hand, slammed the effort the Eagles' effort on Fox Sports News' AFL Tonight, adding that the club's list management team must make ruthless calls in the coming months.
"If I'm Adam Simpson, I get rid of eight or 10 on the list and bring in younger blokes who want to work hard. Certainly look for speed, but look for effort too," Walls said.
"They've got too many players who like to be forward of the ball to get the easy take, the easy receive."
LISTEN TO THE ROUND 20 REVIEW FOX FOOTY PODCAST BELOW, OR
Walls was particularly scathing of the Eagles' lack of pressure on Sunday, which saw them lose the tackle count to St Kilda by 20.
Four players - Jack Darling, Luke Partington, Malcolm Karpany and Will Schofield - failed to lay a tackle for the entire game, while eight players - Jamie Cripps, Mark Hutchings, Josh Kennedy, Eric Mackenzie, Chris Masten, Jeremy McGovern, Jackson Nelson and Dom Sheed - finished with just one tackle each.
"It's just disappointing to have a team come over and put in an insipid display like that," Walls said.
"These are the facts: There were 12 Eagles players who between them had a total of eight tackles. There was a young man for the Adelaide Crows, Hugh Greenwood, who had 12 tackles himself in the first half (against Port Adelaide on Sunday).
"They're not prepared to work hard enough, the Eagles. And as a result they lost a game that, on talent, they should have won."
The Eagles now face an uphill task to feature in this year's finals series.
While they will start as favourites against Carlton at Subiaco Oval this Saturday night, they face a nightmare final two weeks of the season against the second-placed GWS Giants at Spotless Stadium then first-placed Adelaide at home in the final round.
LIVE stream every game of every round of the 2017 Toyota AFL Premiership Season on FOX SPORTS. Get your free 2-week Foxtel Now trial and start watching in minutes.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spotless Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Kennedy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Subiaco Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Darling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Masten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dom Sheed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagles</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Partington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Will Schofield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JEREMY McGovern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Crows</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Simpson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Hutchings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saints</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toyota AFL Premiership Season</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox Sports News' AFL Tonight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Karpany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eric Mackenzie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FOX SPORTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamie Cripps</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxtel Now</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jackson Nelson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Walls</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ROUND 20 REVIEW FOX FOOTY PODCAST BELOW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hugh Greenwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GWS Giants</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
