<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443499896161813</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/lifestyle/parenting/babies/is-puttin-babies-in-boxes-an-awardwinning-idea/news-story/e1fa7422bf76652dd6b78e0837847b72</url>
  <title>Is puttin babies in boxes an award-winning idea?</title>
  <content>
A Sydney business selling cardboard boxes for babies to sleep in has been nominated for an award. Picture: Supplied

Share

AN idea to replace newborn babies' cushy cribs with basic cardboard boxes has been short-listed for an Australian business award.
Tuutu is a baby supplies business founded by Sydney woman Susanna Heiskanen.
The online store offers a number of packages including products for newborns like baby wipes, mittens, and mattress covers, but its star product is the box they arrive in.
The simple cardboard box is just that. It's similar to one you'd find in a mailroom or office storage space, but according to Tuutu it can promote "safe sleeping, health and wellbeing of babies and their mothers".
Inspired by the Finnish government's baby box program, the box is used as a bed for the baby, its lid can double as a changing table, and it can later be used as a storage box for toys or become a toddler's toy itself.
In Finland, where Tuutu's founders both come from, most children start their lives sleeping in a box.
The scheme, offering mothers a choice between about $200 cash and the baby box, has been running since 1938 and the government distributes about 40,000 boxes a year.
After growing up in Finland where most children start their lives sleeping in a box, Ms Heiskanen sought out something similar for her child when she became a new mum in Australia, and was surprised she couldn't find anything.
"It is undeniably the best Finnish invention and as Finns we are extremely proud of it roots that are based on a beautiful foundation to promote safe sleeping, health and wellbeing of babies and their mothers and to provide an equal start in life for anybody," she said.

Tuutu's baby boxes come with a package of baby products, but it's all about the box. Picture: SuppliedSource:Supplied
"Having done our own journey to parenthood in Australia, we realised there was nothing like the Finnish maternity package with a ready set of baby essentials available in Australia. Hence we wanted to provide one for the Australian parents with Australian brands and taking into consideration Australian culture and climate"
Ms Heiskanen said the baby box, which comes packed with a small mattress and a package of newborn baby essentials, had been designed with sustainability in mind.
The business's co-founders want to continue promoting their idea and build awareness of the concept among hospitals and government organisations.
Tuutu is a sustainability award finalist in the AusMumpreneur Awards 2017. The winners are due to be announced at a ceremony in Sydney later this month.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SuppliedSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Heiskanen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Finland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Susanna Heiskanen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AusMumpreneur Awards 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Finns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuutu</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Finnish</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
