<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443667399889253</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4838183/up-up-and-away-with-wollongongs-skydive-the-beach/?cs=12</url>
  <title>Wollongong's Skydive the Beach acquires Byron Bay Ballooning</title>
  <content>
Illawarra adventure company expands: Wollongong's Skydive the Beach has this month acquired Byron Bay Ballooning in Byron Bay. Picture: Byron Bay Ballooning.

Skydive the Beach's quest to become the world's largest adventure tourism company has taken another leap skyward with the acquisition of .

Since completing its first public offering in 2015 the business that started in Wollongong in 1999 has already become Australasia's biggest adventure tourism company.
Since 2015 the business also known as Skydive Australia has acquired Australia Skydive and and Raging Thunder Adventures and Reef Magic Cruises.
Chief executive Anthony Ritter said Byron Bay Ballooning was not the company's first venture into ballooning. That was on the Atherton Tablelands last year.
"Raging Thunder Adventures in Cairns is white water rafting, hot air ballooning, inner barrier reef tours, sea kayaking and canyoning. And in May just gone we bought Reef Magic Cruises which is taking people out to the outer barrier reef and one of those big pontoons."

Mr Ritter said company was looking for opportunities around the globe but the latest acquisition further strengthens its existing adventure offering in Byron Bay where it has been operating a tandem skydiving business known as Skydive Byron Bay since 2005.

Mr Ritter said the merging of the two businesses will create a new adventure hub for tourists and thrill-seekers looking to experience the beauty of Byron from a breath-taking perspective. Around 3000 people a year enjoy the coastal views with Byron Bay Ballooning which will soon relocate to Skydive the Beach's skydiving headquarters in Byron Bay. But the overall business will where the call centre is located.
"The past two years have seen Skydive the Beach expand significantly," he said.

The goal is to continue that in a range of sports and experiences.

"There is potential everywhere in all adventure tourism. We are certainly looking at a lot of expansion plans. In 2010 we were just a drop zone in Wollongong. We have grown a lot in seven years. We are looking all over the world. We made that comment that we want to be the largest and most respected in the world so we have to branch out not just in Australia and New Zealand. We are looking at a number of opportunities overseas in all adventure tourism."
Mr Ritter said the performance of the company over the last 12 months would come out in the annual report at the end of August.

Managing director Anthony Boucaut described Byron Bay Ballooning as a great new asset in a landmark location.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reef Magic Cruises</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Atherton Tablelands</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Byron Bay</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia Skydive</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Boucaut</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Ritter</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong's Skydive</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Byron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beach</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raging Thunder Adventures</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Ritter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Skydive Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Skydive</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Byron Bay Ballooning</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australasia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thunder Adventures</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Skydive Byron Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
