<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443839198583989</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-07/developers-reveal-new-sexy-design-for-hobart-skyscraper/8780610</url>
  <title>Developers reveal new-look design for proposed five-star hotel tower in Hobart</title>
  <content>
Singaporean-based developer the Fragrance Company has released revised images for its proposed skyscraper in Hobart's historic Sullivans Cove precinct.
The updated design for the five-star hotel has been submitted to Hobart City Council as part of a statutory planning process and formal consideration of the application.
It comes after the developer submitted .
Now the revised plans, designed by Xsquared Architects of Hobart, show a structure with a mirror-like exterior.
"It's not a mirror-glass building, it's a semi-transparent glass facade," Xsquared director Peter Scott said.
"The building is a lot more curvy, a more sexy shape than it was before.
"We wanted it to have changing reflections at all times of the year by curving it, and what you'll see night and day is a changing facade that will both mirror the environment that its in but also reflect what's happening inside."
Mr Scott said the new design took into account a range of factors including the area's streetscape, wind effects, shading and pedestrian connectivity.
He said the footprint of the building had been reduced, but making the building narrower meant they had to go higher to keep the desired floor area (25,000 square metres).
The 210m tower would contain 457 rooms, restaurants, conference centre and 99 on-site car spaces.
The current height limit in the Sullivans Cove area is 18m and the proposed tower would be about four times higher than Hobart's tallest buildings.

"With the change in the shape of the building on a floor-by-floor basis we've had to add back that area in somewhere and the only place to put it is to basically increase the height," he said.
Mr Scott said, if approved, the hotel could be operational by the end of 2020, assuming construction commenced by the end of this year.
He made no apologies for the building standing out.
"It's not going to blend in," he said.
"It will be a prominent building, I'm not here to suggest that won't be the case, it will become something Hobart is remembered for."
The Fragrance Group has also put an application in for a second hotel on Collins Street, designed by S. Group Architects which jumped in height from 73m to 94m.

'No support for high rise'

Last month, Hobart City Council planning director Neil Noye said he was surprised when the formal planning application revealed the extra height on the buildings.
He said the .
Meanwhile, .
The meeting of more than 400 people in the Town Hall demanded the council allow broader community input into the changes.
Brian Corr, president of Hobart not Highrise, the group that organised the Town Hall meeting, said at the time there was no support for controversial plans.
"In fairness to the Hobart City Council, I think they will refuse these two buildings," he said.
"In all honesty, I can't find any reason why they wouldn't."
The council has 31 days to respond to the Fragrance Group's plans.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Singaporean-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>S. Group Architects</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Xsquared</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hobart</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sullivans Cove</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Scott</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Scott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fragrance Company</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brian Corr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neil Noye</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Xsquared Architects of Hobart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collins Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Town Hall</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hobart City Council</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fragrance Group</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
