<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443577205574605</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:38</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-07/how-sour-cherry-became-most-photographed-tree/8781812</url>
  <title>Distinctive cherry tree in Maleny becomes one of Australia's most photographed trees</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

An incredible story of generosity has been revealed behind the growing popularity of one of Australia's most photographed trees.
Professional photographers have for years beaten a well worn path to 'One Tree Hill', capturing sweeping views over the magnificent Glass House Mountains from Maleny in the Sunshine Coast hinterland.
On an average weekend, bridal parties compete for space and dodge cow pats around the base of a striking tree in a beef cattle paddock.
But what most people do not know is that the tree has helped raise more than $40,000 for local charities, and built a rich bond between its owner Florence Woods and the community she calls her extended family.
"If you give, you will receive tenfold and that's how I look at it," the mother of eight said as she opened her 80th birthday celebrations to the people of Maleny.

The story of One Tree Hill began more than 20 years ago, when Mrs Woods's late husband Frank came up to their farmhouse to tell his wife they had had an unexpected visitor.
"He said 'Hey Florence, there was a fella from London at the fence today when I was working in the top paddock', and I said 'What was that for? What are you talking about?' and he said 'Oh, he's been looking all over the place for it, he finally found it'.
"He'd seen a photograph in London and he'd wanted to have a look at this tree, and he was amazed at the sight of it," Mrs Woods said.

It would be the start of international recognition for a distinctive native sour cherry tree with a hollow twisted trunk, lush leafy canopy and magical views.
Mr Woods was then approached by the first of what would become a steady stream of professional photographers.
Every cent of the more than $40,000 photographers have paid for the use of One Tree Hill has been gifted to local charities.

External Link:

'One Tree Hill' Facebook video
The first beneficiary was the local nursing home, which was fundraising for a hydrotherapy pool, and the generosity has not stopped.
"So the men's shed, historical society, the hospital, naval cadets and any other charity in the town or anyone in strife," Mrs Woods said.
One Tree Hill has become so busy that Mrs Woods takes bookings for the paddock where their Droughtmaster cattle graze.
Photographers are briefed not to leave farm gates open and to watch out for the cow pat minefield the livestock leave behind.
"They have to. Either that or they go for a slip," Mrs Woods laughed.
It is estimated 10 per cent of Australia's weddings are held on the Sunshine Coast, and One Tree Hill has become a favoured destination.

"The place is, well, it's pretty sacred to us, because the kids go over there and the grandchildren and sit and say 'Oh, we talked to grandad today'," Mrs Woods said.
"This was Frank's property and he passed away seven years ago."
Professional photographers have an unwritten agreement to donate $50 every time they use the land, and Amy Hinks, from Amy Hinks Photography, organised a special birthday gift for Mrs Woods.

"There's a network of professional photographers that we're in and the majority of us have shot at One Tree Hill more than once," Ms Hinks said.
"I put together an album with 170 photos of everyone's favourite One Tree Hill photos.
"They range from landscape photography to weddings. There's some maternity photos and family photos so Mrs Woods can have memories and see what everybody uses her land for.

"She's so giving and she will always have a good chat on the phone."
The octogenarian's generosity doesn't stop at One Tree Hill.

Mrs Woods is also a member of Maleny's Busy Needles group, which knits clothing for premature babies and makes knee rugs, mittens, elbow warmers and socks for the Erowal aged care facility, Maleny Hospital and Prince Charles palliative care.
The 80-year-old is already thinking about the toys she will knit for the Salvation Army's Christmas Appeal and has no plans to slow down.
"No, why should I?" she said.
"I'm having fun. I have my friends, I have my family and the community has become my family.
"I get a lot of love, I give a lot of love and I'm enjoying life. That's how it should be."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glass House Mountains</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Droughtmaster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny's Busy Needles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Charles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salvation Army's Christmas Appeal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Woods</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Wood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tree Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Florence Woods</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Erowal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amy Hinks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hey Florence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Hinks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amy Hinks Photography</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Wood</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frank</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tree Hill' Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>One Tree Hill</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>1.7</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
