<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443706054595597</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/retail/woolworths-customers-billed-twice-in-payments-glitch-20170807-gxr15n</url>
  <title>Woolworths customers billed twice in payments glitch </title>
  <content>
Woolworths customers have been advised to check their bank statements after the retailer charged hundreds of customers twice because of a payments processing glitch.
Woolworths was forced to apologise on Monday after customers who shopped at Woolworths supermarkets, liquor stores, BIG W stores and petrol stations as far back as March and used their Visa cards were billed again overnight for the same transactions.
Customers vented their anger on social media, accusing Woolworths of stealing their funds and questioning the retailer's use of their credit card data.
"Today I have been double billed by Woolworths for transactions from the 11th of March, Woolworths have stolen almost $300 and I want my money back," one customer wrote on Woolworths' Facebook page.

"You have taken money from my account for transactions made in March ... how long until I get my money back and more importantly why are you retaining details of my card when I have not given you permission to do so?" asked another customer.

Woolworths blamed the double-dipping on payments processor Cuscal, saying that due to a processing error "a limited number" of customers had been billed incorrectly.
"Cuscal have confirmed they will rectify any payment errors as soon as possible and they have also confirmed that no impacted customer will incur incorrect charges related to the incident," a Woolworths spokesman said.
"If customers have further concerns around their own personal financial circumstances, Cuscal encourages them to contact their local financial provider directly."
Accepted responsibility

Several customers claimed the double-dipping had left their accounts short of funds to pay automated payments, their cards had been declined or they had incurred overdrawn fees.
"Thanks Woolies, your glitch left my bank account $160 in the red," one customer said.
Some institutions initially blamed Woolworths for the processing error, but Cuscal issued a statement late on Monday accepting responsibility.
"Due to a Cuscal processing error last night some incorrect transactions were posted to our clients' customers' accounts this morning," the statement said.

"We apologise for the stress and inconvenience this is causing people. We are working urgently to correct the errors and anticipate all transactions will be corrected by tomorrow.
"No customers will be out of pocket due to incorrect charges or transactions arising directly from this incident - we will work with our clients to make sure this happens.
"People should wait for the charges to be reversed or talk to their financial institution with any immediate financial problems."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BIG W</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woolworths' Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cuscal</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woolworths</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
