<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443577205574600</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:38</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/business/riding-hitech-wave/news-story/65f2770ff1a3446a072dbe6a681a7f35</url>
  <title>Riding hi-tech wave</title>
  <content>
ONE of the world's leading innovators is putting Adelaide on the international map as a driving force in digital communications and hi-tech industries.
Tom Hajdu, co-founder of music production company tomandandy and strategic innovation incubator disrupter.com, is the driving force behind turning Adelaide into Australia's first - and only - gigabit city.
Working with the SA Government, Mr Hajdu has helped put technology in place to offer users 100 times the national average speed and 10 times the download speed of the NBN, making Adelaide the capital of ultra-fast internet.
"Adelaide has all the ingredients for success," said Mr Hajdu, who in June this year was appointed SA's first chief adviser on innovation by Premier Jay Weatherill.
"It has the most potential in any city that I've visited in Australia to succeed in the long term. There's a lot of opportunities to invest here because it has the capacity to grow.
"The digital economy will be the main driver for the global economy for the next two or three decades.
"What has impressed me about Adelaide is that it has recognised this. It's moving quickly to seize the opportunity and has understood that infrastructure is the key foundation to pivoting successfully to create jobs in the future, a future that is outward looking and connected to the world."
One of Mr Hajdu's goals as SA's chief innovation pioneer is to help forge business growth within the state and foster new start-ups. To this end, 14 innovation and business precincts have been transformed into ultra-high-speed internet districts offering gigabit upload and download speeds.
One international business that has taken advantage of the digital infrastructure in place in SA is Fleet Space Technologies, an innovative company that plans to deploy 100 nano-satellites to cover Earth in order to enable interconnectivity, maximise the resource efficiency of human civilisation and enable the next industrial revolution.
Fleet's co-founder Flavia Nardini is an aerospace engineer who has worked for the European Space Agency and TNO in the Netherlands.
Originally from Rome, Italy, Ms Nardini created Fleet Space Technologies in 2015 through support from the SA Government and Australian investors. The company has offices in Los Angeles and Europe but its headquarters remain in Adelaide.
"Adelaide is a super positive place. Most of my team is here, we operate and do everything here," Ms Nardini said. "Fleet is a very global company. Even one satellite covers all Earth so I need to be very close to my customers. But everything is happening in SA. We build tech here, all the ideas are here, the supply and development - everything is here in Adelaide."
And Nardini predicts the digital and technological revolution that SA has embraced so fully will ensure the state remains a major player on the national and global scene.
"Important innovation is going to happen in the coming five to 10 years, where there will be devices connected in every industry, from oil and gas, mining, agriculture, transport - so much is going to happen in our future," she said.
"We're really hoping we can stay here and ... show future investors that things can happen here. We have the location, the people and the support to make things happen in SA."
PICK UP THE SPECIAL EDITION OF THE CITY WITH THE NEW ADELAIDE SUPPLEMENT TOMORROW. FIND IT AT RUNDLE MALL, JAMES PLACE, ADELAIDE CENTRAL MARKET, ADELAIDE RAILWAY STATION.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>12</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Los Angeles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hajdu</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flavia Nardini</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TNO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>European Space Agency</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Hajdu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Nardini</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ADELAIDE RAILWAY STATION</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rundle Mall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NEW ADELAIDE SUPPLEMENT TOMORROW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ADELAIDE CENTRAL MARKET</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rome</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Jay Weatherill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JAMES PLACE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA Government</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fleet Space Technologies</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SPECIAL EDITION OF THE CITY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netherlands</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nardini</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
