<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443710349562985</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4839688/murray-faces-forced-time-off/?cs=306</url>
  <title>Murray faces forced time off</title>
  <content>
CHARGE: Central Newcastle halfback Brad Murray (top) tackles opposite Western Suburbs number Sam Keenan late last month. Picture:

Central Newcastle halfback Brad Murray could be sidelined until the play-offs following a spear tackle on Kurri Kurri's Jake Moore at St John Oval on Sunday. 
After being put on report Murray was charged on Monday with a grade two dangerous throw and may risk taking the case to the Newcastle Rugby League judiciary.

Not only do the Butcher Boys host Macquarie next round in a battle for second spot and a home qualifying semi-final but entering an early guilty plea by Tuesday won't lessen his suspension.

Carry-over points from an incident last season, involving an appeal for referee abuse, means Murray will automatically miss the remaining two regular rounds unless downgraded by the panel on Wednesday night.   

The 27-year-old, who will on Tuesday officially re-sign at the Butcher Boys for next season, has been one of the competition's best performers in 2017.  

Elsewhere and Goannas reserve grader Tory Neville faces a five-week suspension after headbutting a Western Suburbs opponent at Cessnock on Saturday. 

Neville, who was sent off for the incident, could have the grade four striking charge reduced to a three-week punishment and 75 carry-over points with an early guilty plea.   
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Suburbs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurri Kurri's Jake Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Rugby League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Butcher Boys</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Keenan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St John Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad Murray</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tory Neville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central Newcastle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macquarie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goannas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cessnock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
