<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443620155248349</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:48</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/messenger/north-northeast/hayley-mitchell-a-finalist-in-miss-ink-tattoo-competition/news-story/02a736ffa14c224e26381eabe1404eeb</url>
  <title>Tatts for my brave sister</title>
  <content>
AFTER learning her sister had an advanced stage of breast cancer, Newton resident Hayley Mitchell realised life was too short to let fear get in the way.
Hayley is preparing for the Miss Ink & Miss Tattoo grand final in Canberra next month after wowing judges at a competition heat in Adelaide in February.
Her sister, Tennielle, encouraged her to enter the competition after seeing her initial hesitation.
"She was the one who said to me 'you should do this, life is short, don't let this stop you from doing things'," Hayley says.
"Because I'm a stay-at-home mum I don't get out and socialise a lot.
"It was a good opportunity to meet people, get out of my comfort zone and learn how to be comfortable in my own skin.
"I thought if I could get through this I could give my sister a bit of hope, and myself a bit of hope as well."
Tennielle has had chemotherapy and is winning her battle with cancer.
Hayley latest tattoo of Dorothy from The Wizard of Oz is a reminder of her sister's struggle to overcome the disease.
"It's a favourite childhood show for me - in the tattoo (Dorothy) has the shoes and she's holding flowers," Hayley says.
"The flowers represents my sister and how she'll always be by my side."
Hayley's other tattoos include a hula girl, combining her past as a belly dancer and love of Hawaii, and a mermaid surrounded by sea creatures, representing motherhood.

Life in ink: The tattoos of Adelaide

"I've also got a spitfire aeroplane on my thigh with a pin-up girl attached to it with some flowers, cloud work, sunbeams and a line from a Marilyn Manson song: No salvation, no forgiveness.
"It's in memory of my grandfather, William, who flew aeroplanes in World War II ... I wanted to represent what he did and how special he was to me."
Miss Ink & Miss Tattoo contestants are judged on their tattoos and their choice of casual, formal and swimwear outfits.
Hayley will compete in the September 30 grand final under the stage name Sugarbomb Betty.
The name came to her with the help of her husband, Jono, and it combines her love of sweet things in life, her interest in planes and one of her favourite names.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Miss Ink</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tennielle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jono</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sugarbomb Betty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dorothy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Miss Tattoo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hayley Mitchell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hayley</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World War II</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawaii</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marilyn Manson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tatt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wizard of Oz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>William</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
