<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443796248910240</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/news/world/north-korean-says-it-will-launch-thousandsfold-revenge-against-the-us-over-un-sanctions/news-story/9f27699671fbdb66631578dd9ebd28bd</url>
  <title>North Korea vows revenge over sanctions</title>
  <content>
NORTH Korea says it will launch "thousands-fold" revenge against the United States over the adoption of tough U.N. sanctions imposed after its intercontinental ballistic launches.
The North's statement issued today came two days after the U.N. Security Council unanimously approved  (A$1.26 billion).
Pyongyang's statement said the sanctions were caused by a "heinous U.S. plot to isolate and stifle" North Korea.
It says the U.N. sanctions will never force the country to negotiate over its nuclear program or to give up its nuclear drive.

It says it will take "action of justice" but didn't elaborate.
The sanctions passed at the weekend were a "violent violation of our sovereignty", Pyongyang said in a statement carried by its official Korean Central News Agency.
"We will not put our self-defensive nuclear deterrent on the negotiating table" while it faced threats from Washington, it said, "and will never take a single step back from strengthening our nuclear might".
The United Nations Security Council at the weekend passed a new set of sanctions against Pyongyang over its weapons programs, including bans on the export of coal, iron and iron ore, lead and lead ore as well as fish and seafood from the impoverished state.
The measures were approved unanimously - including by China, the North's sole major ally and economic lifeline, and Russia.
Tension has been running high since the nuclear-armed North staged two successful ICBM tests last month, .
Pyongyang threatened to make the US - which drafted the latest sanctions package - "pay the price for its crime... thousands of times".

China has urged North Korea to abide by UN resolutions and end the testing of missiles.

China urges Nth Korea to end missile testing
"If the US... believes that it would remain safe because its mainland is an ocean away from us, nothing would be a bigger misjudgment than that," it said.
Other nations that "collaborated with the US" to support the resolution would also be "held accountable", it added.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pyongyang</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korea</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-11</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>U.S</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>U.N</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>U.N. Security Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nth Korea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Korean Central News Agency</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ICBM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Nations Security Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
