<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443667399889292</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/07/17/52/clean-bill-of-health-for-hmas-canberra</url>
  <title>Clean bill of health for HMAS Canberra</title>
  <content>
One of the Australian Navy's leading lights has returned to full strength with HMAS Canberra successfully completing her first stint at sea since undergoing major maintenance.
The 230-metre warship, which experienced problems with its propulsion system earlier in 2017, departed Melbourne on Monday after restocking and giving crew a well-earned break.
The aircraft carrier has just completed 36 days as part of training exercise Talisman Sabre, in partnership with the United States and New Zealand, off the Queensland coast.
Ahead of Wednesday's 75th anniversary of HMAS Canberra I sinking during WWII, Captain Ashley Papp said the vessel was back at full strength.
"The ship performed incredibly well with more than 1100 people onboard at one point, helicopters, tanks, watercraft and a large number of Defence assets," Cpt Papp told reporters during an hour-long tour.
"That's a big practice for us and our New Zealand and American counterparts."
HMAS Canberra, worth about $1 billion, is now bound for Sydney where she will undergo routine maintenance before joining the anniversary celebrations.

Related Articles

HMAS CANBERRA
* Max speed 20 knots
* 230.82 metres long (1.5 times the size of the Spirit of Tasmania) and about 17-storeys high.
* On-board hospital features an emergency room, two surgical theatres, intensive care unit, pharmacy, dental surgery and X-ray machine.
* Galley capable of producing 6000 meals a day.
* Holds 1.5 million litres of diesel, and can last 45 days at sea.
* Houses 400 Navy, Army and Air Force personnel.
* Space for nine helicopters in its hanger.
* Capable of supporting amphibious operations such as disaster relief, humanitarian aid and evacuation operations.
(C)  AAP 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Max</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HMAS Canberra I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>X-rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Navy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Talisman Saber</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ashley Papp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cpt Papp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Air Force</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WWII</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spirit of Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Houses 400 Navy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday's 75</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HMAS Canberra</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
