<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443456946488181</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>http://www.businessinsider.com.au/tour-of-trump-national-golf-club-bedminster-new-jersey-2017-8</url>
  <title>See inside Trump's New Jersey golf club where he will be spending the next three weeks</title>
  <content>
President Trump is getting ready for a mega vacation.

Friday, Trump is heading out to the Trump National Golf Club in Bedminster, New Jersey, for 17 days, .

In the past, Trump has been vocal about his disapproval for taking vacations: "What's the point? If you're not enjoying your work, you're in the wrong job," Trump wrote in his 2004 book, "."

This stint away could also be due to renovation works going on in the White House. According to the AP, the entire West Wing will be empty by the end of the week so that they can replace the heating and cooling system.

Bedminster is one of the few golf clubs in the Trump family business that the president built from the ground up instead of purchasing and refurbishing. He reportedly holds a special affinity for it.

The club sits in a small town of 9,000 that has just 16 members on its police force, . Bedminster Township  for costs incurred on the president's trips to the golf club.

Take a look around Bedminster and the club, and get the history of how it came to be one of Trump's favourite retreats.

NOW WATCH: Executive Life videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump's New Jersey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump National Golf Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Wing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Executive Life</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bedminster Township</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Jersey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bedminster</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
