<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443757594203921</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/the-turnbull-government-is-going-to-push-for-another-same-sex-marriage-plebiscite-2017-8</url>
  <title>The Turnbull government is going to push for another same sex marriage plebiscite</title>
  <content>
The stalemate over marriage equality looks set to continue in Australia until at least the end of 2017 after a special meeting of the Liberal Party room to debate the issue decided to try to obtain parliamentary approval for a plebiscite once again.

The party has been split between those who favour of same-sex marriage and hardline conservatives against it, while others have sought to find middle-ground in order to end the long-running debate which has distracted the government from its economic agenda.

Liberal MPs met in Canberra this afternoon after prime minister Malcolm Turnbull called an extraordinary meeting to debate the issue, which has come to the surface again via a private private members' bill from a group of Coalition MPs, led by WA senator Dean Smith for a parliamentary "free" vote on the issue.

The idea has the support of several backbench Liberal MPs, including Trevor Evans, Tim Wilson, Trent Zimmerman and Warren Entsch, who consider crossing the floor against the wishes of their party.

Labor backed the private member's bill as "an acceptable compromise" after caucus met to discuss the issue earlier today.

Cabinet also met earlier in the day and has gone into the meeting with a three-step plan to end the debate, starting with plebiscite once again. If that fails to gain majority support in parliament, the next step would be a postal vote on the issue, an idea put forward by immigration minister Peter Dutton.

Lobby group Australian Marriage Equality has already threatened a legal challenge if the postal vote plan goes ahead.

If both of those ideas fail, the Cabinet's Plan C is free vote by the end of the year.

The Senate  on same sex marriage in October last year.

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cabinet's Plan C</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trent Zimmerman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Dutton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Marriage Equality</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MPs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coalition MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
