<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443491306227061</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:18</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/entertainment/television/marvels-next-big-tv-project-inhumans-is-getting-caned/news-story/9c3b6885d68f730071a1d51b10c81dff</url>
  <title>Marvel's next big TV project is getting caned</title>
  <content>
THINGS are not looking good for Marvel's latest TV venture, Inhumans.
The new TV series is set to debut next month but the pilot was screened for American TV critics just before the Television Critics Association summer press tour. The reaction has not been kind with Marvel TV executives and the shows' writers grilled at the panel session on the tour.
Inhumans draws from the Marvel comics of the same name and focuses on a race of humans altered by alien DNA. The story centres on the Inhuman royal family, headed by Black Bolt, whose voice has destructive powers, his wife Medusa whose hair can be lethal and Maximus, the brother of Black Bolt who wants the throne for himself.
Inhumans was originally slated to be part of Marvel Cinematic Universe's movies before it was shifted to a smaller format, though the double-episode pilot will screen in the US in IMAX theatres.
One site, Spoiler TV, posted the first review but it has since been removed because it broke embargo rules. Spoiler TV called it "simply awful" and "absolutely terrible". It gave a special lashing to the dialogue, labelling it "atrocious" and that the only redeeming feature is the character of Lockjaw, a teleporting giant dog which the reviewer said was "adorable".
While other reviews have not yet illicitly surfaced, the reception Marvel TV boss Jeph Loeb and Inhumans showrunner Scott Buck received at the TCA panel confirms other critics were less than impressed.
Uproxx critic Alan Sepinwall tweeted the panel was "awkward" while LA Times entertainment reporter Libby Hill tweeted "You'll be happy to know that the Inhumans panel is just as uncomfortable as the Inhumans pilot".
Responding to criticism of the pilot, Joeb testily defended the show when a reporter asked if the episode had turned out as expected.
"I can tell you that it was written on the material that you were given that the show that you have seen is not the finished product. If you're asking me whether or not it was done, it's not. So to be perfectly honest, I don't understand your question," he shot back,  .
When another reporter suggested to star Anson Mount the show wasn't very good, Mount invoked Ben Affleck and the Oscar winner's reaction to Batman V Superman's critical drudging.
"You're making me feel like Ben Affleck right now," he said, .
Inhumans is the latest Marvel TV project and its third with US TV network ABC. The first was Agents of SHIELD, which also features Inhuman characters and will exist in the same universe. Agents of SHIELD recovered from a widely panned first season to recently being renewed for a fifth season.
ABC and Marvel's second series was Agent Carter, which was critically beloved but little watched and cancelled after two years.
The collaboration between ABC and Marvel has always been regarded as less critically successful than the collaboration between Netflix and Marvel whose series including Jessica Jones and Luke Cage have been lauded for their complex characters and visual mastery.
Only Iron Fist received less than stellar reviews. The showrunner for Iron Fist, Scott Buck, is the same as that for Inhumans. Buck has been replaced by Raven Metzner for Iron Fist's second season.
Marvel also has two other upcoming TV series, Runaways and Cloak and Dagger, on US streaming site Hulu and TV network Freeform, respectively.
Continue the conversation on Twitter with .
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Batman V. Superman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LA Times</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jessica Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alan Sepinwall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Agents of SHIELD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeph Loeb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spoiler TV</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Television Critics Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joeb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TCA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Buck</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hulu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iron Fist</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Cage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anson Mount</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Affleck</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Medusa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>American TV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uproxx</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DNA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raven Metzner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Agent Carter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oscar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marvel</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MAXIMUS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marvel TV</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IMAX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Libby Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marvel Cinematic Universe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Black Bolt</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US TV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
