<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443590090476832</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/rugby-union/union-news/will-genia-all-but-confirms-he-will-return-to-australian-rugby-with-queensland-reds-20170807-gxqv31.html</url>
  <title>Genia all but confirms he will return to Queensland Reds</title>
  <content>
Wallabies halfback Will Genia has all but confirmed he will make a return to Australian rugby next season with the Queensland Reds. 
Genia is the only member of a 34-man Wallabies squad without an official Super Rugby club for next year after making the decision to return from French club Stade Francais. Photo: Stuart Walmsley
The 29-year-old has been linked with the Reds for a number of months and expressed his desire in June to return to the club that gave him his first start in professional rugby, saying he would rather go back to Paris than run out for another Super Rugby team. 
"It's pretty much finalised, I've just got to nut out the last little bits of the detail and it should be announced soon," Genia said. 
Asked whether that club was the Reds, Genia laughed and tried to throw a curve ball, saying: "I don't know where it is. My manager is taking care of that, so I'll just wait and see where I'm going to play." 
Genia signed a contract with the Australian Rugby Union last November and has spent the past few months trying finalise details with the affected club, given he may have to take a pay-cut to come back with the Reds.  

The Rebels have also been thrown in the mix, but given how hard Genia and his management have pushed for him to return to Queensland, the odds are shortening of seeing the incumbent Wallabies No. 9 alongside long-time teammate Quade Cooper. 
"I'd love to play with Quade," Genia said. "He's one of my really good mates and played pretty much my whole professional footy career with Quadey, so if that opportunity comes up it's something I'm really looking forward to.

You will now receive updates from

Rugbyheaven Newsletter

Rugbyheaven Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"I'm looking forward, once it's all done and announced, to moving on. It's not been something that has bothered me too much because for the back part of the year I'm home in Queensland outside of being in camp with the boys. 
"At the end of the day, I understand, particularly with Queensland, that coming back at this time with their squad being full, it's going to be quite tough. I'm not too fussed. I haven't been too bothered by it." 
Genia said he had a newfound desire to make an impact in Australian rugby. 
"In hindsight, I needed to get away because maybe that hunger probably wasn't there for Super Rugby but it was there when I played for Australia," he said. "To go away and come back, there's definitely the hunger to want to come and perform in what I consider to be the best provincial rugby competition in the world." 
Genia was guaranteed a starting spot in June but now that Nick Phipps is back in the picture, the New South Welshman will no doubt keep the 78-Test stalwart on his toes. 
"There's always competition and that's a good thing," Genia said. "If guys are pushing each other to perform on the training paddock, that translates into playing well on the field. Whatever Cheik [Wallabies coach Michael Cheika] wants to do, I'll back the boss." 
The Wallabies have arrived in Cessnock and will spend the week in camp before moving base to Penrith ahead of the Bledisloe Cup opener on August 19. 
A poor crowd is expected on the back of a tough year for Australian rugby, but Genia has urged fans to show their support because of the potential history that beckons. 
"Why wouldn't you want to be there?" he said. "Every chance that we get to play them is an opportunity to beat them which we haven't done in a long time. If we work hard and we get that done, you want to be there to witness that." 
And does Genia have any interest in trying out some of the fine wines the Hunter Region provides during the week?
"I don't drink mate," he joked. "The Coke Zero tastes the same." 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quade Cooper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Will Genia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Super Rugby</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Rugby Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rugbyheaven Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Genia</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stuart Walmsley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bledisloe Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New South Welshman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quadey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cheik</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Cheika</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wallabies</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Penrith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stade Francais</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Reds</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coke Zero</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Phipps</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cessnock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wallabies No</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter Region</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
