<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443499896161817</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Life Hacker</source>
  <url>https://www.lifehacker.com.au/2017/08/is-it-legal-to-encourage-suicide-in-australia/</url>
  <title>Is It Legal To Encourage Suicide In Australia?</title>
  <content>
Last June, a 17-year-old Massachusetts girl named Michelle Carter was convicted of involuntary manslaughter after repeatedly urging her boyfriend to commit suicide via text message. It was a landmark case in the US, with prosecutors successfully arguing that sometimes, words alone can be the deciding factor in a homicide case. But how do the laws work in Australia? Let's find out.

First, we should point out that this article does not relate to assisted suicide or euthanasia, which is something else entirely. Instead, we're focusing on the "reckless and wanton" encouragement of another's suicide (to use a phrase from the Carter case) with wilful disregard for their probable consequence.

There are no laws in Massachusetts specifically relating to one person encouraging another to commit suicide. However, in Australia, it is indeed a crime to incite another person to take their own life. As outlined in the :

(1) A person who aids or abets the suicide or attempted suicide of
another person is guilty of an offence punishable, on conviction, by
imprisonment for 10 years.
(2) If-
(a) a person incites or counsels another person to commit suicide;
and
(b) the other person commits, or attempts to commit, suicide as a
consequence of that incitement or counselling;
the firstmentioned person is guilty of an offence punishable, on
conviction, by imprisonment for 10 years.

This includes so-called "suicide pact", where two or more parties agree to end their lives but one survives for whatever reason. Some states go further, with prohibiting the sending of emails or text messages with the intention of causing the recipient to inflict self-harm. The Carter case would therefore have been less contentious here in Australia.

With that said, the prosecution would be to establish causation and context plays a big part. Repeatedly urging your mentally unstable boyfriend to kill himself could end in a conviction of up to ten years in prison. Yelling "kill yourself!" to a tail-gating motorist is definitely anti social, but not a jailable offence - even if they obliged you and drove off a cliff.

WATCH MORE: Travel Ideas

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATCH MORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carters</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Travel Ideas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Legal To Encourage Suicide In Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michelle Carter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Massachusetts</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
