<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443718939497637</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4839194/greens-launch-mayoral-tilt/?cs=305</url>
  <title>Greens launch mayoral tilt</title>
  <content>
Kick-start: Greens Newcastle lord mayoral candidate Therese Doyle, NSW Greens Hunter spokesperson David Shoebridge and council candidate Thomas Levick.

The impact of the November Supercars race and the truncation of the city's old heavy rail line are key examples of why Newcastle needs new leadership, Greens lord mayoral candidate Therese Doyle says.
Cr Doyle held a campaign "kick starter" at the Convict Lumber Yard in Newcastle's east end on Monday, where she appealed to residents who were dissatisfied with decisions from council and the state government in recent years.
She criticised council about a lack of community consultation as to whether the Supercars race should be held in Newcastle as well as the route of the track.
"This is an event that, I believe, many of the councillors are hoping will bring some good news for Newcastle," Cr Doyle said. 

"That's not what I have seen so far."

Greens member of the Upper House, David Shoebridge - also the party's Hunter spokesperson - said Newcastle could be "so much more than what the state government wants to make you".
"The Greens have a long history with Newcastle Council," he said.

"One of our first Greens councillors in NSW was elected right here.
"This is a precious part of the state with a deep and rich heritage - both natural and colonial."
Voters will go to the polls on September 9 for the local government elections.

Others in the race for the city's top job include sitting Labor lord mayor Nuatali Nelmes and independent candidate Kath Elliott.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Upper House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Doyle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November Supercars</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thomas Levick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Shoebridge</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nuatali Nelmes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kath Elliott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Greens Hunter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Convict Lumber Yard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Therese Doyle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greens Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
