<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443452651520660</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4839343/toronto-phoenix-smash-major-league-rivals/?cs=12&utm_source=latestnews&utm_medium=cpc&utm_campaign=Latest%20news%20traffic</url>
  <title>Toronto, Phoenix smash Major League rivals</title>
  <content>
NEWCASTLE Major League big guns Toronto and Phoenix Charlestown unleashed all of their firepower on Sunday.
Phoenix walloped White Sox 17-1 at Windsor Park while Toronto were even more destructive in belting Boomerangs 29-1 at Stevenson Park.

Moko Moanaroa
The Tigers jumped out of the blocks with 10 runs in the top of the second as Ben Reeves struggled for control, giving up eight walks and three hits and hitting a batter.
Mark Anderson came on and was more accurate, but the Toronto batters smashed him to all corners of the Mayfield West ballpark, belting 20 hits off his two and two-thirds innings.
Dillon McMaster's grand slam home run to left centre was the high point of the Tigers' 12-run mauling in the top of the fifth.
Moko Moanaroa was the only starter to not get a brace as Toronto tallied 26 hits. 
Mitchell Laird batted in Boomers' only run and collected two of their nine hits.
Phoenix were just as clinical against Sox, plating 17 runs from 17 hits.
Cameron Henderson continued his big-hitting form with three RBIs from a home run and a single. He belted four homers last week.
Jaron van Dyke drove in four and Josh Wingrove three as both collected two singles and a double.
Phoenix can join Toronto at the top of the table next week if they beat Belmont at Windsor Park on Sunday.
Toronto are leading the way with 10 wins and two losses but with a bye on Sunday cannot add to that tally.
Phoenix are next best with a 9-2 win-loss record, while a defeat on Sunday will almost certainly relegate Belmont (7-3) to a third-place finish.
Boomers (1-10) and Sox (1-11) are well out of finals contention but will have plenty to play for at Plattsburg Park as they both look to avoid the wooden spoon.
Meanwhile, Laird was the hero in second grade as Boomers handed Toronto their first loss for the season.
Laird secured a walk-off 11-10 win with a two-run single to left field in the bottom of the seventh.

The exciting finish gave the Boomers faithful something to cheer about on the club's Past, Present and Future Day.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toronto</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laird</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Anderson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Major League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mayfield West</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moko Moanaroa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NEWCASTLE Major League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitchell Laird</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dyke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dillon McMaster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Plattsburg Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Future Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RBIs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Wingrove</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PHOENIX</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Windsor Park</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron Henderson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jaron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stevenson Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belmont</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Reeves</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phoenix Charlestown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
