<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443710349562932</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/entertainment/confidential/glitter-strip-bare-gold-coast-news-and-gossip/news-story/29d1f5e987b9130d88977b7f1c832a19</url>
  <title>Yummy mummy joins campaign trail</title>
  <content>
LABOR has deployed a "yummy mummy" in a bid to unseat veteran Gold Coast MP Jann Stuckey.
Georgi Leader, a financial planner and attractive mum-of-two, is one of two glamour candidates unleashed by Labor on the Glitter Strip as the state election looms.
Good-looking Labor Left lawyer Meaghan Scanlon is also set to light up election placards in Gaven, which she will try to wrest from the LNP's embattled Sid Cramp.
The 30-something Leader will take on 62-year-old Stuckey in Currumbin, the Gold Coast's southernmost seat, which the latter has held since 2004 when she prised it from the disgraced Beattie government minister Merri Rose.
Stuckey, an at-times controversial Tourism and Commonwealth Games Minister in the Newman Government, holds Currumbin with a whopping 20.2 per cent margin.
But after gaining a 15 per cent swing at the 2015 election, Labor appears to be targeting the seat which has a strong Greens and working-class presence.

While governing from the Gold Coast last week, State Cabinet held a "town hall" meeting at Currumbin RSL and a candidate photo shoot and media conference at Currumbin Surf Club.
Currumbin-based green group the Gold Coast Hinterland and Environment Council (GECKO) got an early heads-up on the Government's shock decision to torpedo an integrated resort and casino planned for the Southport Spit.
Labor is obviously hoping the decision will win it some greenie points - not to mention votes - in Currumbin.
Leader stood unsuccessfully against another former Newman government minister Ros Bates in Mudgeeraba at the last election, while Scanlon mounted a failed challenge against scandal-prone ex-Turnbull government frontbencher Stuart Robert in Fadden at last year's federal poll.
Scanlon won a bruising factional battle over veteran campaigner Michael Riordan to narrowly gain party preselection for Gaven.
Meanwhile in Currumbin, voters have a choice of two fairly predictable campaign slogans: "Follow the Leader" or "Stick with Stuckey".LNP CRAMPING SID'S STYLE?
IT'S the whisper that won't go away.
Member for Gaven Sid Cramp has been in the firing line, with the LNP still yet to officially endorse him as its preferred candidate for the looming state election amid fears he is planning to defect to One Nation.
Two weeks ago, Cramp - the only LNP member yet to be ratified as the party's candidate for the poll showdown - was given a dressing-down by party heavyweights over a bizarre neighbourhood stoush caught on video.
It is understood Cramp filmed the whole exchange on his mobile phone, but so did his neighbours, which has left LNP officials worried.
Further fuelling their concern is the emergence of impressive Labor candidate for Gaven Meaghan Scanlon.
Cramp did little to shut the rumour of his defection down when we first raised it with him some months ago and he has not returned several calls from Glitter Strip Bare in recent weeks.MICK'S 'WHEELY' COME A LONG WAY
WHEN it comes to his surfing wheels, Mick Fanning has certainly come a long way from his days driving an old Ford Laser.
The Gold Coast-based surfing world champ will be pulling up at the beach in style after last week signing a sponsorship deal with Mercedes-Benz, which will see him promoting the luxury marque's new Marco Polo camper and X-Class ute.
It's a far cry from his first set of wheels, a Ford Laser - and the red Datsun his mum Liz famously used to drive him and his brothers to the surf in when he was a grommet.
Fanning was sponsored by Ford for several years, and even Porsche for a time, and the Mercedes deal is a step up in the pimped-ride stakes, befitting his multimillionaire status.
It was a big week for Fanning, with his induction alongside fellow surfing shark attack survivor Bethany Hamilton into the Surfing Hall of Fame in California.
He is now preparing for the next event on the World Surf League championship tour, the Billabong Tahiti Pro at the terrifying Teahupoo.CORBY OUT AND PROUD
SCHAPELLE Corby is becoming increasingly emboldened when it comes to getting out and about in public.
Just over two months since her dramatic return from Bali, when she was spirited back into Australia in a cloak-and-dagger security operation, the convicted drug smuggler is slowly but surely coming out of hiding back home on the Gold Coast.
She took to Instagram to post a picture of herself, sister Mercedes and some friends enjoying one of the Coast's most popular spots, Burleigh Hill, on Sunday evening.
The headland is packed with punters on Sundays, but Corby clearly had no qualms about being seen.
It can't be too long before she starts bobbing up in bars and nightclubs on the Glitter Strip, with her fans posing for the inevitable selfies with the "Ganja Queen", as she was dubbed by the Indonesians.'I DATED BETTY CUTHBERT'
THE death of athletics golden girl Betty Cuthbert brought back misty-eyed memories for veteran Gold Coast journo Ross Thompson.
Thompson, a former top TV reporter on the Coast, briefly dated Cuthbert back in the 1960s.
"I first met Betty a week after the end of the 1956 Olympic Games when, as a cadet journalist, I was sent to Macarthur Girls High School in Parramatta which honoured her with special mementos by the headmistress, Miss McCabe," he recalled.
"I was the only male among some 500 schoolgirls and teachers, and Miss McCabe highlighted it when she called me on stage and said: 'Look girls, this young man is from the Advertiser but doesn't he look like he is Betty's brother?'
"Betty and I became friends after that, and I visited the family home/nursery at Rydalmere on many occasions, both as a sports writer and socially.
"Four years later, Betty came to work as a receptionist at the Daily Mirror's Parramatta office and we went out several times before she became tired of the adulation and lack of privacy, prompting her decision to move to Perth.
"We met up twice more before she became reclusive and her carer banned any further contact from most people.
"That was a sad day, but today is worse for me - and I'm sure many, many more people, particularly journalists who met her. She treated us with respect and help."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympic Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Riordan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cuthbert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Betty</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LNP</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labor's Left</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indonesian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glitter Strip</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McCabe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgi Leader</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surfing Hall of Fame</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Mirror's Parramatta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Miss McCabe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ford Laser</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Merri Rose</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mercedes</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SCHAPELLE Corby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ros Bates</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>One Nation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LNP CRAMPING SID'S STYLE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DATED BETTY CUTHBERT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ross Thompson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Surf League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gaven Sid Cramp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Betty Cuthbert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burleigh Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macarthur Girls High School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geckos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Datsun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stuart Robert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Currumbin-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Cabinet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Currumbin RSL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fanning</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>X-Class</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stuckey</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mick Fanning</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fadden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gaven</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Games Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mudgeeraba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Teahupoo.CORBY OUT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beattie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Currumbin Surf Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bali</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glitter Strip Bare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rydalmere</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bethany Hamilton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parramatta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast MP Jann Stuckey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gaven Meaghan Scanlon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Porsche</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southport Spit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newman Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mercedes-Benz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Billabong Tahiti Pro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast Hinterland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Environment Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sid Cramp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Currumbin</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marco Polo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meaghan Scanlon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WHEELY' COME A LONG WAY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thompson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scanlon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
