<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443547140802941</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-07/star-dog-easton-wood-avoids-surgery-could-play-in-finals</url>
  <title>Star Dog avoids surgery, could play finals</title>
  <content>
Wood hamstrung early
Bulldog Easton Wood has left the ground clutching his left hamstring

Easton Wood has avoided surgery on his hamstring

WESTERN Bulldogs vice-captain Easton Wood has escaped surgery on his injured hamstring, but will be sidelined until at least the start of this year's finals series.

Wood injured his left hamstring in the first quarter of the Bulldogs' win over the Brisbane Lions at the Gabba on Saturday.

Bulldogs physio Chris Bell said Wood had suffered a 'high grade' hamstring tear, but the club is confident he can still play some part in the 2017 finals if the seventh-placed Bulldogs are to qualify.

"We've worked through a process which has included specialist opinion and we've decided that the best form of management will be conservative management, and that Easton does not require surgery," Bell told the club's website.

"We have started our rebab programming already and hope to have Easton running at the back end of this week."

Star defender Jason Johannisen, who was a late withdrawal ahead of the game against the Lions with hamstring tightness, is likely to be available for Friday night's massive clash against Greater Western Sydney.

"Jason is a real high speed athlete so we weren't prepared to take any risk with these symptoms so we withdrew him from the game," Bell said.

"JJ's come in really well today (Monday) and we'll work through a process with him this week to determine if he's available to play this weekend."

Dynamic forward Jake Stringer may also be passed fit if he gets through training this week.

Stringer has not played since injuring his hamstring against Carlton in round 17.

"Jake has continued to show great progress on his hamstring injury. He completed a game-like training session on the weekend and has pulled up really well," Bell said.

"If Jake ticks [the] boxes this week with training he'll be available to play."

However, a call on Tory Dickson, who reported quad tightness in the club's main training session on Thursday before the game against the Lions, will be made later in the week.

"We were forced to withdraw Tory from availability on the weekend... [he's] come in really well today though on our assessment and we'll go through a process this week to determine if he's back into full training and if he's able to play."

Mitch Honeychurch is also expected to be available after recovering from a facial infection.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JJ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stringer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gabba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greater Western Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Johannisen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Bell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldog Easton Wood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Easton Wood</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch Honeychurch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Easton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bell</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Star Dog</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Lions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tory Dickson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldogs</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake Stringer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
