<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443667399889316</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4839796/just-three-ambulances-left-to-cover-sydney-as-triple-0-calls-surge/?cs=7</url>
  <title>Just three ambulances left to cover Sydney as triple 0 calls surge</title>
  <content>
In the event of an emergency, the first thing a person does is ring triple zero and the voice on the other end of the line renders assistance and sends out help.

But, on Monday a number of people who rang triple zero for an ambulance found they were left without help.
Fairfax Media understands there were more than 30 outstanding triple zero jobs on Monday morning and more than 10 that were time-critical medicals.
At one stage, only three ambulances were available to cover Sydney for a brief time and some paramedics were asked to work overtime.
"NSW Ambulance experienced a surge in demand from 10am [Monday] morning with an increased number of triple zero (000) calls for assistance in the Sydney metropolitan area," a NSW Ambulance spokesperson said.
"We implemented standard surge procedures which proved effective in managing this demand,
"All staff across Local Health Districts and NSW Ambulance worked to transfer patients at emergency departments to enable paramedics to be released as soon as possible to respond to triple zero (000) calls."
NSW Ambulance put a call-out to their social media followers asking them to consider if their "urgency is an emergency".
"Pls Share Our Message: NSW Ambulance is experiencing a high volume of Triple Zero (000) calls today," the post said.
"We ask you to consider Is Your Urgency an Emergency? before calling for paramedic care. Unsure? Call us and our qualified Triple Zero call takers will get the right care for your condition."

NSW Ambulance said that the post was part of their annual winter campaign: "Is Your Urgency An Emergency?", aiming to educate the public about the clinical capability of the department and how patients can find the right care for their condition, which might not aways be an ambulance.
"While this increase in demand placed additional pressure on emergency departments and NSW Ambulance, ambulance paramedics were available to respond to medical emergencies," the spokesman said.
The spokesperson said winter was their busiest period.
Fairfax Media also understands that two special operations response team paramedics were taken away from the Wolli Creek crane incident to assist in the surge of triple zero calls.
The paramedics were brought in to assist and watch over Fire & Rescue NSW in the operation to remove the crane.
Gerard Hayes, from the Health Service Union, said paramedics are at breaking point and Monday's surge was the "worst in recent memory".
"Today firefighters were left exposed as specialist paramedics were called away to what should be routine jobs," he said.
"We also have the unacceptable situation where the public is being urged to avoid calling triple zero.
"Despite constant pleas to our political leaders, we are experiencing yet another day when the ambulance system is plunged into crisis," he said.

The story  first appeared on .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Local Health Districts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Urgency An Emergency</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Health Services Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Triple Zero (000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wolli Creek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Share Our Message</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Triple Zero</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rescue NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Ambulance</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gerard Hayes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
