<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443839198584015</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:39</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/news/politics/samesex-battle-goes-back-to-the-senate-20170807-gxr7gb</url>
  <title>No prospect of a free vote on same-sex marriage</title>
  <content>
The Coalition's same-sex marriage saga will continue until Christmas at least after a clear majority of Liberal MPs and Senators argued to either stick with the current policy of holding a plebiscite, or conduct a postal ballot to test the public mood, before having a Parliamentary vote.
The final policy decision should be resolved Tuesday when the Liberals and Nationals meet for their joint party room meeting to adopt a formal Coalition policy.
Either way, there is no prospect of moving directly to a free vote in Parliament as has been pushed publicly for the past week by five .
On Monday, a meeting of Liberal-only MPs and Senators agreed by a ratio of four-to-one to support in principle a cabinet proposal in which the government would put to the Senate once more the legislation to establish a national, compulsory plebiscite. Late last year, the Senate rejected such legislation.

In the likely event this legislation is rejected again, the next step would be to have a postal plebiscite which the government believes does not need legislation and says it has legal advice to back this.

If the postal vote supports same-sex marriage, there would be a parliamentary vote either just before or after Christmas. If the postal vote fails to support a change, it is unclear what would happen.
Sources said 27 or 28 Liberal MPs and Senators spoke in favour of either a plebiscite or postal ballot while just seven spoke in favour of a motion put by Senator Smith to abandon the plebiscite policy and moving straight to a free vote. These were the five rebels plus NSW MP John Alexander and Victorian MP Jason Wood.
The seven registered their support by a show of hands while there was no show of hands for those who wished to stick with some sort of plebiscite.
The Nationals are generally supportive of a postal vote rather than persisting with pushing the Senate for a plebiscite because, as one source said, we just want it off the agenda".

Former prime minister Tony Abbott was among a small group who argued that a postal ballot would not be authoritative. Signalling a split with key conservatives Peter Dutton and Mathias Cormann who developed the cabinet compromise, Mr Abbott contended the Coalition should stick with a plebiscite and persist for years if necessary.
to the Howard government trying more than 40 times over several years to have the Senate water down unfair dismissal protections for workers before finally doing so after it won control of the Senate at the 2004 election.
"We should have another go and if that fails, we should have another go," he said before the meeting.
He was backed by fellow NSW conservative Craig Kelly while moderates Julian Leeser and Russell Broadbent argued against a postal vote on the basis it may not survive a challenge by same-sex marriage advocates, who argue it needs legislation to appropriate the money to fund it.

But other conservatives said it was likely the Coalition would adopt the Cabinet proposal so long as "serious efforts" was made to secure Senate passage f the plebiscite legislation "rather than a step on the way to a postal vote".
Senator Cormann, the government's best Senate negotiator, told the party room meeting he would negotiate robustly with the Senate to try and effect a change of mind.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senators</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Dutton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russell Broadbent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian MP Jason Wood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW MP John Alexander</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Cormann</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julian Leeser</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mathias Cormann</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MPs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal-only MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Howard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
