<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443624450215662</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:49</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/victoria/police-review-could-unlock-20year-mystery-of-two-murdered-st-kilda-sex-workers-20170807-gxqsyt.html</url>
  <title>Police review could unlock 20-year mystery of two murdered St Kilda sex workers </title>
  <content>
Cold case detectives are taking a fresh look at the savage murders of two sex workers who were taken from the streets of St Kilda more than 20 years ago.
Reviews of the Amanda Byrnes and Samantha Mizzi cases could lead to $1 million rewards being posted for information on the murders, and forensic evidence being analysed for the first time.Photo: Michael Rayner
The reviews may also categorically rule out a single killer being responsible for the deaths, amid lingering concerns that this possibility had not been investigated.
Fairfax Media reported last month about , two of three unsolved murders involving St Kilda sex workers since 1991.

The families of both women were told within days of the article's publication that the cases were being reviewed.
Both victims were young mothers to infant children and worked the streets because of heroin addictions.

Cold case detectives confirmed the reviews but would not comment further.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Amanda's sister, Kerrie, still has many questions about the case.Photo: Chris Hopkins
"I welcome any new inquiry into my sister's murder and hope that it will expose and punish the monster who stole her life," she said.
"Amanda was a cherished and loved sister, mother, daughter and friend."Photo: Supplied
The Mizzi family also welcomed news of the review.
Ms Byrnes, 23, was killed on April 6, 1991. 
She had been working near the intersection of Carlisle and Foster streets when she accepted a job from a man in a white or cream Morris Minor panel van.
Just down the road from where she was picked up, several witnesses saw a woman's legs coming out the open passenger door of a van, which was being driven slowly but erratically.
It looked as if whoever was inside was trying to escape.
The van was seen soon after near Wattie Watson Oval in Elwood.
Ms Byrne's body was found there the next morning. 
She was naked, apart from a fingerless glove on her right hand, and had been ferociously beaten to death with a hand-held metal tool known as a wad cutter.
Byrnes had 16 separate injuries, including skull fractures, a broken jaw, and broken ribs.
Despite what was described by the homicide squad at the time as an "intense police investigation", and the detailed statements of several witnesses, nobody has been charged.
The car was found to be a cream or white Morris Minor panel van, of which about 1800 were registered in Victoria at the time.
The driver of a similar van seen in the area was described as being about 30, caucasian, with brown hair of about collar length, and a medium build and height.
One man also described the driver as "rough-looking".
Less than three years later, Ms Mizzi, 24, was working near the intersection of Inkerman Street and Brighton Road.
It was March 29, 1994.
About 11pm, Tiffany, another sex worker, was picked up by two young men and driven into a car park at the rear of an office building on Brighton Road.
As they got out of the car, Tiffany heard a "husky, deep breathing choking-type groan", and then found Ms Mizzi, barely alive in undergrowth.
She had been bashed with a blunt instrument so severely that parts of her skull were embedded in her brain.
She was naked, and none of her clothing or jewellery was ever found. She died in hospital the next day.
There were suspicions about a former partner, but police also questioned a known street crawler seen acting strangely in the area on the night of the murder.
Since 2014, when Victoria Police overhauled the system used to allocate rewards for unsolved crimes, about 20 cold case murders have been reviewed and allocated a $1 million reward.
Anyone with information about either case is urged to contact Crime Stoppers on 1800 333 000 or via crimestoppers.com.au
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Byrne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kerrie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 29, 1994</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Mizzi, 24</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Hopkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Inkerman Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Byrne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morris Minor</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Mizzi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samantha Mizzi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crime Stoppers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amanda Byrnes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tiffany</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wattie Watson Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Rayner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brighton Road</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mizzi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlisle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Byrnes, 23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amanda</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
