<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443542845835505</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/entertainment/celebrity-life/celebrity-selfies/justin-theroux-posts-sweet-photo-celebrating-second-wedding-anniversary-with-jennifer-aniston/news-story/10baa08b1c1fd60d72174a07cacbc45e</url>
  <title>Justin Theroux posts sweet photo celebrating second wedding anniversary with Jennifer Aniston</title>
  <content>
Jennifer Aniston &amp; Justin Theroux Are Married!
0:49

Jennifer Aniston and Justin Theroux have reportedly tied the knot after being engaged for three years. Sources say the wedding occurred in Jen's backyard with guests like Howard Stern, Chelsea Handler and Lisa Kudrow turning out for the fun.

August 7th 2015
2 years ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment - syndicated/

Justin Theroux posts a sweet anniversary message to Jennifer Aniston.

Share

IT'S been two years since Jennifer Aniston and Justin Theroux married in a top secret wedding ceremony at their Los Angeles mansion.
Since then, they've continually proven they're #ultimatecouplegoals. And on their second wedding anniversary, Theroux took the opportunity to celebrate the milestone with a super sweet photo - making us just a little bit jealous in the process.
Over the weekend, the 45-year-old actor posted a sweet snap of himself relaxing with his famous wife. In the pic - backlit with a rather angelic glow of sunlight - Aniston, 48, plants a kiss on her man's cheek.
Theroux captioned the moment with three simple emojis: A cupid's arrow, a love heart and the peace sign.

A post shared by @justintheroux on

Theroux frequently gushes about his relationship with the Friends star, telling Rhapsody magazine in April: "Marriage makes the small things much smaller and the big things small."
He added: "You have an ally. It's good to have someone have your back."
The two stars first started dating in 2011 before tying the knot in a top secret ceremony at their Bel Air pad in August 2015. Only a handful of their famous pals attended the intimate backyard affair, with Howard Stern, Chelsea Handler, Sia, Ellen DeGeneres and Lisa Kudrow on the guest list. Talk show host Jimmy Kimmel officiated, while Courteney Cox served as Jennifer's maid of honour.

Justin Theroux and Jennifer Aniston continually prove they are #couplegoals.Source:Getty Images
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getty Images</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jennifer Aniston</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Los Angeles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theroux</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jimmy Kimmel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rhapsody</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin Theroux Are Married</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin Theroux</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SIA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lisa Kudrow</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Howard Stern</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aniston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bel Air</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Courteney Cox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chelsea Handler</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ellen DeGeneres</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jennifer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
