<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443839198583933</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/07/17/54/bernadette-burns-brittney-dwyer-grandfather-murder-adelaide</url>
  <title>Queensland woman pleads guilty in murder of Adelaide grandfather</title>
  <content>
Partners in crime Bernadette Burns and Brittney Dwyer travelled from Brisbane to Adelaide to rob an elderly man of his life savings - but their plot ended in murder.
Burns on Monday joined Dwyer in admitting to the killing of Dwyer's grandfather, 81-year-old Robert Whitwell in his northern suburbs home.
The pair drove to Adelaide in August last year to rob Mr Whitwell, believing he kept hundreds of thousands of dollars stashed in a backyard shed.
Burns, 22, was due to stand trial in the Supreme Court on Monday but instead pleaded guilty to murder under an infrequently used section of South Australia's criminal code.
Dwyer pleaded guilty to a straightforward murder charge in September with the Supreme Court told last month that the killing of Mr Whitwell was "almost sociopathic in style".
Few details have been revealed, but prosecutor Jim Pearce said Dwyer entered the man's home wearing gloves and armed with the knife and there was an element of preparation, including the long drive.
Dwyer also told people in Brisbane that her grandfather "might have to die", the prosecutor said in sentencing submissions.

Related Articles

Mr Pearce objected to the proposed tendering of a psychiatric report prepared about Dwyer because it raised allegations that Mr Whitwell may have sexually abused her as a child.
He said the allegations were raised at "one minute to midnight" and in circumstances where Mr Whitwell was unable to defend himself.
"It's insidious that a man should have his reputation besmirched in that way," he said.
"It is just simply an invention to explain why she did what she did.
"The killing is almost sociopathic in style."
Defence counsel Craig Caldicott, said the issues raised in the report were not pressed by the defence and Dwyer was not sure herself whether her "flashbacks" were "real events or not".
Both Burns and Dwyer will return to court on August 29.
Another friend of Dwyer, Shelby Holmes, was last month given a nine-month suspended sentence after admitting to trespassing in Mr Whitwell's house several months before his death.
On that occasion, Holmes had also travelled with Dwyer to Adelaide with the intention of robbing Mr Whitwell but the pair had backed out.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bernadette Burns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dwyer</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Whitwell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shelby Holmes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jim Pearce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holmes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Pearce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Caldicott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Whitwell</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brittney Dwyer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Supreme Court</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
