<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443796248910238</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:29</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/news/victoria/ask-izzy-power-cards-relaunched-to-help-melbournes-homeless/news-story/17a08d9ba197c3a55bc74900aa44a221</url>
  <title>More women, children on city streets</title>
  <content>
DONATE TO ASK IZZY WITH A $15 POWER CARD

WOMEN and children fleeing domestic violence make up the fastest growing homeless demographic in Australia, according to new data.
And the number of older women who find themselves sleeping on the streets is also surging.
Homelessness experts kicked off Homelessness Week with a group panel discussion in Melbourne focused on technology-driven strategies to combat the country's rising number of rough sleepers.
Facilitated by Herald and Weekly Times chairman Penny Fowler and REA Group CEO Tracey Fellows, the panel relaunched the Ask Izzy powercard which enables those without access to power points to charge their mobile phone to find shelter, food and other vital services.
About 80 per cent of Australia's homeless population have a smartphone and support services are increasingly developing tech-based strategies to engage with and provide ongoing assistance to the homeless community.
David Spriggs, chief of Infoxchange, a not-for-profit company which developed the world first app, said online searches for shelter peaked at 11pm.
Online requests then shift toward finding food and blankets in the early hours of the morning.
Mr Spriggs said women and children escaping family violence were the largest and fastest growing homeless demographic.
"People experience mental health issues and Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islanders round out the top three groups of people (we engage with)," he said.
Launch Housing Deputy CEO Dr Heather Holst said Australia's property market was partly to blame for rising homelessness, particularly in youths.
"There has been pure population growth and a failure of our housing market to keep up," she said.
"There are now higher rents and its becoming more difficult for young people to get into mortgages.
"That means they have a lot more difficulty staying in or getting in. It's a competition situation."
Dr Holst said there had been a big rise in senior women living on the streets.
"They are very invisible in the homeless population," she added.
"If you haven't secured your own house and maybe there has been a divorce or maybe you never quite got out of renting, and as your ability to earn wanes you are on your own. It's grim."

The campaign, which was launched in December last year, generated $174,000 in donations which was used to distribute more than 120,000 Ask Izzy battery recharge cards.
Ms Fellows encouraged Victorians to dig deep to help improve lives on the street.
"So much of what we do is about property and the importance of having a home, but we also recognise that not all of us have the privilege of having a roof over our head each night," she said.
"While homelessness exists all year round, it's important to have a dedicated week where we discuss the issue and continue to raise awareness - in the workplace, around the dinner table, and in the wider community."
The Ask Izzy app was developed in partnership with News Corp Australia, Google and the REA Group.
The easy-to-use directory provides users access to thousands of nearby support services including crisis accommodation, food, showers, financial and legal help and is free to use through the Telstra network.
"Homelessness can happen to anyone. No one should be without a home," Ms Fowler said.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>REA Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Weekly Times</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ask Izzy</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Spriggs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Infoxchange</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REA Group CEO Tracey Fellows</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Homelessness Week</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Telstra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Torres Strait Islander</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Spriggs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Housing Deputy CEO Dr Heather Holst</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Holst</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Fellows</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aboriginal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Penny Fowler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Fowler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Google</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASK IZZY WITH A $15 POWER CARD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
