<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444182795973666</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:59</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/western-australia/bruce-rock-child-sex-accused-in-court/news-story/58274f2790c12f74e70aaeab41a5cd06</url>
  <title>Bruce Rock child sex accused in court</title>
  <content>
A THREE-YEAR-OLD girl was sleeping next to her brother in a Bruce Rock donga when a stranger broke in and offered them lollies before repeatedly sexually assaulting her, a jury has been told.
The girl's mother, who was in bed in an adjoining donga with her partner, heard noises coming from the room where her children were sleeping in the early hours of the morning in May last year.
Thinking their children had just woken up early, the woman and her partner went back to sleep after he banged on the wall and told them to go back to bed.
But they realised something more sinister had happened when the man checked on his children in the morning and found a cigarette and lollies in their room.
Merredin man Philip Arthur Dalton was in the area on the night and admits he stole frozen food and a freezer bag from a fridge near the donga.
Police say he is the person who went into the children's room and assaulted the girl but Mr Dalton has pleaded not guilty to three child sex offences.
Addressing the jury during Mr Dalton's District Court trial today, defence lawyer Simon Freitag described the case as every parent's worst nightmare.
He told the jurors there were two questions that needed to be answered: what happened in the donga and who did it?
"Keep your eyes and ears open for anyone else who might be connected to this offending," Mr Freitag said.
The children's father was in Bruce Rock for work and his family travelled to the area to spend the night with him.
They watched movies and ate pizza before the children went to sleep in one donga and their parents went to bed next door.
In her recorded interview with police, the three-year-old spoke about an angry man or angry bird who came into her room during the night.
"That naughty angry bird," she said.
"The angry bird offered me lollies and then angry bird that say shut up.
"They come in and sit on my bed and him had shoes, shoes on and him cuddle me."
Her older brother told police he did not want to eat the lollies because they were poisonous but said his sister ate them.
The boy described hearing the man whisper a secret into his sister's ear.
"I could keeping an eye on her," he said.
"I couldn't yell out because I knew he was going to do that to me."
The prosecutor told the court Mr Dalton had been drinking at a friend's house before he went wandering around Bruce Rock.
He said Mr Dalton saw an opportunity and did something he might not have done in the "cold, harsh light of day".
"It seems to be an offence of opportunity more than anything," the prosecutor said.
The trial continues.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Dalton</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruce Rock</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Merredin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>THREE-YEAR-OLD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Freitag</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Dalton's District Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon Freitag</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philip Arthur Dalton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
