<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443976637539741</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/07/18/40/entertainment-legend-maria-venutis-fight-to-get-back-on-her-feet-after-stalker-induced-stroke</url>
  <title>Doing it her way: Entertainment legend Maria Venuti</title>
  <content>
Iconic Aussie entertainer Maria Venuti is still in fine voice after suffering a "catastrophic" stroke last November.
The actress and singer was confronted by a male stalker at her home and suffered a stroke afterwards.
A 38-year-old man carrying flowers was arrested fleeing the property at the time.
Since then, Maria and her family have been focusing on getting well - and A Current Affair can reveal just how far she's come.
"They said it was one of the most catastrophic strokes they have ever seen," daughter Bianca said.
"At the beginning, the neurosurgeon said she would need a feeding tube (and) she may be in a bed in a nursing home for the rest of her life."
However, Venuti's family knew all too well the 75-year-old wouldn't give up.

Related Articles

"I said, can I quote you on that when she is better in six months, and they said 'please do'," Bianca said.
"I said don't worry, you don't know my mum and what she's capable of."
In her treatment at the Mount Wilga Rehabilitation Hospital, Venuti has been supplementing her efforts to re-learn how to speak with some spontaneous singing.
She suffered significant damage to the left side of her brain from the stroke, but the singing is helping to stimulate the creative hemisphere of her brain.
Although it will be a long road back, the Venuti family are celebrating every victory.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bianca</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maria Venuti</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Wilga Rehabilitation Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Current Affair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Venuti</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
