<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444010997278804</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/federal-politics/political-opinion/samesex-marriage-same-problem-malcolm-turnbull-fails-to-resolve-crisis-20170807-gxr814.html</url>
  <title>Same-sex marriage, same problem: Solution eludes Malcolm Turnbull</title>
  <content>
It was the special party room meeting called to fix Malcolm Turnbull's "special" problem.
A desperate search by a riven government for unity on an issue about which most electors are unfazed, but which has had party room ideologues threatening civil war and defection.Photo: Andrew Meares
Instead of progress however, it has achieved little, merely kicking the can down the road while underlining Malcolm Turnbull's authority deficit, and highlighting his well-recognised authenticity problem. The quintessential damp squib.
Turnbull's tremulous leadership is daily reinforcing the adage that its better to die on your feet than live on your knees.Photo: Richard Wainwright
Locked into policy prescriptions of his unpopular predecessor, and thus locked into the unpopularity of his predecessor also, Turnbull keeps choosing the latter. He keeps opting for peace today ahead of the legitimising fight he must eventually face.
Turnbull courts the footlights of moderate leadership but his government casts the shadow of an ideological Tony Abbott.

The Prime Minister is no doubt frustrated that outsiders fail to appreciate the depth of feeling within his party, and the unique complexity of his dilemma.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

But voters are simply not interested - especially those directly effected by a discrimination on marriage law that has been less controversially swept away in comparable countries.
It wasn't for these voters anyway that he parked his stated support for marriage reform. That was ambition pure and simple.
The best result for Turnbull was for resolution. But he never asserted his will. Never took the risk. Thus, he has ensured only that the focus on same sex marriage will continue to dominate his distracted administration. That it will go on obliterating other issues and fanning divisions, while MPs remain blithely indifferent to the ongoing insult to voters who, through their sexuality, are denied a basic, but crucial social recognition.
This issue had been disastrously mismanaged by the Abbott government and then needlessly gaffer-taped in that dysfunction by its successor.
There will be a renewed focus on the issue before the Senate vote, and that will probably intensify as the contingent stages play out.
Focus group research published on Monday by Fairfax Media framed the problem chillingly: Turnbull is a disappointment, a leader in name rather than function.
Yet quantitative polling also shows hope. He is still preferred prime minister and doubtless remains the government's best asset.
But for how much longer, as voters increasingly ask: what does he stand for?
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Meares</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Wainwright</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
