<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443753299236573</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4838643/ipri-event-in-wollongong-to-celebrate-science-week/?cs=12</url>
  <title>IPRI event in Wollongong to celebrate Science Week</title>
  <content>
Professor Gordon Wallace
The talented researchers at the Intelligent Polymer Research Institute (IPRI) at the University of Wollongong's Innovation Campus will open their labs to the public on August 17 to celebrate .
director Professor Gordon Wallace said the IPRI Open Day was an important way for the community to learn about the ground breaking scientific research being undertaken at IPRI.
"We are all conscious as scientists that it is our community that we are working for, so it is important to open our doors to let people have a look at what is happening right on their doorstep,'' Prof Wallace said.
"We are the headquarters for a national research centre that is globally connected. There are many opportunities for established, emerging and new commercial enterprises to benefit from this, and in turn our community will benefit through the creation of the jobs of the future.''
People are encouraged to come and meet the brilliant minds behind the soft robotic prosthetic hand, stem cell research, nerve and muscle regeneration projects, the Bionic Bra and the Biopen.
Visitors can tour the world class lab facilities and learn from friendly researchers about their cutting-edge technologies. Half hour tours will operate between 9am and 4pm.
Bookings are essential at .

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Intelligent Polymer Research Institute</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Wollongong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Innovation Campus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IPRI</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bionic Bra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Gordon Wallace</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prof Wallace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Biopen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IPRI Open Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Science Week</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
