<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444053946952469</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-07/steve-fesus-called-pizza-shop-after-wife-disappeared/8782668</url>
  <title>Steve Fesus called pizza shop and woman after wife went missing, a NSW court hears</title>
  <content>
A man accused of killing his wife and burying her body in a shallow beach grave made three phone calls the day he claimed she went missing, one to a pizza shop and two to a woman he allegedly had an affair with, a jury has heard.
Steve Frank Fesus, 46, has gone on trial in the NSW Supreme Court for the murder of Jodie Melissa Fesus in August 1997.
The body of the 18-year-old mother of two was found on Seven Mile Beach on the New South Wales south coast after an anonymous man called police with a tip-off.
Mr Fesus has pleaded not guilty, but the Crown says the security guard strangled his wife to death.
In his opening address, Crown Prosecutor Greg Smith told the jury Steve and Jodie Fesus' marriage was dysfunctional, unhappy and at times violent.
He said Ms Fesus had confided in a friend she thought her husband was having an affair and said "I've had enough, I'm leaving him".
The court was told the couple had a heated argument at the home of friends on August 11, 1997 - the last time anyone but Mr Fesus would see Ms Fesus alive.
"The accused was fuming for the rest of the evening and he was still fuming when they left [the friends' house] that night," Mr Smith said.
"It is the Crown case that the accused strangled and killed the deceased, then transported her body to Seven Mile Beach in the family vehicle and buried her body in a shallow grave, sometime between 9:00pm on the 11th of August and 5:30am the 12th of August."
Phone call placed to pizza shop

On August 12, the friends who witnessed the argument phoned and then dropped around to the Fesus' Shellharbour home to check if everything was OK.
It is alleged Mr Fesus said his wife had gone missing and the friends asked if he had called anyone, to which he replied he had called his mother.
Mr Smith told the court that was incorrect.
"The first phone call was to Pizza World at 6:33pm that evening and the second one was to [a female work colleague] at 7:40pm, then there was another call to her at 9:47pm," Mr Smith said.
"The accused made no attempt to contact any of the deceased's relatives."
Mr Smith said Mr Fesus waited until the following day to contact his wife's family or report her missing to police.
It is alleged he went to the police station a second time the day after that, with the female work colleague, to report he thought his wife may have been back to the house because he found a packed bag with some of her belongings.
The Crown said Mr Fesus and the woman then "went to Lake Illawarra foreshore car park and became intimate".
Court hears of days after Ms Fesus' disappearance

The court was told that not long after Ms Fesus disappeared, Mr Fesus asked one of her friends what he should do with her clothes.
"The deceased had only been missing for a period of two days ... his intention to give her clothes away within two days, indicates he knew she would not be returning or would not need her clothes or other belongings," Mr Smith said.
The court heard that on August 25, Mr Fesus went to find out if he could begin claiming the sole parent pension.
Mr Smith said the public servant who served Mr Fesus asked, "Is the other parent still living?"
"[The public servant said] the accused ticked the 'no' box indicating the other parent was deceased and when [the public servant] questioned him the accused said 'oh' and then ticked the yes box.
"At this point the accused became flustered and didn't know what to do next."
The jury was told the body of Ms Fesus was discovered almost three weeks later.
Mr Smith said as well as circumstantial evidence, they would hear direct evidence that Mr Fesus confessed to an undercover police officer in July 2013 that "he killed Jodie and buried the body".
The Crown will continue opening its case tomorrow. The defence will then open its case.
The trial before Justice Peter Johnson is expected to last eight weeks.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jodie Melissa Fesus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New South Wales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pizza World</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Smith</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 1997</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Fesus</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seven Mile Beach</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Frank Fesus, 46</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Fesus</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Fesus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Supreme Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 2013</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 12</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown Prosecutor Greg Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jodie Fesus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jodie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fesus' Shellharbour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake Illawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justice Peter Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
