<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444139846300013</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/07/19/16/myer-shops-back-in-time-with-australia-lives-here</url>
  <title>Myer Bourke Street</title>
  <content>
Not many people can say they've clung onto a childhood toy for more than half a century - but in the case of Pauline Renzow, her vintage Barbie has been by her side since 1962.
It was a gift for her 8th birthday.
"She was the new toy that every girl wanted then. I was so rapt to get her," Ms Renzow said.
And now, the iconic doll - along with the original box she came in - is on display in an exhibition that's as Aussie as they come.
'Australia Lives Here' is the newest campaign from Myer - and it features 100 of the most memorable items that have been sold over the past 100 years.
From the first vacuum cleaner, to the first television - and everything in between - the collection is a celebration of memories created across the ages.
"There aren't many retailers that have been in existence for 100 years so we thought it was time to celebrate," Myer's marketing manager, Mike Scott said.

Related Articles

Historian Stella Barber helped curate the exhibition.
She had the task of narrowing down ten decades worth of items, down to the 100 on display.
"Things are very disposable and a lot of people have cleanouts, but a lot of these things are coming to the fore," Ms Barber said.
But the collection isn't complete.
There are 70 pieces currently on show - so curators are calling on the public to fill in the gaps, and submit a story along with their well-kept treasures.
"For example the Speedo bathers. They remember with fondness their dad wearing his old maroon bathers, and having a dig at him, but celebrating the fact they've survived," Ms Barber said.
Other items on the hit list include a 1940's Sunbeam Mixmaster, hotpants from the 70's, an original Sony Walkman, and a Coolgardie Safe from the 1900's.
And, if you manage to dig up one of these old relics - there's a good reward.
Successful applicants will win the modern day equivalent of .
In the case of the Coolgardie Safe - the contributor will walk away with a brand new fridge.
"We might get multiple entries around one particular product, and the winning prize will be the story which is the most powerful and the most emotive," Mr Scott said.
The exhibition is on display at Myer's Bourke Street store until mid-September.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sony Walkman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia Lives Here</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barbie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Renzow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Myer Bourke Street</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Scott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Myers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Renzow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mike Scott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Barber</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Speedo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunbeam Mixmaster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coolgardie Safe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stella Barber</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
