<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444096896626297</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/07/18/42/inside-victorias-adult-parole-board-brett-mcleod</url>
  <title>Inside Victoria</title>
  <content>
"Out of touch"..."soft on criminals"... "they should all be sacked".
Those are just some of the comments directed at Victoria's Adult Parole Board in recent years.
Tensions ran especially high after the murder of Jill Meagher, when it was revealed the man who killed her, Adrian Earnest Bayley, was on parole at the time.
There were other cases of appalling crimes committed by parolees.
Far from being out of touch, one woman on the Parole Board then knew more about what it was like to be a victim of crime than most, Carmel Arthur.
In 1998, she was Carmel Miller. Her husband, Rodney, was a policeman and they had just welcomed their baby boy into the world.
Then, in one of the most shocking crimes in Victoria Police history, Rodney and his partner Gary Silk were murdered while on patrol.

Related Articles

Ms Arthur had no soft spot for criminals when she joined the Adult Parole Board nine years ago. She assumed everyone in jail must be there because they're bad.
Over time, her views have evolved.
Some people have backgrounds that have left her "gobsmacked".
The man whose parents gave him a special gift for his 10th birthday: his first hit of heroin.
Another whose Dad made him watch while a "friend" raped his mother, before she ended up killing her husband.
Ms Arthur understands why some people turn to crime.
"And there are some people who should stay in jail for a very, very long time," she added.
When deciding who should get parole, Ms Arthur told 9NEWS she agonizes over every decision.
Her guiding principle is "How would I explain that to a victim of crime? How would it make me feel?"
At times she speaks with the vulnerability of someone who has suffered one of the worst imaginable losses.
Yet when talking of the conditions those granted parole must meet, she has the authority of a prison warden.
"If you don't do what you're told, we will cancel you," she said.
Former Judge Peter Couzens took over the Parole Board with one central purpose, to restore public confidence.
Part of that mission is to be more open, such as the interviews they granted to 9NEWS.
But it is results which matter most.
Changes instituted since the Callinan Review - better resourcing, more sitting days, fewer parolees in the community - appear to be working.
The year after Jill Meagher's murder the number of men on parole who committed serious violent or sexual offences was 60. This year it is five.
After nine years and three terms on the Parole Board, Ms Arthur is about to step down.
The lesson she's learned: "Unless you address drug addiction and mental health and homelessness, you will not quell the number of victims in our community."
And if anyone knows about criminals and victims, it's her.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gary Silk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carmel Arthur</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carmel Miller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria's Adult Parole Board</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Callinan Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adrian Earnest Bayley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parole Board</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jill Meagher</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judge Peter Couzens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rodney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Arthur</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adult Parole Board</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
