<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444225745647381</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/07/19/55/slain-queensland-mother-knew-her-killer--police-say</url>
  <title>Slain Queensland mother</title>
  <content>
Police believe slain mother-of-two Donna Steele knew the person who killed her and dumped her body in a remote creek in Queensland's north.
The body of Ms Steele, 42, was found at the popular fishing spot of Leggett's Crossing, north of Cooktown, yesterday morning.
Her death is now being treated by homicide detectives as a murder.
Detective Inspector Geoff Marsh said police were "confident" the killer was known to Ms Steele, but they have not yet identified a suspect.
"There's nothing to suggest it's a random attack ... we're confident this is a known person to her," he said.
Det. Insp. Marsh said Ms Steele was last seen on Wednesday at about midday at the town's IGA supermarket, but that they were trying to piece together her movements afterwards.
He said she was reported missing on Thursday by her partner when he returned from working away from the coastal community.

Related Articles

"Upon his arrival home the absence of the mother of the two children was of great concern to him and he made a report to the police," Det. Insp. Marsh said
The father is now caring for their two boys, aged eight and 10, while helping police with their inquiries.
Det. Insp. Marsh said four crime scenes had been established in the region, and police were taking statements.
State Emergency Services (SES) volunteers today scoured the banks of the creek.
Police divers from the state's south east - where Ms Steele is originally from - also conducted a search of the waterway.
No weapon has been found, and detectives would not confirm reports her body was wrapped up.
An autopsy of Ms Steele's body will be conducted tomorrow.
With AAP
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cooktown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iGA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Steele</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leggett's Crossing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Emergency Service</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SES</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marsh</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donna Steele</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DET</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insp</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Detective Inspector Geoff Marsh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
