<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444139846300016</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/news/northern-territory/katherine-man-earns-big-payout-after-accidently-betting-600-on-race-at-darwin-cup/news-story/3826d0f67a814a94bfd777540ebc7e10</url>
  <title>Accidental punt pays off for Cup racegoer</title>
  <content>
A HUNGOVER punter at yesterday's 2017 Carlton Mid Darwin Cup is counting his lucky stars after accidentally betting $600 instead of $60 on a horse and taking home a whopping $1220.
Steve Budarick of Katherine hit the Darwin Casino a little too hard on Sunday night before making an appearance at the popular race meet.
"The bet was a bit of an accident but it was probably the wisest thing I have ever done," he said.
"I've got an account here and when I was placing the bet I ended up lingering too long on the zeros and accidentally bet $600 instead of $60.
"It wasn't really part of the plan but $1200 will well and truly cover the weekend and more - it's been a great 48 hours.
"You could say I accidentally put the icing on the cake."
Mr Budarick joined 19,402 other racegoers from all over the country and overseas to place bets on the 85 runners across nine races at the Darwin Turf Club's hugely-popular annual Picnic Day race meet.
Thoroughbred Racing Northern Territory chief executive Andrew O'Toole said this year's Cup Carnival was once again a resounding success, bringing in over a whopping $30 million to the local economy.
"All the retailers call it Christmas in July - the hats and clothes sales, hair, fingernails, restaurants and the cabs - it's definitely a great boost to the economy here in Darwin," he said.
"The Cup is going from strength to strength and the Carnival is just getting bigger, better and stronger and the money of course that it brings to the economy is not to be underestimated."
Punter Richard Simon of Melbourne made the trek up to the NT for this year's Cup to celebrate his birthday, along with his twin brother who lives in Darwin.
"It's a bucket list thing for me to come to the Darwin Cup - I came up here on Sunday night for some sun and met up with my twin brother," he said.
"We'll have a bet in each race and make sure we have a drink or two in between - what better way to celebrate our birthday."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carnival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton Mid Darwin Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin Casino</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Budarick of Katherine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Budarick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew O'Toole</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cup Carnival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Simon of Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin Turf Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thoroughbred Racing Northern Territory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Picnic Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
