<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444139846300057</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-07/call-for-lords-prayer-to-be-dumped-from-tasmanian-parliament/8782684</url>
  <title>Greens call for daily Lord's Prayer to be dumped from Tasmanian Parliament</title>
  <content>
The Tasmanian Greens will push to have the Lord's Prayer removed from parliamentary proceedings when changes to Standing Orders are debated this week.
Greens leader Cassy O'Connor said the party would move an amendment that instead asked members to pray or reflect on their responsibilities as parliamentarians.
"The days have long passed that the Lord's Prayer should be recited every sitting day," she said.
"There's a very strong argument in 2017 to make sure that Parliament reflects the diversity of the Tasmanian community, the diversity of faith and spirituality."
Tasmanian parliamentary records show the Lord's Prayer has been recited at the start of each sitting day since at least 1930 and has been part of the Standing Orders since 1937.
"We're not saying that members shouldn't be given the opportunity to pray each morning when Parliament sits, but what we should be praying for or reflecting on is that we fulfil our duties to the people of Tasmania," Ms O'Connor said.
The Greens also called for Tasmania's first people to be acknowledged at the start of each sitting day instead of only at the start of a new parliamentary session.
"What we should be doing each day of the Parliament is acknowledge we're standing on the land of the Mouheneener people," she said.
"At the moment the Parliament pays lip service to the first people."
Opposition Leader Rebecca White said Parliament should not reflect just one religion.
"My personal view is that a modern parliament should be respectful to the traditional owners of the land and that we should be respectful to all religious beliefs," she said.
Pollies need 'all the help they can get'

Mark Brown from The Australian Christian Lobby said it was an important tradition.
"The teachings of Jesus, the words of Jesus, have had an incredible impact in Australian culture, and it's the basis of our legal system, our political system, and therefore it's just appropriate that we honour the traditions by saying the Lord's Prayer in Parliament," he said.
"Obviously, we are asking for God's help in the Lord's Prayer and I think everyone would agree our parliamentarians can use all the help they can get."
Anglican Bishop of Tasmania Richard Condie said the prayer should stay.
"Regardless of your personal beliefs, Australian laws and society are based on Christian values and a Christian framework, and the Lord's Prayer acknowledges and expresses those values and framework," he said.
Premier Will Hodgman said removing the Lord's Prayer was not a priority for the Government.
The Greens made a .
In the latest census .

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms O'Connor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anglican Bishop of Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cassy O'Connor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mouheneener</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leader Rebecca White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Standing Orders</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jesus</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>God</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Christian Lobby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian Parliament</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Will Hodgman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lord's Prayer</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian Greens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Condie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
