<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443839198583980</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4838647/drugged-nowra-truckies-who-drive-together-go-to-court-together/?cs=300</url>
  <title>'Drugged' Nowra truckies who drive together go to court together</title>
  <content>
'Drugged' Nowra truckies who drive together go to court together

Police speak with the drivers of two trucks, both from Nowra, beside the Sturt Highway at Hay. Officers had pulled over the first truck for a compliance check, prompting the second driver to stop. Picture: Facebook / Traffic and Highway Patrol Command - NSW Police Force

Police said both drivers tested positive to cannabis and methamphetamine. Picture: Facebook / Traffic and Highway Patrol Command - NSW Police Force

Items found in both trucks. Picture: Facebook / Traffic and Highway Patrol Command - NSW Police Force

Items found in both trucks. Picture: Facebook / Traffic and Highway Patrol Command - NSW Police Force

Items found in both trucks. Picture: Facebook / Traffic and Highway Patrol Command - NSW Police Force

exit

Two Nowra truck drivers were allegedly driving drugged when stopped by police on a highway in south-western NSW at the weekend. 
The first driver was pulled over on the Sturt Highway near Hay about 1am on Saturday. 
Police said the 43-year-old man, from Nowra, tested positive to cannabis and methamphetamine.

A search of the truck located of 1.6 grams of methamphetamine, half a gram of cannabis and glass pipes.

At the same time, another heavy vehicle stopped nearby because its driver knew the man being spoken to by officers.

Police spoke to the driver of the second truck, a 32-year-old man also from Nowra.

The second driver also tested positive to methamphetamine and a search of his truck located half a gram of cannabis and half a gram of methamphetamine and glass pipes.

Both drivers were taken to Hay police station for oral fluid tests. Both failed and they were banned from driving for 24 hours.

They will face Hay Local Court at a later date.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hay</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nowra</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sturt Highway</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Police Force</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hay Local Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Highway Patrol Command</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
