<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443714644530289</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/news/not-in-my-wildest-dreams-antibank-mps-weigh-in-on-cba-scandal-20170807-gxquqy</url>
  <title>'Not in my wildest dreams': anti-bank MPs weigh in on CBA scandal</title>
  <content>
The  has bolstered the case for a royal commission into the financial sector, banking crusader and Nationals Senator John "Wacka" Williams says.
Senator Williams told The Australian Financial Review he had not thought "in my wildest dreams" that the alleged misconduct at CBA would have been possible. 
"Unfortunately a lot of the news we get out of banks is not good news and adds to the call for a royal commission," said Senator Williams, who has championed the need for a sweeping probe into white collar crime for seven years.
Asked whether embattled CBA chief executive Ian Narev should go, Senator Williams said he was entitled to the presumption of innocence but it was up to the board to settle his fate.

"The buck always stops with the boss," he said.

"If one of my staff did something wrong with one of my travel claims, that's my responsibility. If someone fails to update software, it still comes back to Mr Narev as boss."
And as well as , Labor will grill Mr Narev when bank bosses next front the House of Representatives economics committee in October.
Labor committee member, WA MP Matt Keogh, said the allegations against the CBA reinforced the need for senior executives to be held personally liable for deficiencies in upholding anti-money laundering and terrorism financing laws.
"It's not acceptable to hide behind the corporate veil of the bank, which cops the fine," he said.

The Greens Treasury spokesman Peter Whish-Wilson said the case highlighted cultural problems in the industry, urging the bank's board to consider Mr Narev's position and axe senior staff bonuses.  
Senator Whish-Wilson was concerned bonuses for branch managers may have been tied to the uptake of the intelligent deposit machines used by criminals
Royal commission resisted

But NSW Liberal MP Craig Kelly said while it appeared the CBA thought it could operate above the law, he did not believe a royal commission was necessary.

"They will have to answer for what they have done and face a very significant and heavy fine," he told the ABC.
"I'm not sure a royal commission would change that."
Australian Bankers' Association chief Anna Bligh maintained a royal commission was unwarranted.
"There is no doubt these are very serious allegations and I think that all Australians want to see their banking system not only strong but safe and protected against people who want to do the wrong thing," she said.

"I am, however, comforted by the fact that the regulator in this case has clearly had sufficient powers to gather the evidence they believe to take the matter to court."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nationals Senator John</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Williams</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anna Bligh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA MP Matt Keogh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Narev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Narev</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>House of Representatives</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wacka</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Bankers' Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-0.67</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Whish-Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greens Treasury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>William</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBA</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-12</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Liberal MP Craig Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Whish-Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
