<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443925097931329</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/sport/basketball/adelaide-coach-joey-wright-says-us-imports-bring-valuable-experience-as-preseason-training-begins/news-story/b3823323045edccb95762d066f17a557</url>
  <title>Sixers boosted by experience</title>
  <content>
ADELAIDE coach Joey Wright believes the 36ers have "ticked all the boxes" and added valuable experience to their squad which reported for the start of pre-season training yesterday.
The club has lost Terrance Ferguson to the NBA and reigning league MVP Jerome Randle but added US imports Ramone Moore and Shannon Shorter, both aged 28, and Ronald Roberts, 26.
"We have a defensive presence we think we need, the offensive guns out there on the court and leadership," Wright said.
"Last year we didn't have the finances to bring in guys with experience, we had to bring in guys who were early (in their careers), but this year we have brought in guys who have played some big-time basketball."
The Sixers squad yesterday reported for its first official day of pre-season training, minus the imports who are yet to arrive and Mitch Creek and Matthew Hodgson, who are with the Boomers for the Asia Cup starting tonight.
Adelaide guard Nathan Sobey is being eased into training as he recovers from a groin injury which hampered his training camps with NBA clubs and forced him to miss Boomers selection.
Sobey trained with Utah, Brooklyn, Minnesota and LA Clippers in the off-season and said he could still take confidence from the experience.
"I really enjoyed that, I got to test myself to see where I was at," Sobey said.
"Unfortunately circumstances when it came to the summer league - I went down with a little injury and wasn't fit to play a lot - but that's the way it goes.
"I'll rest up and get ready for this season. . . it will be more a mental thing - stepping up and taking that leadership role a bit more than just playing.
"Trying to teach the young guys what we're about in Adelaide and what we're trying to build."
The Boomers are in Lebanon preparing for their Asia Cup opener against Japan on August 8.
They then play Hong Kong and Chinese Taipei before the quarter-finals start on August 17.
All Australian NBL clubs are represented in the 12-man team.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese Taipei</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sobey</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian NBL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MVP Jerome Randle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BROOKLYN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Hodgson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Sobey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lebanon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hong Kong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ronald Roberts, 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sixers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia Cup</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch Creek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Utah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terrance Ferguson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ramone Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wright</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joey Wright</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minnesota</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shannon Shorter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LA Clippers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
