<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444139846300029</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/lifestyle/food/qld-taste/ekka-2017-the-culinary-history-of-the-ekka/news-story/19c9f4af03175bf6683679ad70af97c8</url>
  <title>The culinary history of the Ekka</title>
  <content>
FROM Butter Board sandwiches to the CWA's Devonshire tea, food has always been an essential part of the Royal Queensland Show. Take a look back at the culinary history of the Ekka.
1870s
For the second annual Exhibition in 1877, three refreshment booths were built to feed the masses that attended the show. One seated 300, another 200 and the third was the temperance booth. However, demand far outweighed supply with not enough food to go around. Documents at the time declared "caterers were taxed to the utmost".
What was on offer, though, was quite the feast with breakfast consisting of chops, steaks, cold joints and "made dishes" for one shilling and sixpence. At lunch it was poultry, ham, tongue, lamb, pork, beef and mutton accompanied by salads and mashed potato with an ale or porter. While at the alcohol-free temperance booth, patrons could choose from ham and beef sandwiches, sausage rolls, mutton pies, bread and cheese, and drinks, such as ginger beer, sarsaparilla, lemonade and tea and coffee. For dessert it was doughnuts, jelly and ice cream, fruit and pastries.
In 1879 an oyster stall was build to showcase the state's fishing industry.
1880s
Show organisers introduced catering regulations governing who had the right to sell food and drinks at the grounds. A "refreshment committee" specified the content and prices of breakfast, lunch, tea and drinks. Patrons would pay nine shillings for a large bottle of claret, 15 shillings for an "extra quality" bottle of champagne and one shilling for a small beer.
The vendors who had bid successfully to sell food and drinks included businesses, plus voluntary organisations, such as the Red Cross and the Women's Christian Temperance Union.
1920s
Ham and beef sandwiches and pies were the most common food available, but, despite an increase in vendor numbers, there was still not enough food to go around, leading many patrons to bring their own picnics.
In response to the shortage, in 1924 the QCWA's Metropolitan Branch set up a stall in the main pavilion selling sandwiches, fruit, homemade preserves and novelties.
"The ladies who frequented the Ekka found that there were no lunches really available, so the first lunches they supplied was a sandwich in a paper bag," says Sylvia Raper, convener of the QCWA kitchen at the show.
"It's always been just basic food that country people know and enjoy, but we do the scones, jam and cream and we've always done Anzac biscuits and a fruit cake."
1930s
The economic downturn in the early 1930s meant many showgoers looked to the budget-friendly option of bringing their own meals, with grassy, shaded "luncheon lawns" created for people to eat.
In 1938 an economic upturn sent punters to the Ekka. Records show one food hall's daily sales consisted of 3180 bread rolls, 45 hams, 360 eggs, 40kg of pressed beef, 36kg of corned beef, 13kg of sausages, 10kg of steak, 600 lettuces and 780 beetroots. Around 1000 main meals were served each day, plus morning and afternoon teas consisting of cakes, apple pies and jelly.
It is also believed the classic show treat of fairy floss was first introduced in the late 1930s. Historic images have been found of women enjoying the sugary fare in 1939.
1940s
In 1946 some of the dining halls turned to self-service in a bid to reduce long queues and waiting times. However, with rationing still in play for some products, supplies were simply inadequate, estimated to be 40 per cent short.
What was not in shortage, however, were potatoes, with the Tasmanian Potato Marketing Board serving 10 tons of hot chips in a single day.
Showbags also provided a source of food for hungry punters with everything from salted nuts to chocolates and lollies on offer.
1950s
This was the decade of change for the Ekka and marked the introduction of some of its most iconic foods, including the dagwood dog, strawberry ice cream and Butter Board sandwiches.
Ice cream giant Peters had long been associated with the show but around 1950 decided to combine strawberries, ice cream and fresh cream in the form of a sundae. It was an instant hit and, though it started out as a commercial product, the ice creams are now sold as a fundraising venture for charities, community organisations and schools.
Butter Board sandwiches got their name as they were provided by the Queensland Butter Board as a marketing initiative. They were initially available from two bars and were filled with "picnic ham, flavoursome cheese and chef-cooked brisket". The sandwiches are still available today, made by husband-and-wife team Russell and Gina Cronk, who have been a part of the show for 42 years. Today's versions feature lots of butter, fresh ham, cheese and pickles.
1960s
In 1968, in conjunction with Woolworths, butcher Ken Crotty started the Class 35 Competition; which is a legendary beef challenge that looks at the yield of a pen of three cattle. The competition continues to this day and will run in the Woolworths Fresh Food Pavilion. Showgoers are taught about the different cuts of meat, plus how to debone meat and make sausages.
1970s
The once-popular Temperance Dining Hall ran its last service in 1978 offering set meals featuring the choice of roast beef, sausages, or a meat pie with vegetables and bread, plus scones and pikelets for dessert with a cup of tea. The hall was replaced by a 200-seat public bar.
2000s
In 2006 the now hugely popular Woolworths Fresh Food Pavilion was launched featuring an array of food producers showcasing everything from curry pastes to cheeses; as well as cooking demonstrations. This year it will host Craft Beer Alley and is where hungry punters can get their hands on the favourite $2 cheese toastie.
In 2009, for the first year since 1924, the QCWA was not part of the show as its refreshment stall building was removed. Its absence caused public outrage with punters begging for its return.
2010s
In 2010 the QCWA moved into its new home in the old Tunnel Bar underneath the John MacDonald Stand where it sells its beloved burgers, sandwiches, cakes, biscuits and Devonshire teas using nothing but the freshest ingredients.
"The produce, I order that in every day, fresh produce from Australian suppliers," Raper says.
In 2013 the Royal Queensland Steakhouse launched in the new Royal International Convention Centre. The a la carte restaurant serves award-winning beef and lamb from the annual Royal Queensland Food & Wine Show Awards headed by executive chef Sean Cummings.
This year the restaurant moves into the concourse above the convention centre offering bargain-priced steaks from $35-$50, plus award-winning wine from the show.
"If you went to any top-notch steakhouse around the country like Rockpool Dining you're looking at $100-plus steaks and the quality we've got going on in the steakhouse is right up there," Cummings says.
The past three years has also seen a dramatic move away from traditional, greasy food to more gourmet offerings and the launch of food stalls serving everything from vegan ice cream to chicken wings.
"Probably the biggest evolution has been as people's tastes change they want to have that high quality offering because people are becoming more discerning," Cumming says.
In 2017 there will be a cheeseburger pie, pizza in a cone, CocoWhip coconut ice cream and rainbow bagels, alongside multicultural offerings, such as Asian dumplings and curries.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>CocoWhip</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QCWA's Metropolitan Branch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal International Convention Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Temperance Dining Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Butter Board</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Showgoers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rockpool Dining</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anzac</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HAM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John MacDonald Stand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Women's Christian Temperance Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Queensland Show</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woolworths</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ekka</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sean Cummings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sylvia Raper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Butter Board</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian Potato Marketing Board</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tunnel Bar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CWA's Devonshire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wine Show Awards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Queensland Steakhouse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craft Beer Alley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Devonshire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cumming</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QCWA</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gina Cronk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ken Crotty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Red Cross</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Class 35 Competition</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woolworths Fresh Food Pavilion</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Queensland Food</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
