<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443448356553315</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:08</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/south-australia/satac-website-crashes-on-first-day-university-applications-open-in-sa/news-story/43a33d90ec4cd1b05e8e0dc7263f8798</url>
  <title>Uni application website crashes on opening day</title>
  <content>
A TECHNICAL glitch has been blamed for SATAC's website crashing for about an hour today, on the opening day for applications for university and TAFE courses in 2018.
Strategy and policy manager David Hallam described the malfunction - "where our web-based application lost connection with our database" between 10.40am and 11.40am - as "highly unusual".
He said SATAC, the South Australian Admissions Centre, had been taking online applications for universities in SA as well as the Northern Territory since 2004, and Monday was the first time in six years there had been an issue.
"As you could imagine we do a huge amount of preparation in advance of opening our admissions cycles - actually beginning the process in February, so it is generally very slick," Mr Hallam said.
"(Today) we opened at 9.00am as planned and monitored what was going on quite closely and by 9.30am we had about 250 people who had registered and commenced applying.
"The way our system is set up, staff are notified as soon as there is an issue with the server and this is what happened today. This allows IT to come together to find the problem and fix it as soon as possible.
"We think there would have been only a small number of applicants inconvenienced."
Mr Hallam said typically about 900 applications are received on opening day, with many of those for courses that don't accept late applications such as dental surgery, oral health and veterinary bioscience at the University of Adelaide and drama at Flinders University.
Mr Hallam said applications peak in September, ahead of the closing date.
Just after 3pm on Monday, 830 people had registered and began applying, he said.
Each year about 44,000 people apply through SATAC for courses at TAFE as well as Flinders University, the University of SA, the University of Adelaide, Torrens University (Australia), Charles Darwin University, CQUniversity and the Tabor College of Higher Education.
Mr Hallam encouraged anyone on the site when it failed to try again.
"You can apply now for courses starting in Semester 1 and for many courses starting in midyear and other teaching periods," he said.
"Up to six course preferences can be selected in an undergraduate or postgraduate application."
Mr Hallam said information for course fees in 2018 was also available by clicking on "undergraduate", then "clarify" and finally on "SATAC fees".
For more information go to .

* A second young woman admits her role in the murder of a Craigmore grandfather
* Australian Olympic golden girl Betty Cuthbert dies at 79
* A weekend of wild weather leaves our coastline battered
* A Melbourne teenager in hospital after an apparent sea lice attack
* 100th birthday celebrations at Government House for SA's Rat of Tobruk
* Some long faces at Alberton after a humiliating Showdown defeat

More Adelaide news - August 7
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flinders University</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CQUniversity</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian Admissions Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craigmore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Government House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of SA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA's Rat of Tobruk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Betty Cuthbert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SATAC</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tabor College of Higher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Torrens University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Hallam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Territory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TAFE</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Olympic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hallam</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Semester 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charles Darwin University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alberton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
