<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443624450215692</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/rural/2017-08-07/fruit-and-vegetable-bouquets-a-hit-for-sa-creator/8781312</url>
  <title>Fruit and veggie bouquets a hit for SA creator</title>
  <content>
If you are in a romantic rut and looking to impress, could everyday fruit and vegetables be the answer?
Choosing a dozen capsicums over roses may seem strange to some, but it is the creative idea one SA resident hopes can satisfy the heart - and a hungry stomach.
Adelaide Hills resident Vlada Kazimirchuk is the founder of Lunch Bunch, creating edible arrangements using local fruit and vegetables.

With 16 years' experience as an interior designer, Ms Kazimirchuk has found her calling in creating edible arrangements using everyday fruit and vegetables.

With 16 years' experience as an interior designer, Ms Kazimirchuk has found her calling in creating edible arrangements using everyday fruit and vegetables.

Supplied: Lunch Bunch

Having found a number of edible arrangements from Russia, she has since turned the idea into a viable business.
"It is a sustainable gift," she said.

"Who says 'yes' with flowers ... it is so 1920s."

"Now it is all about wow effect, and about surprising your friends."
Having worked as an interior designer in Sydney for 16 years, Ms Kazimirchuk is a creative person by nature.
She said creating edible arrangements offered another level of creativity and personal control often lacking in her previous profession.
"It is a very exciting and long process from the concept to the final product," she said.
"There are a lot of people involved, and things can go differently.
"I rely only on my hands, and I create exactly what I want and it is very rewarding."
From a bouquet of mushrooms to an arrangement with avocados, Ms Kazimirchuk cites a bouquet including dried fruits, chillies and biscuits as one of the more unusual requests.
But she said the stranger the order, the more her creative side comes out.
"I love it - it is a challenge," she said.

"You can never repeat the same bouquet twice."

Fruit gifts finding local market success

When it comes to marketing fresh produce as a gift, Ms Kazimirchuk is not alone.
Riverland fruit packer P Costi and sons is trying to bring the fruit-giving custom to local shores by selling premium lines of citrus in gift boxes.
The packer's general manager, Helen Aggeletos, said the idea had proven to be an international success.

A common sighting overseas, one Riverland citrus packer hopes gift boxes of citrus will take off in Australia.

A common sighting overseas, one Riverland citrus packer hopes gift boxes of citrus will take off in Australia.

ABC Rural: Tom Nancarrow

"We looked at some of our Asian markets, and for them the custom of gift giving fruit is an old custom and very sought after," she said.
"We thought why not introduce it to the Australian public as well."
Ms Aggeletos said she hoped, much like cherries given at Christmas time, the boxed fruit would show itself as a worthwhile venture.
"You can always go to the supermarket and buy fruit and give it as a gift, but we thought let's set up a nice box that is attractive to the public, and is specifically focused on gift giving."

"It is very strong in the Asian countries, and I hope in Australia it also takes off.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riverlands</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lunch Bunch</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Hills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC Rural</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vlada Kazimirchuk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Kazimirchuk</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P Costi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Aggeletos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Nancarrow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Helen Aggeletos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
