<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443976637539773</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/07/18/25/pete-evans-diet-doco-slammed-for-dangerous-claims</url>
  <title>Pete Evans</title>
  <content>
Controversial celebrity chef Pete Evans has been slammed by health experts for his new documentary which claims diet can treat chronic illness.
Evans's documentary The Magic Pill spruiks the paleo diet as a potential treatment for diseases and conditions including diabetes, cancer and autism.
The paleo diet prescribes a strict nutritional regime of leafy vegetables, meat, fish and fruit.
Dairy, cereal products and processed foods are forbidden.
Australian Medical Association (AMA) president Dr Michael Gannon said the documentary "irresponsible".
"These are dangerous claims and they're unfair on the people facing the battle of their lives," he told A Current Affair.
The Magic Pill focuses on several people who are suffering from different chronic conditions.

Related Articles

They each follow the paleo diet for five weeks, and the documentary claims it helps drastically reduce their symptoms, and their need for traditional medicine.
One of the case studies, Abigail, has autism, is non-verbal and suffers from epilepsy.
The documentary claims that a paleo diet helped her to speak for the first time.
"The parents of a child with autism spectrum disorder face many challengers and the last thing they need are false claims about treatments that are likely to make improvements to their child's wellbeing," Dr Gannon said.
Dr Gannon likened the film to the documentary Vaxxed, which was slammed as anti-vaccine propaganda by critics.
"We can't have self-proclaimed experts, celebrity or otherwise, make claims that are potentially harmful to the community's health," he said.
Chris Varney, director of autism support network iCan, said the documentary also contributed to the "scaremongering" around autism.
"(Evans) has not only potentially led families down a harmful path, he's also damaged the community understanding that we're trying to create," he said.
"Stick to healthy eating, Peter, I don't think you know anything about autism."
Nutrition Australia's Aloysa Hourigan advised people wanting to improve their health to first see a qualified nutrition or dietetic professional.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abigail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Medical Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Michael Gannon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pete Evans</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Gannon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Current Affair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nutrition Australia's Aloysa Hourigan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ICAN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Varney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magic Pill</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AMA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vaxxed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
