<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444487738656953</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/entertainment/confidential/the-blocks-clint-amos-sheds-tears-at-sad-passing-of-beloved-grandad/news-story/72a39d709f97ff498928d87934c763ff</url>
  <title>Clint weeps for beloved grandfather</title>
  <content>
CLINT Amos has described the moment he broke down outside his house on The Block as his father told him his grandfather had passed away.
The former rugby league star discovered that his family had switched off the life support to his grandfather, John Amos, who was 89, while filming for Monday night's episode of the Channel 9 show.
Clint said he had just received a grilling from foremen Keith Schleigerand Dan Reillyabout their when he stepped outside to receive the call.
"I knew straight away something was up. I remember leaning over and I broke down. I had a tear just from hearing my father's voice breaking," Clint said.
"To hear my father say that his father was about to pass was the most difficult thing I've had to encounter."
The 33-year-old said John had gone to hospital the week prior, which his family had kept secret to allow him to focus on The Block.
But he said "too much was at stake" to quit, waiting until tools down to talk to producers.

The Block is back for 2017 - first week promo courtesy of The Block/Nine Network

The Block 2017: First week promo
Clint and Hannah were granted leave to attend the funeral, flying to the Gold Coast late Thursday night and returning to Melbourne the following afternoon.
Clint said he was blown away by the generosity of the contestants, who were willing to put the competition aside to pitch in.
"I know it's a competition, so to pause and think about us was pretty special," he said.
"They were all willing to help out with a paintbrush."
He described his grandfather as a "giant of a man" who would always pick out the positives of his rugby league games.
"He would always say 'hello Clinto, how's my rugby league superstar'," he said.
"He really enjoyed watching me play footy."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hannah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Keith Schleigerand Dan Reillyabout</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Block 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clint Amos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clint</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clinto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Block/Nine Network</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Amos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
