<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443581500541936</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>New Daily</source>
  <url>http://thenewdaily.com.au/money/your-budget/2017/08/07/woolworths-glitch-slugs-customers/</url>
  <title>Woolworths IT glitch slugs customers with not-so-fresh bills</title>
  <content>
Angry Woolworths customers say they have had money withdrawn from their accounts because of a computer glitch that has re-processed six-month-old transactions.
Woolworths has blamed the transactions on its payment processor, Cuscal.
"We have received confirmation from Cuscal, one of our payment processors that service credit unions and other financial institutions, that due to an error at their data centre, a limited number of Woolworths customers may have received incorrect transactions," the company said in a statement.
A spokesman for Cuscal confirmed that the "processing error" occurred on Sunday night.
"We apologise for the stress and inconvenience this is causing people. We are working urgently to correct the errors," Cuscal said in a statement.
It is not known how many people have been affected, but dozens of angry Woolworths customers took to social media to complain about the withdrawn cash.

Very angry Woolworths. Over $180 dollars in transactions taken from our account without permission today. That is A LOT...
Posted by  on 
Tony Dafter from Narrabri in New South Wales noticed Woolworths had taken $61.12 from his Visa debit account this morning.
He immediately called Woolworths' customer service line.
"They said it is a known issue being reported today and they are taking details, but they have no idea when it will be sorted or when I will get my money back," Mr Dafter told the ABC.
"I want the money back now. It was quite easy for them to withdraw it, so I don't understand how it can't be returned today."
Jake Brown from Mitcham in Victoria said he had about $150 withdrawn from his account on Monday based on transactions he made at Woolworths and BWS in March.
"We are extremely tight this week but will be OK for one day. What about others who are not?" Mr Brown said.
He contacted his bank and Woolworths, which both described the transactions as a basic system error.
Fears bank details kept on file

Mr Brown said he was deeply concerned his account details may have been kept on file by Woolworths for six months.
"Why are credit card details still on file? And if they're kept on file by a third party, how secure are they?" he said.

It's so so lovely that I have sick children and tried to pay for medications and guess what... my card was declined!...
Posted by  on 
Woolworths has promised to reverse the transactions on Monday.
"We are working closely with Cuscal and can confirm any payment errors will be corrected within 24 hours," the company said.
"We apologise for the inconvenience this may cause customers. If further information is required please contact 1300 767 969."
-ABC
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BWS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New South Wales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Narrabri</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cuscal</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woolworths</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Dafter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Brown</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woolworths IT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Dafter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MITCHAM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
