<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444358889635877</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/sport/football/les-murrays-state-funeral-plans-confirmed-with-final-farewells-to-be-made-at-st-marys-cathedral/news-story/efbdad840af2ce67686274cfb5ee8fbc</url>
  <title>Plans confirmed for Les Murray's final farewell</title>
  <content>
THE state funeral of Les Murray will take place next Monday at St Mary's Cathedral in Sydney, giving football fans the chance to pay tribute to a giant of the game in Australia.
, it was announced that the state funeral promised by Premier Gladys Berejiklian would start at 11am on Monday, with guests attending asked to wear white.
The colour has been chosen specifically by Murray's family "in honour of a multicultural world", said a statement on the SBS website.
Murray came to Australia as a child refugee after being born in Hungary, and saw football as powerful tool to encourage multiculturalism. For more than three decades he was one of football's most vocal proponents, presenting its coverage on SBS and lobbying to boost the game's standing.
When she announced last week that Murray would be given a state funeral, Berejiklian called him an "inspiration to many communities".
"Les's good work was not limited to sport alone," she said. "Les, who came to Australia as a refugee from Hungary, was an inspiration to many communities across our multicultural society.
"Les epitomised the post-war generations of migrants who helped make Australia what it is today. Les passionately embraced his new life and gave back to his community in spades."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les Murray</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Gladys Berejiklian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hungary</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berejiklian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Mary's Cathedral</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
