<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444268695321272</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/sport/football/a-league/teams/victory/kosta-barbarouses-fitting-right-in-after-returning-to-melbourne-victory/news-story/2ac5c956f42e2c287bef4693a9c55849</url>
  <title>Kosta fits right in back at Victory</title>
  <content>
KOSTA Barbarouses feels like he never left Melbourne Victory, so smooth has been his transition back into the club.
After three years at Victory - including the 2014-15 championship - Barbarouses join-ed Wellington on a two-year deal last season.
, with the move to Victory happening quickly.
Barbarouses said he did not want to divulge much -behind the decision to leave, "out of -respect to Wellington."
"They were fantastic about the whole situation," he said.
"There was some personal stuff I had to deal with.
"But because I didn't have anything planned football-wise, once I decided to leave Wellington, Victory moved very quickly."
The Kiwi winger said the move to Victory on a two-year deal, in terms of where he saw his career tracking, was "totally unexpected", but now he is back, he felt at home.
"Kevin (Muscat) knows what he'll get out of me and I know what the club is all about," he said.
"I've already had three wonderful years here, and even coming back into training on the first day, I didn't need anything explained to me.
"It's a good feeling to know you're welcomed and you fit straight back into a system that you know works and that you work well in."
Barbarouses netted a hat-trick in a friendly against Bentleigh last week and has put his hand up to play in tomorrow night's FFA Cup clash with Brisbane Roar at Perry Park.
"I played 45 minutes last week and the body feels good," he said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muscat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Roar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kosta Barbarouses</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kosta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perry Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MELBOURNE Victory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bentleigh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wellington</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kiwi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barbarouses</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
