<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443882148257684</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/afl/afl-news/western-bulldogs-premiership-captain-easton-wood-could-return-if-dogs-make-finals-after-avoiding-hamstring-surgery-20170807-gxr5r7.html</url>
  <title>Western Bulldogs premiership captain Easton Wood could return if Dogs make finals after avoiding hamstring surgery</title>
  <content>
The Western Bulldogs are confident premiership captain Easton Wood will be fit to play in the finals if the club makes it that far after deeming that the defender does not need hamstring surgery.
There had been fears Wood's season was over after he hurt his hamstring in Saturday's win over the Brisbane Lions, but while scans confirmed a "high-grade" injury, Wood will not go under the knife, with the club tipping that he will be back running by the end of the week. The Dogs' head physiotherapist Chris Bell said on the club's website that the Dogs had sought specialist opinion before determining that Wood did not require surgery.

Up Next

Dockers end their losing streak

01:30

More AFL Real Footy Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

AFL plays of round 20

It's all about the six pointers; Hannebery through traffic kicks a ripper, Coniglio has a claim to GOTY in Canberra, McDonald-Tipungwuti nutmegs Petrevski-Seton at the G, Billings clutch kick against West Coast and Eddie Betts is back from surgery to work his usual magic from the pocket.

In circumstances similar to those that preceded their improbable premiership run last year, Wood will have extra time to prepare himself for the finals courtesy of the bye after round 23. 
Having won four games in a row, the Bulldogs' premiership defence remains alive, with Luke Beveridge's side seventh on the ladder with 11 wins and eight losses.Photo: AAP
Their next test comes on Friday night at Etihad Stadium against a resurgent Greater Western Sydney. Bell said Jason Johannisen (hamstring tightness) and Tory Dickson (quad tightness) - both of whom missed the comeback win over the Lions - could return to face the Giants. In further positive news, forward Jake Stringer should be available to return after a three-match absence with a hamstring strain.
Veteran Dale Morris could also be back before the end of the home and away season as he recovers from a broken wrist, while Mitch Honeychurch should also be available this week having dealt with a facial infection.

Bell explained why Johannisen and Dickson had missed the game against the Lions. "Jason is a real high-speed athlete so we weren't prepared to take any risk with these symptoms so we withdrew him from the game," Bell said on Monday.

You will now receive updates from

Realfooty Newsletter

Realfooty Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"JJ's come in really well today and we'll work through a process with him this week to determine if he's available to play this weekend.
"We were forced to withdraw Tory from availability on the weekend ... [he's] come in really well today though on our assessment and we'll go through a process this week to determine if he's back into full training and if he's able to play."
Bell added that Stringer and Morris had been progressing well in their respective recoveries. "Jake has continued to show great progress on his hamstring injury. He completed a game-like training session on the weekend and has pulled up really well," Bell said.
"If Jake ticks our boxes this week with training he'll be available to play.
"[Dale's] completed some really good football sessions and we've continued to progress his contact. We're working closely with the surgeon to progress him week by week but really optimistic that we're going to see him back in the next couple of weeks."
The Dogs had flagged resting captain Bob Murphy from the Lions match but he was a late inclusion after Johannisen withdrew. The 35-year-old has had issues recovering from six-day breaks, raising concerns about whether he will take on the Giants.
Premiership hero Tom Boyd hasn't played since round 13 as he deals with mental health issues, although Dogs coach Luke Beveridge said last week that he could yet return "in the next couple of weeks".
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Petrevski-Seton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JJ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dale Morris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johannisen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stringer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greater Western Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Johannisen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Realfooty Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Bell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eddie Betts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Beveridge</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Easton Wood</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch Honeychurch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dickson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bob Murphy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Bulldogs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Real Footy Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coniglio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bell</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDonald-Tipungwuti</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>G</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dockers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Lions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tory Dickson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Boyd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hannebery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake Stringer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
