<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444397544342213</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4836235/man-accosted-schoolgirl-at-dapto-train-station-court/?cs=4110</url>
  <title>Dapto train station: Man charged with allegedly inciting teenage girl to commit act of indecency</title>
  <content>
File image

A Wollongong man charged with asking an underage girl to commit a sexual act will return to court later this week. 
Wollongong resident Kalevi Keijo Paju, 57, faced Wollongong Bail Court on Sunday, charged with inciting someone under 16 years to commit an act of indecency.
According to police documents, Paju has a number of mental health issues and is currently on a Community Mental Health Plan. 

It is alleged about 7.15am on Friday the 15-year-old victim was at Dapto Railway Station on her way to school in the northern suburbs. 
About 7.20am, Paju allegedly sat on the same bench near the victim, and began a conversation with her. The Paju allegedly asked the victim, "do you want to come around the back of the building and relieve me?"
The victim believed he was asking her to perform a sexual act. After seeing the victim's mobile phone, Paju asked the victim if she wanted to take a selfie.
The victim told the station manager of the incident and was taken into the office.
While she was explaining what had happened, Paju left the platform. 
Police report that when the northbound train arrived the victim got on the train.
Paju allegedly attempted to get on the train, but was stopped by the station manager. 
Paju was allegedly identified from CCTV footage, and police attended his home on Saturday morning. 
He was arrested and taken to Wollongong Police Station.
According to police documents, Paju participated in an interview where he made admissions to the offence. During Sunday's bail court it was revealed that the accused has paranoid schizophrenia and is on a disability support pension. 

Police expressed fears for the safety of the public, and concerns Paju has two previous failures to appear. He was granted bail to reside in his home, with conditions that he report to police daily, not loiter in any area frequented by children, attend the Wollongong mental health team, not to approach any child under 18 unless in the company of a responsible adult, and not to go within 50 metres of any school. The case was adjourned to Wednesday at Port Kembla Local Court. 

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paju</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dapto Railway Station</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong Police Station</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dapto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCTV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong Bail Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Community Mental Health Plan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kalevi Keijo Paju</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Kembla Local Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
