<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444526393363313</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/07/20/52/guildford-successfully-blocks-building-of-mcdonalds</url>
  <title>WA heritage town successfully blocks building of McDonald</title>
  <content>
Residents in Western Australia's heritage town of Guildford have won their fight against super-sized fast food giant McDonald's, with a development panel rejecting the build of a 24-hour restaurant.
After months of protesting, it was the victorious outcome locals were hoping for.
Close to 100 residents packed into the Midland Town Hall today to hear the decision handed down.
In front of a Joint Development Assessment Panel, locals gave their reasons against the build of the multi-million dollar 24-hour restaurant behind the historic Guilford Hotel.
After three hours, the panel made the decision to give the fast food giant the boot, sighting heritage integrity and an adverse impact on local businesses through traffic and parking major contributing factors.
"I think it was a good decision handed down, I think it supports the community," Guilford Mayor Mick Wainwright said.
"The community did a very good job of explaining why they don't believe a McDonald's is required in Guildford or should be allowed in Guilford."

Related Articles

Local resident Jacqueline Gilmore said she is ecstatic with the outcome.
"We are absolutely thrilled that we don't have to try and safe guard our children from traffic and parking problems," Ms Gilmore said.
"Drop off and pick up won't be impacted as much," she added.
Statistics show Guilford Grammar is one of the healthiest schools in the country, according to childhood health expert Doctor Garry Tester.
"To have a fast food outlet like McDonald's 150 metres away is a real tragedy if it was allowed to be built," Dr Tester said.
In a statement, McDonald's said it is disappointed with the outcome, with the site zoned for commercial use and a strong belief it meets the relevant planning requirements.
It is yet to decide whether it will appeal the decision.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Guilford Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Tester</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDonald</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacqueline Gilmore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joint Development Assessment Panel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doctor Garry Tester</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDonald's 150</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Gilmore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Guildford</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Midland Town Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Guilford Grammar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Guilford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Guilford Mayor Mick Wainwright</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
