<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444268695321248</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/07/20/02/motorist-launches-online-campaign-to-reduce-the-cost-of-speeding-fines</url>
  <title>Adelaide motorist launches online campaign to reduce the cost of SA speeding fines</title>
  <content>
A disgruntled Adelaide motorist has launched an online campaign to reduce the cost of South Australian speeding fines, which are by far the highest in the nation.
John Campbell, a young father from Payneham South, came up with the idea after being slugged $660 for two relatively minor offences within a fortnight.
"(The) first one was for $230 going five kilometres over (and) the other one was $430 for 10 kilometres over," Mr Campbell said.
Mr Campbell, a digital marketing specialist, decided to use his online skills to start a website called , which compares speeding fines in South Australia to those interstate.
For driving 5km/h over the limit, South Australians are fined $230 compared to $114 in New South Wales.
For driving 25km/h  over the limit, South Australians are slugged $814, compared to less than $500 in all other states.
"How do you justify that?" Mr Campbell asked.

Related Articles

"It's more than just a slap on the wrist. It's kind of crippling."
People interviewed by 9NEWS had varying views on the campaign.
"If you don't speed in the first place then you won't get a fine," one woman argued. 
Another driver said: "I would sign that petition. I don't see reason for any difference from one state to another."
Mr Campbell isn't calling for fewer speed cameras in South Australia and he doesn't want drivers to get away with speeding.
Put simply, he just wants the punishment to fit the crime.
"My campaign is purely about reducing the speeding fines to be in line with the other states," Mr Campbell said.
"You can't claim that double the fines means that we somehow have safer roads, because we don't.
"More people die on the roads here per million people than the average of the other five states."
The online petition at  has been signed by more than 1000 people since it was launched on Saturday evening.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>New South Wales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Campbell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Campbell</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Payneham South</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
