<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444268695321260</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/rugby-league/league-news/wests-group-set-to-takeover-newcastle-knights-after-members-vote-20170807-gxr9ub.html</url>
  <title>Wests Group set to takeover Newcastle Knights after members vote</title>
  <content>
The Wests Group is set to assume outright ownership of the Newcastle Knights on November 1 after their takeover proposal was overwhelmingly endorsed by the club's members.
A total of 13,635 members voted in last week's unofficial mandate and the ballot returned a 93 per cent approval rating.

Up Next

Australian sport great Betty Cuthbert dies aged 79

03:34

More Sports HQ Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Rare two-in-a-row for the Knights

Brock Lamb starred for Newcastle, with fan favourite Nathan Ross failing to finish the game with a suspected fractured back in Round 22 against the New Zealand Warriors.

Wests will now enter on Wednesday week into an interim partnership with the NRL, which has owned Newcastle's franchise since the demise of controversial Nathan Tinkler three years ago.
The transitional period will give Wests a chance to undertake extensive due diligence and address issues such as the board structure and season-ticket logistics before taking control on the first day in November.

Wests chief executive Phil Gardner said he was delighted that so many members took the opportunity to vote. In comparison, an estimated 2500 Knights members voted (97 per cent in favour) in the 2011 privatisation ballot that handed the club to Tinkler.
"It's a great vote of confidence, firstly in the Wests Group, our board of directors and what we can do," Gardner said. "But it also showed that everyone in the town is behind the Knights and they really want the team to be successful.

"That gives us incredible confidence going forward, that so many people are behind us, and with us."

You will now receive updates from

League HQ Newsletter

League HQ Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

The Wests vote was not a formal process, because the group's directors would have been constitutionally entitled to make such a decision any way, but they felt a "plebiscite" was essential before proceeding.Photo: Darren Pateman
The deal hinged on Wests committing $10 million towards a proposed rugby league centre of excellence at Broadmeadow. If, as expected, it proceeds, their investment will be matched on a dollar-for-dollar basis by the state government.
Wests will not pay out any of the liabilities the NRL has incurred during its three-year tenure as Knights owner, but are expected to contribute towards running costs before the November 1 handover. 
Gardner said that after months of negotiations with the NRL, there was no reason to suspect that any anomalies would be discovered during the due-diligence process.
"I don't believe that in this, the NRL would not be completely honest in any way, shape or form in everything that they're doing," Gardner said.
He thanked the incumbent Knights board of directors, who will stand aside on August 15, saying they "have done a fantastic job".
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Knights</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darren Pateman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand Warriors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sports HQ Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>League HQ Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Betty Cuthbert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brock Lamb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phil Gardner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Tinkler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gardner</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broadmeadows</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wests Group</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Knight</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 15</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 1</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Round 22</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Ross</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tinkler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
