<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444238630549549</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>SBS</source>
  <url>http://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/2017/08/07/australian-students-take-out-world-holiday-space-camp</url>
  <title>Australian students take out of this world holiday at Space Camp</title>
  <content>
A group of Australian students could become the next astronauts after spending their holidays at Space Camp.

By

Anita Clark

9 MINS AGO 

Ninety kids from 14 schools took part in the life changing journey to the Hasse Junior Space School in Houston, Texas.

The trip aimed to encourage more girls to study science, technology, engineering and maths.

Angie Rofail, 13, said she had the chance to "defy gravity" and "experience G-Forces" forces by riding a multi access trainer which simulated tail spins in space.

The Year 8 student said she was hooked after space camp and wanted to become an astronaut.

Year 9 student Tashi McCarthy said the mission was to become space cadets.

"We sat in a control room and everyone had a particular job, whether it was in mission control (or) the international space station," she said.

"We would communicate with each other and we got our rocket to launch that was my favourite part."

The course dived into marine biology, forensics and robotics.

Teacher Fiona Hendricks said she hoped the trip will ignite a fire within these girls that will encourage them to follow stem career paths, like engineering or scientific based work.

Space Camp allows students to travel to the US from Australia twice a year during the school holidays.

 

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tashi McCarthy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>G-force</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anita Clark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Year 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Angie Rofail, 13</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Texas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MINS AGO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hasse Junior Space School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fiona Hendricks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Space Camp</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Houston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
