<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443925097931293</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/07/18/45/martin-place-tent-city-sydney-cbd-clover-moore</url>
  <title>Confusion reigns over Mayor Clover Moore's 'tent city' deal</title>
  <content>
Uncertainty hangs over a deal to pack up a tent city in Sydney's CBD after a spokesman for the homeless contradicted an announcement by Lord Mayor Clover Moore that an agreement had been reached.
Cr Moore held a press conference on the steps of Town Hall on Monday evening where she said a deal had been done with Lanz Priestley, dubbed the Mayor of Martin Place.
She said council would help pack the camp up from Tuesday morning and transfer the approximately 70 residents to a "communal safe space" until temporary and permanent accommodation was found.
"I'm pleased to report I have negotiated an outcome with Lanz Priestley," Cr Moore said.
"Accommodation has been offered to people and they realise pressure is mounting and the crisis was really developing."
But as the press conference wound up, Mr Priestley appeared on the steps and cast doubt on the deal, saying the proposed safe space did not include beds.
"My understanding is that we have somewhere to transition the people to," he said.

Related Articles

"If we don't have somewhere for them to sleep we will have the same problem.
"If, in the Lord Mayor's mind, we're talking about a different concept, I think we need to have another discussion."
NSW Family and Community Services and council would chip in $100,000 each to establish the space, Cr Moore said.
NSW Premier Gladys Berejiklian issued a final ultimatum to council earlier in the day warning them to remove a homeless settlement in Sydney's CBD, or the state government would.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lanz Priestley</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Family</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lord Mayor Clover Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mayor of Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lord Mayor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mayor Clover Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Moore</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Priestley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Community Services</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Town Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney CBD</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Premier Gladys Berejiklian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
