<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444324529897032</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:32</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>SBS</source>
  <url>http://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/2017/08/07/tributes-flow-australias-golden-girl-betty-cuthbert</url>
  <title>Tributes flow for Australia's Golden Girl, Betty Cuthbert</title>
  <content>
SBS World News Radio:  Some of Australia's greatest Olympians have been paying tribute to Betty Cuthbert, who has died at the age of 79.

32 MINS AGO 

It was at the 1956 Melbourne Olympics that Betty Cuthbert first made her mark as a track and field champion.

Then aged 18, she she won gold in the 100 and 200 metres and in the 4-by-100 metres relay.

At the Tokyo Olympics, she overcame an injury to win her fourth gold in the women's 400 metres.

Cuthbert was known for her humility and liked to keep a low profile.

"Now when I see the video of what I did in 1956, I think 'did I do that?' you know, you just can't imagine it. I've never liked a lot of publicity and I think, well I know that's why I moved across to the West to get out of the public eye."

Fellow Olympian Cathy Freeman has tweeted "Thank you for the inspirational memories, Betty Cuthbert. Rest in peace."

Robert de Castella also used Twitter to pay tribute, writing "RIP Legend Betty Cuthbert, an inspiration to us all in so many ways."

The Chief Executive of Athletics Australia, Michael Hall, says Betty Cuthbert ranks as one of Australia's greatest track and field champions.

"She'd have to be right up there, wouldn't she? I mean we've had some amazing names across our history of the sport but when you take a moment like now and look back at what she did achieve, she'd have to be right up there in the conversation as one of our true greats."

Cuthbert was diagnosed with Multiple Sclerosis in 1969 and eventually lost her ability to walk.

Michael Hall says she campaigned and raised funds for reearch into M-S.

"Her attitude of campaigning for research into the condition, just her will to keep going on and promoting the sport and promoting what was really valuable for her."

At the 2000 Sydney Olympics, Betty Cuthbert was wheelchair-bound and former Olympian Raelene Boyle assisted her around the Sydney Olympic stadium as part of the cauldron-lighting ceremony.

Raelene Boyle says Cuthbert became one of the athletes and women she most admired.

"She was well prepared, she was able to go out there, a free spirit, and win. That beautiful running style that she had and her mouth wide open, that's probably one of the things she's remembered most for, the mouth wide open."

The Western Australian government has offered Betty Cuthbert's family a state funeral, which Premier Mark McGowan says she thoroughly deserves.

"She was a wonderful Australian, a Golden Girl from a golden era of Australian sport and I think it's appropriate considering her record that we offer a state funeral."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>M.S</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cuthbert</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raelene Boyle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympian Raelene Boyle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chief Executive of Athletics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Betty Cuthbert</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RIP Legend Betty Cuthbert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Hall</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MINS AGO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Olympics</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Mark McGowan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBS World News Radio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tokyo Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Castella</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Golden Girls</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia's Golden Girl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Multiple Sclerosis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympian Cathy Freeman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
