<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444487738656977</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/swoop/wallaroos-veteran-ash-hewson-to-take-no-prisoners-at-world-cup/news-story/6b52a03cc7fd41bfcb91eee1b5006154</url>
  <title>Wallaroos veteran takes no prisoners</title>
  <content>
ASH Hewson isn't the type to worry about having to stop a huge forward from crossing the Wallaroos' line.
Hewson, 37, may only weigh 64kg but the veteran Aussie fullback not only tackles people on weekends, it's often her day job, too.
"I have been in a couple of situations where it has definitely come in handy, being able to tackle a 100kg criminal running at you," Hewson said.
"Tackling is the way I usually bring people down because they're bigger than me."
That day job? Prison guard.
"In the men's maximum security at Long Bay," Hewson said.
It goes without saying there are few people tougher than Hewson in Australian rugby. In the men's or women's games.
The Wallaroo will feature in her third World Cup on Thursday morning when Australia play their first game, against hosts Ireland.
Hewson will bring the attacking spark that the Wallaroos hope can break the spirit of the Irish and their fans. But for the Aussie girls, Hewson provides more than attack.
She is also the uncompromising standard-bearer of strength for the Wallaroos.
Just as Hewson's rugby skills come in handy when dealing with hardened crims, working in Long Bay has helped her in rugby, too.
"Physically and mentally, they cross over a fair bit," Hewson said.
"The first shift was quite daunting. It is something you get used to but it is very important not to become complacent once you do get used to it because it can be quite dangerous.
"As a female, you are in a very male work environment but it's an environment I -really thrive in. It's very team orientated.
"All the sport I have played in my life you have to have that camaraderie and teamwork, knowing someone has got your back, leading from the front, all of that."
Presence is important in her job but Hewson said the key trait in dealing with inmates is a lot simpler: showing respect.
"Nine times out of 10 in that environment - like anywhere in society - if you treat people with respect, you'll get it back," Hewson said.

"You'd be surprised with inmates. Mostly you will get that respect back tenfold because a lot of time in their life, and it's the reason they're in there, they've never been treated with respect."
Still, every now and then it gets "interesting" and there is some rugby training before rugby training.
Her status as a long-serving Australian player - Hewson made her debut in 2009 - helps out occasionally.
"I once had one swearing and threatening me, and he got pulled up by the other inmates," she said. "It was like 'don't talk to her like that, she plays for Australia'."
Hewson grew up in Jervis Bay playing league with the boys until she had to stop at age 12. She switched to soccer and her sporting pedigree began to shine. By the age of 16 she was on a NSW Institute of Sport scholarship.
A few years later she was in the Matildas' wider squad for the Sydney Olympics but just missed the cut.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ireland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Long Bay</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hewson, 37</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matildas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Irish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Institute of Sport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASH Hewson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hewson</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jervis Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
