<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444354594668572</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/news/government-puts-off-marriage-equality-legislation-while-it-tries-to-consult-voters/news-story/f05edec2d3f9fc00d34315ef667535c9</url>
  <title>The battle to do nothing on SSM</title>
  <content>
The Government is now committed to a plebiscite Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull has sneered at and a postal ballot he knows is even worse.
That's the outcome of the  - a string of concessions installed to protect Mr Turnbull's leadership.
The plan is to have another crack at getting Parliament to approve a SSM plebiscite and if that fails to conduct a postal ballot.
It is all about being seen to do something without actually voting in Parliament on the central issue. At best, a free vote on legislation appear mid-2018.
In fact the substantive matter of marriage equality has come second to the desperate bid for an end to the embarrassing and consuming internal clash over who is running the show.
It has seen the Prime Minister confronted by an outspoken right-wing group, which has provoked action from a pro-gay rights counter force.
This clash also has seen the Liberals dump their once-proud investment in the right to a free vote - which could decide same-sex marriage, for or against, in a few weeks - in favour of regimentation.
Worse, there is now the possibility of a protracted and inconclusive barney which will see Mr Turnbull and predecessor Tony Abbott continue to snipe and niggle each other.
The most alarming words in Monday's jumbled Liberal Party debate over same-sex marriage came from Tony Abbott. They were, of course, fighting words.
Mr Abbott said on 2GB former Liberal Prime Minister John Howard had tried 40 times to get Parliament to dump Labor's unfair dismissal laws before he was successful, and he wanted the same persistence applied to a SSM plebiscite.
He was exaggerating wildly as Mr Howard only got his way when the Coalition won control of the Senate at the 2004 election and the Senate passed Work Choices.
And it is likely Prime Minister Turnbull will not be able to get the national plebiscite proposal passed unless he has the numbers in the Upper House. And that isn't going to happen this side of the election scheduled for 2019.
Labor today decided to again vote against a plebiscite. This will see a renewal of the government line that Bill Shorten is the worst enemy of gay marriage.
The debate has exposed shifting positions of the protagonists.
In August, 2015 - just after the six hour Liberal and National meeting which produced the plebiscite plan, Mr Turnbull was not impressed.
The following month he ousted Prime Minister Abbott.
"The reason I haven't advocated a plebiscite after the next election is that it would mean, it will mean, that this issue is a live issue all the way up to the next election and, indeed, at the next election and, if we are returned to office, it will be a very live issue in the lead-up to the plebiscite itself.," said Mr Turnbull back then.
Mr Abbott also has changed policy.
Speaking after the party room discussion in August 2015, the then-Prime Minister said: "I have come to the view, I believe this is the party room view, that this is the last term in which the Coalition party room can be bound, although we will definitely maintain the current position for the life of this term.
"Going into the next election, we will finalise another position.
"The disposition of the party room this evening is that our position going into the next election should be that in a subsequent term of parliament, this is a matter that should rightly be put to the Australian people."
Since then Mr Abbott has dumped the free vote, and Mr Turnbull has picked up his plebiscite.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Prime Minister John Howard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GB</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Upper House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2015</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Abbott</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Howard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SSM</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Abbott</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Work Choices</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
