<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444655242384657</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/infrastructure/downer-extends-12b-spotless-offer-for-seventh-time-20170807-gxqxik</url>
  <title>Downer extends $1.2b Spotless offer for seventh time</title>
  <content>
Downer EDI has extended its $1.2 billion takeover bid for Spotless for the seventh time as its stake in the services group gradually moves towards 90 per cent.
Downer said on Monday that it would  until August 14, unless it is further extended.
The contractor now owns 86.7 per cent of Spotless, but remains short of the 90 per cent it needs to compulsorily acquire the remaining Spotless shares.
It will not be able to get more than 90 per cent of Spotless unless the company's second biggest shareholder, New York-based hedge fund Coltrane Asset Management, tenders its 10.64 per cent stake into the offer.

Coltrane has not responded to The Australian Financial Review's requests for comment and its intentions remain unclear. It may be waiting for the release of Spotless' annual results on August 24 before making a decision.

Downer initially planned to close its takeover offer of $1.15 per share in cash in mid-May but has been forced to keep moving the closing date of the offer to secure the support of Spotless shareholders.
Spotless was dumped from the important S&P/ASX200 index on Monday morning by S&P Dow Jones Indices because of the limited liquidity in the stock with Downer having snared such a large chunk of the company.
Spotless has had a tumultuous time in two separate stints on the ASX, making a return as a listed company in May, 2014 after two years under the ownership of private equity firm Pacific Equity Partners.
Spotless had been a listed company for decades until PEP took it private in 2012 with a $720 million buyout and then re-floated it at $1.60 per share. This ascribed a value which was $1 billion higher than when PEP bought it and resulted in the company being largely spurned by Australian institutional investors wary of its chequered past.

Downer when it appointed four directors, including Downer chief financial officer Michael Ferguson, along with two of its non-executive directors, Philip Garling and Grant Thorne. A former Downer executive director, John Humphrey, also joined the board.
But that newly re-shaped board will be disbanded if Downer is able to de-list Spotless and take it off the ASX.
Downer can only proceed with the delisting without getting approval from investors if Spotless has fewer than 150 shareholders who own shares worth at least $500 when its takeover offer closes.
If Spotless still has more than 150 shareholders, Downer will need to hold a meeting to ask for investors' approval and set out a timetable for the delisting, which will also need to be approved by the ASX.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Downer</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coltrane Asset Management</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P Dow Jones Indices</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Downer EDI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Ferguson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pep</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grant Thorne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 14</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 24</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philip Garling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Humphrey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pacific Equity Partners</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P/ASX200</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spotless</name>
    <count>13</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coltrane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
