<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444655242384649</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/sport/cricket/the-ashes/cricket-australias-sponsorship-freeze-end-with-a-new-ashes-partner-confirmed/news-story/c900c365ee9478c575f0ed4dcb7f542a</url>
  <title>Cricket Australia's sponsorship freeze end with a new Ashes partner confirmed</title>
  <content>
'Time to get on with it'
1:30

Cricket: Steve Smith has joined Fox Sports News to discuss the overdue ending to the pay saga.

August 4th 2017
3 days ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Sport news and galleries/Cricket news and galleries/

Cricket Australia CEO James Sutherland (L) and Australian Cricketers' Association CEO Alistair Nicholson attend a press conference in Melbourne on August 3, 2017. Australia's bruising and protracted cricket pay dispute was finally resolved on August 3 with players and management agreeing on a new "in-principle" deal, ensuring upcoming series against Bangladesh, India and England can go ahead. / AFP PHOTO

Ben Horne

Share

CRICKET'S sponsorship freeze is over with a new Ashes partner on board to help fill the $13 million void left by the Commonwealth Bank.
Financial group Magellan has signed a lucrative three-year deal to be the new naming rights sponsor of the Australian home Test series, starting with this summer's Ashes flagship.
It's understood Magellan had virtually agreed to terms months ago but held off on signing on the dotted line until the pay dispute saga was sorted and the Ashes was set in stone - hence why a deal has been announced just days after an MOU heads of agreement was drawn up last Thursday.
The Daily Telegraph has been told the Magellan deal could be worth as much as $6-7 million, although some doubt was expressed from elsewhere in the industry that an investment company making its first foray into sports sponsorship in a bid to create some brand awareness would splash that much cash.

Australian Test captain Steve Smith (left) and vice-captain David Warner.Source:AAP
Cricket Australia have had to restructure its major sponsorship arrangements after the Commonwealth Bank made the decision to scale down its broad commitment to the international game and focus more on sponsoring women's, grassroots and disability cricket.
Under the previous deal Commonwealth Bank held naming rights for the Test series itself as well as logo rights on the Australian Test and one-day shirts.
However, CA has now split the domestic sponsorships into two compartments with Magellan sponsors for the series, but not to appear on team apparel.
It's understood CA are hoping to announce a Test, one day and T20 shirt sponsor within the next fortnight, with MasterCard rumoured to be in the running.
KFC has recommitted as major partner for the Big Bash and Twenty20 series cricket and all signs suggest Cricket's financial prosperity has not been impacted by the pay war.

It was way back in early April that CA was anticipating it could soon announce its new list of corporate partners.

However, that was all put on hold when the pay war escalated into one of the ugliest disputes since World Series Cricket.
Pressure from anxious existing and future corporate partners was one of the major reasons that ultimately forced a resolution to the saga, as well as Cricket Australia's determination to save the Bangladesh Test series.
CA corporate sponsors contribute a minimum of $1 million to the game per year and their trust in the business, the protection they would be afforded and the future of the sport was paramount.
Magellan co-founder Hamish Douglass said his company had full faith in cricket's ability to deliver for major sponsors.
"Test cricket is the premium form of the game and its attributes of patience, skill and dedication to excellence are aligned with Magellan's approach to preserving and growing our clients' wealth over the long term," he said.
"Test cricket has a large and diverse following throughout Australia and this partnership with Cricket Australia represents a unique opportunity to highlight the benefits of global investing nd to position Magellan as a trusted partner in that journey."
ENDS
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cricket Australia CEO James Sutherland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MoU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamish Douglass</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big Bash</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Series Cricket</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mastercard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Cricketers' Association CEO Alistair Nicholson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twenty20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magellan</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KFC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bangladesh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP PHOTO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>India</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Warner.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cricket Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Sport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Horne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>L</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 3</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>T20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Smith</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bangladesh Test</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ash</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Test</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Bank</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Telegraph</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox Sports News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
