<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443448356553305</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/markets/equity-markets/miners-and-cba-drive-asx-rally-20170807-gxqrp0</url>
  <title>Miners and CBA drive ASX rally</title>
  <content>
Investors bought shares across the board on Monday, thanks to an upbeat lead from Wall Street, a bump in commodity prices and short-term traders snapping up a depressed Commonwealth Bank. 
Mining and energy stocks were the best performing sectors, while utilities were a moderate drag on the bourse. 
The benchmark S&P/ASX 200 Index and the broader All Ordinaries Index each lifted 0.9 per cent to 5773.6 points and 5824.5 points, respectively. 
In early trade on Monday, investors had tentatively circled the Commonwealth Bank, which slumped 4.6 per cent at the end of last week thanks to proceedings against the bank by Austrac.

But after the bank released a statement saying the 53,700 breaches of money-laundering laws it's accused were the result of one software error, traders thought it time to cash in on the dip in price, and CBA closed the day 0.8 per cent higher at $81.52. 

The rest of the big four banks also enjoyed solid buying, with ANZ closing up 1.1 per cent, Westpac closing up 1.3 per cent and National Australia Bank lifted 0.8 per cent.
"After a strong sell off on Friday, it doesn't take much for investors to take advantage of a pullback in Australia's largest stock,"  said Gary Huxtable, senior adviser at ASR Wealth Advisers.
"Particularly on a day where equity markets are pricing in continued improvement in macro-economic conditions."
Positive US jobs data on Friday boosted sentiment on Wall Street, lifting the Dow Jones to its eighth successive record close.

A surge in iron ore futures gave the the big miners buying support: BHP Billiton and Rio Tinto both finished the day 1.7 per cent higher, with the latter climbing to its highest level in nearly six months. 
Australia's largest oil company Woodside Petroleum announced a third gas discovery off the coast of Myanmar, though analysts remain cautious about the company's foray into Myanmar. Shares closed up 1.3 per cent to $29.42. 
In other equities news, Bluescope Steel enjoyed a 5.9 per cent jump on Monday after Ord Minnett upgraded the steel producer to an "accumulate" rating. 
Mantra Group leapt 5.5 per cent after the hotels group announced the $52.5 million acquisition of the Art Series Hotel chain.

Starpharma led gains in the Small Ordinaries index, jumping 9.2 per cent on successful results for two advanced clinical trials of the biotech firm's treatment for bacterial vaginosis - a serious condition that can cause infertility and other serious problems.
Stock Watch: Crown Resorts

Shares in Crown slumped 4.3 per cent further on Monday, extending Friday's selloff after the company reported a slide in earnings due to high-net worth gamblers staying away.  A number of analysts put out updates on the stock, and while many have reduced their earnings forecasts and target prices there haven't been any recommendation downgrades. Crown on Friday had announced another $375 million buyback to supplement about $1.1 billion of capital management. Citi analyst Rohan Sundram, who rates Crown a 'buy' while lowering his price target to $12.40 from $13.75, notes that one factor supporting the shares in recent months may now be gone. "We no longer anticipate further near-term capital management for Crown in addition to the buyback announced," he said. Sundram says the 5 per cent dividend yield is now his primary attraction to Crown.
Market movers

Aussie dollar
The Australian dollar struggled to gain any traction on Monday, fetching US79.33¢ as investors digested strong gains on Friday in the greenback. The US dollar had been under pressure for months as a series of poor economic indicators added to uncertainty about the Federal Reserve's rate rise plans. But the greenback  won a reprieve on Friday when US jobs numbers rose more than expected. The Reserve Bank last week warned that further gains in the Aussie would threaten its outlook for growth and inflation, although it felt current levels were not a major threat.
Job ads
Job advertisements rose for a fifth straight month in July, suggesting a strong pick up in employment seen in recent months could run for a while yet. A monthly survey by ANZ showed total job ads increased by 1.5 per cent in July, from June when they rose 2.7 per cent. Ads of 177,879 were up 12.8 per cent on July last year and at their highest since 2011. After sharp increases in employment from March to June, the government measure has finally caught up with the strength seen in ads and nudged the jobless rate down to 5.6 per cent.

Iron ore
Iron ore futures in China exploded out of the blocks on Monday, up 4.6 per cent and reaching the highest level since March 22 and extending the rally from June 14 to over 46 per cent. Strength in Chinese steel prices, driven by low inventory levels and strong demand, has seen Chinese steel mill margins balloon in recent months, encouraging firms to raise output levels to take advantage of strong operating conditions. That in turn helped to bolster iron ore demand, explaining the large gains seen in recent months.
Oil
Oil prices held near nine-week highs on Monday, buoyed by robust US jobs data last week and a slight fall in US drilling, although rising output from OPEC capped gains. Brent crude was fetching $US52.20 a barrel in late Monday's trade and West Texas Intermediate was fetching $US49.38 a barrel. Prices for both benchmarks have been on the rise, hovering near their highest since late May, when oil producers led by OPEC rolled over a deal to reduce output by 1.8 million barrels per day until the end of next March.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woodside Petroleum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Starpharma</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gary Huxtable</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Myanmar</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Reserve</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US52.20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dow Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUSTRAC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rohan Sundram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wall Street</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Texas Intermediate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sundram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown Resorts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 22</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Series Hotels</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Tinto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BHP Billiton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BlueScope Steel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reserve Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westpac</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>All Ordinaries Index</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P/ASX 200 Index</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Small Ordinaries</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US49.38</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US79.33</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASR Wealth Advisers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ord Minnett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 14</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Australia Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANZ</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Bank</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OPEC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Citi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
