<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444230040614757</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/sport/boxing/amir-khan-marriage-rocky-from-the-star/news-story/ab071c3d5b5419b3cd07442ada8f5f4a</url>
  <title>Amir Khan marriage rocky from the start</title>
  <content>
Amir Khan and wife.

Kate JacksonThe Sun

Share

FROLICKING in a hot tub with a near-naked blonde woman, Amir Khan was having the time of his life.
Then, as the Marbella sun sank beneath the horizon, the boxer's attention switched to a brunette.
Few would have guessed that just weeks earlier the two-time world champion boxer had proposed to New York model Faryal Makhdoom with a $164,000 diamond ring.
They wed in 2013 - and rumours of his infidelities continued to dog them, with reports of his alleged cheating with at least nine women.
Faryal also accused his family of bullying and physical abuse.
On Friday came the unsurprising announcement that the pair had split.

Faryal Makhdoom.Source:Instagram
Weary friends breathed a sigh of relief - and asked themselves how the marriage had managed to last for long.
Others boggled at the extraordinarily public way Amir, 30, had announced the breakup.
It began with the relatively calm tweet: "So me and the wife Faryal have agreed to split. I'm currently in Dubai. Wish her all the best."

One minute later he added less calmly: "Faryal moved on quick. Always mentioned to me how much she wanted to be with another guy, from all people another boxer @anthonyfjoshua."
Soon Faryal joined the fray, in a Twitter spat that lasted more than an hour - although she later insisted her account had been hacked.

A post shared by Faryal Makhdoom (@faryalmakhdoom) on

Horrified heavyweight champ Anthony Joshua, 27, waded in too, protesting he had never even met Faryal and posting the music video to Shaggy's hit It Wasn't Me.
Faryal, 26, insists the first she knew of her marriage being over was when she read Emir's tweets.
She also posted a video over the weekend admitting of the marriage: "Obviously with the fights ... the drama, all that, it was just too much for everyone, especially for us as a couple." Drama is putting it mildly.
So me and the wife Faryal have agreed to split. I'm currently in Dubai. Wish her all the best.

In January, Amir's dad Sajjad had predicted: "Their marriage is heading the wrong way, probably for divorce."
But it seems it had been heading the wrong way right from the start.
Amir and Faryal met in 2011 through a mutual friend and got engaged in January 2012.
Faryal was just 20 and later admitted she struggled to understand his Bolton accent. The political science student said: "It was like he was speaking in a foreign tongue."

British Boxer Amir Khan has split up with his wife Faryal Makhdoom.Source:Getty Images
Rumours soon surfaced that Amir, who is worth $37 million, had bedded model Natalie Fox.
Meanwhile, Playboy model Carla Howe claims the pair slept together and that he was "obsessed" with her 34DD breasts.
And between popping the question and their wedding, Amir headed to Marbella, where he reportedly enjoyed his hot-tub romps with solicitor Tanya Reid and promotions girl Natalie Kane.
When the fling hit the headlines, Amir tweeted: "U all know I'm engaged and love my fiance @FaryalxMakhdoom to bits. Me and Faryal trust each other regardless where in the world we are."
After the pair wed at a $1.3 million bash at New York's Waldorf Astoria hotel on May 31, 2013, Amir promised he was ready to settle down.
He declared in an interview: "I've got to look after Faryal, so I won't be going out partying as much with my friends. I don't want that any more, I want to do the family thing."
But stories of his alleged infidelity continued to hit headlines.
While Faryal was pregnant with their daughter Lamaisah, now three, he is said to have bombarded Bolton shop worker Clair Nuttall with lewd texts.

Amir Khan punches Lamont Peterson during their world title fight.Source:Getty Images
She claims he urged her to perform sex acts on him and begged for a threesome.
She said: "Amir is a cheating scumbag. He treats her like s*** and every other woman he hooks up with. It's disgusting. She needs to kick him out once and for all because becoming a dad won't change him."
He also reportedly bedded French lingerie model Eglantine-Flore Aguilar, who said on the weekend she had contacted Faryal to say she should dump her husband.
She said: "I warned her he's a dirty love rat."
Faryal accused the women of being "home-wreckers".
Then glamour model Christie Lee Hoyle, who met Amir at a charity event, revealed the fighter turned up at her flat allegedly boasting about the number of women he had seen behind his wife's back.
She also claimed he begged her for bath time pictures.
Just eight weeks after the birth of Lamaisah, a 26-year-old brunette claimed they had met five times in a Bolton car park, where Amir had kissed and fondled her in her car.
Preferring to remain anonymous, she said: "He's got a beautiful wife and a lovely baby but he still thinks he can play the field. He really believes all this King Khan crap he's surrounded himself with."

Canelo Alvarez (R) knocks out Amir Khan during the WBC middleweight title fight.Source:AFP
In 2015 Welsh Big Brother star Lateysha Grace claimed he once offered her $3,200 for a foursome in Miami, which she turned down.
Then there was the tape of Amir performing a sex act on himself while chatting on Skype to an American model, allegedly made soon after his wedding.
After that emerged in January this year, Amir and Faryal appeared on ITV's This Morning together, to insist the tape was made before they met. They also said it was leaked by someone out to humiliate them, possibly a family member.

A post shared by Amir Khan (@amirkingkhan) on

The tensions between Faryal and Emir's family are believed to have started even before their wedding.
In March this year Faryal revealed that her family had been very offended when Emir's family demanded she sign a prenup three weeks before the wedding,
She said: "I couldn't care less about the money but my parents were very insulted because they were so well off. They didn't make Amir sign a prenup."
And referring to an apparent row with his family while she has been pregnant in May 2014, Faryal ranted on Snapchat last December: "When you force your son to divorce his wife. When she's nine months pregnant!!" And your son doesn't ... and he sticks besides his wife. He's called a p***y!??? OK, I'm guessing Islam teaches us to get married and divorce our wives and treat them bad???"

Faryal Makhdoom.Source:Instagram
She later claimed members of his family had slapped her, thrown a TV remote control at her and demanded to know her every movement, including trips to the local supermarket.
And she added: "I never felt I could do anything right. I was bullied physically and mentally."
She also claimed his family had accusing her of being fake and called her "Michael Jackson" for having cosmetic work to her face.
Meanwhile, Emir's dad Sajjad branded Faryal "evil" and said the family "never know when she'll explode and what pack of lies will come next".
Mid August I'm off to San Francisco to start my training. Putting everything behind me and moving forward. Get back on top with big fights👊🏽

Amir has since moved to San Francisco, and has cut ties with his backroom team which had included his father, uncle and best friend.
He has also thrown himself into charity work, including handing out supplies to refugees and making a humanitarian trip to Peshawar, Pakistan, after a terrorist attack.
Yesterday he posted a picture of himself gazing nobly out of a window with the caption: "No pressure. Just relax and watch it happening."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lateysha Grace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King Khan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Faryal's 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mid August I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getty Images</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MIAMI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eglantine-Flore Aguilar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dubai</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Skype</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Welsh Big Brother</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peshawar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Natalie Kane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>San Francisco</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pakistan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amir Khan</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Faryal</name>
    <count>18</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Faryal Makhdoom</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WBC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Playboy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York's Waldorf Astoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FaryalxMakhdoom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tanya Reid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Jackson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christie Lee Hoyle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emirs</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kate JacksonThe Sun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amir</name>
    <count>14</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clair Nuttall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Snapchat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Faryal Makhdoom.Source</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Natalie Fox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Joshua</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ITV's This Morning</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>U</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>R</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carla Howe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolton</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sajjad</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>British Boxer Amir Khan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canelo Alvarez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marbella</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 2012</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lamaisah</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lamont Peterson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
