<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444616587678289</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/brand/rear-window/narev-due-for-aba-callup--if-hes-still-around-20170807-gxqvrl</url>
  <title>Ian Narev due for Australian Bankers' Association call-up - if he's still around</title>
  <content>
If CEO Ian Narev succeeds in his intention to stay on at the Commonwealth Bank, he could, in December, also find himself chairing the Australian Bankers' Association - the main lobbying body for Australia's banks.
Which could be very awkward, given the latest banking scandal. But it's CBA's turn - the chairmanship of the lobby group gets handed around the big four in a set manner, and the last CBA chief to head up the role was Ralph Norris, appointed in 2009. He was succeeded in turn by ANZ's Mike Smith, Westpac's Gail Kelly, and current chair Andrew Thorburn, from NAB, who's been there since late 2015.
Having done the merry-go-round, it's CBA's turn again, and with the bank insisting it was business-as-usual on Monday, it seems, for now, that Narev will take up the role in December, joining former Queensland premier Anna Bligh as the other public face of the organisation. Which is brilliant, isn't it: a Labor premier and a tarnished big bank CEO to make the industry's case to a Liberal government.
Even before AUSTRAC accused CBA of breaching the Anti-Money Laundering and Terrorism Funding Act,  it was possible Narev wouldn't end up chairing the body. After all, he's headed the bank for nearly six years, and is a fairly busy man, also being a director of the Business Council of Australia. When the members of the ABA meet in December, they may ask questions about whether Narev can commit to remaining at CBA for another two years.

Perhaps, however, they won't have too much choice in the matter. The other members of the big four have all had a go, and it'd be hard to remove Australia's largest bank from the rotation. And while the body also includes a collection of small and regional banks (and its current deputy chair is Bendigo and Adelaide Bank's Mike Hirst), never in recent memory has a minor led the lobbying arm of the industry. That's due to practical rather than constitutional limitations: the ABA is rather thinly staffed, and the chairman of the organisation usually volunteers his or her bank's resources to provide the grunt work needed to deal with any inquiries or the like that come up - 0nly the big four can easily commit to this.

Should Narev fall on his sword, , it's possible his successor could fit into the ABA chairmanship. Internally, retail banking chief Matt Comyn is seen as the most likely to be promoted up, but to demonstrate action on the scandal, perhaps CBA will look for an outsider when it comes time to replace Narev. Which might concern the other banks - do they want a newbie heading up the ABA?
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anti-Money Laundering</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anna Bligh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO Ian Narev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAB</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Business Council of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Comyn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUSTRAC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Narev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terrorism Funding Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bendigo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Bankers' Association</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ralph Norris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westpac's Gail Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Thorburn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Narev</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANZ's Mike Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aba</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Bank's Mike Hirst</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBA</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
