<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444616587678284</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/rugby/gps-flanker-waita-setu-likely-to-miss-premier-rugby-grand-final/news-story/d7653d5db8c1a4a05eb6b587c38f9ab2</url>
  <title>GPS to Waita and see on flanker</title>
  <content>
FORMER Reds flanker Waita Setu will plead for a late arrival at his new English club Coventry so he can shoot for a first GPS premiership since 1996.
Setu's joy after last Sunday's 42-24 semi-final upset of University came with a caveat now the club is booked for the Premier Rugby grand final at Ballymore on August 20.
"That was a terrific win to be part of but now my visa is sorted, my new club wants me in England this week," Setu, 25, said.
"I'll try my best by asking for a late arrival but, if not, I'm contracted and won't be able to stay for the grand final."
Setu, who played three games as a fill-in flanker for the Reds last year, has been chasing a fulltime professional deal for years and will do nothing to jeopardise his contract.
He has already missed two pre-season trials and the likelihood is GPS will need to find a new backrow partner for Mitch King and Michael Richards for the decider.
University reeled out of their second loss to GPS in three weeks with plenty of regrouping needed to beat Sunnybank in Sunday's prelimi-nary final at Ballymore.
Red Sea Faagase and Reuben Leilua will stiffen the side as new starting props but a replacement will likely be needed for regular lock Phil Potgieter after his head knock.
Personnel changes will mean nothing unless Uni cures the spate of unforced errors, with dropped ball and poor passing under the pressure applied by GPS.
Sunnybank will get a lift in the pack with regular captain Brendan Mitchell, water boy in the last-play semi-final win over Wests, certain to return after his own head knock.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Red Sea Faagase</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Setu, 25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Rugby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brendan Mitchell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Setu</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coventry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ballymore</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reuben Leilua</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunnybank</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GPS</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Richards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phil Potgieter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch King</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waita Setu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
