<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444539278265432</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:22</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-07/bumper-crowd-tipped-for-catstigers-tickets-limited</url>
  <title>Bumper crowd tipped for Cats-Tigers, tickets limited</title>
  <content>
MRP hits Cats, Brown speaks, more
Monday Footy Feed with Matt Thompson and Nathan Schmook

GEELONG is expecting Saturday's blockbuster clash against Richmond to draw the biggest crowd at Simonds Stadium since the 2013 qualifying final against Fremantle.

With a top-four spot on the line and Patrick Dangerfield returning from suspension to take on Brownlow favourite, Dustin Martin, the Cats hope the crowd will get near to the qualifying final attendance of 32,458.

Even with Joel Selwood injured and the Match Review Panel hitting the Cats hard, the game shapes as one of the most crucial contests this season.

The Cats have not declared the game a sell-out because limited seats are made available daily when reserved seat holders who can't make the game make their ticket available as part of the club's seat return program. 

Although the process happens daily, Geelong expects more seats to be available later in the week as part of that resale program.

Chief commercial executive Justin Reeves told AFL.com.au the 3000 tickets available to Richmond members had been snapped up but he expected more Tiger fans to attend the game.  

"To play a big Melbourne club at Simonds Stadium on our home ground is fantastic," Reeves said.

He said it was important to the Cats to be able to play Melbourne teams at home with the capacity increasing due to the redevelopment of the stadium and the introduction of lights giving the AFL more flexibility when scheduling Geelong games. 

The Cats have attracted three crowds above 30,000 this season after the Brownlow Stand was opened with a crowd of 30,458 against Adelaide in round 11 the biggest of the season. 

The only previous crowd above 30,000 at Simonds Stadium this century was the Cats' first game under lights in 2013, with the qualifying final crowd being the biggest crowd since 1993 when the Cats played Essendon. 

Geelong and Richmond have not attracted more than 30,000 to a game at Simonds Stadium since round 18, 1967 when the two teams later played each other in the Grand Final.

Cats CEO Brian Cook has been annoyed at ongoing commentary questioning the decision to schedule the game at Simonds Stadium and perplexed at any suggestion it should be moved to play at Richmond's home ground. 

The same match at the MCG in round 21 last season when Richmond were out of the finals race attracted 45,567 spectators, while a Cats home game at the MCG in round seven, 2014 attracted just 34,377 people. 

Cook told K-Rock on Friday night the Cats make $400,000 more with a packed Simonds Stadium than they would if they attracted a 60,000 crowd to the MCG.

Geelong plays seven games at Simonds Stadium this season but is lobbying to have more influence over where it plays its 11 home games.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MRP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MCG</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Schmook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simonds Stadium</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Match Review Panel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Thompson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joel Selwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday Footy Feed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cats-Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Dangerfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reeves</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cats CEO Brian Cook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>K-Rock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin Reeves</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Final</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow Stand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fremantle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dustin Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
