<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444719666894961</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:04</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Gizmodo</source>
  <url>https://www.gizmodo.com.au/2017/08/its-cool-theinhumans-director-didnt-like-the-first-trailer-either/</url>
  <title>It's Cool, The Inhumans' Director Didn't Like The First Trailer Either</title>
  <content>
Courtesy of Marvel Studios

If you watched the  for Marvel's Inhumans TV show and were like, "what the hell was that?" Good news! The director of the show didn't care for it much either.

Talking to , director Roel Reine shares his thoughts, along with some interesting production tidbits:

The hair wasn't even done? That explains it. They just needed more time to really figure out their style. I'm sure in the final version the aesthetic will really shine. Good, that's a relief, then. Because those trailers have been awful. The special effects were all over the place and -

"﻿I was really happy with that second trailer," he added.

Oh. OK then.

﻿"I'm very happy we kind of changed it around," Roel sad. "The second trailer really got all the fans back on track and they really like it now and they really want to see it. I was really happy with that second trailer."

Oh. Well, then. I mean, the second trailer wasn't terrible, was it? Medusa's hair just looked silly as opposed to atrocious, and, alright, there is that space probe on a green screen lunar background that kind of makes me believe the moon landing was faked. And the teleportation effect looks kind of like a George Lucas scene transition. OK, it wasn't a very good trailer, either.

That's fine. The TV show, built out of the idea for a scrapped Marvel Cinematic Universe film, could still be good, even if the visual design is giving me some late-season Smallville vibes. We'll find out when it premieres on IMAX screens September 1, followed by its network premiere on ABC September 29.

[]

WATCH MORE: Entertainment News

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marvel's Inhumans TV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roel Reine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marvel Studios</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATCH MORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC's September 29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smallville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>First Trailer Either</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Medusa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Inhumans' Director Did</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IMAX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George Lucas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marvel Cinematic Universe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
