<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443757594203917</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/more-sports/pole-vaulter-kurtis-marschall-feels-like-he-belongs-on-world-stage/news-story/0e6ffec4c388a001c58a76d04bbb85c9</url>
  <title>Marschall belongs on world stage</title>
  <content>
POLE vaulter Kurtis Marschall received a late call-up to the Rio Olympic team, but felt like a fish out of water.
Fast forward 12 months and Marschall is lining up in a world championships final feeling he belongs.
"Going into Rio last year I was way out of my depth," Marschall said.
GOLDEN GIRL:
"I just squeaked in, jumped the qualifier in Mannheim (Germany) and I wasn't really up and about at Rio.
"Whereas all the other boys had been prepping for years for Rio.
"I was just happy to be there, whereas this time it's more I've been there, I've done that, I know all the boys, I've seen them all on the circuit and I can just put that in my back pocket."
Marschall, 20 sneaked into the final after surviving a countback.
The South Australian progressed in equal 11th after a first-time clearance at 5.60m. He missed three attempts at 5.70m.
Canberra's Kelsey-Lee Roberts, 25, made the javelin final.
She qualified seventh with 63.70m.
The Commonwealth Games bronze medallist has been one of the form throwers this season, raising her personal best three times in the lead-up to London to 64.38m.
She didn't waste any time in qualifying with her second throw of 63.70m gaining her an automatic path to the final.
"I'm doing a little happy dance," Roberts said.
"It puts everything that I've done all season into practice. I've been really happy with this season.
"It took a little bit to get going at the start, I was just sort of waiting because I knew that the form was there, but to come to Europe, throw well at my first couple of Diamond Leagues, it has helped set me up for a good campaign here.
"My goal all season has been to throw a PB at the world championships, so that's what I want in the final."
Australia's other representative Kathryn Mitchell didn't progress with a best effort of 57.42m.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kathryn Mitchell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marschall</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mannheim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurtis Marschall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamond League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra's Kelsey-Lee Roberts, 25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Golden Girls</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roberts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marschall, 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
