<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444569343037169</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/entertainment/television/the-biggest-blind-side-on-australian-survivor-yet-sees-one-of-the-more-likeable-contestants-leave-samoa/news-story/b0af92f89250ca2dc8415aa8d9b9d205</url>
  <title>Survivor blindside means good bye</title>
  <content>
AIMEE Stanton was the victim of a huge blindside on Australian Survivor, but that's exactly the way she wanted to exit the game.
Stanton, 23, became the latest victim of super fan Aaron 'AK' Knight's huge game play, exciting Samoa after she thought she was that safe, she left all her clothes behind on the beach before tribal council.
The Victorian plumber said rather than be upset about what happened, she praised AK, and her former strong allies, Jarrad Seng and Peter Conte, to make the move.
The new alliance puts pressure on alpha male Lockie Gilbert, who was Stanton's biggest supporter in her Samatau tribe.

He now looks very vulnerable if the Samatau tribe looses the next challenge.
"It's just a game, and I thought great, they got me," Stanton said.
"I got so blind sided, and seriously, I could not wipe the smile of my face for literally three weeks because of it.
"The bloody cheeky buggers got me, but good on them."
Stanton said she should have realised that Seng and Conte were up to something after she went up to them on the beach TO ask them what they were talking about, and they replied: "the weather."

Mark and Sam have become extremely close in Australian Survivor 2017. But is becoming a 'power couple' the ultimate mistake contestants can make in the game of survivor?

Is this the ultimate survivor mistake?
But she thought she was so safe, it didn't even occur to think they were up to something.
In the end Stanton got five votes, and AK got four, and she went home.
As for Gilbert, Stanton believes the new alliance of five wanted to get rid of her first because she was so close to him, and they wanted to keep him as he is a real asset in the immunity challenges.
"I was so close to him, I think that's why I got booted off," she said.
"They obviously couldn't get rid of the top dog, Lockie, because he was carrying the team in challenges.
"So why not just get rid of little b...ch."
Stanton now wants to see the huge game player AK take out the whole thing.
"Everyone knew he was playing the game so hard, now that I think about it, why didn't we get rid of him earlier?" she said.
"He is actually such a beautiful and such a great guy.
"He is just playing the game hard to win.
"I would like to see him win."
Based in the outer east of Melbourne in Lilydale, Stanton now plans to have some time off from her job as an air conditioning plumber.
"I'm going to go back, but first I just want to travel around a little bit," she said.
"I had always planned to do a bit of travel and then get back to tinkering with the air cons I suppose."
Australian Survivor is on Sunday and Monday nights on Channel 10 at 7.30pm.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AK</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Survivor</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seng</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lilydale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Conte</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lockie Gilbert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stanton</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aaron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarrad Seng</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aimee Stanton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Conte</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lockie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samoa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gilbert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stanton, 23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Survivor 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AK Knight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samatau</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
