<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444311644994913</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/sport/afl/teams/fremantle/luke-ryan-named-round-20-rising-star-after-starring-in-fremantle-win-over-gold-coast/news-story/c06f027bb9066282c9e2d890b5673337</url>
  <title>Dockers' intercept king a Rising Star</title>
  <content>
FREMANTLE defender Luke Ryan is used to carving out a career - on and off the field.
Ryan, 21, who shelved a carpentry apprenticeship to pursue "every kid's dream", has now claimed the Dockers' first Rising Star nomination for the season.
The Coburg VFL product was rewarded for his 28 disposals and 16 marks against Gold Coast.
MATCH REPORT:
BAROMETER:
The impressive haul included a club-record nine intercept marks - one off the league record.
"I don't really look into that stuff to be honest, just more about improving each week, and the team improving each week, is the main priority," Ryan told the Herald Sun.
Ryan credited teammates for giving him the freedom and confidence to work off his direct opponent and move into dangerous positions.
"It's more the other defenders helping me from behind like Michael Johnson, Joel Hamling and Lee Spurr," Ryan said.
"A real tight back six just helps me do it, and give me the confidence, so if it wasn't for them I wouldn't be doing what I'm doing on the footy field."
Ryan was recruited with pick No.66 in the national draft after a breakout VFL season at Coburg.
The 186cm defender rocketed into draft calculations last year and went on to win the Fothergill-Round Medal, awarded to the most promising player under 23.
Ryan praised Coburg coach Peter German and goalkicker - former St Kilda sharpshooter - Ahmed Saad for fast-tracking his development.
"This time last year I was playing down at Coburg and now I'm here lucky enough to get the Rising Star," Ryan said.
"I went down to Coburg, played one year of VFL there and learned off Ahmed Saad (and) Peter German ... it helped my knowledge about what to expect (at AFL level)."
Ryan vowed to repay teammates after he was suspended last month for one game for drinking alcohol after the Western Derby.
"We breached (team rules) and we're all about putting them behind us and learning from those mistakes so it never happens again, so I did owe the boys and I will make it up to them."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coburg</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fothergill-Round Medal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joel Hamling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rising Star</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter German</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Derby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VFL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan, 21</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coburg VFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herald Sun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fremantle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Ryan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ahmed Saad</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dockers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lee Spurr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
