<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444144141267361</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/business/mining/electric-vehicle-battery-manufacturers-looking-to-invest-in-lithium-mines-20170807-gxqmbs</url>
  <title>EV and battery manufacturers looking to invest in lithium mines: Pilbara Minerals</title>
  <content>
A desire to secure supply of raw battery materials, such as lithium, will encourage electric vehicle and lithium-ion battery manufacturers to directly invest in mines, Pilbara Minerals managing director Ken Brinsden says.
Supply chain integration has already begun to emerge in the thriving lithium industry, with the producers of lithium chemicals teaming up with Australian miners to get new operations into production.
But Mr Brinsden said even bigger companies further up the supply chain were already starting to consider investing in battery raw materials to secure supply, in what he said would be the "next catalyst" for the lithium sector.
"I reckon it is starting to dawn on them that there could very well be a supply issue and I think they are going to have to start motivating some capital upstream to be able to establish that security in their supply chain," Mr Brinsden said on the sidelines of the Diggers and Dealers mining conference in Kalgoorlie on Monday.

"If you think about the investment required downstream in battery making and car making capacity the capital being deployed is huge - billions and billions of dollars.

"So the idea they might spend a couple of hundred million at the raw material end to assist in security of supply makes a lot of sense."
The adoption of electric vehicles and energy storage systems, which use lithium-ion batteries, has boosted demand and pricing for lithium over the last couple of years.
A string of Australian companies are racing to get projects into production to meet the spike in demand but some analysts forecast, even with the new production, demand will exceed supply into next decade.
Pilbara Minerals is developing the , which it expects to commence production in the second quarter of 2018.

Mr Brinsden said the Perth-based company already had a "healthy level of engagement" with large upstream players keen to discuss the security of future supply.
"They do genuinely want to talk about the supply base and where it is going to come from," he said.
"They are paying a lot more attention to it than they might have historically. I think the worm has turned and there is an issue in the industry with respect to that supply base and I wouldn't mind betting that you start to see some of those bigger organisations try and get a seat."
West Australian lithium miners, including Pilbara Minerals, are  through participating in the plants that convert the spodumene concentrate produced from their mines into the lithium chemicals used in the batteries.

Elsewhere at the Diggers and Dealers conference, Roy Hill Holdings chief executive Barry Fitzgerald said the company's namesake iron ore project was close to achieving its nameplate production rate of 55 million tonnes a year, after being set back by challenges during the ramp-up.
In the month of July, Roy Hill, which is majority-owned by Gina Rinehart, said the project ran at an annualised rate of about 53 million tonnes.
"We are comfortable we are well on the path to overcoming the issues," Mr Fitzgerald said.
"As we get closer we will find perhaps one or two other smaller ones but we are far more comfortable [that] we know the beast."

Mr Fitzgerald said the Pilbara iron ore project had been selling a product, which met its targeted ore grade of about 61 per cent iron. Despite the slower than targeted ramp-up the company's relationships with its customers and financiers remained strong, he said.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roy Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pilbara Minerals</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pilbara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gina Rinehart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Brinsden</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roy Hill Holdings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barry Fitzgerald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kalgoorlie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Fitzgerald</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ken Brinsden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
