<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443710349562948</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/sport/afl/dayne-beams-says-brisbane-is-looking-to-heap-more-misery-on-rivals-gold-coast-in-qclash/news-story/c39d147d4b441704253e781d74736a25</url>
  <title>Lions aim to inflict more pain on Suns</title>
  <content>
BRISBANE skipper Dayne Beams says the Lions have no sympathy for the Suns' under-siege football department and want to create further disruption with a big QClash win.
A derby loss has already cost one Suns coach his job and Rodney Eade faces the prospect of following predecessor Guy McKenna out the door if he cannot engineer a win over the last-placed Lions.
Eade and the entire football department are out of contract and fighting to save their jobs.
BAROMETER:
MUST WIN:
Dean Solomon, the most highly rated of the Suns assistant coaches, has been linked to GWS.
Brisbane are aware the immense pressure already on their neighbours would magnify with a loss on Saturday and intend on adding to the Suns' woes.
Beams said with no finals appearance to play for, his young side had agreed to try to cause havoc on the rest of the competition.
"We've spoken about it as a group ... that we could play a part in shaping the top eight, and that's probably talking more about the game we just played (against the Western Bulldogs)," Beams said.
"I guess when you can cause any disruption or you can do anything to another club, it's a nice thing to play for, it creates motivation within the group."
The Lions' may have already mortally wounded their rivals.
They ambushed Gold Coast in the opening quarter of the Round 1 QClash at Metricon Stadium with the first seven goals of the game and hung on to win by two points.
It set the scene for another year of underachievement by the Suns.
Brisbane also have their own motivation for winning, having been very open with their desire to avoid the wooden spoon.
They trail the Kangaroos and Carlton by a game, plus percentage, and will need to win at least two of their final three matches to avoid finishing last.
Coach Chris Fagan last week said the number one draft pick was not a greater prize than winning every game possible.
Lions chief executive Greg Swann has also reacted angrily to suggestions the club would be in line for a priority draft pick, which can be granted by the AFL Commission to battling clubs, saying he did not think the club would finish last.
Beams strongly endorsed that view.
"We see the next three games (Gold Coast, Melbourne, North Melbourne) as winnable,'' he said.
"That's our mission as a group to jump off the bottom of the ladder. It starts this week.
"(There's) no better feeling than to beat the Gold Coast, and hopefully North have a loss and we can jump off."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Round 1 QClash</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Guy McKenna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Solomon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QClash</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Metricon Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Fagan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Swann</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dayne Beams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GWS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rodney Eade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
