<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443585795509392</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/breaking-miner-dies-after-workplace-incident-bma-c/3209785/</url>
  <title>BREAKING: Miner dies after workplace incident, BMA confirms</title>
  <content>
THE miner who was injured in a workplace at the Goonyella Riverside mine on Saturday morning has died in hospital.

Daniel Springer, 31, died leaving behind wife and baby boy.

His wife, Carmela Xiriha Springer took to Facebook overnight Sunday, revealing the heartbreak of losing her best friend.

"Today I lost the love of my life, the person who has given me the second love of my life," Mrs Springer posted.

"My best friend and person who always said they loved my cooking even it was terrible..."

Her post was met with an an outpouring of condolences to the family of the miner with all devastated by the loss.

Facebook friend, Jake Tredwell, wrote: "My heart sunk last night when I heard that one of the biggest bloody legends of all time had been taken from us.

"Hands down one of the funniest blokes I've ever met and by far the most positive.

"I know you touched a lot of people brother and damn sure will be missed.

"Thoughts are with your family.

"See you on the other side Springer."

.

BMA confirmed his death this afternoon.

"It is with deep sadness that BHP Billiton Mitsubishi Alliance (BMA) confirms that a colleague, a contractor from Independent Mining Services (IMS), has ... passed away as a result of injuries sustained in an incident that occurred during maintenance work at the Goonyella Riverside Mine in Queensland on 5 August 2017," a spokesperson for the company said.

"We extend our deepest sympathies and support to his family, colleagues and friends at this very sad and difficult time."

The spokesperson said a full investigation was under way and BMA would continue to work closely with relevant authorities.

"Support services are in place for family, friends, the contractors involved and all of our people at Goonyella Riverside Mine," they said.

Queensland Ambulance Service was called to the site about 1am Saturday morning. He was was first taken to Mackay Base Hospital and then to Townsville Base Hospital for the emergency surgery.

Night of crashes rounds out weekend of heartbreak on Coast roads
Raped nine-year-old, abused eight-year-old
Greens' Coast election campaign in disarray
Close call for Coast motorists as debris goes flying on motorway
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
A NATIONAL exhibition of ceramic art has been launched on the Coast
ONE of Hollywood's most adorable couples is over.
New celebrity cooking show fails to fire for Seven.
The legendary creator isn't so sure about how Netflix works.
*WARNING this story contains spoilers*
TARA Reid reveals what's coming in the next installment of TV movie.
Garth Prowd's vision made huge impact on Sunshine Coast community
Home sells in just one day
Winners in Master Builders regional housing and construction awards
Ray and Gert will celebrate 70 years of marrive this week
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BMA</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Springer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garth Prowd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IMS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Independent Mining Services</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tara Reid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BHP Billiton Mitsubishi Alliance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville Base Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake Tredwell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carmela Xiriha Springer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Springer, 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goonyella Riverside</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Springer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Ambulance Services</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackay Base Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goonyella Riverside Mine</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greens' Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
