<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444230040614748</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/afl/afl-wildcard--round-gets-tossed-out-20170807-gxr9ue.html</url>
  <title>AFL wildcard round gets tossed out</title>
  <content>
The AFL has abandoned plans to introduce a pre-finals wildcard round in 2018 as it heads towards a record-breaking season of attendances with the final eight unlikely to be decided until round 23.
With strong evidence that head office policy has created a more even competition and that audiences are responding accordingly, the AFL has set aside plans to radically reform the home-and-away fixture for the short term.Photo: AAP
However, the internal fixture review team head by league executive Travis Auld will continue to work to perfect a formula with the intent to kick start the competition during the season should the close finishes and tight conclusion to the 2017 season prove to be a one-off.
Two days of talks this week involving the 18 club chiefs will see the AFL reveal it will retain a watching brief on the on-field results of its equalisation strategies. After 20 rounds of football 11 teams remain strongly in contention for September while even Hawthorn and Collingwood - sitting 12th and 13th on the ladder - remain mathematical possibilities to play finals.
Having struggled to find a better system than the current 22 rounds over 23 weeks, the fixture reform working group also including Sydney chief Andrew Ireland and Brisbane football boss David Noble, has not met since May and is unlikely to be called together until after the conclusion of finals and potentially not until next year.
The meeting of the 18 clubs this week will also examine a radical new ticketing system to maximise attendances in which club members can on-sell reserved seats. This is a recognition that too many clubs are recording big membership increases but failing to fill premium seats.

Gillon McLachlan, recently forced to let go two key executives following revelations of in-house affairs, and his executive Tanya Hosch will also unveil key details of the revamped Respect and Responsibility Policy alongside former Victorian Police chief Ken Lay, Australian Human Rights Commissioner Kate Jenkins and Our Watch CEO Mary Barry.
AFL chief McLachlan has been a prime mover behind fixture reform and shortly before the mid-point of the season said there was a strong appetite among club bosses for a wildcard round before the finals in which potentially four teams would play for seventh and eighth spot.
While the clubs were less enthusiastic head office will oversee further exploration of the move to schedule 17 games in which every team plays each other once before dividing the competition into three conferences of six. Then the top, middle and bottom tiers of the ladder would all play each other.
Another proposal will explore an 18-4 breakdown allowing for a second showdown, West Australian Derby and other key rivalries while a third will examine an 18-5 split in which four teams play a 23rd game to vie for the bottom two places in the eight.
The AFL proposal argues that breaking the competition into three lots of six after 17 or 18 games would also inject interest from midway through the season given clubs would be playing for season-defining spots by late June-early July.
However despite a series of off-field dramas at AFL House the competition's attendances and broadcast numbers are thriving with home-and-away crowds averaging 33,904 per game after 171 matches to date. (In 2008, before the introduction of Gold Coast and greater Western Sydney home-and-away attendances averaged 36,992).
The league expects Nick Riewoldt's last home-and-away game against Richmond at the MCG could be the fixture to lift the 2017 crowds above the record-setting 6,525,071 achieved in 2011. To date 5,797,709 have attended AFL games in 2017.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MCG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Human Rights Commissioner Kate Jenkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Noble</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gillon McLachlan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McLachlan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Watch CEO Mary Barry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Riewoldt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tanya Hosch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ken Lay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June-early July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Australian Derby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Travis Auld</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Ireland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Responsibility Policy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
