<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444010997278816</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4839760/confusion-reigns-over-fate-of-martin-place-tent-city-deal/?cs=4219</url>
  <title>Confusion reigns over fate of Martin Place tent city deal</title>
  <content>
Confusion reigns over fate of Martin Place tent city deal

SYDNEY, AUSTRALIA - NOVEMBER 25:  Sydney Mayor Clover Moore poses for a picture in Martin Place on November 25, 2016 in Sydney, Australia.  (Photo by Daniel Munoz/Fairfax Media)

exit

An encampment of homeless people in Martin Place will be moved on as early as Tuesday morning after the City of Sydney Lord Mayor, Clover Moore, announced a plan to dismantle the camp.
Cr Moore told a press conference on Monday that an immediate temporary 24-hour "safe space" would be established where those currently living in tents in Martin Place would be relocated.
Cr Moore said the City would contribute $100,000, and she expected the Department of Family and Community Services to also contribute $100,000 to establish a permanent 24-hour facility that provided food, showers and laundry facilities, as well as links to homelessness services.
The $100,000 funding contribution was passed at the city's council meeting on Monday night.
Cr Moore said the negotiated solution had the support of Premier Gladys Berejiklian, with whom she had spoken on Monday afternoon.
Describing the outcome as a "peaceful resolution" Cr Moore said the so-called mayor of tent city Lanz??? Priestley had agreed, on behalf of the homelessness camp, to dismantle the tents as soon as Tuesday morning, when the first council trucks would move in.
However, there appeared to be ongoing confusion over the details of the temporary space on Monday evening, including where the space would be located.
Mr Priestley said that he understood the temporary space would include the provision of sleeping arrangements for the homeless. But Cr Moore said no accommodation would be provided.
"If we don't have somewhere for people to sleep, then we still have the same problem," he said. "In the Lord Mayor's mind, if we are talking about a different concept, I think we have to have another discussion."
Cr Moore's press conference came ahead of fiery City of Sydney council meeting, where councillors said they had been ambushed by the mayor's announcement.
Independent councillor Angela Vithoulkas??? said councillors had not been briefed on details of the proposed solution but were expected to "either blindly agree" or disagree and be labelled "against supporting the homeless situation."
Liberal councillor Christine Forster said Cr Moore's proposed solution did not address the issue of whether people would be allowed to continue to camp in the busy thoroughfare if they chose not to honour the agreement reached with Mr Priestley.

Relieved to say we've negotiated a peaceful resolution to the crisis in  after my meetings today with Lanz Priestley & Premier.??? Clover Moore (@CloverMoore)

Mr Priestly agreed to dismantle tents in  if 24/7 communal safe space established in city centre while permanent space developed??? Clover Moore (@CloverMoore)

Minister for Family and Community Services has already given support to a 24/7 safe space??? Clover Moore (@CloverMoore)

Tonight I will ask councillors to support a City owned community facility & $100,000 in funding to govt's permanent facility??? Clover Moore (@CloverMoore)

Cr Moore said her recent discussions with Premier Gladys Berejiklian had not produced a long-term housing solution, and called on the state government to extend the City's affordable housing levy across the entire local government.
Ms Moore said talk in recent days from the NSW Police Commissioner, Mick Fuller, of "throwing people in the back of trucks" was "really scary for homeless people".
Earlier on Monday, Ms Berejiklian urged the City of Sydney to "do the right thing" and resolve the issue.
Ms Berejiklian said that if the City didn't use their existing powers, then the state government would be forced to step in.

The story  first appeared on .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lanz Priestley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lanz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Berejiklian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Gladys Berejiklian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lord Mayor</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clover Moore</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Police Commissioner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 25</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CloverMoore</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Mayor Clover Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Moore</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Priestley</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin Place</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Priestley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mick Fuller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Priestly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City of Sydney</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Community Services</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Angela Vithoulkas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Munoz/Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christine Forster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Family</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
