<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444311644994908</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/sport/athletics/athletics-tributes-for-betty-cuthbert-20170807-gxr5yb.html</url>
  <title>Golden Girl still inspires</title>
  <content>
The legacy of Betty Cuthbert was still keenly felt by every athlete to wear the green and gold, especially those competing now in London at the world championships who were moved to learn of the death of Australia's greatest athlete, Jess Trengove said.
Australia's athletics team woke to the news that Cuthbert, the Golden Girl of the track, had died. Despite generations apart Cuthbert's legacy, her legend, as the only athlete man or woman to have won gold in all sprint events, lived strong in their hearts and minds.Photo: SUPPLIED
Athletics Australia has sought permission from the IAAF for athletes who wished to, to be able to wear black arm bands when they compete in London as a tribute to Cuthbert.  
Trengove only hours before learning of Cuthbert's death had finished ninth in the marathon in London - the best result by an Australian woman at a world championship. She was moved and saddened by Cuthbert's death.
"Betty was a legend of the sport and Team Australia extends our sympathies to her family and friends at this sad time," she said.
"You can be sure that the green and gold will be doing all that they can to honour her legacy here in London. She was one of the best we've ever seen compete for Australia and she inspires athletes to this day when they put on the national uniform."

Catherine Freeman, the two-time world champion 400 runner who won Olympic gold and silver, expressed her sadness at the death of the woman who broke ground not only for Australian women in the sport but women around the world at a time when they had only just been accepted to compete in the Olympic Games.
"It's a very sad day, there's no doubt about it," Freeman said. "Betty is an inspiration and her story will continue to inspire Australian athletes for generations to come. I'm so happy I got to meet such a tremendous and gracious role model, and Olympic champion."
Dual world champion 400m hurdler Jana Pittman described Cuthbert as Australia's best.
"RIP BettyCuthbert. Thank you for everything you did for our country in the sporting arena!! You are the greatest Aussie track athlete ever!" she said.
Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull and Opposition Leader Bill Shorten both sent messages of condolence.
"Rest in Peace Betty Cuthbert - an inspiration and a champion on and off the track," Turnbull said.
Shorten, likewise, said Cuthbert would "forever be a golden girl".
Jane Fleming, a dual Olympian and two-time Commonwealth gold winner, said the timing of Cuthbert's death was ironic because the final of the women's 400m at the World Championships was due to be held within 24 hours.
The time Cuthbert ran when she won gold in the 400 in Tokyo in 1964 (52.01s) would have seen her qualify for the semi-final in London.
"It was the only perfect race I have ever run," she later said of that  victory. She set 16 official world records, either as an individual or in relay teams.
A member of the IAAF Hall of Fame, Cuthbert is also a Legend of the Sport Australia Hall of Fame. 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympic Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cuthbert</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Betty</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Freeman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Opposition Leader Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tokyo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Championships</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Betty Cuthbert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trengove</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RIP BettyCuthbert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Legend of the Sport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jane Fleming</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Athletics Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Team Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jess Trengove</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia Hall of Fame</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Golden Girls</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catherine Freeman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jana Pittman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IAAF</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IAAF Hall of Fame</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peace Betty Cuthbert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
