<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444526393363291</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:19</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/lifestyle/relationships/sex/inside-the-seedy-world-of-chinas-underground-vice-clubs-where-prostitution-is-rife-and-strippers-bathe-in-tubs-of-beers/news-story/d09b12dce578955ee21de0cc1deaab5d</url>
  <title>Inside the seedy world of China's underground vice clubs where prostitution is rife and strippers bathe in tubs of beers</title>
  <content>
Four women wear masks and little clothing as they take on a shift at the club. Picture: Sergey Melnitchenko

Ellie CambridgeThe Sun

Share

TAKE a peek inside China's underground vice clubs where anything goes as scantily-clad workers bathe in beer and drink with clients.
, nightclubs still find ways to appeal to guest's more base desires.
Photographer and dancer Sergey Melnitchenko took these startling images after trying to make ends meet as a model and dancer in Chengdu.
When he got a job in one of the city's nightclubs he decided to document what goes on with his camera.

China has a ban on strip clubs and sex work but underground clubs exist where sordid acts take place. Picture: Sergey MelnitchenkoSource:Supplied

One woman who works at the club is pictured attaching tape to her nipples. Picture: Sergey MelnitchenkoSource:Supplied
He said: "Transvestites, girls bathing in tubs of beer, drunk actors and even more drunk visitors.
"All of this - club, the club where I'm working.
"At one moment I realised how many great things are going on here that's how the series 'behind the scenes' appeared."
He says club workers are limited to dancing drinking and playing games with clients, who also enjoy drinking copious amounts as they frequent the underground nightclubs, however prostitution is still reportedly rife within the city.

Anything goes in these clubs where activities become dark and seedy. Picture: Sergey MelnitchenkoSource:Supplied

Make up and costumes add to the exciting element of the underground club. Picture: Sergey MelnitchenkoSource:Supplied

In the backstage area of the club workers embrace as they get ready for work. Picture: Sergey MelnitchenkoSource:Supplied
In many of the photographs the workers are wearing underwear or costumes.

In one shot a man has clown face paint while others wear masks on stage.
Originally from Mykolayiv city in Ukraine, Melnitchenko spent four months in the club, which he has not named.
He described the venue as a huge bar with a stage where workers would perform and interact with guests.

A woman talks with a man who has come to frequent the club. Picture: Sergey MelnitchenkoSource:Supplied

One woman prepares to go on stage. Picture: Sergey MelnitchenkoSource:Supplied
Another photographer captured China's seedy underworld in a fascinating series of images going behind the scenes of its brothels.
These amazing photos captured by Paolo Marchetti give an insight into the dark side of the Yunnan province, south of China, where rich business men visit during the night to be entertained.

In many of the photographs the workers are wearing underwear or costumes, and have marks on their body. Picture: Sergey MelnitchenkoSource:Supplied

Wigs and outfits are heavily used for the niche activities which keeps punters pouring in. Picture: Sergey MelnitchenkoSource:Supplied

Two people carry out an act on stage in wigs and wearing underwear and heels. Picture: Sergey MelnitchenkoSource:Supplied
And just last week it was revealed that a Chinese fight club legally adopts orphaned children and trains them in mixed martial arts is under investigation.
A documentary released on Pear Video - a popular Chinese alternative to YouTube - has courted much controversy in China, leading to authorities in Chengdu, Sichuan province, to investigate the Enbo MMA Club.
This article originally appeared on  and has been republished with permission.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chengdu</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SERGEY MELNITCHENKO</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ukraine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sergey MelnitchenkoSource</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>YouTube</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melnitchenko</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mykolayiv</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ellie CambridgeThe Sun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sichuan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yunnan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pear Video</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Enbo MMA Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paolo Marchetti</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
