<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443585795509347</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:40</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/finance/work/leaders/martin-places-tent-city-will-be-cleared/news-story/2cfca6ff1079361d853ca025cd1d609c</url>
  <title>Martin Place's tent city will be cleared</title>
  <content>
The tent city in Martin Place. Picture: Christian Gilles

Share

MARTIN Place's tent city will be cleared after a deal was agreed to by Sydney Mayor Clover Moore.
It comes after NSW Premier Gladys Berejiklian issued a final ultimatum to City of Sydney council warning them to remove a homeless settlement in Sydney's CBD, or the state government would.
Dismantled by the authorities once already, the tents have become the centre of a slanging match between the NSW Government and the City of Sydney council.
On Tuesday, Premier Berejiklian said housing staff has visited the camp 41 times to offer alternatives to sleeping rough, but some had no intention of moving.

Sydney Lord Mayor Clover Moore previously said she wouldn't support moving the homeless "without certainty they have support and permanent homes to go to."
"That isn't politicking, it is doing my job to support society's most vulnerable, as my community expects," Ms Moore said in a statement on Sunday.
Ms Berejiklian said Family and Community Services staff had been to the camp 44 times and found 70 people accommodation.
"Anybody who wants to be elsewhere will be provided that accommodation," she said.

Opposition social housing spokeswoman Tania Mihailuk called on the state government to end the stand-off and do more to tackle homelessness in NSW. Ms Mihailuk said a lack of social and affordable housing was contributing to the problem.
"The current housing crisis has led to a situation where the only option for many people is crisis accommodation, couch surfing or rough sleeping on the streets," she said.

Housing Services representatives from the NSW Government at Martin Place. Picture: Richard DobsonSource:News Corp Australia
More to come.
- With AAP
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Berejiklian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tania Mihailuk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Mihailuk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard DobsonSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Lord Mayor Clover Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Mayor Clover Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin Place</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City of Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Community Services</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Berejiklian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christian Gilles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Government</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Premier Gladys Berejiklian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
