<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444010997278822</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:19</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/law-order/amadeo-macchiavelli-jailed-for-his-part-in-huge-walker-flat-drug-lab-bust/news-story/28e3e783e486dee1a435edb99424e924</url>
  <title>Huge drug lab lands dad to jail</title>
  <content>
A "FAMILY man" has been jailed for more than seven years over a huge rural drug laboratory and ordered to serve a suspended sentence for attempting to pervert the course of justice in a murder investigation.
Amadeo Macchiavelli pleaded guilty to drug trafficking charges over the discovery of an in the Murraylands in February 2014.
Police found more than 190,000 ecstasy and NBOMe tablets, a pill press and precursor drugs capable of manufacturing $50 million worth of methamphetamine.
The 34-year old also pleaded guilty to a further drug trafficking charge over a separate July 2014 raid which uncovered a large amount of pure methamphetamine and cutting agents at a Croydon Park property which he rented.
District Court judge Rauf Soulio said that despite the magnitude of the Walker Flat drug haul, he accepted Macchiavelli was "mid-range" player in the scheme.
"You were not a financier or organiser of the operation but were rather a guaranteed purchaser of some of the resulting product," Judge Soulio said.
Macchiavelli must also serve a six-month sentence for attempting to pervert the course of justice over the investigation into the 2012 .
Macchiavelli admitted he cleaned his luxury silver Porsche before police could examine it following Mr Hatzis' death outside a Light Square nightclub.
Macchiavelli, who was described as a "family man" in glowing character references, received a total head sentence of seven years and six months but could be released on parole by Christmas next year.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judge Soulio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macchiavelli</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hatzis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>District Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Light Square</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walker Flat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rauf Soulio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murraylands</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Porsche</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBOMe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Croydon Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amadeo Macchiavelli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
