<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443491306227080</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:18</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4839683/australia-a-soft-touch-for-foreign-bribery/?cs=4219</url>
  <title>Australia a 'soft touch' for foreign bribery</title>
  <content>
Australia a 'soft touch' for foreign bribery

SYDNEY, AUSTRALIA - FEBRUARY 18:  Senator Chris Ketter during the public hearing of the Senate Inquiry into Asset Recycling at State Library Of New South Wales on February 18, 2015 in Sydney, Australia.  (Photo by Daniel Munoz/Fairfax Media)

exit

Australia needs tougher laws to tackle foreign bribery and company directors should be held responsible for serious corporate crime, a federal inquiry has heard.
On Monday the Senate economics references committee, which is holding an inquiry into foreign bribery, heard that Australia's enforcement efforts were failing, with just two corporate convictions achieved since 1999 when foreign bribery laws were enacted.
Labor senator Chris Ketter said he was concerned by evidence that Australia was seen as a "soft touch" when it came foreign bribery. "Almost all witnesses acknowledged that Australia lags behind the US and UK when it comes to preventing foreign bribery," he said.
There have been calls for tougher laws, as well as a single agency to deal with foreign bribery cases, but stakeholders remain divided on whether the law should reverse the onus of proof in foreign bribery cases.

Hold directors liable

KordaMentha representatives told the committee on Monday that the best way to ensure companies prevented bribery was to enshrine their responsibilities in law.
The firm's written submission to the inquiry suggests the government introduce offences similar to Britain's Bribery Act's "failure of a commercial organisation to prevent bribery", and that failure to report bribery also be made an offence.
It also wants directors and senior management to be held personally liable. "A reverse onus burden of proof placed on directors or senior managers will create a higher degree of urgency in respect of compliance," its submission said.
KordaMentha also wants whistleblower protection introduced into the Australian Criminal Code and for the federal government to establish a  for whistleblowers, similar to the US.

Reverse onus of proof

The Australian Institute of Company Directors (AICD) general manager of advocacy, Louise Petschler, told the hearing that the organisation was "naturally hesitant" about reversing the onus of proof on its members.
In its written submission the institute said it did not support the creation of a new foreign bribery offence based on the fault element of "recklessness" and that it opposed a new corporate offence of failing to prevent foreign bribery because "Australian companies are already burdened with a complex array of compliance costs".
It said the proposed "failure to prevent" offence should apply only to a subsidiary in a corporate group where factual elements of both control and fault were attributable to the parent company. The AICD's submission noted that corporations were involved in "legitimate relationship-building activities" such as hospitality and a new offence based on recklessness would "make it very difficult for business to develop appropriate and clear guidelines for such activities".
The institute also favours a test of "dishonesty", over the proposed test of "improperly influence". It suggested the concept of dishonesty was well known and understood in Australian criminal law, while the concept of improper influence had never been judicially considered.

'Magnet' for corrupt money

But Senator Nick Xenophon asked the AICD why it was opposed to an improper influence test given Australia had a reputation for being a "magnet for corrupt money". He said there needed to be an urgent overhaul of weak laws and enforcement regimes.
Senator Xenophon also alluded that directors be held liable for breaches including ones such as those alleged against Commonwealth Bank. , some of which .
The Uniting Church's Mark Zirnsak recommended that real estate agents and other professionals, including lawyers and accountants, be made to report any suspicious transactions, including property purchases, to Austrac.
He told the hearing that local property companies were setting up offices in Asia to attract business investors, but that some large transactions they handled appeared to be suspicious. Based on anecdotal evidence given to his organisation from real estate agents, he said prices paid were often well above the asking price or market value.
Fairfax investigative journalist Nick McKenzie told the inquiry that criminals were able to get away with bringing dirty money into Australia and China because investigators lacked resources and expertise.
Follow Nassim Khadem on  and .

The story  first appeared on .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uniting Church's Mark Zirnsak</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Xenophon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Library Of New</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Wales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUSTRAC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick McKenzie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asset Recycling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Nick Xenophon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Criminal Code</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Institute of Company</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate Inquiry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Ketter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nassim Khadem</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AICD</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Munoz/Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Chris Ketter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KordaMentha</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain's Bribery Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louise Petschler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 18</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
