<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444311644994927</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:29</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/entertainment/television/dirty-tricks-lifting-lid-on-glass-recyclings-dirty-secret/news-story/d3e41082b245521a10dc4add6934f635</url>
  <title>Lifting lid on recycling's dirty secret</title>
  <content>
TAKING out the bins is a weekly ritual but the reality of what happens next is far from transparent.
In revelations set to shake Australians' faith in recycling, hundreds of thousands of glass is being bagged and stockpiled in warehouses, or worse, sitting crushed in mountains, stockpiled or dumped in landfill because it's cheaper to buy new than recycle.
The revelation, and evidence that Queensland is being used as a landfill dumping ground with hundreds of thousands of tonnes of rubbish hauled in from interstate, will air on ABC's Four Corners tonight.
It reveals the reality of recycling glass is at best it's a facade that might make the ritual of sorting the garbage seem a pointless waste, because it's cheaper to import glass bottles than recycle them.
"There'll be an uproar when communities or residents know.," Four Corners is told.
Hundreds of thousands of tonnes of glass is accumulating in recycling companies around Australia, with waste industry saying the situation is "unsustainable" because there's no "viable" market for it, the  reports.
Four Corners footage features massive warehouses filled with bagged-up, crushed glass.
Recycling company Polytrade blows the whistle saying a "failure of regulation" means companies don't know what to do with it.
And with Australia consuming about 1.36 million tonnes of glass packaging a year, the situation is getting worse. The price slump in the recycling industry hasn't helped.
"We are back in the dark age and we don't know what to do. We are receiving more and more glass with nowhere to go," Polytrade Rydalmere manager Nathan Ung said.
"The predicament ... is there's no viable market anymore, there's nowhere for the glass to go."
Polytrade says the regulator, NSW Environmental Protection Authority, is aware of the problem - the EPA prohibits stockpiling large amounts in NSW.
"We're dumbfounded because we're receiving glass every day, we don't know what to do with it," Mr Ung said.
"We're forced to stockpile it, and yet there's an EPA regulation that there's a stockpile ruling that we can't stockpile to a certain amount."
A confidential report says glass recycling has reached "crisis" point in New South Wales, with the increasingly attractive - and low cost "solution" - especially in rural and regional areas, to dump it in local landfill.
Australian Council of Recycling (ACOR) president Grant Musgrove claims government inaction and low commodity prices has created "a perfect storm'.
In Victoria, Mr Musgrove said "hundreds of millions of dollars being raised as revenue from the landfill levy" is not being spent.
"Recycling is effectively being taxed to prop up a state government budget," he said.
QUEENSLAND A DUMPING GROUND
Four Corners also reveals rubbish is being trucked in volumes of up to 60,000 tonnes a month from NSW into Queensland by rogue waste operators to save money on dumping in landfill.
Queensland has no waste levy, so interstate operators stand to save millions, the program says, by hailing the waste across the border.
"It's just this giant waste dump for all of Australia to bring their waste to," one source tells the program.
"The rogue element have continued to fly under the radar and the good part of the industry have had to pay the penalty for that," says an industry insider.
Reporter Caro Meldrum-Hanna reveals the trade in rubbish is in some areas so lucrative that unscrupulous operators who are gaming the system and making a fortune in the process.

Four Corners dumps the truth about what's happening to our rubbish. Supplied by ABC

Trashed
Four Corners' Trashed: The Dirty Truth About Your Rubbish airs at 8.30pm Monday on ABC.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corners' Trashed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New South Wales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Ung</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACOR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caro Meldrum-Hanna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Musgrove</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grant Musgrove</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC's Four Corners</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dirty Truth About Your Rubbish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Polytrade Rydalmere</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Polytrade</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Ung</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EPA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Environmental Protection Authority</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Council of Recycling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QUEENSLAND A DUMPING GROUND</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
