<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444573638004501</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/isaac-humphries-returns-home-to-start-his-professional-career-with-sydney-kings/news-story/8ffff31cd703c1ef745c8f8ad18776b5</url>
  <title>Isaac's professional dream starts at home</title>
  <content>
IT has been years in the making, but Sydney-born centre Isaac Humphries finally donned the purple and gold on Monday morning.
Sporting a smile a mile wide beside coach Andrew Gaze, Humphries couldn't be happier to represent his hometown Kings.
Going professional after a successful two-year stint at University of Kentucky, the seven-footer from Caringbah had big dreams.
The highly rated 19-year-old worked out with several NBA franchises over the summer, including Washington, after going undrafted.
Humphries could have signed a lucrative deal in Europe, but the lure of starting his professional career where his basketball journey began motivated him to sign with the Kings.
"I did have options in Europe, but Sydney stuck with me strong," Humphries told The Daily Telegraph.
"At the end of the day it wasn't about money. It's about where I think I would fit best right now.
"I think being at home and with the Kings, which is a great organisation and team, hopefully it plays out as a career development.
"It's my first pro contract, so it is really cool to be playing in Sydney.
"The Kings were pursuing me for a while. They came over to watch me train and play a couple of times.
"I always held them in the back of my head because it's my hometown and the idea to come back and play for my home city is indescribable. In the end I just thought Sydney was the right move for me now."
Humphries is also excited about playing alongside Sydney's experienced Australian stars like Brad Newley and Kevin Lisch.
In fact, he says their presence is a major reason why he linked with the Kings.
"It was something I thought about a lot, just because I eventually want to play for the Boomers," he said.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney-born</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad Newley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Gaze</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Humphries</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Isaac</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Kentucky</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caringbah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin Lisch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Isaac Humphries</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Telegraph</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
