<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443585795509341</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/07/17/05/security-guard-left-in-a-wheelchair-after-brutal-gold-coast-assault</url>
  <title>Gold Coast security guard left in a wheelchair after assault at surf club</title>
  <content>
A moment of split-second madness has changed a Gold Coast security guard's life forever, after he was viciously bashed while on the job.

Veteran officer Ricky Wood is recovering in a wheelchair after the brutal assault at the Burleigh surf life saving club just over a week ago and is unsure whether he'll ever be able to walk properly again.
"You don't think people got the mongrel in them to do stuff like this," Mr Wood said in an exclusive interview with 9NEWS.

The former bodyguard to the stars said he was just five minutes into his shift when he asked a group to leave because he thought they were taking drugs.
They flew into a fit-of-rage, pinning the security guard down as they repeatedly punched and kicked him.
"I think I was just in and out of consciousness," Mr Wood said.
"Got no teeth anymore, a black eye, just get the shakes when I get nervous and my left-hand side's pretty much gone."

Related Articles

Doctors believed Mr Wood may have suffered a minor stroke.
"You don't come to work thinking this is going to happen to you," he said.

Wiping away tears, Mr Wood said he will never be able to work as a security officer again, following his 15-year career.
He is now calling for mandatory rules around guards working with a partner.
"Venues should not have one guard on," he said.

A Queensland Police spokeswoman said six people had been quizzed by officers over the incident but no charges had been laid.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Wood</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ricky Wood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burleigh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
