<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443448356553311</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:08</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/07/15/46/mariam-daoud-rachael-brown-hit-run</url>
  <title>Mother says she is</title>
  <content>
Mariam Daoud moved house this weekend. She just couldn't walk out her front door anymore and stand near the road where her life changed forever.
"Yeah, I'm still alive, but I'm dead from the inside," she told 9NEWS.
"It hurts so much. In a split second that girl changed my life."
"That girl" is Rachael Brown. She was driving home from her work at Chester Hill Public School on October 12, when she hit Mariam - who was standing next to her friend's car, outside her house.
Witnesses saw Mariam's body slam into another car, her legs were thrown into the air and her head collided with Brown's windscreen. She then fell onto the road and slid a short distance before coming to rest behind another car.
CCTV shows items being thrown into the air from the collision. It also shows Brown's Subaru drive away, mount the edge of a driveway and come to a stop outside a childcare centre, where it waited for less than three minutes before driving away.
All of this happened in front of Mariam's 12-year-old son, who she says is traumatised from the incident.

Related Articles

When police tracked down Rachael Brown later that night, they noticed the damage to her car in the driveway, and blood on its windscreen. Brown told them she was aware of the damage but chose to ignore it, and instead of reporting the accident, went home to sleep.
That's what Mariam will never forgive nor understand.
"If I hit a cat or a dog I would stop to see what I had done, or I would go down to see if I could help, for her to, just, like, hit and run, I don't know. I've got no words to actually describe that person," she said.
Mariam is still in constant pain, almost two years after the accident. She suffered a severe traumatic brain injury, multiple fractures and has had several surgeries.
Doctors say she is unlikely to work again.
"I'm telling you, she killed me. Yeah I'm here, my body's here, but that's about it. You know, she killed everything about me.
"Before the accident I was always you know, smiling, jumping around like a little kid, laughing, being there with friends. But now, I've lost everything." 
This week, a District Court judge will decide what punishment Rachael Brown will serve.
She has pleaded guilty to leaving the scene of an accident and dangerous driving occasioning grievous bodily harm.
At the time of the accident she was on a good behaviour bond for drink driving and altering a prescription. Her traffic history also includes five speeding offences.
Whatever sentence she gets, it won't be enough for Mariam.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yeah I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mariam Daoud</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brown's Subaru</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>District Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rachael Brown</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCTV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chester Hill Public School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OCTOBER 12</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brown</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mariam</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
