<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444612292710972</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/sport/afl/jonathan-brown-fires-up-on-the-couch-following-ban-handed-to-tom-hawkins/news-story/f5ebe8777e64736bbd70ec4ca5b124e6</url>
  <title>'We are losing our way': Browny fires up</title>
  <content>
BRISBANE triple premiership great Jonathan Brown has made a passionate plea to the AFL, saying the game is "losing our way" if suspensions continue to be handed down for "insignificant incidents".
Brown's comments come after Geelong forward Tom Hawkins was offered a two-game ban - with an early plea - for striking Swan Dane Rampe, with the penalty impacted by his bad record.
WATCH BROWNY FIRE UP IN OUR VIDEO PLAYER ABOVE
Earlier in the night, Cats football manager Steve Hocking confirmed to Fox Footy's AFL 360 that the club wouldn't challenge Hawkins' ban, as the potential of a three-game ban, should the challenge be unsuccessful at the tribunal, was too great a risk.
But Brown launched an impassioned plea on Fox Footy's On The Couch, saying the Hawkins incident was "nothing more than a forceful push".
"That is a joke," Brown said on Monday night.
LISTEN TO THE ROUND 20 REVIEW FOX FOOTY PODCAST BELOW, OR
"I know he's got form and we can all get on our high horse and say 'look he's got to stop doing these sorts of actions'. (But) it was a forceful push. That is ridiculous.
Brown said people in the northern states sometimes accused the AFL of "being soft", as players were often suspended for "superficial actions".
"Why as a sport do we want to rub players out for these little, insignificant incidents?" Brown asked.
"We are losing our way. I'm all for protecting the players and setting the right example for junior footballers ... but we are losing our way."
Brown said harsher fines, such as $10,000, would be a more appropriate penalty and stop supporters "jumping up and down saying 'we've gone soft'".
"This is where the players need to agree to it," Brown said.
"Going forward, we need to change the way we suspend players."
LIVE stream every game of every round of the 2017 Toyota AFL Premiership Season on FOX SPORTS. Get your free 2-week Foxtel Now trial and start watching in minutes.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Hocking</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathan Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Browny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATCH BROWNY FIRE UP IN OUR VIDEO PLAYER ABOVE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toyota AFL Premiership Season</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swan Dane Rampe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawkins</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FOX SPORTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxtel Now</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox Footy's On</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brown</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ROUND 20 REVIEW FOX FOOTY PODCAST BELOW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Hawkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox Footy's AFL 360</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
