<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444182795973677</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-07/commbank-response-to-money-laundering-allegations-woeful/8782316</url>
  <title>Commonwealth Bank response to money laundering allegations 'woeful', Nick Xenophon says</title>
  <content>
Politicians from all sides are asking for answers from Commonwealth Bank chief executive Ian Narev over allegations it facilitated money laundering activity and turned a blind eye to terror financing.

Key points:

Nick Xenophon is calling for a major overhaul of anti-money laundering regulations
Labor has redoubled its calls for a royal commission in light of AUSTRAC's allegations
Former and current Liberal MPs say a royal commission still is not the answer

Financial intelligence agency AUSTRAC has filed claims in the Federal Court  by failing to report suspicious transactions on time.
But  and says his attention is focused on preparing the bank's annual results announcement on Wednesday.
South Australian senator Nick Xenophon said Mr Narev's response to the allegations was "pretty woeful".
He is calling for a major overhaul of anti-money laundering regulations.
"[The Commonwealth Bank] need to take this seriously. I don't think they have," Senator Xenophon said.
"Potentially 53,000 offences, potentially $1 trillion worth of fines - it really begs the question.
"We need to be brought into line with laws in the UK and the US where there can be criminal responsibility on the part of senior executives and directors for this sort of offence."
The bank admits the nearly 54,000 law breaches were caused by a software error, but Senator Xenophon said the Commonwealth Bank board must now decide Mr Narev's fate.
"If it can be shown that an organisation didn't do everything possible, have measures and risk controls to prevent this sort of offence from occurring, then the directors and senior executives of a corporation ought to be liable," he said.
"The buck stops with the CEO and the board of directors. The sort of spin that Mr Narev has given in the last 24 hours has been pretty woeful."
Labor renews calls for banking royal commission

The bank itself also remains the target of public anger and frustration and Labor has redoubled calls for a royal commission into the banking sector.
In a statement, Labor's financial services spokeswoman Katy Gallagher said Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull must act in the interest of Australians.
"The charges by AUSTRAC against the Commonwealth Bank relating to breaches of money laundering and anti-terrorism laws are extremely serious and deeply concerning," Ms Gallagher said.
Coalition MP Craig Kelly said while the Commonwealth Bank still has a lot of explaining to do, a royal commission remains a bridge too far.
"It appears that the Commonwealth Bank have thought they could operate above the law," Mr Kelly said.
"[They] have acted what appears to be illegally, they've been caught through the existing system, they'll have to answer for what they've done, and they face a very significant and heavy fine.
"I'm not sure how a royal commission would change that or would add any value to what's already there."
Former Liberal leader John Hewson agrees, and said a royal commission would be a waste of time and money.
"They've moved into the courts and they're solving the problem - the royal commission just pushes out years and costs a fortune," Mr Hewson said.
"[AUSTRAC] is doing its job, the process is running, and the people are being brought to account. I don't think you can ask for anything more than that."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Xenophon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hewson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Gallagher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUSTRAC</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Narev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Narev</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Xenophon</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coalition MP Craig Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katy Gallagher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Hewson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Bank</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
