<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443499896161789</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/finance/work/careers/macquarie-university-launches-250000-medical-degree/news-story/747621cd10a82525bf904012a658c4ab</url>
  <title>Macquarie University launches $250,000 medical degree</title>
  <content>
Seven News: University students protest fee changes
0:30

Students are protesting over university fee changes outside of Crown Casino ahead of treasurer Scott Morrison's post-budget speech. Courtesy: 7 News

May 12th 2017
3 months ago
/video/video.news.com.au/News/

Macquarie University's medical degree has just got the tick of approval from Australia's medical board.

Share

IN great news for school leavers from wealthy families and a terrifying blow to everyone else, an Australian university has launched a $250,000 degree.
From 2018, up to 40 Australian students and 20 international ones will be able to enrol in Macquarie University's four-year, graduate-entry Doctor of Medicine program.
Domestic students will pay $64,000 per year, totalling $256,000. International students will have to fork out $280,000 over the four years.
The university claims the course will provide students with "a high-quality and innovative learning experience". Students will be required to spend a placement at a hospital in Hyderabad in India as well as placements at Sydney's Royal North Shore hospital.
According to the university's executive dean of medical and health sciences Professor Patrick McNeil, the course will aim to "train future leaders in healthcare, who are patient and safety focused, culturally responsive, globally aware and equipped to work within increasingly digital health systems".
The course has just received the go-ahead from the Australian Medical Council and Medical Board of Australia despite opposition from doctors' and students' groups.
Australian Medical Students Association vice president Douglas Roche told news.com.au the organisation was "appalled".
"This brings many challenges, the first being the barrier to entry. It's going to cost more than $250,000 which is going to be a deterrent to many low SES (socio-economic status) students to study medicine. In addition they're not going to be guaranteed a job when they graduate," he said.
Mr Roche said the course would also create challenges for the medical workforce, where there is currently a glut of junior doctors desperately trying to get into specialist fields to further their career prospects.

"We have a large number of doctors who are now trying to qualify for specialist training and this is going to exacerbate that," he said.
"Because of the debt these students will be in they're more likely to want to go into higher paying specialties, which is not what the community needs."
National Union of Students president Sophie Johnstone told news.com.au the introduction of a $250,000 degrees would lead to a much bigger problems in the education system.
"It's worrying especially for a degree like medicine where we're saying only the wealthiest people in Australia can be doctors, can be doing research into curing diseases, and the more disadvantaged group of people can't do that," she said.
"It's already taking us into this two-tiered education that was feared when the concept of $100,000 degrees came up. We're already there."
The Australian Medical Association has labelled the course a "cash grab".
In a tweet commenting on Macquarie's announcement of its new course, the AMA said: "Australia needs more training places for medical graduates, not new $250,000 degrees."
Last December AMA president Michael slammed the "ill-conceived" proposed degree, and wrote to Rural Health minister David Gillespie saying as much.
"This is an ill-conceived (idea) that will simply waste precious health system resources for the benefit of a privileged few who will be able to afford entry," Dr Gannon wrote.
"The University has failed to consult with the profession and we feel that it is driven largely by financial considerations, and for reasons of prestige as opposed to addressing genuine medical workforce needs."
Unlike other Australian universities, Macquarie will not receive government subsidies to its medical degree, meaning students will have to pay the high fees.
At Bond University, which is offers Australia's only existing private, full-fee medical degree, students already pay more than $350,000 to complete the course.
A spokeswoman for Macquarie University told news.com.au there was government assistance and scholarships available to students entering their Doctor of Medicine degree.
Domestic students are eligible for FEE-HELP with the maximum a student studying medicine can borrow in 2017 financial year at $126,101.
Scholarship options can cover up to $50,000 of students fees. There are two indigenous scholarships and one "medical leader of the future" scholarships for that amount, and up to five other scholarships worth $30,000 a year.
Macquarie University has advised admission to the program will be "highly competitive", and as well as forking out for the fees, applicants will need to "demonstrate a high level of achievement in tertiary study and the Graduate Medical School Admissions Test (GAMSAT), as well as completion of a number of prerequisites".
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Gillespie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FEE-HELP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doctor of Medicine</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Roche</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Medical Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Medical Students Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Union of Students</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hyderabad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Gannon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bond University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SES</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>India</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macquarie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Morrison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macquarie University</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Patrick McNeil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rural Health</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Medical Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown Casino</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Medical Board of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney's Royal North Shore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GAMSAT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Douglas Roche</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AMA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December AMA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sophie Johnstone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graduate Medical School Admissions Test</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
