<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443495601194437</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/entertainment/tv/the-great-british-bake-off-has-been-given-a-quirky-revamp-welcoming-a-comedian-to-its-judging-line-up/news-story/317e01fdd6e7ccc47da8d398a43c5800</url>
  <title>The Great British Bake Off has been given a quirky revamp, welcoming a comedian to it's judging line up</title>
  <content>
Trailer: The Great British Bake Off
1:00

The Great British Bake Off, coming soon to the UK's Channel 4...

August 7th 2017
8 hours ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment - syndicated/

Is this the greatest trailer ever for a food show?

delicious

Share

WITH food shows common, standing out from the pack isn't an easy task but it's an important one. But The Great British Bake Off is a series that has done this with aplomb with the launch of the trailer for its new season. A quirky trailer is an ideal accessory for a show that has had somewhat of a quirky revamp - moving from the BBC to Channel 4 and welcoming comedian Noel Fielding to its judging line-up.
The definition of thinking outside the box, the trailer is a sing-a-long with a bounty of baked goods. Bread, profiteroles, croissants, cakes, bagels, tarts, eclairs and pasties unite to croon to Paul McCartney's We all stand together.

Mikey Please of creator Parabella, told UK site It's Nice That, the trailer is an homage to British eccentricity and patriotism. "[It's] an homage to all things great and British and baked. A celebration of broken, imperfect things. Of togetherness despite differences. Of weirdos. Of home. The over the top efforts that people go to in order to make a really fancy pants cake," he explains.

But the project itself wasn't without its trials and tribulations, with a team of bakers and animators working together to create 335 baked characters. 500 eggs, 50kg of flour and 28kg of sugar was used in the making of the advert. "Pretty much everything you see on camera is edible," says Mikey. "That we used real cake, icing and bread, lent the film a crusty authenticity. It also meant that stuff crumbled, sunk in the oven, went too soggy, went too hard. Turns out bake-mation is similar to stop motion animation in that it's riddled with little hiccups that become central to the final piece."
But the project itself wasn't without its trials and tribulations, with a team of bakers and animators working together to create 335 baked characters. 500 eggs, 50kg of flour and 28kg of sugar was used in the making of the advertisement, which may not be to everyone's tastes but is without a doubt just as fun as the show itself.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BBC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Great British Bake Off</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mikey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noel Fielding</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mikey Please</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nice That</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parabella</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul McCartney's We</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK's Channel 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
