<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443895033159764</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:52</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/sport/boxing/jeff-horn-sweat-and-blood-await-as-he-prepares-for-manny-pacquiao-rematch-20170807-gxqqb9.html</url>
  <title>Jeff Horn: Sweat and blood await as he prepares for Manny Pacquiao rematch</title>
  <content>
These are good days for Jeff Horn. He drives a shiny new sponsor-supplied Lexus, instead of a Camry that has been around the block at Acacia Ridge one too many times.
His new-found fame has opened doors he never realised existed prior to his ownership of the WBO welterweight belt, won in such memorable style in early July. And if the rumblings are true, a life-changing payday is on the way before Christmas. A baby, too, with wife Jo.

Up Next

Australian sport great Betty Cuthbert dies aged 79

03:34

More Sports HQ Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Horn stuns Pacquiao and boxing world

Jeff Horn produced an upset for the ages beating boxing legend Manny Pacquiao via unanimous decision for the WBO welterweight title.

But if Horn wanted something to bring into focus the renewed challenge that awaits him later in the year, it was in the corner of the boxing ring as he returned to training for the first time since dethroning Manny Pacquiao.
There, in a gym decked out with finery from the fight at Suncorp Stadium, was a white pad still stained with Pacquiao's blood. This was where the Filipino icon sat as his corner tried to stem the bleeding from two deep gashes to the head in the brutal and controversial unanimous decision loss.

Horn didn't fare that much better in the beauty stakes. The cut above his eye, which threatened to have the fight stopped, still shows a visible scar and minor swelling five weeks after the fact. Other than that, he's on top of the world.
"It does bring back some memories," Horn said. "That's the exact corner the pad was in and it's still got the blood on it. It's pretty much like I'm nearly there - except with 50,000 people less."

It was hardly a Ricky Hatton moment (the English champion famously expanded his girth between fights) but it was a contented Horn that returned to the mercy of trainer Glenn Rushton on Monday, weighing 10 kilograms more than his fighting weight thanks to an indulgence in chocolate and donuts.

You will now receive updates from

Sport Newsletter

Sport Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Talk of a rematch has gained momentum in the past week, with Top Rank's Bob Arum saying Pacquiao had told him he wants to exercise the clause in his contract and fight Horn for the second time.Photo: AAP
Given he's a Senator in the Philippines, a nation combating Islamic militants on their own soil, when and where the fight will happen remains anyone's guess. Already a November window has widened to include December, with one of the Australian east coast capitals the staging point.
Horn just wants to make sure he's in shape should Pacquiao spring a fight six weeks out. The controversy over the scoring, reviewed in his favour by a further five judges, has left him hungry to prove this was no highway robbery.Photo: AP
"I'm happy for a rematch, especially after all the flak I received before the second scoring came out. Now it's out, I still receive people saying I didn't win. I'm willing to prove it again and beat him for the second time," Horn said.
"I'm still proving a point. I've got to make sure I train just as hard. I never say I want a knockout but it's always easier if the fight ends before the 12th round." Photo: Phil Lutton
Horn's fighting style and relative lack of hype to international pundits means he's likely to start as the underdog in just about every big fight he encounters. That's unlikely to give him much concern but he knows if Pacquiao comes back, he's coming back harder than the first time.
"I can improve a lot more from where I have been in the past. I think I did well in the last fight, I'll do better the second time," he said. "I've done it before, I know what I have to do to try hard and do it again. I know I can push through to more levels."
Rushton believes the rematch is now 99 per cent probable. The when and particularly, the where, are up for debate. The Horn camp remain keen for another outing at Suncorp Stadium but talk of air curtains around the ring and giant coolers remains fanciful.
More likely, it would head indoors. The Queensland government has first and last rights but their entertainment centre only holds 13,000 fans. Melbourne has Etihad Stadium with a roof while Sydney's Qudos Bank Arena holds 21,000, which should suit Nicole Kidman, who has told Arum that's the right city for the sequel.
Everything now hinges on Pacquiao, who could yet make life so difficult that any rematch goes to the "too hard" basket. It's not like the 11-time world champion doesn't have enough to keep him busy in his political life, which he must abandon for two months to avenge his loss.
Rushton again urged Pacquiao to sign up to VADA random drug testing should the fight eventuate. That doesn't appear to be a deal-breaker given how loud money talks in boxing but any resistance from the Filipino's camp would raise eyebrows as he tries to rebound on the verge of turning 39.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senators</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Filipino</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suncorp Stadium</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lexus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Top Rank's Bob Arum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney's Qudos Bank Arena</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philippines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicole Kidman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VADA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sports HQ Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Betty Cuthbert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WBO</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rushton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenn Rushton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ricky Hatton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pacquiao</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phil Lutton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeff Horn</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manny Pacquiao</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Acacia Ridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Camry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
