<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443499896161783</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:20</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/coast-child-rapist-may-die-in-prison/3209762/</url>
  <title>Coast child rapist will probably die in prison</title>
  <content>
A SUNSHINE Coast man who raped his nine-year-old step-granddaughter and sexually abused his eight-year-old step-granddaughter is expected to be in prison or under a suspended sentence until his death.

The 72-year-old bowel cancer patient, who cannot be named to protect the identity of his victims, appeared in Maroochydore District Court yesterday for sentencing on three counts of rape and six counts of indecent treatment of a child under 12 in his care.

Doctors have estimated he has 30 months to live, and the man will spend 10 of those months in prison, after which his sentence will be suspended until August 2021.

The elderly man sat in the prisoner's dock, dressed in a blue jumper and slacks as judge Gary Long made the sentencing remarks.

Mr Long said the man took advantage of the girls' vulnerability and the family's trust in the offences committed from April to June, 2015.

"(The girls) themselves indicated this was not isolated offending," Mr Long said.

The court heard the man digitally raped the older girl three times, made her kiss him and touch his genitals, and took baths with her in which his genitals touched her.

He also touched the younger girl's genitals while she was sitting on his lap.

Mr Long also took the man's early guilty plea, his age and his deteriorating health into consideration in the sentencing.

The man's family sat in the courtroom's public gallery during the proceedings.

Night of crashes rounds out weekend of heartbreak on Coast roads
Greens' Coast election campaign in disarray
Anger over being thrown out of Coast venue
Close call for Coast motorists as debris goes flying on motorway
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
A NATIONAL exhibition of ceramic art has been launched on the Coast
ONE of Hollywood's most adorable couples is over.
New celebrity cooking show fails to fire for Seven.
The legendary creator isn't so sure about how Netflix works.
*WARNING this story contains spoilers*
TARA Reid reveals what's coming in the next installment of TV movie.
Garth Prowd's vision made huge impact on Sunshine Coast community
Home sells in just one day
Winners in Master Builders regional housing and construction awards
Ray and Gert will celebrate 70 years of marrive this week
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garth Prowd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2021</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tara Reid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Long</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore District Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gary Long</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greens' Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
