<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444655242384663</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:49</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/news/west-footscray-train-station-fatal-stabbing-victim-cousin-of-soldier-found-dead-after-bucks-party/news-story/7138503464654b40f487e859e7380700</url>
  <title>Stabbing victim related to buck's party soldier</title>
  <content>
THE family of an Australian soldier who was found dead after a buck's party has suffered another tragedy, with the cousin of the deceased servicewoman identified as the man who was fatally stabbed on Saturday night.
Marcus Rowley, a 24-year-old Melbourne man, has been confirmed as the victim who died after .
The father of two had returned from Perth only three days before he was killed.
Mr Rowley had attended the funeral of his cousin, Natasha Rowley, the Australian soldier who was  on July 16.
Ms Rowley's body was discovered in the shower by a group of men who had been celebrating a buck's party.
Her funeral was held last Tuesday in Perth. Mourners were asked to wear a "splash of purple" to the service.
Mr Rowley, an Epping resident, was found by emergency crews after they were called to Ashley St in West Footscray on Saturday night.
Ambulance Victoria crews found Mr Rowley suffering significant stab wounds to his back.
Paramedics attempted to revive the young father but he died on the scene.
A 35-year-old Avondale Heights man has since been taken into custody over the incident.
"Homicide Squad detectives are investigating the circumstances surrounding the death and are awaiting the results of a post mortem," Victoria Police spokeswoman Leading Senior Constable Melissa Seach said.
Mr Rowley's former partner, Caris Miles, told Seven News of the pain the now fatherless family will endure.
"I don't understand how you could take a father away from his kids, especially when they are so young and they will never know him," she said.
"I still don't believe it. I still am expecting him to call or to be like, 'It's a big joke'. He was such a good person and taken way too soon."
Ms Miles said Mr Rowley had been rocked by the sudden death of his cousin and was still recovering from the shock when he was killed.
In a Facebook post on July 18, Mr Rowley posted a photo of himself with Ms Rowley. The post came just two days after Ms Rowley was found dead at The Oaks on Market apartments.

Police say the death of a woman found in a Melbourne hotel room is being treated as suspicious.

Melbourne hotel death deemed 'not suspicious'
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Avondale Heights</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Rowley</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oak</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 16</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Natasha Rowley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ashley St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caris Miles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Epping</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ambulance Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leading Senior Constable Melissa Seach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Footscray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marcus Rowley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seven News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Rowley</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Miles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
