<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444101191593677</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/lifestyle/relationships/whats-the-worst-way-to-get-dumped/news-story/ab7f4fa51b74278229b4e7da409d00bd</url>
  <title>Is this the worst way to dump someone?</title>
  <content>
EARLIER this year, a "friend" of mine was dumped by a man she'd been seeing for a while. My friend - let's call her 'Cherri Fackville' - was pretty surprised by the dumping.
Her man friend invited her out for a drink, smiled at her and told her she looked beautiful (which she did, she'd taken a long time with her hair that evening), and chatted cheerily for a while before mentioning that he'd met someone else.
And so there she was, poor, beautiful Cherri Fackville (who is also intelligent, funny, and an excellent conversationalist) heartbroken in the middle of a pub.
"Why couldn't you have told me in an email?" she asked him, blinking back tears.
"Because I don't like doing things that way," he said.
"Well I don't like being upset in the middle of a pub," she told him, before throwing her drink in his face and leaving. (Okay, she didn't actually throw her drink, she placed it carefully down on the table, but still.)
Back at home, Cherri raged down the phone to her friend, who I'll call 'Kylie', because that's actually her name. "Why did he have to invite me out so he could dump me in public? Why couldn't he do it by email like a regular person?"
"Insensitive bastard," Kylie proclaimed. And Cherri nodded vigorously and agreed.
But later that night, as Cherri was lying in bed, she remembered another dumping she experienced. (Honestly, it's absurd, these men don't appreciate how fabulous she is.) On that occasion, the man in question emailed her, informing her in a brief, eloquent message that he had met someone else. (Not the same 'someone else' as the more recent man, though that would have been quite poetic.)
And on that occasion, when she received her exit papers online and not in person, she was outraged.
"How could he just cut me off like that via email?" she yelled to Kylie. "What kind of person does that?"
"An insensitive bastard," Kylie proclaimed. And Cherri nodded through her tears, and agreed.
So what is the best way to dump someone, I wondered, as Cherri tried fitfully to sleep. Is it in person, which arguably honours the relationship, but makes you vulnerable and distressed in the presence of the dumper? Or via email, which is impersonal and distant, but offers you privacy to deal with your hurt?
Neither, I decided. They both suck.
Because in the case of breakups, it is not the medium. The message is all that matters. I mean, sure, no-one wants to get broken-up with via Facebook, or by hearing the news from someone else, or - god forbid - by a post-it.

Breakups deserve a modicum of gravitas and consideration, and you can't convey that on a square of yellow paper.
Ultimately, however, being rejected is going to hurt, no matter how the rejection is presented. You can wrap it in a sonnet, you can offer it with flowers, or you can scribble it on a postcard, and it's still going to say the same thing: I don't want to be with you anymore.
So to both of Cherri's exes I say this: You did the right thing. There's no easy way to dump someone, and you both did it as best you could.
And I also say this: You're an utter, utter fool. My friend Cherri Fackville is a catch. And she'll do much better than you.
You can follow Kerri Sackville on  and .
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kylie</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cherri</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cherri Fackville</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kerri Sackville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
