<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443452651520693</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-07/donald-trump-administration-chaos-us-can-recover-zoellick-says/8782188</url>
  <title>US can recover from Donald Trump's chaos, World Bank ex-boss tells Diggers and Dealers forum</title>
  <content>
The United States will recover from any perceived damage caused by the chaos engulfing Donald Trump's administration, a former World Bank president has told the Diggers and Dealers mining forum.
Speaking after delivering the forum's keynote address in the WA mining town of Kalgoorlie, Robert Zoellick said the strength of the US private sector remained its primary advantage, but global uncertainty was still a serious concern.
"Can the United States recover from any self-inflicted wounds? Sure," Mr Zoellick said.
"[But] what I am getting some added worry about is that as people are uncertain about US direction, they will inevitably start to make adjustments - and some of those might be mistaken."
Mr Zoellick served as World Bank president from 2007 to 2012, after stints as a deputy secretary of state and a senior US trade representative under president George W Bush.
Despite the uncertainty surrounding Mr Trump's approach to foreign policy, he said it was critical that global leaders did not overreact.
"I'm a person who has been very committed to the international security, economic and political order that the United States helped create over 70 years," he said.
"...I think that Trump doesn't value that to the same degree, but this is more than one man."
He pointed to North Korea, and the rising nuclear ambitions of leader Kim Jong-un in the Asia Pacific, as the number one risk to global security.
Australia, Mr Zoellick said, had a critical role to play in calming tensions in the region, as well as easing diplomatic issues emerging during the Trump administration.
"I hope Australia can play a steadying role," he said.
"Because Australia has a lot of ties and Australians understand the US system better than many throughout Asia.
"It's important not to underestimate the dangers, but it's also important not to overreact in an international sense."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Zoellick</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Bank</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kim Jong-un</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George W. Bush</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Zoellick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia Pacific</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kalgoorlie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
