<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443706054595604</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/afl/afl-news/carlton-ready-to-shake-off-the-blues-and-launch-a-cash-splash-20170807-gxqxl9.html</url>
  <title>Carlton ready to shake off the blues and launch a 'cash splash' </title>
  <content>
Carlton are preparing to launch a cash splash in a year when the Blues could also boast the No.1  picks in the national and pre-season drafts.
As the Blues begin to fine tune their desired post-season shopping spree, they are also becoming increasingly confident that star midfielder Bryce Gibbs will remain.

Up Next

Dockers end their losing streak

01:30

More AFL Real Footy Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

AFL plays of round 20

It's all about the six pointers; Hannebery through traffic kicks a ripper, Coniglio has a claim to GOTY in Canberra, McDonald-Tipungwuti nutmegs Petrevski-Seton at the G, Billings clutch kick against West Coast and Eddie Betts is back from surgery to work his usual magic from the pocket.

Should Gibbs stay, the Blues say their salary cap will still have ample room to accommodate the headline acts on their hit list; out-of-contract Greater Western Sydney Giants, Josh Kelly and Jacob Hopper.
It's understood the Blues have a significant amount of room under their salary cap, which has only grown since the AFL's new collective bargaining agreement was brokered. There will be even more room once players are moved on.

Kelly is weighing up a nine-year, multimillion dollar offer to join North Melbourne, while St Kilda are also in the race for the silky midfielder.
Former Essendon great Matthew Lloyd said over the weekend he sensed the Giants were losing Kelly.

"I think that people at the Giants believe that by the day and by the week, they're losing touch with Kelly and that he, in a sense, is withdrawing himself from that football club," Lloyd said on 3AW.

You will now receive updates from

Realfooty Newsletter

Realfooty Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"He's still playing OK, but they feel like he doesn't look them in the eye like he used to. Maybe they feel like that he's out the door?"Photo: AAP Image
Fairfax Media understands the Giants were astounded by Lloyd's comments, insisting Kelly had become even more active in asking about the welfare of teammates and their families in recent weeks. It's also understood Kelly has the option of signing a short- or long-term deal with the club.
Midfielder Hopper, the No.7 overall selection in the 2015 draft, returned to the side last weekend after a long-term ankle injury. He hails from TAC Cup side North Ballarat. The Giants are confident he will stay.Photo: Julian Smith
The Blues, with list manager Steve Silvagni as their mastermind, have made it clear midfield depth is a priority, an issue highlighted by recent injuries to hard-nut midfielders Patrick Cripps and Ed Curnow. This has meant skipper Marc Murphy has had to return to more of an inside role, having relished more time on the wing until the injuries.
The Blues, set to possibly finish last  this year but boasting five Rising Star nominees, know they will need to make strong progress in 2018 in what will be coach Brendon Bolton's third year in charge. That they again will have one of the top draft picks will help to either secure quality young talent or consummate a deal for an established star in the right age bracket.
While Kelly and Hopper remain top of the priority list, Fairfax Media can reveal the Blues have also flagged strong interest in Port Adelaide's Jackson Trengove. The out-of-contract utility has indicated he wants to stay at Alberton. The Power are understood to have a tight salary-cap and Trengove, 26, is understood to be on about $750,000 in a heavily back-ended deal.
The Blues are also circling Giants small forward Devon Smith, the runner-up in the 2014 best and fairest. Smith, a product of the Geelong Falcons, is out of contract this year and said last month he "hopefully" would re-sign with the club.
The future of Dale Thomas, who will earn only a fraction of his $750,000 wage should he stay, remains unclear. His management is happy to wait until the end of the season for an answer, although there is industry speculation Thomas, 30, will go on. The former Collingwood premiership star hopes to play on.
The Blues have not yet made a call but are debating whether to re-sign him for another year with a view to bolstering overall depth of not only the senior list but also the VFL team, which has been recently decimated by injury.
Thomas had asked the Blues in May to waive the trigger clause - understood to have been 15 senior games - giving him the option of another season. The Blues agreed to his request. His 15th game came against Essendon on Saturday, when he had a season-high 22 touches. Bolton has praised his leadership.
Gibbs requested a trade home to South Australia at the end of last year, a decision which he then described as family oriented. While the Crows are believed to be still interested in the gun midfielder, the Blues are confident of retaining him, given they are yet to be officially told that Gibbs will again seek a trade at season's end.
He is contracted until the end of 2019 and the Crows would have to provide a suitable deal involving a first-round draft pick and a quality, established player to have any chance of snaring him.
"With two years left on his contract I'd expect him to be at Carlton," Blues chief executive Steven Trigg said last month.
Gibbs has enjoyed another stellar year, averaging 27 disposals and is one of the hot favourites to take out the best and fairest.
Key forward Levi Casboult is an unrestricted free agent and has the opportunity to explore the open market. He has been linked to Richmond and Fremantle. His financial demands are likely to determine whether the Blues maintain him or match any rival offer.
Ruckman Matthew Kreuzer has arguably enjoyed his finest season and has triggered a clause tying him to the club next year. He is likely to be granted an extension of multiple years beyond 2018.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Petrevski-Seton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CROWS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Lloyd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Realfooty Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trengove, 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eddie Betts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bryce Gibbs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rising Star</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide's Jackson Trengove</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Devon Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Cripps</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong Falcons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dale Thomas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ed Curnow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Real Footy Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coniglio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDonald-Tipungwuti</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greater Western Sydney Giants</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thomas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacob Hopper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hopper</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lloyd</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brendon Bolton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Kreuzer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>G</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Ballarat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TAC Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Levi Casboult</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JULIAN SMITH</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fremantle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marc Murphy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gibbs</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelly</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP Image</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dockers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Silvagni</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hannebery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steven Trigg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alberton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
