<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443456946488093</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/messenger/planning-minister-john-looking-into-the-possibility-of-new-heritage-bill-after-discussion-paper-backlash/news-story/3d6679a264ff4fb55eb9d22da9e322ef</url>
  <title>John Rau cagy on new heritage Bill</title>
  <content>
PLANNING Minister John Rau is working on new laws to reform the state's heritage protection system - but will not say what they might be or whether the legislation will even see the light of day.
Mr Rau saidhe was "looking into the possibility" of a heritage Bill following the release last year of a discussion paper canvassing changes to the local heritage listing process.
Residents, councils and National Trust SA voiced concern about the paper, which suggested allowing heritage-listed buildings to be demolished on "merit" and handing control of assessments to the state Planning Department.
Mr Rau said he had not "settled" on any changes, but highlighted his concern that the criteria for local heritage listing had been "diluted" because of a confusion between heritage and character.
"Heritage is about individual properties ... character is about the feel of the street," Mr Rau said.
"What has happened in the past is that the two have become blurred and we have had some attempts to achieve a character outcome by diluting the heritage criteria.
"What I want to do with the new planning zones is to create ... character outcomes without having to have regard for heritage."
Mr Rau planned in the coming months to have some "discreet conversations" with industry experts before deciding whether to pursue a heritage Bill before next year's state election.
"I would need to discuss it with Cabinet and I need them to either say 'yes' or 'no, we are not happy'," he said.
"I have been working on this for a while, but if we are not ready then it will not happen."
The Planning Department last year received 190 submissions on the discussion paper after it extended the period of public consultation amid an overwhelming response.
Norwood, Payneham & St Peters Council letterboxed almost 22,000 homes about the proposed changes, which it feared might result in "significant and irreversible" damage to the area.
St Peters Residents' Association president David Cree last week said the state's heritage protection system "worked very well" and there was no basis for reform.
How do you think the state's heritage laws should be changed, if they should be?
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minister John Rau</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Peters Residents' Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Planning Department</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Rau</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Payneham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Cree</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Trust SA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NORWOOD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Rau</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Peters Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
