<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444272990288648</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/rugby-union/union-news/competition-for-wallabies-back-row-spots-heating-up-ahead-of-bledisloe-cup-opener-20170807-gxr27h.html</url>
  <title>Competition for Wallabies spots heating up ahead of Bledisloe Cup</title>
  <content>
One of the biggest question marks two weeks out from the Bledisloe Cup opener is the make-up of the Wallabies back row. 
Across the ditch, New Zealand's back row of Jerome Kaino, Sam Cane and captain Kieran Read is all but assured and one of the most rock-solid departments in the All Blacks team.Photo: Daniel Munoz
Michael Hooper, Australia's new full-time captain, will start at openside breakaway and provide the glue to the Wallabies back row. 
This year, however, there is no David Pocock. He doesn't come back into the fold until next year, leaving Australia a player short in the pilfering department and without someone who can be a genuine threat over the ball. Photo: Stuart Walmsley/ARU media
That leaves Lopeti Timani, Sean McMahon, Ned Hanigan and Jack Dempsey in the 34-man Wallabies squad with Test experience to their name. 
The quartet is raring to go in Cessnock, desperate to prove to Michael Cheika their worth and why they should get a gig in Australia's starting XV on August 19. 

There is also 22-year-old rookie Adam Korczyk from the Queensland Reds, who was surprised by his inclusion in a reduced squad, having playing almost half his games off the bench this year in Super Rugby. 

You will now receive updates from

Rugbyheaven Newsletter

Rugbyheaven Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"With the Bledisloe coming up, I'm trying to put my hand up to try and make the matchday 23 and do my best," Korczyk said.
"I've still go to learn my role a bit more with the knowledge and the game plan but I'm just trying to get on top of that and get my knowledge down pat. 
"When I made the final cut it was exciting. I want to be a Wallaby, that's the goal. I'm glad to be here." 
Korczyk was born in Auckland and moved to Australia when he was 12, having played mostly soccer given his family originated from Poland. 
His preferred position is No.6 but he is highly unlikely to see any Test action for the next little period.
As for the preferred candidates, Cheika identified Hanigan, a NSW Waratah, as one of Australia's best players in the June series. 
The 22-year-old started in all three Tests and caught the eye of many astute judges but there is no reason why Cheika could not pick McMahon at No.6. 
McMahon can play anywhere in the back row and started his last two Super Rugby matches for the Rebels at No.6, even if he was predominately used at No.8 during internationals last year.
Cheika, however, is a big fan of Timani at No.8 and without Scott Higginbotham in this squad, the big-boned Tongan's chances of starting at the back of the scrum are increasing.
Dempsey, who was used as a development player on last year's spring tour, came off the bench against Italy in Brisbane but is unlikely to push ahead of Hanigan in the pecking order  before the Rugby Championship gets under way.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cheika</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Timani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>XV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>All Blacks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Super Rugby</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Waratahs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Hooper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rugbyheaven Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bledisloe Cup</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Munoz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dempsey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Dempsey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ned Hanigan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tongan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Korczyk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Poland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Cane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Cheika</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jerome Kaino</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wallabies</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McMahon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Reds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Pocock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sean McMahon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lopeti Timani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Korczyk</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cessnock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hanigan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Higginbotham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bledisloe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Auckland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rugby Championship</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kieran Read</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stuart Walmsley/ARU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
