<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444320234929594</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:31</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/nsw/my-heart-will-never-be-the-same-christopher-mcgrail-shot-by-police-in-grafton-20170807-gxqycl.html</url>
  <title>'My heart will never be the same': Christopher McGrail shot by police in Grafton</title>
  <content>
A northern NSW man shot dead by police described himself as a "shattered father [and] disgruntled ex-partner" and had posted online about his hatred of police.
Christopher Peter McGrail, 45, was  at about 4pm on Sunday after police were called to a domestic disturbance at a unit.

Up Next

Moore announces tent city deal

00:54

More NSW News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Man shot dead by police in Grafton identified

Christopher McGrail has died in hospital after police shot him during a stand-off on a Grafton Street. Vision: Seven News.

Mr McGrail, known to his friends as Uncle Hop, allegedly confronted three officers on the street with a knife.
Police deployed capsicum spray and a Taser but both failed to subdue the man, NSW Police Assistant Commissioner Max Mitchell said on Monday.

He was then shot twice and died several hours later in hospital.
Mr McGrail was recently released on parole after serving time in prison for a police chase, possession of cannabis and domestic violence. He had convictions for methamphetamine supply, drug possession and other domestic incidents.

He was on bail on charges of assaulting and stalking his ex-partner and having an offensive implement in a public place.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

In a rambling post on his Facebook on Thursday, he accused the police of "aiding and abetting those u dispise [sic] yet u deal your lies and shun the 1 who blows the whistle...u bashd a boy whos now a man on problem."Photo: Facebook
In other posts, he wrote "f--- the 50 and their corruption" and called the police "swine".
However, he also said that suicide awareness was "an issue close to my heart" following the death of his teenage son in 2015.Photo: Facebook
The ex-partner and mother of his four children appeared to share witness accounts of the shooting online on Sunday before realising it was her ex-partner involved.
After he passed away in Gold Coast University Hospital, she posted: "the 2 most important men in my life... are both reunited".Photo: Facebook
"My heart will never be the same cause now another part has been shattered," she posted, alongside videos of Mr McGrail playing the guitar and singing by their son's grave.
Residents near the Turf Street unit heard police yelling "drop the knife" several times on Sunday afternoon.
One witness said he saw "cops shoot a bloke waving a knife around".
Another witness said they saw three police officers draw their guns before shooting twice.
Mr Mitchell, the commander for the northern region, said on Monday that the response from the three officers - a sergeant and two constables - followed "textbook" procedure.
"No police officer wants to shoot and it is traumatic," he said.
"I've spoken to one of the officers involved, and I'm hoping the local area commander and supervisor have provided excellent support to those officers overnight."
He appealed for witnesses to come forward.
The critical incident follows the  outside Central Station less than two weeks ago.
Both shootings are the subject of critical incident investigations that will be monitored by the new Law Enforcement Conduct Condition.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christopher McGrail</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taser</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central Station</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uncle Hop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Police Assistant Commissioner Max Mitchell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turf Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr McGrail</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grafton Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Mitchell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grafton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seven News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Law Enforcement Conduct Condition</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast University Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christopher Peter McGrail, 45</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
