<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443968047605013</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/07/18/35/customers-furious-after-glitch-sees-woolies-double-dip-on-grocery-bills</url>
  <title>Customers furious after glitch sees Woolies double-dip on grocery bills</title>
  <content>
A billing bungle has seen some Woolworths customers out of pocket by hundreds of dollars after they were charged twice for their purchases.
People who shopped at Woolworths, or other businesses in the Woolworths group such as BWS and Big W, during March, have been urged to check their bank accounts.
It is possible they have been charged a second time for their purchases.
Customers across Australia have been affected, taking to social media to slam the retail giant for the error.
Mum of five Karen Jones lost more than $150 and said it was enough to make her do her shopping elsewhere.
"$150 for them is nothing but for me that's dinner on the table for a week," she said.
The problem is being attributed to Woolworths' payment processor Cuscal, which has confirmed it has been experiencing errors within its data centre.

Related Articles

The glitch affects online and in-store purchases made with a credit or debit card.
Australian Retailers Association executive director Russell Zimmerman said Woolworths would want to rectify the error "as quickly as possible".
"They've got a name to protect," he told A Current Affair.
Cuscal issued a statement apologising for the "stress and inconvenience".
"We are working urgently to correct the errors and anticipate all transactions will be corrected by tomorrow," the statement read.
"No customers will be out of pocket due to incorrect charges or transactions arising directly from this incident - we will work with our clients to make sure this happens.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BIG W</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BWS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russell Zimmerman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cuscal</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woolworths</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Retailers Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Current Affair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karen Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
