<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444144141267369</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/07/18/26/fake-outdoor-play-areas-on-the-rise-at-aussie-childcare-centres</url>
  <title>Imitation outdoor play areas on the rise at Aussie childcare centres</title>
  <content>
Just as backyards disappear from more Australian homes, a growing number of childcare centres are creating "faux" outdoor play areas indoors.
Early development expert Kay Margetts has raised concerns about fake outdoor areas, including imitation gardens and yards, popping up inside childcare facilities.
These are fully enclosed spaces that simulate nature with sandpits, synthetic grass and artificial plants.
"Indoor spaces with four walls, a ceiling and a floor like a box are being considered to be outdoor play spaces, just because they have sand in them and water in them. There are even centres with concrete trees," Associate Professor Margetts told 9NEWS.
National regulations stipulate that childcare centres must give each child access to an average of seven square metres of outdoor space.
But the Victorian Department of Education and Training has confirmed at least a dozen facilities in Melbourne have been exempt from the rules.
This means the centres have smaller allocations of genuine outdoor space, or entirely enclosed outdoor-like playgrounds.

Related Articles

Associate Professor Margetts has said regular exposure to nature is essential for the development of vision, coordination and physical fitness.
"The other thing with outdoor children's play is it builds up confidence because they are leaning to manage risk," she said.
Only About Children - one of the facilities granted a waiver on outdoor space requirements - said it offers a range of learning environments, both inside and out.
And in their urban environments children are taken on regular excursions outside of the campus.
But the City Kids Learning Centre, located in a Melbourne high-rise, is proving it is possible to provide plenty of alfresco space for kids to play in an urban jungle.
Tiny tots and older children spend time outside daily thanks to a huge roof top play area.
Centre Director Kristy Godfrey said it is a fantastic space that replicates the "real world".
"That's life. You walk through the city in the rain and sunshine so that's what we continue here," Ms Godfrey said.
And whether the forecast is for rain, hail or shine their nature loving little clients are eager to get out and about.
"It's a fantastic space for children to connect with the outside world."
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Margetts</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City Kids Learning Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Godfrey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kay Margetts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Centre Director Kristy Godfrey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Department of Education</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
