<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443757594203941</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/deliveroo-considers-equipping-rider-huts-with-games-consoles-2017-7</url>
  <title>Deliveroo is considering fitting rider huts with games consoles to entertain drivers while they wait for orders</title>
  <content>
London startup Deliveroo is toying with the idea of putting games consoles into huts that it provides for some of its food delivery couriers.

The rider huts can be found in car parks and on industrial estates where Deliveroo has launched its pop-up restaurant parks, known as Deliveroo Editions.

Deliveroo Editions include six or seven portable kitchens and they allow restaurants to split up their in-house dining and delivery services.

Rohan Pradhan, head of Deliveroo Editions, told Business Insider at  that Deliveroo is considering kitting out the rider huts with gaming equipment so that riders can have some fun while they're waiting for jobs.

Deliveroo has raised approximately $US474 million (£358 million) from investors so a few games consoles for riders are unlikely to put too much of a financial strain on the company.

Pradhan did not specify what kind of gaming equipment Deliveroo could provide to riders but it could be PlayStations, Xboxes, or Nintendos.

Deliveroo and other food delivery companies like UberEats  from riders and trade unions since they launched over pay and how they choose to classify their couriers. Providing riders with games consoles could be interpreted as a sign that Deliveroo is keen to get riders on side.

"Deliveroo Editions is the biggest development in the market since Deliveroo first launched," said Pradhan in a follow up statement provided by Deliveroo. "Editions is a relatively new focus for the business and one we will continue to innovate in, striving to provide the best service for customers, restaurants and of course our riders."

A Deliveroo spokesperson added that putting computer games in the huts is "just an idea for now" before going on to say "as Editions grows, I'm sure we will see further developments around this."

NOW WATCH: Tech Insider videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Xboxes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US474</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pradhan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deliveroo Editions</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UberEats</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deliveroo</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tech Insider</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nintendo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Business Insider</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rohan Pradhan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edition</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PlayStation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
