<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444268695321252</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/comment/the-age-editorial/voters-faith-in-australian-politics-slumps-amid-housing-affordability-woes-20170807-gxr59a.html</url>
  <title>Voters' faith in Australian politics slumps amid housing affordability woes</title>
  <content>
When a focus group was asked to discuss politics, the assortment of mostly younger undecided voters from marginal seats did not mention Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull or Opposition Leader Bill Shorten in an entire hour.
Perhaps one reason Mr Turnbull and Mr Shorten do not seem to register as much as they might hope is voters are sceptical about politicians' ability to ameliorate a housing-cost crisis exacerbated by insufficient public transport, schools, community facilities, commerce and hospitals.Photo: Dan Soderstrom
Like other participants in recent work for Fairfax Media by polling organisation Ipsos Research, the potentially decisive voters in that focus group resoundingly presented housing unaffordability as the most potent issue. In the land of The Great Australian Dream - home ownership - disquiet about ever owning a home is surging. The proportion of people renting because they can not afford anything suitable is rising. A decade ago, five Melbourne suburbs had a median house price of $1 million. There are now 121.
Support for mainstream political parties is at historical lows across the world. Fresh parties and independents have been the primary beneficiaries. In the US, the UK (Brexit) and France, mainstream disillusionment with mainstream parties has driven dramatic change.
The Fairfax research suggests Australia's established parties face further leakage of support. Undecided former Liberal and Labor voters were united in the view that government is failing them. People are unsurprisingly tired of infighting, posturing, waste, entitlement and inaction as they ponder not being able to afford a house while sitting in stationary traffic on the way to a job they are getting paid less to do.
The research indicates that frustrated mass of crawling commuters does not believe Mr Turnbull has achieved anything of worth in the two years since he snatched the prime ministership by promising to be agile. It also shows people think Mr Shorten would be no more effective.
As our special report on the state of the nation revealed in the past four days, the greatest threat to Australians' material wellbeing is that falling real wages will trigger a crisis of confidence and shackle economic growth. In short, there can be no thriving high streets without prosperous backstreets.
People participating in the recent Ipsos work even reported feelings of despair. For the first time in many generations, young people in industrialised democracies like Australia are likely to be poorer than their parents. This is the historic context within which our flailing mainstream political leaders appear to be failing to cement credibility, let alone dominance.

A note from the editor - Subscribers can get Age editor Alex Lavelle's exclusive weekly newsletter delivered to their inbox by signing up here:
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Lavelle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Opposition Leader Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ipsos Research</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ipsos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Shorten</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brexit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dan Soderstrom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Great Australian Dream</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
