<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444612292710965</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/brand/rear-window/queensland-treasury-corp-ditches-brissies-tower-of-power-for-more-expensive-digs-20170803-gxoac7</url>
  <title>Queensland Treasury Corp ditches Brissie's Tower of Power for more expensive digs</title>
  <content>
Last week we brought you the news of Queensland Treasury Corporation's Phil Noble and his .
The champagne taste, honed during his days as a high-flying investment banker, seems well and truly to have accompanied Noble into his gig as an extremely well-remunerated public servant in the service of Premier Annastacia Palaszczuk. 
And now it appears, that expensive taste extends to his choice of digs.
Despite the fact the Queensland taxpayer controversially forked out more than $650 million to build the so-called Tower of Power - a 41-storey, state-of-the-art office building on the banks of the Brisbane River, commissioned in 2012 under then premier Campbell Newman and which now houses some 5000 public servants, Noble and Co. have opted instead to move into the decidedly more ritzy - and pricey - 111 Eagle St. 

With its commanding views over the Storey Bridge and east to Morteon Bay, One One One (as it is known in Brissie business circles) is located within the so-called "Golden Triangle" of the CBD, counts ANZ, Blue Sky Alternative Investments and practically every corporate law firm in Brisvegas among its corporate tenants, and is part of commercial property giant GPT Group's portfolio of high-rises. A portfolio that also includes Australia Square and the MLC Centre in Sydney and 100 Queen St and 150 Collins in Melbourne. 

According to our Brisvegas building spies, the QTC has recently signed up to an eight-year lease in 111 Eagle St and will take over floors 31 and 32 occupying a total floor space of approximately 3000 square metres at $875 per square metre. 
That's significantly more rent than other Queensland state government departments are paying to hang their hats in Campbell's Tower of Power where, , the cost per square metre is $743.  
We asked QTC why they had chosen to eschew the brand-spanking new high-rise that had been purpose-built for bureaucrats and instead move into 111 Eagle St, which appeared to be more expensive.
"QTC is a statutory body and is not currently, and has not previously been, co-located with government," came their reply. "As it was nearing the end of its commercial lease in a private-sector building, QTC took the opportunity to test the CBD property market. QTC's contracted lease arrangements are commercial-in-confidence. The move to 111 Eagle represents significant savings on QTC's existing arrangements." 

But not cheaper than moving into 1 William with their public service confreres. But that would mean slumming it with the hall-shufflers - and who'd want to do that when they could be comparing Zegna suits with the private sector set they secretly want to be part of? 

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blue Sky Alternative Investments</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Treasury Corporation's Phil Noble</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zegna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisvegas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tower of Power</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane River</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Campbell's Tower of Power</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Treasury Corp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>One One</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Golden Triangle" of the CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QTC</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brissie's Tower of Power</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noble</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Campbell Newman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GPT Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brissie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MLC Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Annastacia Palaszczuk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Storey Bridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morteon Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia Square</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANZ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>William</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagle St</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
