<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444105486561009</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/sport/boxing-mma/jeff-horn-declares-hell-beat-manny-pacquiao-more-convincingly-in-rematch/news-story/c44a2ae8eaaf6294192efecd15f3b6fb</url>
  <title>Horn wants rematch to end all doubt</title>
  <content>
, world welterweight champion Jeff Horn hit the gym for the first time since he .
Horn has been promised $2 million to defend the WBO title against Pacquiao, who under the terms of the contract to secure their July 2 Battle of Brisbane, will be paid much more than that for the return contest.
On a diet of chocolate and donuts, Horn has put on 10kg since he weighed in at just over 66kg for the biggest fight in Australian history but says his hunger for another win over Pacquiao has him feeling ravenous.
Pacquiao's promoter Bob Arum is keen for "The Fighting Schoolteacher'' to tackle the great Filipino in December and if successful then defend his WBO title against unbeaten American Terence Crawford in April 2018.
Horn has not even seen Crawford fight but says he's ready for the biggest bouts he can get.
"I want to fight the very best,'' he said on Monday at the Stretton gym where he started boxing 11 years ago as a bullied schoolboy.
"Manny will probably be better prepared for me in this fight. He knows what to expect now but I will fight differently to our first bout and bring some more surprises.
"Winning the world title was a dream come true and now I have the dream of being champion for many years and beating all challengers. Bring them on.
"I'm really happy to fight the rematch because .

"But I'll beat Manny even more convincingly this time. I don't want to say I'm looking for the knockout but a KO certainly puts all arguments away.
"I can push through to even higher levels of fitness for this fight.''
Horn-Pacquiao had a bigger economic impact for Queensland than the 2014 G20 Summit featuring heavyweights Barack Obama and Vladimir Putin.
Horn, whose wife Jo will give birth to their first child in January, predicts the crowd will even surpass the Australian record of 51,025 who packed Suncorp to see a huge upset as a bloodied Horn took a 12-round decision over 11-time world champ Pacquiao in a thriller.
His trainer Glenn Rushton says plans are in place to have huge air conditioning units to cool the fighters from Brisbane's summer heat but concedes issues with rain and storms could force the promotion to an indoor venue such as Melbourne's 56,000-seat Etihad Stadium.
The Queensland Government has the first option on staging the fight and Horn's promoter Dean Lonergan says he will do everything possible to stage it in Brisbane.
Rushton said while Pacquiao had not formally signed for the return fight he has told promoter Bob Arum that he wants to exercise his rematch clause.
"We're looking at the first half of December,'' Rushton said.
"We've seen misting units used in the Middle East to cool sporting venues and that's what we're looking at for Suncorp.
"There are still issues about the weather and the dates so those logistical things are still being decided.
"I want Jeff to be the only man in history to have beaten Pacquiao twice.
"Manny's pride is at stake. He has always done well in rematches and he needs money to fund his lifestyle and his huge charity projects so he will be confident of revenge.
Rushton said he would call for random drug testing before the bout.
"Jeff has always been squeaky clean and he's used to drug testing because he was an Olympian. We want to make sure everything is on a level playing field.''
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stretton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Filipino</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Lonergan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Middle East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suncorp</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WBO</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fighting Schoolteacher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rushton</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crawford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeff</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>American Terence Crawford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenn Rushton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 2 Battle of Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>G20 Summit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bob Arum</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pacquiao</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Horn-Pacquiao</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeff Horn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barack Obama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vladimir Putin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 2018</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manny</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
