<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443791953942916</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:28</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/afl/afl-news/gws-giants-hamstring-woes-no-cause-for-alarm-club-review-finds-20170807-gxr0ds.html</url>
  <title>Giants' hamstring woes no cause for alarm: review </title>
  <content>
GWS officials have discussed the club's long list of hamstring injuries for 2017 and have found no need to alter training methods or implement measures to prevent and treat hamstring concerns.
The Giants' two most important key forwards, Jeremy Cameron and Jonathon Patton, are currently sidelined with hamstring injuries, however the club are confident Patton will be available to play the Western Bulldogs at Etihad Stadium on Friday night.

Up Next

Dockers end their losing streak

01:30

More AFL Real Footy Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

AFL plays of round 20

It's all about the six pointers; Hannebery through traffic kicks a ripper, Coniglio has a claim to GOTY in Canberra, McDonald-Tipungwuti nutmegs Petrevski-Seton at the G, Billings clutch kick against West Coast and Eddie Betts is back from surgery to work his usual magic from the pocket.

Patton will need to get through training this week to prove his fitness but barring any reoccurrence of the hamstring complaint the No.1 pick in the 2011 national draft will be fit to play. However the Giants will not be hesitant to be cautious with the 24-year-old should they need to be.
Cameron - who missed rounds 17 and 18 - played round 19 before reinjuring his hamstring and missing round 20. He is still expected to be sidelined for at least two more weeks. The club is confident he will be fit to play finals.

Patton and Cameron are crucial to the success of the GWS forward line. Cameron leads the club's 2017 goalkicking with 42 majors in 16 games, while Patton is second, booting 36 goals in 16 games.
The other Giants players to succumb to hamstring injuries this year are Phil Davis (minor tear), Tendai Mzungu (tear), Sam Reid and Zac Williams (strain).

While the Giants recognise the number of hamstring injuries suffered by their players this year is high, they do not think it is high enough to be a worrying trend across a list of more than 40 players.
Club officials have analysed their fitness and conditioning regime and decided they wouldn't do anything differently to tackle hamstring injuries.Photo: AAP
GWS have had the most players miss games in 2017 through all types of injuries. They have had the second most amount of games missed by first 22 players behind Hawthorn.
Fairfax Media reported in July that the Giants also felt their total injury list was not a cause for concern, but rather, bad luck.Photo: Sitthixay Ditthavong
Most  of the Giants' long-term injuries, the wider injury assessment found, have come in high-impact or unlucky circumstances, including at least three syndesmosis incidents and two torn ACLs.
In more positive injury news for the Giants, the club is happy with how off-season recruit Brett Deledio got through his first AFL game since last year's round 17  on the weekend.
Deledio has battled persistent calf issues since moving to the Giants before the 2017 season, but played a full game in the win over Melbourne on Saturday.
While he only had eight disposals, the Giants say Saturday's game was more about Deledio's body holding up to the physical stresses of an AFL match.
The Giants will regain small forward Toby Greene back from suspension for the Bulldogs clash but will lose Shane Mumford to suspension.
Ryan Griffen and Tim Taranto are still two to three weeks from playing while Matt Buntine and Adam Kennedy are out for the season after tearing their ACLs.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Petrevski-Seton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACLs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zac Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tendai Mzungu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toby Greene</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eddie Betts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Taranto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patton</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan Griffen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Buntine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Real Footy Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coniglio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDonald-Tipungwuti</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeremy Cameron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane Mumford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deledio</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>G</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Kennedy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brett Deledio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phil Davis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sitthixay Ditthavong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GWS</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>11</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathon Patton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Reid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dockers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hannebery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
