<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651443710349562913</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/opinion/vicki-thomson-proposed-university-funding-cuts-are-an-outrageous-cash-grab/news-story/70c0f6eabb7fed0a51c9e94525c77b09</url>
  <title>Universities cannot afford funding cuts</title>
  <content>
WHILE the war of words on university-funding legislation continues in Canberra, it can indeed seem like some far away esoteric fight over a Budget cut. For South Australia it is anything but.
What happens to the nation's universities affects South Australia per capita far more than any other State. The proposed funding cuts to our three universities, ($26 million per year by 2021) are now at the mercy of the Senate crossbench, in particular the Nick Xenophon Party, and are the deepest funding cuts proposed for universities in 20 years. Importantly they come on top of many years of successive university funding cuts.
At the same time, the 53,000 undergraduate students at our three universities will be charged more to study, and made to pay back their student loans from a much lower income level once they are in the workforce.
The unfairness of this is obvious when many of these young people are, at the same time, attempting to enter an increasingly out-of-reach housing market in a fragile state economy.
The harsh facts are that SA is mainly a city State. Greater Adelaide has a population of 1.3 million which is 78 per cent of the state's population, and the city's three universities collectively employ more than 10,200 people. Only the state's public service is larger.
So the proposed Budget cuts to universities will directly cut jobs within the state's major non-Government employer. This will directly impact families, mainly across Adelaide.
It will also begin to have a multiplier effect on the state's economy at a time when it has said goodbye to Holden. Surely the state cannot afford, socially or economically, any more bad news?
Yet we know that already research carried out by the University of Adelaide indicates a $26 million per annum cut will lead to the potential loss of 152 full time jobs either directly or indirectly employed by the University.
And the impact on Adelaide will be compounded in some of the state's smaller population centres, where there are either university health centres, campuses or study centres; such as Mount Barker, Victor Harbor, Murray Bridge, Port Pirie, Mt Gambier and Port Augusta.
Universities have not said enough is enough without good reason. For every Budget cut, be it family, business or a not-for-profit university there comes a tipping point. For us that is 2017. Job losses, of support, professional, and academic staff, plus larger class sizes, a reduction in course options, the loss of one-on-one access to a lecturer for many students, delays in required building upgrades and maintenance, and deferrals of new buildings and essential research equipment will impact students, their families and the State's economy.
They will be paying more for far less, and we do know that the majority of South Australian students prefer to study in their home state, as my two sons have done.
In making this choice, our students deserve to have their three local universities funded adequately and fairly, to provide a quality education and deliver the quality research that saves and changes lives and living.
Instead we have deep concern for current and future SA students - their experience at university, and their right to receive 'bang for their buck'.
Their right to access the post graduate study that is now a requirement of so much employment is also at risk from the legislation.
This can affect, for example, veterinary science, architecture, teaching, nursing, and clinical psychology students.
This is important, because we operate our SA universities in a nation where government policy already means some students are charged 80 per cent of the cost of their chosen course. This makes us the sixth most expensive nation for tertiary study in the OECD.
The magnitude of the proposed Budget cuts to universities saw the National Union of Students and the Group of Eight (which represents the University of Adelaide in SA) recently present almost identical evidence condemning the cuts to a recent Senate Committee hearing.
This same committee heard very emotive evidence of just how badly students, in what are called 'enabling' courses, will be affected by the cuts.
Again this is worrying for South Australia where we know enabling courses with strong individual support on offer, are a lifeline to potential students who, for life or employment hurdles, would otherwise feel too disenfranchised to realise their study potential.
It is unconscionable that these South Australians so deserving of an opportunity should now be told their enabling course will be made available only through more than $3000 in student loans.
There is also a vast hidden hit in the legislation against our best and brightest SA graduates.
Our state will lose 3500 allocated post graduate places mainly in professional degrees such as teaching, nursing, architecture and psychology.
Changes to how these young graduates can access these essential post graduate courses (which many must complete to practise) means they potentially will be lured to the eastern states, most likely aggressively poached by Victorian Universities.
It is a disaster for our state's economy to lose that next generation of professionals. That is what will occur, as once they leave few return.
In total this legislation needs Nick Xenophon and his team to see it for what it actually is - an outrageous cash grab from South Australian's young students and graduates.
They don't deserve it. It's bad policy and it's cruel policy.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray Bridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Group of Eight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Union of Students</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Xenophon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OECD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Gambier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Pirie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Universities</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Augusta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Barker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate Committee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Xenophon Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victor Harbor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
