<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444182795973720</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/federal-politics/political-news/transcript-finance-minister-mathias-cormann-explains-liberal-partys-samesex-marriage-policy-20170807-gxr920.html</url>
  <title>Transcript: Mathias Cormann explains Liberal Party's same-sex marriage policy</title>
  <content>
Below is a transcript of Finance Minister Mathias Cormann's press conference explaining the Liberal Party's position on same-sex marriage. Senator Cormann addressed the media at Parliament House in Canberra  of Liberal MPs. 
Mathias Cormann: As you know, the parliamentary Liberal Party held a meeting this afternoon to consider whether or not the policy we took to the last election to give the Australian people a say on whether or not the definition of marriage should be changed at a plebiscite, whether that policy should be changed. The parliamentary Liberal Party party room maintained our commitment to give all Australians the opportunity to have a say on whether or not the definition of marriage should be changed to allow same-sex couples to marry and to do that through a plebiscite. I'm happy to take questions.
Reporter: Senator Cormann, does this mean that you will put the original plebiscite bill back to the Senate? If it fails, as people expect it will, is the postal plebiscite a backup option?
Cormann: Well, the government's intention is to put the plebiscite bill that was defeated in the Senate last year back before the Senate, and to ask the Senate to reconsider. Clearly, our preference is to give effect to the commitment we made at the last election to its fullest extent possible, which is why we will be asking the Senate to support the compulsory attendance at the plebiscite as per the legislation that was introduced into the Parliament last year.
Reporter: If that bill fails, will you have a postal vote, or do you have to have another meeting?
Cormann: Well, the government is absolutely committed to keep face with the commitment that we made, to keep faith with the commitment that we made to the Australian people and that is to give Australian people a say on whether or not the definition of marriage should be changed. Our preference is to do that through a compulsory attendance plebiscite and legislation to that effect. We'll come back before the Senate, we hope, this week. If that were to fail, the government believes that we have a legal and constitutional way forward to give the Australian people a say on whether or not the definition of marriage should be changed through a non-legislated, voluntary postal plebiscite.

Reporter: Does that have to go back to the party before you tick off on that postal vote?
Cormann: Well, the meeting today was a meeting of the parliamentary Liberal Party party room. The meeting today was for the specific purpose to determine whether or not the policy we took to the last election on giving Australian people a say on whether or not the definition of marriage should be changed, that was the purpose of the meeting today - whether we should change our policy on the plebiscite, or go to a free vote now. The Liberal Party party room resolved to maintain the commitment that, as a parliamentary Liberal Party, we took to the last election. It is now going to be a matter for the joint party room tomorrow in the ordinary course of events, in the usual way, to determine, you know, all of the processes from here on forward.
Reporter: With either plebiscite, minister, given you feel it's so important for the Australian public to be heard, with either version of the plebiscite will Liberal Party members be bound by the results and vote whichever way the Australian people decide?

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Cormann: Well, the position of the government is that if the plebiscite vote comes back with a 'yes' vote in favour of changing the law to allow same-sex couples to marry, we will have a private members' bill to change the law to allow same-sex couples to marry, there would be a free vote informed by the plebiscite outcome and our expectation would be that that law would pass the Parliament.
Reporter: Are you going to hold that by a specific time, by the end of the year, or is that to be decided?
Cormann: The specifics in terms of the process from here will be a matter for the joint party room tomorrow.
Reporter: If the plebiscite is defeated does that mean no public vote?
Cormann: If the public determines they are not in favour of changing the law to allow same-sex couples to marry, then the government will not be facilitating consideration of a private members' bill to change the law.
Reporter: MPs have expressed frustration that this issue is distracting from your main agenda. Doesn't this resolution tonight mean that it will continue to be a distraction for the government.
Cormann: The Liberal Party party room today had a very good meeting. We had a very courteous, respectful and professional meeting to deal with an issue on which there is a diversity of strongly held views on both sides of the argument. The reason there is a diversity of strongly held views in our party room is because the Liberal Party party room and the Coalition party room for that matter is a reflection of the many views across the community, and that is, of course, why in the lead-up to the last election, the Liberal/National Coalition went with a promise to the election to give the Australian people a say on whether or not the definition of marriage should be changed. So we as a government are committed to maintain that promise to the Australian people, to keep faith with the commitment that we made to the Australian people in the lead-up to the last election.
Reporter: How quickly can a postal vote be conducted, given you want a vote in the Senate this week on the original plebiscite plan?
Cormann: Well, the purpose of the meeting today - the purpose of the Liberal Party party room meeting today was to determine whether or not our policy that we took to the last election should be changed or whether it should be maintained. The Liberal Party room determined that it should be maintained. Obviously there will be further announcements - well, further discussions and further decisions - and ultimately further announcements on next steps in due course.
Reporter: How do you pay for a postal plebiscite if there's not an appropriation bill to Parliament and if you have legal advice to that effect can we see it?
Cormann: As I said to you, the government believes that there is a legal and constitutional way for the government to facilitate a voluntary, non-legislated postal plebiscite and this is now a matter that is, of course, a matter for consideration by the joint party room meeting at the appropriate time, and these matters will all be able to be addressed when we are in the position for further announcements.
Reporter: Can we see your legal advice?
Cormann: We deal with these matters in the usual way.
Reporter: If there was a 'no' vote to the postal plebiscite, what would happen then? The government wouldn't facilitate any bill in the House?
Cormann: As I've indicated in response to a previous question, the government is committed to give the Australian people a say on whether or not the definition of marriage should be changed in the Marriage Act. Our preference is to do this through a compulsory attendance plebiscite. If that were not to be able to get through the Senate, the government's view is that there is a legal and a constitutional way forward, keeping faith with the commitment that we made, giving the Australian people a say through a voluntary postal plebiscite. Whichever form the plebiscite is, whether it is a compulsory attendance plebiscite or a voluntary postal plebiscite, if the verdict of the Australian people is that they do not want the law on - and the definition of marriage in the law changed - then the government will not be facilitating a private members' bill to change the law.
Reporter: But if there was a private members' bill, would members still be bound?
Cormann: I think that I very clearly expressed the position of the government.
Reporter: What's the cost of the postal vote? There have been figures of $40 million, $100 million - is there a guide?
Cormann: Again, these are still matters that are subject to consideration in the joint party room tomorrow. Depending on the decisions made by the joint party room tomorrow, there will be further announcements and we will be able to answer all of these questions in due course.
Reporter: How do you persuade Labor and the crossbench and is there any room to trade or horse trade here, short of shaming them? Is there any other options the government has?
Cormann: Well, we believe - we are certain in our commitment to the Australian people before the last election - we want people to have a say on whether the definition of marriage in the Marriage Act should be changed. The government is committed to keep faith with the promise we made at the last election. It is now up to others in the Senate, who may have voted against the plebiscite in the past, and make a decision on whether they prefer a compulsory attendance plebiscite or whether they prefer a postal voluntary plebiscite. If there are concerns about a voluntary postal plebiscite, then I would encourage those senators who are so concerned to consider supporting the government's bill for a compulsory attendance plebiscite.
Reporter: In short is the government's strategy continuing to do what it has done once and failed - is nothing going to change?
Cormann: As I've indicated to you, the government is committed to give the Australian people a say. Our preference is to give the Australian people a say through a compulsory attendance plebiscite. Should that not succeed through the Senate, the government believes that there is a legal and constitutional way forward to give the Australian people a say through a non-legislated, voluntary postal plebiscite. Now, in the scenario where the Senate maintains its past position, then that would be the way that the government believes we can keep faith with the promise that we made.
Reporter: Have the five rebel MPs committed not to be bringing a procedural motion to the floor? Was that part of their speeches to the party room?
Cormann: I'm not going to go into the detail of the party room discussion. You wouldn't expect me to. Let me just say again, it was a very good meeting, it was a very courteous, very respectful, very professional discussion. At the end of the discussion, the Liberal Party party room resolved to maintain the policy that we took to the last election, and that is to give the Australian people a say on whether or not the definition of marriage should be changed in our Marriage Act. Thank you very much.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marriage Act</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>19</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal/National Coalition</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Finance Minister Mathias Cormann</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra  of Liberal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Cormann</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mathias Cormann</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Does</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Party</name>
    <count>13</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cormann</name>
    <count>16</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parliament House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
