<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444101191593686</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:40</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/news/northern-territory/nt-police-in-standoff-with-woman-at-wanguri-property/news-story/703636877158b39486827091c33c6d6b</url>
  <title>Police storm home after stand-off</title>
  <content>
Three children have been dramatically rescued from a Wanguri home by police, seconds before heavily armed officers stormed the property to end a five-hour stand-off.
Police were seen coaxing the three children to the fence of the Margaritis St property before pulling them over one by one just before 3.30pm Monday.
The first child dragged to safety climbed to the top of the fence and into the open arms of a waiting policeman.
Two other boys, believed to be of primary school age, followed over the fence within minutes.
Moments later, heavily armed police bashed down the front door and entered the property. It appeared the children were not physically harmed during the stand-off.
A woman was later removed from the home in handcuffs on a stretcher by paramedics and police.
An NT Police spokesman said the woman was taken to Royal Darwin Hospital for a mental health assessment
He said the woman was not arrested and the children were not threatened during the incident. Earlier, as the stand-off reached its climax, five Territory Response Group members dressed in army fatigues and armed with rifles stood with their weapons pointed at the property.
Two plain-clothed officers and paramedics stood nearby as negotiations continued.
Neighbours said the street was blocked off at around 10am.
One neighbour told the NT News she was shocked to learn of the stand-off.
"It was a bit of a shock. When we drove past in the morning there was only one police car blocking the street," she said.
"When we came back we could hardly drive down the street."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NT News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Territory Response Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NT Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Darwin Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wanguri</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Margaritis St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
