<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444096896626327</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:39</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/news/turnbull-governments-decision-on-same-sex-marriage-plebiscite-sparks-angry-online-response/news-story/76f7189340516d691b5b019454030b44</url>
  <title>Turnbull Government's decision on same sex marriage plebiscite sparks angry online response</title>
  <content>
The Turnbull Government will continue to support a plebiscite on same sex marriage. Picture: Joel Carrett/AAP

Share

THE Turnbull Government will be sticking with its policy to hold a plebiscite on same sex marriage but many just want the politicians to get on with it.
Today, the , and failing that it will hold a voluntary postal vote on the issue.
But the decision was disappointing to many on social media who were angry about the result, calling it "cravenly stupid".
One Twitter user said: "Disappointed in the Australian Government get over yourselves and do want the people want it's not gonna hurt anybody".
Senator Jacqui Lambie, who does not support gay marriage but has said she will vote for it if Tasmanians want it, was also critical of the decision tweeting: "a postal vote isn't an election promise, it's an admission of failure".
Disappointed in the Australian Government get over yourselves and do want the people want it's not gonna hurt anybody
As expected, the Liberals have opted for the most cravenly stupid and damaging option available to them on marriage equality. Bravo, Mal.
So disillusioned. Expect nothing and they still let you down.
So they voted AGAIN so people not affected will have 'a say', wont be bound by it, & then have parliament vote anyway? 😡
So, I can be dragged to court for "divorce" procedure but I can't actually get married? Is this serious,  ? 😔
I really hoped  would show leadership, but the spineless fool just handed Labor the next election
Another day, another disappointment from this useless government. Gays have been denied  for so long I'm losing care factor
Sadly, the Government has tonight decided not to do their jobs
What's the point in paying politicians to run govt if they in fact don't govern nor show leadership ?!
But others didn't know what the fuss was about.
what do these Marriage Equality 'advocates' have against a plebiscite? Cause they know what the result will be...
How hard is for people to understand that wanting a plebiscite has nothing to do with disapproving same-sex marriage?
Better than the gutless labour and liberal party deciding. Let us vote!!!
There were similar comments on Facebook with many just wanting the government to get on with it.
"Gay marriage could be legal in 15 minutes if these w*****s pulled their finger out and realised the sky won't fall in. I want close friends to be able to marry the person they love," one man wrote.
But others disagreed, with another saying: "its up to the people to decide, not the government".
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MAL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marriage Equality</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Jacqui Lambie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull Government</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Government</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bravo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joel Carrett/AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
