<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444745436699253</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/foxconn-executive-iphone-8-wont-be-cheap-2017-8</url>
  <title>A Foxconn executive has apparently said the iPhone 8 'won't be cheap'</title>
  <content>
Luo Zhongsheng, an executive at Taiwanese manufacturing giant Foxconn, published a (now deleted) comment on Weibo claiming that Apple's upcoming "iPhone 8" won't come cheap, .

The problem lies with the iPhone's organic light-emitting diode (OLED) display, which Apple tweaked specifically to accommodate the phone's new design.

If the rumours -  - are correct, it will feature a so-called "notch" at the top, which places the front sensors in the top centre of the screen and leaves extra space at the sides.

Zhongsheng said the extra work required for this firm would lower the device's production yield - essentially meaning it will take longer and be more expensive to produce.

"The OLED's (production) yield is only 60%," Zhongsheng wrote in his post, confirming  the same figure. "Cutting the display into this special shape looks really difficult, and the cost won't be cheap. I estimate that the iPhone 8 won't be cheap."

In addition to Zhongsheng's comment, some new pictures of what seems to be a copper gold iPhone 8 appeared on Weibo. There's no way to confirm that these are real, and no iPhone has previously used this colour.

So far, rumours have suggested the iPhone 8 will come in traditional black and white, and possibly .

NOW WATCH: Tech Insider videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPhone 8</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Weibo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OLED</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luo Zhongsheng</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxconn</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taiwanese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tech Insider</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPhone</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zhongsheng</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
