<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445037494481221</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:18</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/dont-let-toll-road-operators-make-outrageous-returns-toll-group-ceo-20170807-gxqood</url>
  <title>Don't let toll road operators make 'outrageous returns': Toll Group CEO </title>
  <content>
Logistics company Toll Group is happy to pay tolls on motorways as long as toll road operators do not make "outrageous" returns, chief executive Michael Byrne says.
Rising toll fares on roads in big Australian cities are becoming increasingly contentious as some  at big price increases, and consumers complain about
Family-owned trucking group Linfox has  in the price of heavy vehicle tolls on Melbourne's CityLink, which is managed by Transurban, arguing the fare rise - which was implemented in April - should be delayed until work to widen the road is complete in 2018. Linfox has said its trucks may use alternative arterial roads instead of CityLink.
But Mr Byrne, who is  to turn around the business, said the company's 16,000 trucks would not be going back on to residential streets.

"Someone's got to pay," Mr Byrne told The Australian Financial Review. "You can't say you want this infrastructure to be more efficient and then not pay for it."

However, toll fares should be predictable and transparent, Mr Byrne said. "We want to see people have a return on the capital invested in public companies that run toll roads, but we don't want it to be an outrageous return.
"That's up to government to regulate."
Transurban, which delivers its annual results on Tuesday, is highly profitable. The company's net profit is expected to almost double in fiscal 2017 to $436 million, according to estimates from Citigroup.
Transurban's proportionate earnings before interest, taxation, depreciation and amortisation - which measure income relative to the company's ownership stakes in its toll road assets - is expected to rise 11 per cent to $1.64 billion.

into the financing and transparency of toll roads is under way, with Transurban arguing that toll roads deliver billions of dollars in social, economic and environmental benefits.
Union agreement

The Australian Trucking Association (ATA) has called for the Australian Competition and Consumer Commission to regulate toll fares, which are set by state governments, arguing the arrangements for setting fares are not always transparent.
Transurban has been able to negotiate with state governments to raise fares on some motorways to help pay for the development of roads.

Analysts say governments need to be careful about permitting bidding wars for motorways like Sydney's WestConnex, which will be sold to the private sector, because the more a bidder pays, the bigger financial returns they will demand.
Governments are building more toll roads to try to alleviate congestion, with Victoria on Monday announcing proposals for, which could cost up to $23 billion.
Separately, Toll has reached an "in principle" deal on a new $1.4 billion enterprise bargaining agreement with the Transport Workers Union (TWU) after months of talks, avoiding a potential strike.
The agreement preserves existing protections on working hours, penalty rates and dispute resolution clauses, according to the TWU.

"It will enhance superannuation payments to 14.75 per cent over three years and include job security protections, casual permanent conversion and better utilisation of the existing workforce," said TWU national secretary Tony Sheldon, adding it would "set the ground work for a productive, efficient and well-trained staff".
Meetings will be held around the country seeking endorsement of the proposal.
Mr Byrne, who held several meetings with the TWU and attended a global meeting of unions in Los Angeles in July to discuss Toll's expectations for its 44,000-strong global workforce, said he had been pushing for a "forward thinking" agreement.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Citigroup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Trucking Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Byrne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Los Angeles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Competition</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TWU</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Transurban</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Byrne</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CityLink</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Transport Workers Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Linfox</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Consumer Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Group CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toll Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ATA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney's WestConnex</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne's CityLink</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Sheldon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
