<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445278012654604</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:14</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/north/school-repairs-desperately-needed-as-roof-and-ceiling-cracks-up/news-story/a1f1ab9fd9e455a79432fe9a8bb345af</url>
  <title>Fix our crumbling school</title>
  <content>
FALLING pieces of ceiling plaster which caused a classroom evacuation is just one incident behind parents of a Northcote primary school pleading for the State Government to pay for urgent repairs.
The alarming incident this year highlighted the dire need for repairs at the dilapidated Northcote Primary School, in which large areas are fenced off for safety. The plaster scare followed an incident in March in which a teacher was almost hit by a falling lump of tile when pieces of the school hall roof fell into a playground.
The 19th century hall is now fenced off and awaiting emergency repairs.
Parents fear it is only a matter of time before a child is hurt and have launched a campaign calling on the State Government to fix the school's "leaking ceilings, collapsed floors and rotting foundations".

The State Government has been aware of the ageing school's problems since 2011, when a report found "serious structural issues" in several buildings.
Education Minister James Merlino said the State Government had contributed more than $500,000 to date to the school.
But school council president Ian Taylor said the repair bill was likely in excess of $2 million.
Parent Erin Slattery said the campaign, which had gained more than 500 signatures, was about putting children first.
"You fear for the safety of your children when you sit in assembly,'' she said.
Northcote state Labor MP Fiona Richardson said she would meet with the school's leadership.
There will be a school council meeting on August 16 to discuss the future of the school.
Northcote Primary School principal Kerrie Williams did not return the Leader's calls.
Details at ilovenps.com.au
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Erin Slattery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Education Minister James Merlino</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kerrie Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northcote</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 16</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northcote Primary School</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labor MP Fiona Richardson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
