<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445037494481257</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:18</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/scabby-deflated-by-coal-union-concession-20170807-gxr03n</url>
  <title>Glencore forces union to stop calling strike-breakers scabs</title>
  <content>
Scabby the Rat has suffered another deflating defeat, this time in Queensland where the mining union has agreed to withdraw the imposing inflatable insult from current and future picket lines at the epicentre of its national contest with Australia's biggest coal exporter, Glencore.
from picketing duties at the Oaky North mine in the Bowen Basin was the least of a collection of concessions offered late last week by the union to Glencore and the Fair Work Commission.
The mining union and its construction industry affiliate have also agreed to ensure that paid officials do not use the words scab, maggot and grub in any future protests over progress at Oaky North or in online conversations about the increasingly tense contest with Glencore.
The union concessions arrived, as well, with commitments that constrain the conduct of a cohort of 26 at Oaky North accused by Glencore of breaching the company's codes of conduct while involved in recent strike action.

On Friday, Glencore locked out Oaky North workers for a third consecutive eight-day period. It is the fourth time . Glencore's firm and enduring response was made possible by the union's earlier exercise of strike action, aimed at forcing the pace of efforts to replace an enterprise agreement that expired more than two years ago.

Pursuing a hard line

After the strike action, Glencore issued disciplinary notices to 26 workers who it alleged had over-stepped the company's policy on harassment, bullying and discrimination while active on either, or both, the Oaky North picket line and Facebook.
On the one hand, the coal miner's initiative might be regarded as provocative. On the other, though, the union might well have better anticipated that Glencore might pursue a hard line given that, from what we understand, the company's behavioural standards were formally reinforced to the 600 or so Oaky North workers in briefings that occurred during the interregnum between the first two-day lock out in June and the three that followed a month later.
With the notices issued, the CFMEU headed to the Fair Work Commission to test if Glencore had breached the good-faith bargaining requirements of the Fair Work Act.

That case remains at its hearing stage but its further progress may prove moot given the union's concessions and the company's matching commitment not to pursue the misconduct cases for the duration.
But in defending its case, Glencore presented the commission with evidence of misconduct that included video of the picketing workers. One of the union officials captured in those recordings was the Queensland president of the CFMEU mining and energy division, Stephen Smyth. We have not seen the recording but claims that the president offered a fearfully colourful performance appear to have been reinforced by the restraints accepted by the union on the conduct of its paid officials.
'Bereft of vision'

Last week Glencore's global coal boss

"This is the union trying to grab power, the union putting its interests ahead of its member's interests," he said.
"What we have seen in the past few weeks is a union bereft of vision, a union returning to 1970s tactics, a union that believes that conflict is a way to create and enrich employment. A union that still supports and condones disgraceful behaviour, where gutless bully-boys abuse and intimidate those who want to work and those who don't want to have anything to do with their so-called national campaign."
Like management at Anglo American and BHP, which both remain in dispute with the CFMEU over open workplace agreements, Glencore's boss assessed the union platform as an unacceptable breach of management prerogative.
"This is the union trying to tell business how it should run its business," he said, citing union claims over the way Glencore might employ and deploy contractors, how workers were rostered and how management might communicate with staff.

Within 24 hours of the Freyberg clarion, Glencore had secured union concessions that suggested that not everything remained the same in this latest contest between big mining and its diggers. Because the agreement between union and company announced, again, that striking employees did not have the right to say or do whatever they wanted when they presented their case on legally constituted picket lines.
Abusive and offensive

Since a landmark case in 2014, a succession of tribunals and courts has consistently held that striking workers are constrained by their employer's codes of conduct. The courts have also found that the use of words such as "scab" are abusive and offensive under the law and could be cause for dismissal.
This has been the case since 2014 when the High Court upheld the dismissal of a coal worker and CFMEU union delegate for the nature of his protest during authorised strike action.

Hank Doevendans' path to a place in the legal textbooks began in 2012 when he was manning a picket at the Saraji mine, which was one of the then seven-strong fleet of BHP operated mines that was striking in the name of a more robust employment agreement.
BHP's resistance of the union proposition resulted in more than a year of industrial action and some very ugly confrontations between striking unionists and employees determined to express their right to work. Those who did work were routinely called scabs and worse.
History says that Doevendans made the mistake of writing rather than shouting his condemnation of workers who refused to strike. He was sacked by BHP for repeatedly holding up and waving a sign that said: "No principles - SCABS - No guts."
Breach of workplace policy

The company's proposition was that the words on the sign represented a breach of a consistently reinforced workplace policy that demanded miners should respect their fellow workers. Saraji management asserted that waving the sign was also antagonistic to a new and evolving operational culture and claimed that Doevendans had exhibited "arrogance" when warned about his conduct.
The union initially fought successfully for Doevendans' reinstatement on the grounds that the dismissal represented adverse action against a union delegate. But subsequent appeals went against the union. Eventually, in 2014, the High Court found it was "incorrect to conclude that, because the employee's union position and activities were inextricably entwined with adverse action, the employee was therefore immune, and protected, from the adverse action".
BHP's 2014 success was widely received as the death knell for the ugly aggression of workplace protest. Calling a fellow worker a scab, mongrel or a maggot is just bullying and the law is increasingly making it plain it really is no longer acceptable.
This reality has now stretched, obviously, to the deployment of an inflatable whose aim is to bully and abuse people who express their legal rights and cross union picket lines.

Employee's right to work

As recently as July,
That union retreat followed closely on a much more important assertion of an employee's right to work unabused and unthreatened through industrial action.
Last year, five contract workers who routinely crossed a picket at CUB's Abbotsford brewery in Melbourne responded to abuse and harassment by exercising the anti-bullying protections offered by the Fair Work Act.
Those laws protect workers against workplace bullying, which is defined as repeated, unreasonable behaviour that creates a risk to health and safety.
The Fair Work Commission made orders against officers, employees and members of the two unions running the CUB strike after finding they stood a risk to the health and safety of the employees being targeted by the picketers.
The orders, which were expanded to cover the whole of the CUB contractor workforce so that the five applicants could not be identified and then targeted, prevented the unions from taking photographs of people going to work. They also prevented union members from shouting abuse at those crossing picket lines. Offensive signs that included terms such as "scab" were also banned.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BHP</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CUB's Abbotsford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Freyberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CFMEU</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saraji</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scabby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doevendans</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bowen Basin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hank Doevendans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anglo-American</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oaky North</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glencore</name>
    <count>15</count>
    <score>-11</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fair Work Commission</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>High Court</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Smyth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fair Work Act</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BHP's 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
