<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444955890100832</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/business/more-full-time-work-as-australian-jobs-ads-rise-for-fifth-straight-month/news-story/66b3523c52df1f0c92b212950dd481f4</url>
  <title>Job ads up for fifth straight month</title>
  <content>
JOB advertisements have risen for the fifth straight month and more full-time roles are on offer, signifying a strengthening economy.
The number of job ads in the ANZ report reached 177,879 in July, a near 6 1/2-year high, according to CommSec. Job ads were up 12.8 per cent on a year ago.
ANZ head of Australian economics David Plank said recent data had shown a clear improvement in the labour market consistent with elevated business conditions, profitability and capacity utilisation.
"In particular, the strength in full-time employment and a solid increase in hours worked are quite encouraging.
"Among other things we think this strength has contributed to the lift in consumer confidence from its recent low point in April.''
He said there were still problems for the job market and he expected the pace of improvement to moderate over the medium term.
The first issue was the high level of casual or part-time work, known as under-utilisation, and economists expected it would only reduce gradually.
The second issue was that while the LNG sector was providing a significant benefit to exports it was a relatively low jobs producer.
"We also don't expect the recent strong pace of public sector jobs growth to continue. Lastly, despite the improvement in labour conditions, wage growth is sluggish and is expected to remain so,'' Mr Plank said.
CommSec's Craig James said the job market was improving because businesses were doing well, but a higher Australian dollar may lead to softer operating conditions for exporters, retailers and import-competing manufacturers.
The Australian Bureau of Statistics also released figures showing retail turnover rose only slightly in June.
Turnover increased in household goods, cafes, restaurants and takeaway food services, clothing footwear and personal accessories. Department store turnover fell and food retailing was unchanged.
In seasonally adjusted terms there were rises in New South Wales (0.5 per cent), Queensland (0.7 per cent), South Australia (0.3 per cent), Tasmania (0.6 per cent), the Northern Territory (1.2 per cent) and Western Australia (0.1 per cent). There were falls in Victoria (-0.3 per cent) and the Australian Capital Territory (-0.1 per cent).
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>CommSec</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania (0.6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LNG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia (0.3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CommSec's Craig James</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New South Wales (0.5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria (-0.3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Plank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Plank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland (0.7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia (0.1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Capital Territory (-0.1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANZ</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Territory (1.2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Bureau of Statistics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
