<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445213588143773</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/queensland/no-new-trains-for-gold-coast-commonwealth-games/news-story/fd0f0172ecd8950e27f1bfdb99cd18c5</url>
  <title>Prepare for Games train pain</title>
  <content>
NEW trains planned to be running to help move thousands of people around at next year's Commonwealth Games will not be ready in time, Government consultants found.
And a lack of train drivers is putting transport plans for the April 2018 event at risk.
The bleak appraisal of the $4.4 billion New Generation Rollingstock program is contained in a July report by -German rail operator Deutsche Bahn for the Citytrain Response Unit.
A section of the report, -obtained by The Courier-Mail, reveals 18 New Generation Rollingstock trains would be needed for the Games.

Prince Charles and his wife Camilla have confirmed they will attend the Gold Coast Commonwealth Games.

Royal to attend Gold Coast Commonwealth Games
The Government had previously insisted the NGR trains would be rolled out this year, but the report states that "due to the current blockages and high risk of 'juvenile failures' a conservative view would be that 18 NGR trains will not be ready by April 2018". It also identified a lack of drivers as an issue.
The DB whole-of-business review into Queensland Rail operations was recommended by the Strachan Inquiry into the Citytrain meltdown caused by a critical shortage of drivers.
It interviewed 78 QR managers and reviewed 250 internal documents reviewed.

First look at 2018 Commonwealth Games accommodation.

GC2018 Village reveal
Transport Minister Jackie Trad yesterday said the Government had been "left to fix the half-price trains the LNP ordered from India".
Opposition transport spokesman Andrew Powell said Ms Trad had "stopped the delivery of new trains at the behest of the unions".
Just 15 NGR trains have arrived so far, but none have yet cleared on-track testing.
The program to deliver 75 new trains is now more than a year behind schedule and beset with design problems.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Trad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DB</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LNP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Citytrain Response Unit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NGR</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deutsche Bahn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Charles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GC2018 Village</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Strachan Inquiry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast Commonwealth Games</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Citytrain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>India</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Camilla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Generation Rollingstock</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Rail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Powell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Transport Minister Jackie Trad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Games</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Courier-Mail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 2018</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
