<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445256537817642</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/sport/norton-finally-gets-boomers-chance/news-story/ac861e8a27b3003e4d778eb8884a3faf</url>
  <title>Norton finally gets Boomers chance</title>
  <content>
Mitch Norton has been summoned to a number of meetings after Boomers train-on camps before and it's always ended the same way - "sorry, you've just missed out on the team."
So it's no surprise the Townsville product was "over the moon" when he was told the news he will make his international debut in Australia's FIBA Asia Cup campaign in Lebanon.
The Boomers kick off their campaign against Japan tonight (AEST) and the Illawarra Hawks point guard wants to prove coach Andrej Lemanis' faith is well placed.
"I'm over the moon," he said.
"It was pretty nerve wracking walking into the room with the coaches there (after training camp), but when they said 'you're good to go, we're taking you to Lebanon' it was a pretty amazing feeling.
"I've been involved in a few camps but this is the first time I'll pull on a Boomers jersey, which is pretty exciting."
The 24-year-old had a strong first season with the Hawks after linking up with them when the Townsville Crocodiles folded.
He helped guide them to the NBL grand final series where they were beaten by Perth, averaging eight points and three assists per game.
Norton is renowned for his defence and love for a scrap, and hope to use those qualities to press his claims for a spot in the World Cup team, when Australia's NBA stars will be available.
The four teams who qualify for the Asia Cup semi finals will qualify for the World Cup in 2019.
Norton said he approached the train-on camp with more confidence than previously after a breakout campaign for Illawarra.
"Coming off the back of a pretty good year with the Hawks I had a bit more confidence about my game that I can match it with the guys there," Norton said.
"I took that into the camp and I guess did well enough to make the team.
"Every time you pull on a Boomers jersey it's a chance to show what you've got on a major stage.
"I'll go out and play my role and try to work on different areas of the game I've been working on and hopefully it's good enough to be invited to a camp with those (NBA) guys.
"Any time you're training with NBA players, listening and watching them is always a major tool."
The Boomers-Japan clash will be televised on Fox Sports from 11pm tonight.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Norton</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia's FIBA Asia Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia's NBA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boomers-Japan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lebanon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HAWK-I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrej Lemanis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Cup</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra Hawks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville Crocodiles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AEST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FOX SPORTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch Norton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
