<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445256537817656</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/comment/loaded-language-in-the-media-the-risk-of-being-politically-correct-20170807-gxqv0y.html</url>
  <title>Can we be politically correct and still say what we mean?</title>
  <content>
"I think it's good that we're all a little racist."
I'm an Australian community pharmacist with Chinese heritage and that's what one of my regular patients said to me one day.Photo: Darron Cummings
A little taken aback, I asked, "Oh? Why do you say that?"
Referring to the recent census results, the patient said that half of Australia's population was not born in Australia (this is not true), but "...I mean I think it's good that we all look a bit different. I think it's good that you look Chinese."
To some, this probably seems like a very strange exchange. In community pharmacy, it's par for the course. Another example - after counselling an elderly patient on her blood pressure medications, the lady looked at me, patted my hand and said, smiling, "You speak English so well for an Asian."
I often compare the way language is used by everyday people to the way language is used in the media. The media constitutes a profession that is generally highly educated (some would say, a part of the "elite" class). They have to think about the language they use a lot more than the average person. Let me ask you - which do you think is a more apt description - "illegal immigrant" or "asylum seeker"?

The Australian Press Council  in most circumstances. The Howard government liked to say "illegal maritime arrivals," whilst the subsequent Labor government preferred "irregular maritime arrivals." Tony Abbott brought back "boat people," a term from the 1970s that originally described refugees fleeing Vietnam after the fall of Saigon. It's a strikingly anachronistic term in the vein of "Chink," "Abo" or "Wog", and shows how much we - and our use of language (at least in public) - have really changed.
The truth is, the language that you use probably gives away how you feel about an issue. The press council warns the word "illegal" may unduly imply "criminality or other serious behaviour", instead emphasising that most people who come here without authorisation are seeking a legal right to stay in Australia as refugees. But some think that "asylum seeker" deliberately avoids the fact these people are entering Australian borders illegally. They are frustrated the media's obsession with political correctness has made it impossible to "call a spade a spade".
Censoring language, however well-intentioned, can be subversive. The Rotherham child sex abuse scandal in the United Kingdom, where at least 1400 children were abused between 1997 and 2013, ignited a firestorm over the problem of . Most of the perpetrators were of Pakistani heritage, but police and officials were blasted for deliberately failing to acknowledge obvious ethnic and community ties for fears of being accused of racism.
The initial reluctance of the German media to cover a  by men described as having North African or Arab appearance was blamed on the media's fear of stoking anti-migrant sentiment during the refugee crisis. It reinforced the perception that the media (knowingly or unknowingly) has a tendency to skew coverage a certain way.
In the US, the president Barack Obama was constantly pilloried by the right for  (he has used those words, just not in that exact order). In 2014, he said,  His intentions were good - he wanted to make the  (few would know the difference). He was wrong - ISIS  and it would be folly to ignore the fact.
To his supporters, US President Donald Trump is the antithesis of political correctness. His diatribes are inarticulate, grossly offensive to grammar-heads and crudely effective. Remember the time he said  Actually, he didn't say that. What he did say was this:
"The US has become a dumping ground for everybody else's problems ... When Mexico sends its people, they're not sending their best. They're not sending you. They're not sending you. They're sending people that have lots of problems, and they're bringing those problems with us. They're bringing drugs. They're bringing crime. They're rapists. And some, I assume, are good people."
He was talking about illegal immigrants (or undocumented immigrants, depending on your political bent). His language is emotive, absolutist and appeals to baser instincts of fear and anger rather than reason or evidence. It's language that incites and exploits stereotypes, and it's dangerous.
Some people voted for Trump because he speaks like them. But many voted for Trump because to. If you can manage to look past the polemic, you'll find embedded within an even more powerful message. To the culturally and economically stagnate, to those who could see no future for themselves or their families on the cusp of the new world of globalisation and technology, Trump said, "I hear you".
An example: implicit within a statement like "Mexicans are bringing drugs and crime to the US" is an acknowledgement of the  gripping many parts of the country as well as concerns about the impact of illegal immigration - in particular  In the latter, there is surprisingly little evidence on either side of the debate - although immigration overall (legal and illegal) . Sadly, Trump's rhetoric scapegoats immigrants, even as it recognises the real hardships faced by his supporters.
The Atlantic: "The press takes him literally, but not seriously; his supporters take him seriously, but not literally."
Language is important. It can be used to incite, obscure, validate, expose. It has meaning, but meaning is in the eye of the beholder (as my conversation with the patient at the pharmacy certainly affirms).
Listening is important too. There is something to be gained by trying to understand another person's point of view. The judgment can come later.
Garyn Tan is a pharmacist and studying a Masters of Economics at the ANU
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mexico</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Kingdom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garyn Tan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mexican</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WOG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ISIS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vietnam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darron Cummings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arab</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North African</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Atlantic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saigon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Press Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotherham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pakistani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Howard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barack Obama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Masters of Economics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
