<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445282307622077</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:15</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Australian</source>
  <url>http://www.theaustralian.com.au/business/technology/samsungs-q9-gets-the-picture-and-sound-perfect/news-story/71e2384119f5ea497b2dae7d9b8f1ab6</url>
  <title>Samsung picture and sound perfect</title>
  <content>
Samsung wants to dazzle us with its latest 4K TV and soundbar system. It comprises the Korean company's premium Q9 QLED 65-inch TV, along with its Sound+ soundbar, subwoofer and wireless rear speakers.
We're currently in the midst of a war over the future supply of TV panels. LG, Sony and Panasonic locally are selling premium TV sets with OLED, or organic LED panels. The panels are not backlit, instead self-emit light. Pixels can be turned on or off separately.
With this technology, blacks are completely black and there's no bleeding of colour from a bright to dark area of the display. The bright colours of OLED on perfectly black backgrounds -offers stunning viewing.
Samsung is still using LED-lit LCD panels for premium sets, but it has modified them to deliver improved image quality using what it calls Quantum Dot LED or QLED technology.
A layer of nanocrystals between the panel and the LED backlighting vastly improves colour control and range.
The top-of-the-range Q9 has LED backlighting on either side whereas the Q7, which I reviewed early this year, and Q8 have it from the bottom. The Q9 display is brighter, up to 2000 nits. You can see more shades of dark when watching 4K HDR (high dynamic range) content with the extra brightness.
Both OLED and QLED deliver stunning images. We tend to argue over relatively small improvements in image quality at the top end of the market. In the end, my preference is OLED, but it's by a micro whisker.
Now to the panels war. If you think Samsung is staying away from producing OLED TV panels, think again.
It is reported that Samsung wants to build the world's biggest OLED panel factory, which will operate by 2019, with a production capacity of 180,000- 270,000 panels a month.
The estimated cost of construction and equipment together is an estimated $US16 billion ($20bn). It is also reported that LG, its Korean rival, wants to build three new OLED factories at a cost of almost $US9bn.
Apple, too, is believed to be considering building its own OLED displays but they would be mainly smaller ones for iPhones and iPads.
OLED panels were difficult to make, had a high factory failure rate and were expensive but, given the billions being invested, they should be common and cheaper in the next few years with production lines cranking up.
As for the Q9, the extra brightness and increased backlighting results in the best picture quality I've seen on a Samsung TV so far.
Samsung promotes a feature called "100 per cent colour volume", which preserves colour quality at high levels of brightness so that they don't look washed out.
The other big plus is the menu system. The Q9 uses the latest version of Samsung's Tizen TV operating system, which has a very clean interface.
Navigating your way around the Q9 with the remote is simple and intuitive. Your main apps -appear in a band along the bottom of the screen. The left-hand side items expand to let you view -the apps store, search content, change sources and access -settings.
Tizen offers a pretty wide choice of apps. In Australia they include Netflix, Stan, Spotify, Foxtel Play, Quickflix and -TuneIn radio.

When you choose an app, a second band appears above the app band with common choices for that app. With Live TV, it comprised the guide, a channel list and schedule manager.
Speech recognition didn't work for me. There were too many mistakes to make voice control usable. Samsung needs to rethink whether it uses its own voice engine or adopts, say, -Google's well-developed option. Netflix didn't accept voice commands on this set.
The set integrates well with Samsung products such as its new UBD-M9500 Blu-ray player. Pop in a disk and the set switches to the correct input. You can control it with the one remote.
Sound+ soundbar
The MS750 5-channel soundbar, together with the subwoofer and wireless rear speakers, were the standout of this review. The previous soundbar solution, the K950 Dolby Atmos, could bounce sound off the ceiling, and redirect it around the room for some amazing 3D sound effects, without needing a bunch of separate speakers.
But most consumers don't have videos with Dolby Atmos sound, so they can't exploit the K950's capability.
The MS750 takes another tack. It accepts that a lot of our soundtracks aren't perfect, so it makes the best of them. It can upscale existing 8 to 24-bit audio to 32-bit to offer great sound.
I listened to several Spotify tracks and the sound quality was amazing. It was very clear even at a high volume. I could hear something like an authentic tone from instruments.
The sound bar contains 11 speakers, and can wirelessly connect to a Samsung TV. You can use the soundbar as a base for mounting the TV above it. Samsung has a special bracket for this.
You can also use a sound bar as an HDMI connection point for other devices to the TV and you can stream songs to the soundbar from your phone or tablet using Bluetooth. The subwoofer offers bass as low as 27 Hz.
Overall, this is a mouth-watering set-up, but it will cost you.
The 65-inch Q9 is available for $8299 and Samsung is bringing --to -market 75-inch and 88-inch -models ($13,999 and $29,999).
The MS750 soundbar costs $999, the SWA-W700 subwoofer $799, and M series wireless rear speakers are $179.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>K TV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UBD-M9500 Blu-ray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LG</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OLED TV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HDMI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OLED</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quantum Dot LED</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>K950 Dolby Atmos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>K950</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samsung TV</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spotify</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Korean</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QLED</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SWA-W700</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sony</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MS750</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxtel Play</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Q7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Q8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Q9</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LED-lit LCD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pixel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samsung's Tizen TV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TuneIn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>K HDR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dolby Atmos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPhone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Panasonic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Live TV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tizen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bluetooth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Google</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quickflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samsung</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$16</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
