<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445256537817648</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Australian</source>
  <url>http://www.theaustralian.com.au/business/technology/singularity-universitys-kaila-colbin-dont-let-technoscenti-rule/news-story/26019be688b7c1efe09ce912969adb81</url>
  <title>Don't let 'technoscenti' rule world</title>
  <content>
Technologists need to take a long and hard look on fostering inclusivity in the conversation around digital transformation or risk widening the social divide, warns Silicon Valley think-tank Singularity University's regional ambassador Kaila Colbin.
According to Ms Colbin, who is bringing the SingularityU Summit to Australia next year, it is critical that the future of society is not left in the hands of an elite ilk of the so-called "technoscenti".
"Technology-driven changes impact every single person in the society and it would be irresponsible to leave the decision on what type of a society we want in the hands of few people on the other side of the world," she said.
Far from being the paragons of virtue, the technology disrupters of the digital age continue to grapple with issues such as diversity, sexism and inclusivity. The firestorm currently raging at Google in response to a widely shared internal memo arguing against gender diversity is just the latest manifestation of a deep-rooted cultural challenge.
Ms Colbin said one step forward would be to open up the discussion more widely and free the topic of disruption beyond the confines of corporate boardrooms.
The SingularityU summit is doing its bit by throwing open the doors to educators, entrepreneurs and millennials through discounted tickets for its conferences.
"Everybody gets the same experience and we want to make a political statement with our approach to pricing," Ms Colbin said.
It is a small step in giving everyone a voice, but does it really -guarantee an informed conversation?
Contemporary social media platforms highlight how easy it is for users to get lost in their filter bubbles and Ms Colbin said part of the problem was algorithms feeding our biases rather than countering them.
"The algorithms are driving the polarised bubbles and what people don't realise is that what they see is customised by technology, it's just one perspective among many," she said. "This all happens behind the scenes driven by the black box of code." It's also a sign of our growing dependency on algorithms which in turn continues to feed our anxiety about machine learning and robots stealing our jobs.
According to Ms Colbin, algorithms unfortunately are beholden to their own biases.
"The thing we need to understand about algorithms is that when they are created they have inherent systemic biases, so for example, if an algorithm is given historical data about recidivism it will embody all the historical -racial injustices," she said.
"This doesn't mean that we can't use algorithm, what we need to do is we need to get wiser about what we can do to build a more aspirational model."
So, how we train algorithms will be crucial to how the artificial intelligence revolution plays out but for Ms Colbin there are far more pressing issues that need to be addressed, especially as technology becomes even more embedded in our life.
"When we look to the future we tend to think about either total dystopia or brave new world but the truth is somewhere in the middle," she said.
For Ms Colbin, the need to normalise the conversation about what impact technology will have on the entire society is growing ever acute.
"The world doesn't need another app from us to help rich people get things done easier."
A big part of that conversation will be to consider what happens to those employed in areas that are disrupted. As menial jobs are automated just where the displaced workers fit into overall value equation will become an important consideration.
According to Ms Colbin, minimum basic income isn't the answer to the impending impact of wholesale automation.
"It's a kneejerk response and it would be lazy of us to say that it will solve all the problems, there are other solutions like affirmative action for humans, special tax incentives, all of these potential solutions need to be on the table," she said.
She is equally sceptical about the importance of coding in our schools, saying that it is not a silver bullet.
"There is some argument that we won't be coding computers we will be training them," she said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>SingularityU Summit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Colbin</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kaila Colbin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Singularity University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SingularityU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Silicon Valley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Google</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
