<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445174933437201</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/news/politics/energy-retailers-look-for-common-ground-ahead-of-pms-energy-meeting-20170807-gxqows</url>
  <title>Energy retailers look for common ground ahead of Turnbull's energy meeting</title>
  <content>
Energy retailers were scrambling to find common ground on moves to help protect vulnerable customers from high electricity prices ahead of Wednesday's meeting with Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull in Canberra.
, the seven retailers have been in negotiations about a common position to take to the meeting.
But they believe the biggest hurdle to lower retail prices was a lack of consistent energy policies from state and federal governments, including the lack of action on a .
The three main areas of discussion included ensuring no vulnerable customer ended up on the most expensive tariff, a code of conduct for a price comparison website and ensuring customers who finished their contract were placed on a comparable market rate.

But it is understood there has not been agreement on a single position to take into the meeting with Mr Turnbull, Mr Frydenberg and Treasurer Scott Morrison.

Australian Energy Council chief executive Matthew Warren, who will attend the meeting as an industry representative, said most retailers already had policies dealing with vulnerable customers and did not put them on standing offers or the higher tariffs.
"It's quite clear high energy prices are a concern for governments but energy prices aren't high because of retail practices," Mr Warren said in an interview with The Australian Financial Review.
"We are always open to discussing with government how we can improve what we do and how we can work together to make things work better for Australian customers. We are going to be giving the government lots of information but everything is so complex. It's not an easy fix."
Mr Warren said there was already a price comparison website ( which is run by the Australian Energy Regulator but he conceded it could be more widely publicised.

The meeting of energy retailers comes after big gas producers were summoned to Canberra early this year to discuss high gas prices and then hit with a gas export restrictions. While energy retailers are expected to be similarly blindsided they could face more regulations or changes to the National Electricity Market rules.
It is understood the three big retailers - Origin Energy, AGL and EnergyAustralia - were more likely to find common ground on some issues going into the meeting but smaller energy retailers - who are looking for ways to boost their market share - were less likely to be on board.
AGL Energy chief executive Andy Vesey last week said the issue of energy affordability in Australia needed "urgent attention."
A spokesman for AGL said the company was committed to making retail arrangements simpler, more transparent, and more equitable but said the best way to bring down prices was to unlock investment through more reliable energy policies such as a Clean Energy Target.

"We have previously called for a standardised industry-wide solution to help customers easily compare plans and are committed to working with industry and regulators, retailers and consumer groups to have this in place by the end of the year," the spokesman said.
"The best way to bring down prices is to increase electricity supply which is why AGL supports a Clean Energy Target to unlock the necessary investment in new generation and ensure our energy system becomes more reliable, secure and affordable."
EnergyAustralia chief executive Catherine Tanna - who was in Hong Kong on Monday delivering results for the company - said it was a challenge to make EnergyAustralia a more profitable business, but also make energy more affordable for customers.
"It's a fine and delicate balance. We're confident we can achieve it, but no one pretends it will be easy," Ms Tanna said.

"Sustainable returns mean we have more funds available for investing in new supplies of cleaner energy. This is the money that will help build a modern energy system for Australia."
A spokeswoman for Origin Energy said the company was acutely aware of how high power prices are impacting Australian households and businesses.
"We've made sure that those people in our hardship program will not pay the recent price increases," the spokeswoman said. "All of us in the industry and the government need to work urgently together on the issue."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catherine Tanna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Energy Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Warren</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hong Kong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Electricity Market</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Energy Regulator</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andy Vesey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clean Energy Target</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Warren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treasurer Scott Morrison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AGL Energy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EnergyAustralia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Frydenberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Origin Energy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AGL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Tanna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
