<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445299487491600</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/business/banking-and-finance/cba-board-must-hold-executives-to-account-shareholders-20170807-gxr0pb.html</url>
  <title>CBA board must hold executives to account: shareholders</title>
  <content>
The Commonwealth Bank of Australia board is under mounting pressure to hold highly-paid executives to account over an alleged breach of anti-money laundering laws, with calls mounting for action to go beyond bonus cuts and to potentially include dismissing senior staff.
As CBA's directors met on Monday ahead of this week's results announcement, investors debated how the board led by Catherine Livingstone should respond to last week's explosive allegations the banking giant repeatedly breached anti-money laundering laws.

Up Next

ASX winners and losers - a snapshot

00:43

More BusinessDay Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

CBA accused of breaching money laundering act

Austrac has launched civil proceedings in the federal court alleging that CBA failed to comply with the law on more than 50,000 occasions.

Financial intelligence agency Austrac last week alleged criminals laundered millions of dollars through CBA's ATMs, and the bank repeatedly failed to properly report and monitor suspicious transactions.
That action has CBA facing hefty fines as well as long-term damage to its reputation. Management bonus cuts are widely expected but given the seriousness of the allegations, some are pushing for tougher action.

John Abernethy, chief investment officer at Clime Asset Management, said the board's reaction needed to be "hard and swift."
Cutting bonuses alone was "pathetic" and "heads should go" among managers in the relevant areas of the bank.

"Once you start moving pay scales into the millions, then these guys have to understand it's not a joke any more," said Mr Abernethy, who is invested in CBA.
"If they want to get paid that, they have to take absolutely responsibility, otherwise why are we paying them?"Photo: Nic Walker
Greens Treasury spokesman, Senator Peter Whish-Wilson, said the board should " make a statement about the future of [chief executive] Ian Narev".
Mr Narev, who has led the bank for six years, did not signal any intent to step down on Monday.Photo: Alex Ellinghausen
However, he admitted the bank had made "mistakes" and said the board would take "very serious account" of the latest scandal to hit the bank when it was deciding on executive bonuses for the year, which are expected to be revealed next week.
"I'm enjoying my job, I'm very dedicated to it. These parts aren't the most pleasant but they're important and the rest of it's up to the board," Mr Narev said on ABC Radio's AM.
These guys have to understand it's not a joke any more.
Clime Asset Management's John Abernethy

The company released a statement on Monday arguing that because the allegations centred on one "coding error" that meant tens of thousands of incidents could instead be viewed as a single breach.
There is no simple domestic precedent for the allegations against CBA, but Morgan Stanley analysts said in a report fines anywhere between $50 million and $2.5 billion were possible.
Banks overseas have been fined billions for larger scale breaches of anti-money laundering laws.
Share the pain

Principal at fund manager Alphinity, Andrew Martin, said if shareholders ended up wearing a cost from the scandal, management should be affected too - though it was too early to say if that is the case.
"If this whole thing gets to a conclusion where there's a financial penalty on the company ... then ultimately the management of the company needs to share in the financial pain," he said.
Some big investors also defended Mr Narev, who runs the most profitable bank in Australia.

Anton Tagliaferro of Investors Mutual believes the CBA scandal is overblown. Photo: Louie Douvis

Anton Tagliaferro, investment director at Investors Mutual, said the situation surrounding CBA, while concerning, was a "storm in a tea cup" when compared with the bank's entire operations.
"All these calls to chop the CEO are a little bit over the top," Mr Tagliaferro said.
"There are 50,000 employees in the CBA, he can't know exactly what each one of them is doing, and that's why within these large organisations you have things like internal audit divisions, and you have all sorts of checks and measures to make sure these things don't happen."
Mike Mangan of 2MG Asset Management was sceptical about how severe the consequences would be for bank management.
"Executives should walk the plank, but based on prior experience that's probably not going to happen. Bonuses should be withdrawn, but based on prior experience that's not going to happen either," he said.
The debate over management accountability came as CBA played down the potential size of fines it will face, saying a string of failures in its automated reporting system may be only one breach of the law.
That is because one leg of the allegations against CBA it that it did not tell Austrac quickly enough about more than 53,506 cash deposits of more than $10,000, and on Monday , so they could be seen as one breach.
Ms Livingstone was appointed chair of CBA in 2016, the same year CBA became the first major lender in Australia to receive a first "strike" - when more than a quarter of shareholders vote against against its executive pay packets.
Mr Narev's pay last year was $12.3 million, making him the highest paid of the big four bank bosses. CBA will face further questions over the scandal when it delivers its full-year results on Wednesday, when it is tipped to notch up a full-year profit of $9.8 billion.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nic Walker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Livingstone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUSTRAC</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Narev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Narev</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louie Douvis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Abernethy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morgan Stanley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alphinity</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mike Mangan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clime Asset Management</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catherine Livingstone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BusinessDay Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Bank of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MG Asset Management</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2.3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBA ATMs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Tagliaferro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anton Tagliaferro of Investors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Abernethy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC Radio's AM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anton Tagliaferro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greens Treasury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Peter Whish-Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asset Management's John Abernethy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Ellinghausen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Investors Mutual</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBA</name>
    <count>15</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
