<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445046084415941</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/mining/china-wont-cave-to-us-pressure-on-north-korea-robert-zoellick-20170807-gxqm92</url>
  <title>China won't cave to US pressure on North Korea: Robert Zoellick</title>
  <content>
US President Donald Trump has made a mistake in  former World Bank president Robert Zoellick says, warning heaping pressure on China is likely to cause tension without yielding results.
Mr Trump has called on China to help end North Korea's nuclear missile program and, frustrated by what he considers inaction, has threatened an investigation into China's trade practices.
Mr Zoellick, a veteran trade negotiator and an official in both Bush administrations, said he thought Mr Trump had "caught himself in a bind" by trying to force action on the issue.
"I actually think Trump has made a mistake by trying to link those two things directly," Mr Zoellick said.

"I dealt with both trade and security issues and I wouldn't have traded US economic interests for our security position. I would have said, 'look, we have a common interest in stopping North Korean nuclear weapon proliferation'."

Mr Zoellick said he did not believe China would intervene.
"I think the view in some quarters of the US, and this would have been true under Hilary Clinton, too, is that, if you press China hard enough, China will solve the North Korea problem," Mr Zoellick told The Australian Financial Review.
'Destabilising the regime'

"I am sceptical about that. I think it either won't or can't.

"What I mean by that is, if China stopped all energy shipments and all trade with North Korea, it could have a huge effect but it would also risk destabilising the regime and I don't think the Chinese want to do that."
China is North Korea's biggest trading partner, closest ally and the countries share a 1400-kilometre border.
A vocal critic of Mr Trump, Mr Zoellick was in Australia to deliver the keynote address at the Diggers and Dealers mining conference in Kalgoorlie, Western Australia.
He said the Trump administration's decision to emphasise the potential for military action was "a very risky venture" but he expected it would "continue to beat that drum as a way of trying to force action".

Missile defense, action against companies supplying North Korea and a united desire to prevent the supply of nuclear weapons to other countries were likely to emerge, he said.
"Trump thinks in terms of the art of a deal and that can suggest creating uncertainty, can now and then involve some belligerency and I think people need to expect that but he has to work with the system," Mr Zoellick said.
Global significance

The Trump presidency would ultimately act as a test of the US political and court systems and the country's private sector, he said, arguing that how those systems responded to Mr Trump's decisions would have global significance.

And it was here he called on Australia to step up.
"Australia is the country in the region most likely to understand those aspects of the US and understand they create certain stabilising forces," he said.
"Having represented the US in different capacities around the world for 30 years, it is a very open system so people think they understand it but it is a pretty complex system. Australians are more likely to grasp that."
In a wide-ranging speech, Mr Zoellick told the more than 2000 delegates gathered for the annual mining conference he was more concerned about the Trump administration's protectionist stance on trade than the  and the .

"I think it is a big problem because the US has been, for the past 70 years, a world leader in creating international trading systems and, if the US moves away from that or starts to take protectionist actions, I think it will have a trigger effect on the openness of international trade [and] countries' growth," he said.
Mr Zoellick painted a fairly positive outlook for the Chinese economy but said he was keeping an eye on China's debt levels, which had increased rapidly to "quite high levels".
"Debt is going up and returns on assets and investment is going down," he said. "So frankly they are borrowing to keep the economy going but they are getting less return."
Mr Zoellick said he was watching the level of capital flow from China because it somewhat reflected "uncertainty about China's growth story".
"If the Chinese themselves lose confidence in the growth prospects, capital will seep out."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Zoellick</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korea</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Zoellick</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kalgoorlie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Trump</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hilary Clinton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bush</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
