<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445260832785013</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/fake-news-starbucks-free-coffee-to-undocumented-immigrants-2017-8</url>
  <title>Starbucks shoots down viral rumour that it's giving away free coffee to undocumented immigrants</title>
  <content>
Starbucks has shot down rumours that the coffee giant was planning to offer discounts to undocumented American immigrants.

"All undocumented Americans will receive any item on the Starbucks menu 40% off," reads a fake coupon that claimed to promote "Starbucks DREAMer Day" that has been being shared online over the last week.

Starbucks debunked rumours about a #BorderFreeCoffee promotion on Twitter over the weekend. 

"We're sorry but you've been misinformed," the company tweeted in response to a tweet accusing the chain of "pandering" to immigrants. "Starbucks is not sponsoring any such event."

The image promoting the fake promotion seems to have spread from a post on 4chan's Politically Incorrect message board.

The message board gained a degree of notoriety during the 2016 presidential election for spreading pro-Trump memes and fake news, such as 

Starbucks is known its progressive politics, including , a program that allows to avoid deportation. 

In January, Starbucks pledged to hire 10,000 refugees after Trump issued an executive order barring refugees from entering the US, sparking conservative boycott threats. Last year, long-time CEO and the current chairman of Starbucks' board, Howard Schultz, endorsed Democratic nominee Hillary Clinton for president.

We're sorry but you've been misinformed. Starbucks is not sponsoring any such event.
- Starbucks Coffee (@Starbucks)

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Howard Schultz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Starbucks DREAMer Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Starbucks</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Starbucks Coffee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hillary Clinton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Politically Incorrect</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BorderFreeCoffee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
