<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445273717687168</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:13</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/north/people-on-low-incomes-priced-out-of-darebin-in-rental-squeeze/news-story/f8225e3b725465db3151e46cbccc1608</url>
  <title>Poor feel rental squeeze in Darebin</title>
  <content>
JUST 39 rental properties in Darebin are considered affordable for people on low incomes, alarming new figures reveal.
The latest , prepared by the State Government, shows less than 2 per cent of all rentals in the municipality were deemed affordable in the past quarter.
A property is considered affordable if the rent is less than 30 per cent of the relevant Centrelink payment. Darebin's median rent is $300 per week.
A search of realestate.com.au last week found 15 properties in Reservoir with rents of less than $300 a week, with the cheapest a 27sq m studio apartment with a weekly rent of $192.
Darebin Community Legal Centre outreach lawyer Beth King said many of her clients on Centrelink had difficulty with rent payments.
"It's disappointing to see that while rents are skyrocketing, income support payments have stagnated," she said.
"We often see three generations of families living in the same home all experiencing financial hardship."
Thornbury teacher Marc De Aizpurua and his partner both work but struggle to pay "well over" a third of their income on rent for their three bedroom house.
The couple chose the suburb because it was close to work and their daughter's school.
"Compared with what else is out there I feel we are getting a decent deal, but that doesn't change the fact it's an incredible amount of money," Mr De Aizpurua said.
He said the money squeeze meant saving for a house deposit was impossible.
"We've pretty much given up on home ownership," he said.
The report showed that the availability of affordable housing in Melbourne had declined from a high of 30.2 per cent of all rental dwellings in September 2005 to just 5.7 per cent.
Victorian Council of Social Service chief executive Emma King said the report showed average rents had grown by 110 per cent since 2001, while wages have only increased by 75 per cent.
Over the 12 months to the March quarter the median rent in metropolitan Melbourne rose 3.8 per cent.
"Renters are often the forgotten victims of a housing market in crisis," Ms King said.
"This is happening just as people are being shut-out from home ownership and are renting for longer - including into retirement."
VCOSS is also calling for an increase to Newstart, stronger rights for renters and for changes to negative gearing and capital gains tax.
Council to Homeless Persons acting chief executive Kate Colvin said tax incentives were encouraging investment in higher-end apartment stock, which was unaffordable and created fierce competition at the cheaper end of the market.
"You've got a lot more people renting than buying, which is squeezing out people on lower incomes who have always been renting," Ms Colvin said.
Federal Opposition Leader Bill Shorten has flagged Labor's intentions to reform negative gearing and the capital gains discount.
Local government areas with the highest proportion of affordable rental dwellings were Melton, Wyndham, Cardinia, Nillumbik and Whittlesea.
While the areas with the lowest proportion - less than 1 per cent of dwellings - were Bayside, Boroondara, Port Phillip, Stonnington and Yarra.
Leader News has sought comment from Federal Treasurer Scott Morrison.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thornbury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Centrelink</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wyndham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Phillip</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darebin</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr De Aizpurua</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kate Colvin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Homeless Persons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marc De Aizpurua</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newstart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 2005</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Council of Social</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VCOSS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cardinia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boroondara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emma King</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bayside</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stonnington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Treasurer Scott Morrison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darebin Community Legal Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whittlesea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms King</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beth King</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Opposition Leader Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1.4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Colvin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nillumbik</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
