<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445303782459025</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/news/flipping-good-exercise-this/news-story/97c5f14255ba74a4003f2a1e8f499a40</url>
  <title>Flipping good exercise this</title>
  <content>
FATHER of six Tom Fowler can front-flip and handspring his way across the floor with the agility of a man half his age.
At 56, Mr Fowler is the oldest member of his Gymnastics Townsville club but he is no slouch on the balance beam and puts some younger gymnasts to shame with his strength on the parallel bars.
Mr Fowler said he had always kept in shape but it was when his daughter started gymnastics that he first went to join in - and he hasn't looked back.
"About two years ago I enrolled my daughter Mikaela, in a gymnastics class and I saw they had adult classes," he said.
"I was just looking through their booklet and I asked how old you had to be to do gymnastics, and she said any age over 16, so I qualified.
"There are other men who go but I am the oldest in the whole club by at least two decades. I am like a lump of four-by-two but since I started doing gymnastics, I can nearly do the splits, and I can do front flips and hand springs."
Mr Fowler, who is a manual arts teacher at the Calvary Christian College high school, said his 15-year-old daughter could still cut some gymnastic moves that he couldn't yet muster.

"She has a bit more finesse than me," he said.
"There's certain muscle-ups I can do that she can't, it takes a lot of upper body strength. I can nearly get up to a handstand on the parallel bars."
Mr Fowler said he hoped he inspired others to have a go at gymnastics.
"The gymnastics has improved my health and I am much more flexible," he said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Fowler</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Calvary Christian College</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gymnastics Townsville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Fowler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mikaela</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
