<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445041789448601</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/news/policy/industrial-relations/woolworths-warns-enterprise-bargaining-system-now-unworkable-20170807-gxqpka</url>
  <title>'Unworkable to all practical purposes': Woolworths says broken bargaining rules risk to economy</title>
  <content>
Woolworths is calling for an overhaul of enterprise bargaining after warning the current system is now so uncertain it is "unworkable" and "a significant risk to the economy".
The retailer revealed its position for the first time in a submission to a Senate inquiry on penalty rates where it complained it had "little prospect" of negotiating a new agreement in light of the Fair Work Commission's decision to axe a similar wages deal by Coles last year and as unions appealed cuts to Sunday penalty rates.
"These are an unprecedented set of circumstances that no business could have contemplated and their collective effect has created a 'perfect storm' for Woolworths and other retailers and their employees," it said.
The submission was made to  into large employers' use of enterprise agreements to cut penalty rates, which initially cited Coles, Woolworths, KFC and McDonald's in its terms of reference.

Woolworths and other major retailers have historically negotiated lower weekend penalty rates in return for higher weekly rates with the Shop Distributive and Allied Employees Association.

However, the industry has been left in limbo since last year when the Fair Work Commission terminated Coles' agreement because its penalty rates trade-off left some part-timers worse off than the award, stressing an interpretation of the 'better off overall test' (BOOT) that requires each individual worker to earn more than the award at any point in time.
Woolworths, which employs more than 200,000 workers, argued such a test is "unworkable" in an industry that needs to respond to major changes in technology and customer buying patterns and where part-time hours need to be flexible to respond to demand.
The retailer's submission backed the Productivity Commission's recommendation that the BOOT should be replaced by a "no-disadvantage test", which would look at classes of employees rather than every single worker.
"The current uncertainty concerning the BOOT is inhibiting bargaining and putting at risk a system of bargaining that has served the Australian economy well. The BOOT provisions require amendment to restore a workable approach," Woolworths' submissions stated.

"Specifically the current emphasis of the FWC on the particular roster worked by individual employees, or potential employees, at a particular point in time renders the BOOT unworkable to all practical purposes."
Penalty cuts phase-in 

The submission also took aim at the workplace tribunal's decision to phase in penalty rate cuts in retail , arguing the delay could "inhibit" bargaining by creating uncertainty about what the correct minimum standard should be when applying the BOOT to any new agreement made during this period.
The SDA and United Voice's appeal of the commission's penalty rates decision in the Federal Court, which will not be heard until September, also created "ongoing uncertainty".

While Woolworths' national supermarkets agreement expired back in 2015 it said it had yet to negotiate a replacement agreement because of these factors. 
The retail giant said this "lack of clarity and inconsistency" around BOOT "is a significant risk to the economy, given the combination of productivity and wages gains that have been made in tandem over the last 20 years".
Woolworths' submission comes as the Australian Industry Group warned the inquiry that it would "not be surprising" if major retailers and fast food companies decided enterprise bargaining "is just too unworkable to bother with and that it is far simpler to just apply the relevant award". 
A submission from the Department of Employment said that almost two thirds of large fast food, retail, hospitality and pharmacy agreements pay less than the award for Sundays.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shop Distributive</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDonald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KFC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woolworths</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Voice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Productivity Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coles</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Employment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SDA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fair Work Commission</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Industry Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FWC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Allied Employee Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
