<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444745436699312</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/sport/cricket/peter-nevill-says-australian-cricketers-have-set-the-bar-for-gender-pay-equality-20170807-gxqoz1.html</url>
  <title>Peter Nevill says Australian cricketers have set the standard for gender pay equality</title>
  <content>
 Test wicket-keeper Peter Nevill says Australian cricketers have set the standard for gender pay equality after a historic pay deal included women for the first time.
After months of bitter negations, the ugly pay dispute between Cricket Australia and its players  and female players were the major winners, earning a massive pay increase from $7.5 million to $55.2 million.Photo: AP
The players  which has been in place for 20 years and a modernised version was agreed upon which will produce a player payment pool for men and women of $459 million.
The huge windfall for the country's best female cricketers is the biggest pay rise in the history of women's sport in Australia and Nevill said it was great to be on the right side of history.
"The player group was so united, both male and female, state and international players, and it's the first time everybody has been included in the one agreement which is fantastic," Nevill said.

"Cricket has now set the benchmark for Australian sport in terms of gender pay equity.
"It is a very positive result out of the MOU and I'm glad everyone can now, including the fans, focus on the upcoming cricket.
"It will be great to get back to actually watching cricket as opposed to just reading about this dispute - I'm very pleased it has been resolved."
More than 230 professional players in Australia were unemployed after the previous pay deal expired on June 30 and Nevill admitted there was a collective sigh of relief when the saga finally ended.
"It's not an ideal situation for anybody when it gets to that point, there's a lot of relief from people that were under some financial pressure there for a while," Nevill said.
"It's pleasing to see that we've maintained what's worked well between Cricket Australia and the players for the past 20 years and to see that modernised to an extent was good as well with a lot of focus on grassroots.
"It was a long process and it gives some surety to the coming season now and the tour of Bangladesh first and foremost which I'm very much looking forward to watching."
The 17-Test glovesman was dropped from the Australian side last summer and despite strong showing for NSW, Nevill hasn't been able to force his way back into the side.
"It was pleasing to put together some good performances with the bat after getting dropped last year and that's all I can do, I have to leave my fate in the selections hands beyond that," Nevill said.
"It's all performance based, you get dropped because you haven't performed well enough, so it's about going back to state level and performing as well as you can."
The 31-year-old is determined to wear the baggy green again and said the fire burns within to reignite his Test career.
"There is no better feeling than playing for your country and I'm very determined to prove myself at that level if I get the opportunity to do so again," Nevill said.
"It's definitely a big goal to get back there but it's sort of something you try and not focus on too much because it can detract from what you're doing, I've got to try and perform as well as I can but also just enjoy it."
Alex Blackwell made 90 runs from 56 balls in Australia's semi-final loss against India in the women's World Cup last month and said with the pay deal sorted, the focus is now on the Ashes.
"It's a great win for cricket in general and in particular the women's game, it's wonderful to see the player group stand so strong together and to have a gender equal pay model in place is something I'm really proud of," Blackwell said.
"The negotiations went on quite a long time and it's great to see the men's and women's Ashes will go ahead.
"It's going to be a great event and something we can look forward to as a country and hopefully win two trophies."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MoU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nevill</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bangladesh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Nevill</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>India</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Blackwell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cricket Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blackwell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ash</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
