<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445269422719777</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/north-west/fundraising-efforts-for-wave-pool-at-tullamarine-enters-its-final-stages/news-story/67c971627f7f6966ea7eab48afa51209</url>
  <title>Still waiting for waves at Tullamarine</title>
  <content>
MELBOURNE'S first surf park, twice the size of the MCG, is yet to get off the ground.
The wave pool to be built on a 7ha site at Airport Drive, Tullamarine, was scheduled to begin construction late last year with the first surfers to hit the waves this year.
But the project, expected to cost $18.5 million, hasn't begun.
URBNSURF brand and content manager Rupert Partridge said they were in the final stages of fundraising for the project and a timeline of works couldn't be confirmed at this stage.
Last year the company secured a 30-year lease from Melbourne Airport to operate the complex.
RELATED:
The surfing lagoon will have wave generating technology, which will deliver man-made waves that offer an authentic surfing experience.
The waves will range from 1.9m high, 32 second long waves - down to 0.6m high, rolling white-water waves, for beginner surfers.
A surf training academy, climbing wall, parkour trail, bouldering course, mountain bike track, running track and other lifestyle sport activities will also be among the features.
The development is meant to generate more than 300 jobs during the construction phase and another 45 full time positions when the surf park opens.
It's anticipated more than $267 million will be injected into the local economy over the project's life.
Hume planning and development director Kelvin Walsh said the council was working hard to encourage businesses to invest in the municipality.
Mr Walsh said the council had held discussions with the owners behind the venture, and would continue to work closely with them and Melbourne Airport in the months ahead to make sure the project was progressing.
Melbourne Airport wasn't able to comment before Leader's deadline.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MCG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tullamarine</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Airport Drive</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hume</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>URBNSURF</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Airport</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelvin Walsh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rupert Partridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Walsh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
