<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445084739122252</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/2044846/brave-kyle-honoured-for-saving-brothers-life/?cs=4110</url>
  <title>Brave Kyle honoured for saving brother's life</title>
  <content>
Brave Kyle honoured for saving brother's life

Charli Squires, 4, with his heroic big brother Kyle Squires, 15. Picture: KIRK GILMOUR

How the Mercury covered the story.

Ambulance chief executive Ray Creen gives the Commendation for Courage award to Kyle Squires. Picture: KIRK GILMOUR

It's official: big brother Kyle is a hero. Picture: KIRK GILMOUR

Charli and dad Jayson Squires watch Kyle receive his award. Picture: KIRK GILMOUR

exit
Kyle Squires's quick thinking and first aid training saved his brother's life.

Yesterday, the 15-year-old from Thirroul was rewarded for his actions with the highest honour from NSW Ambulance.
Chief executive Ray Creen presented Kyle with the Commendation for Courage (Community) Award at Thirroul Surf Life Saving Club for the bravery he showed in 2012.
Kyle, then 14, was in his family's swimming pool with his brothers Charli, 2, and Jack, 5, and their father Jayson.
When Mr Squires went inside for a cup of tea Kyle briefly took his eyes off Charli. Those few seconds nearly cost the toddler his life.
When Kyle turned back to the ledge where Charli had been sitting, he couldn't see him. He then found him on the bottom of the pool.
Kyle pulled Charli out, but he was pale and turning blue.
Kyle cleared Charli's mouth and began CPR, alerting his father who continued resuscitation until the ambulance arrived.
- Ray Creen
NSW Ambulance intensive care paramedic Peter Cribbs was part of the team sent to the Squireses' home. He nominated Kyle for the award.
"His actions exemplify why first aid is so important," he said.
"You never know when you're going to need it and you never know who you're going to apply it to."
Yesterday, Kyle thanked the paramedics for their quick response. He said receiving the award was a proud moment.
"It's an overwhelming experience, it means a lot," Kyle said.
Chief executive Ray Creen said Kyle was an excellent young man who acted courageously and maturely.
"I have no doubt that Kyle saved his young brother's life that day," he said.
"He is a credit to his family and the surf lifesaving club. I'm sure they are all very proud."
Kyle's father said it was difficult to describe how proud he was of Kyle.
"I think he deserves every award they're going to give him for his actions. It's a good day for the family," Mr Squires said.
Kyle and his dad earned their surf lifesaving certificates in 2012 at Thirroul Surf Life Saving Club.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charli</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Cribbs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jayson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charli Squires, 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kyle</name>
    <count>18</count>
    <score>22</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thirroul</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack, 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ray Creen</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thirroul Surf Life Saving Club</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Squires</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kyle Squires</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kyle Squires</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KIRK GILMOUR</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Ambulance</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CPR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Squireses</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jayson Squires</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
