<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445256537817661</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/outer-east/wantirna-mall-pay-parking-may-be-introduced-because-of-people-avoiding-fees-at-knox-hospital/news-story/705cd7185d6688faffcaa5ddd0e10d41</url>
  <title>Parking crisis hits shopping centre</title>
  <content>
VISITORS dodging hefty parking fees at Knox Private Hospital are hogging spots at Wantirna Mall.
Knox Council is considering tighter restrictions at the shopping centre, with Mayor Darren Pearce saying it was a "social problem" that people did not want to pay for parking.

HAVE YOUR SAY: Would you be willing to pay for parking at Wantirna Mall? Tell us below.
The hospital charges $7 for parking for more than 30 minutes, up to $12 a day.
The mall's carpark over the road is free, with bays restricted to one, two and four-hour parking.
As part of the council's draft car parking review, Cr Pearce said it would look at the mall as a "priority".
He said spaces were being used by people who were not shopping there.
"We've got a social problem - people don't want to pay for parking," Cr Pearce said at a recent council meeting.
Cr Pearce told the Leader the solution could involve meters, more patrols, or technology such as in-ground sensors.
"We need to assess the most appropriate option for that area," he said.
"We must ensure it doesn't impact on the business viability of the shopping centre."
Traders welcomed a review, but most who spoke to the Leader said they opposed parking meters.
King Bean Cafe owner Caroline McDonald said parking had been an issue for years.
"Certainly people get angry at the fact that it's supposed to be for our customers," she said.
"Sometimes the carpark's full and you look around and there's hardly anyone shopping."
Knox Private Hospital spokeswoman Megan Edwards said the hospital charged "a reasonable car parking fee".
The health and mall precinct in Wantirna was listed as one of the first areas in Knox that would have a parking management plan put in place as part of the council's review.
The draft policy can be viewed at  or at the council's Civic Centre in Burwood Highway, Wantirna South, with submissions open until the end of August.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Knox Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Megan Edwards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wantirna South</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Knox Private Hospital</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wantirna Mall</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burwood Highway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wantirna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mayor Darren Pearce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Pearce</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caroline McDonald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Knox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Civic Centres</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King Bean Cafe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
