<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444741141731873</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/lifestyle/health/nrl-and-afl-stars-lace-up-for-social-violence-awareness-campaign-step-back-think/news-story/1bd7b61a86a5aa02d0e21ee701f62190</url>
  <title>Football takes a stand against violence</title>
  <content>
IT™S time to lace up and fight violence.

Football codes across the nation will come together this weekend to fight the scourge of social violence.

More than 40,000 people, including some of Australia's biggest NRL and AFL stars will take part in Step Back Think's Lace Up campaign to raise awareness of social violence and how to combat it.

This includes one-punch assaults, pub brawls and street fights.

Australia needs to talk about the violence, it is a societal ill that affects a disturbing number of young people and one that can be prevented.

Twenty Australians lost their lives to coward punches or king-hit punches last year, in 2016:

• Six in NSW

• Five in Qld

• Four in Vic

• Four in WA

• One in Tas

Step Back Think chief executive Anna O'Halloran said the organisation and the campaign is aimed at creating a future where social violence isn't the norm.

"Young people shouldn't think that violence should be a part of their lives," she told News Corp Australia.

"We refuse to think that is acceptable. We want to empower young people with the skills and the confidence to make that happen.

"Twenty people lost their lives to coward punches or kings hits last year. That is not just 20 people, it is 20 families ripped apart and the ripple effect of that is enormous."

This year is the fifth campaign for Lace Up that had 10,000 participants in its first year.

Players in the Round 21 AFL clash between Brisbane Lions and Gold Coast Suns on Saturday at the Gabba will wear orange laces as part of the campaign.

As will players in the Round 23 NRL clashes between Brisbane Broncos and Cronulla Sharks, Melbourne Storm and Sydney Roosters and Wests Tigers and Manly Sea Eagles and players at club level across Australia.

Step Back Think was founded in 2007 as a youth-led committee, and has transformed into today's not-for-profit organisation, after James Macready-Bryan was left with permanent brain damage after being attacked by a stranger on his 20th birthday.

"We want to educate people about thinking about how they will react in a situation when social violence might occur," Ms O'Halloran said.

"And social violence is not just coward punching, it is multiple punches, brawls, it can manifest itself in many ways.

"It is not just the tragic deaths that occur, there are the instances of brain injuries.

"And it is far wider than is reported.

"We want to shift the conversation at the community level so people say this violence does not have to happen.

"The clubs that we talk to and that are part of the campaign they say to us 'we are most than just a sporting club we are raising young people' and in the feedback we are getting and in our research too the message is getting out there.

"Social violence isn't acceptable and it doesn't have to be a reality of life."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twenty Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manly Sea Eagles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gabba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Round 23 NRL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Back Think</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast Suns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Storm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qld</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Step Back Think's Lace Up</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wests Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Roosters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cronulla Sharks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lace Up</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anna O'Halloran</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Broncos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Round 21 AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Macready-Bryan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms O'Halloran</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Lions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
