<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445265127752372</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/comment/the-time-bomb-in-the-australian-electorate-the-major-parties-cant-afford-to-ignore-20170807-gxqpqu.html</url>
  <title>The time bomb in the Australian electorate the major parties can't afford to ignore</title>
  <content>
What do Australians think of Donald Trump's presidency so far? Based on focus groups of undecided voters in marginal seats in Melbourne and western Sydney, we can say three things. First, there's scant approval of the way he's doing his job, and only one voter out of 30 thought he was accomplishing anything. "I don't agree with what he has done," said an older woman in Melbourne, "but he has done stuff."   And even that one, when challenged by others in her group to name an achievement, could not. He'd built a wall, she said, but the others had to let her down with the news that he hadn't, not yet at least.
Second, there's a fair bit of apprehension. "He's going to get us all bombed," said a Sydney woman who described herself as an Avon lady.

Up Next

Who is Frank Madafferi?

09:40

More National News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Turnbull rallies the troops

PM Malcolm Turnbull has called a special Liberal party meeting to try and settle the divisive issue of same sex marriage.

Third, and despite all their criticisms, these Australians have some admiration for Trump. "Trump has balls," said a 44-year-old Melbourne electrician. "A lot of what he says is right." A young Sydney woman who works as a safety manager said: "He says what he thinks." 
And a western Sydney man captured the paradox - Trump may not be smart or successful, but he is admirably authentic: "I don't like him either, but some of the things he said you kinda liked; and obviously he's a complete and utter idiot."
The moderator who conducted the two western Sydney focus groups for Fairfax Media, Ipsos research director Laura Demasi, summarised: "Both groups brought up Trump spontaneously citing him as an - albeit very flawed and reviled - example of leader who says what he believes, has conviction and has the commitment to take action at any cost in contrast to 'our scripted politicians who are puppets'."

A young garage manager from western Sydney put it this way: "I like Trump's things about being accessible - he's talking shit, but it's a bit laid bare about what he thinks. I would like my politicians to represent my views hard. Who knows what Malcolm Turnbull thinks?" 
Ipsos's Demasi observed that Pauline Hanson is discussed in the same light as Trump: "Which really speaks to the perceived dearth of these qualities in our current political leaders on both sides."

Voters are interested in fringe politicians because, as a young Sydney woman put it, "the people we do know are dickheads".

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

And this is the reason that, although Australians see Trump as a failed president to date, Trump-style politics is a real and potent force here nonetheless.
The Australian analogue to Trump is Pauline Hanson. This is no coincidence; she mimics him closely on immigration policy and discrimination against Muslims, for instance. 
When her name came up in one of the focus groups, an older woman voter in western Sydney immediately remarked: "Like her or not, she believes what she says - it's the same with Donald Trump." 
The reflex response from the two main parties is twofold. First, that Hanson and the other minor parties are merely protest votes who can't actually fix anything. The voters in focus groups know this, but they don't expect Labor or Liberal parties to fix anything, either.Photo: AP
So why not vote for Hanson? Or another fringe party? "I'm taking an interest in the smaller parties not because I'm under any delusion that they will fix anything, but to send a message," said a young man in western Sydney.
Liberal and Labor offer only "dirty politics, no solutions - that's why Trump got in," as an older Sydney voter put it. Photo: Andrew Meares
The second response of the main parties is to say, don't worry - they can't really hurt us. These voters can have their fun with the Senate, they say, but when they cast their ballots for the House of Representatives their votes will come back to us  through the system of preferential voting anyway. The focus groups knew this. None actually used the words "preferential voting", but they all seemed quite aware that the system will channel their House votes back to the big parties ultimately. 
If the big parties shrug off the danger, they are merely issuing a dare to the electorate. "I'm considering throwing my vote to one of the parties outside the main two to one day make them viable," said the garage manager. Photo: AAP
He knows that unless the big parties reform, it's just a matter of time and scale. With time, the scale of the protest vote will grow. Until it reaches a scale where it overwhelms the major parties.
First in the Senate, eventually in the House. Arrogance is no response. It is only a challenge, an invitation to yet more anger.
The voters in the focus groups are not naive about Hanson and the other minors. 
The people don't idolise her. They are realistic about her flaws. For example, a young woman who works in the tax office said of One Nation: "They made you worry about Asians and now they make you worry about Arabs."
These voters know that the angry populists like Trump and Hanson are not a solution, only a protest. But they are at the point of disillusionment where they don't believe in solutions any more. 
So what do undecided Australian voters think of Trump? Hopeless in government, perfect as protest. And they are in the mood to protest.
Peter Hartcher is political editor.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laura Demasi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>One Nation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ipsos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Meares</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Avon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frank Madafferi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>House of Representatives</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hansons</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Hartcher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump-style</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muslim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ipsos's Demasi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arab</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
