<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445050379383301</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/real-estate/commercial/development/as-beijing-gets-tough-wanda-tests-market-for-2-billion-australian-exit-20170807-gxr458</url>
  <title>As Beijing gets tough Wanda tests market for $2 billion Australian exit </title>
  <content>
China's Dalian Wanda Group, which is under pressure to crimp its offshore expansion and facing a freeze on bank lending at home, is fielding offers for its two giant development projects in Australia.
The move could be the first of many by mainland companies pulling back from Australia as Beijing tightens its control over outbound investment, potentially putting downward pressure on prices for property, infrastructure and agricultural assets.
The Australian Financial Review has been told by two sources discussions are underway in Hong Kong for the sale of  in Sydney and its $900 million Jewel resort on the Gold Coast.
The end value of the development projects is close to $2 billion, but they have not been completed.

Supplied

One of the sources said a Hong Kong-based buyer was the most likely outcome and said any deal needed to allow Wanda to "save face" after its high-profile entry into the Australian market three years ago.

A spokesman for Wanda, which also owns the Hoyts Cinema chain in Australia, did not respond by deadline on Monday.
Wanda, controlled by one of China's richest men Wang Jianlin,  as concerns mount that it, and other private companies,  and these now posed a systemic risk to the Chinese banking system.
Other companies targeted by authorities include the HNA Group, which holds a 13 per cent stake in airline Virgin Australia, Fosun Group, which made a string of European acquisitions and is developing apartments in Brisbane and Sydney and Anbang Insurance, which bought New York's Waldorf Astoria Hotel in 2014.
The crackdown is expected to filter down to smaller private companies and state-owned enterprises, as Beijing worries about offshore deals going bad and capital outflows putting downward pressure on its currency.

It is also looking to avoid a Japan-style collapse, which followed an offshore acquisition binge by Japanese firms in the late 1980s and early 1990s.
China's outbound investment nearly halved in the first half of this year to US$64.2 billion and its Vice Minister for Commerce Qian Keming said last week that "irrational" offshore investment had been contained.
In 2016 Chinese investors announced outbound deals worth a record US$219 billion, according to data from Dealogic.
"The deals will dry up in the short term," said Fraser Howie, an independent financial analyst and co-author of Red Capitalism: The Fragile Financial Foundations of China's Extraordinary Rise."

"You can't expect the Chinese to come in and pay top dollar at least for the moment. I wouldn't be beefing up my M&A [mergers and acquisitions] team right now."
However, over the longer term, Mr Howie believes Chinese buyers will return.
"There's too much money in China and not enough opportunities so the driver is there. There will be deals done but they will be more scrutinised, smaller, focused and less random."
The crackdown on overseas spending began in late June with news the banking regulator had ordered a review of the sector's exposure to country's most acquisitive firms and their offshore acquisitions of recent years.

Since then The Wall Street Journal and Reuters reported banks have been ordered to stop providing funding to Wanda's offshore acquisitions, although they did not say which projects had been affected.
Wanda is also selling assets at home.
Last month it sold a group of theme parks and hotels in China for $US9.3 billion, despite Mr Wang previously saying he would use this portfolio to outdo Disney.
"The frenzy of Mickey Mouse and Donald Duck and the era of blindly following them have passed," Wang told China's CCTV last year.

Wanda has been among the most active Chinese players in the Australian market over recent years. Along with its flagship developments in Sydney and  it was also talking about , after purchasing Legendary Entertainment in 2016, producer of such hits as Jurassic World.
Up until last year it also operated twice weekly flights from the central Chinese city of Wuhan to the Gold Coast, using Jetstar planes. The idea was to fly in tourists to holiday on the Gold Coast who may then be interested in buying property from Wanda.
Subsidiary Wanda Film Holding, which operates China largest cinema chain, has also announced a planned restructure, although the details are yet to be released.
Wanda sold a parcel of land on the Gold Coast last November to fellow Chinese entertainment group Songcheng for $55 million.
The agent who did that deal, Knight Frank's Roland Evans, is in Hong Kong this week but declined to comment on any discussions taking place.
Wanda stormed into the Sydney property market in January 2015, paying $415 million for Goldfields House at Circular Quay.
It is among the highest profile buildings in the city, with sweeping views of the Harbour Bridge and Opera House and prior to Wanda's purchase had been seen as a prime development site.
Wanda is the process of demolishing the building and planned to replace it with a 5-star hotel, shops and luxury apartments with some of the city's best views.

"Wanda Group has recognised the iconic location," a spokesman said at the time.
"We look forward to creating a new Sydney landmark."
Mr Howie said while the government's latest intervention had been characterised as a crackdown on irrational investment, it marked a concerning trend.
"This is not financial regulation," he said. "This is the state directing private companies on where they can and can't invest. Private companies should be able to make their own commercial decisions."
The government's economic planning agency the National Development and Reform Commission (NDRC), and the Ministry of Commerce (MOFCOM) have tightened their reviews of overseas deal agreements, Reuters reported last week, citing anonymous sources close to the regulators. Companies are being asked to justify target valuations, deal premiums and financing arrangements, the report said.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wall Street Journal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fragile Financial Foundations of China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MOFCOM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Development</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japanese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jetstar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China's CCTV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goldfields House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harbour Bridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jurassic World</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mickey Mouse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Disney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reform Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Wang</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Knight Frank's Roland Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HNA Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hong Kong</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wang</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wang Jianlin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China's Dalian Wanda Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Songcheng</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hong Kong-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anbang Insurance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Virgin Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wanda Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Red Capitalism</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York's Waldorf Astoria Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BEIJING</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan-style</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fosun Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Duck</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dealogic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commerce Qian Keming</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wanda</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Extraordinary Rise</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wanda Film Holding</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Legendary Entertainment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wuhan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US9.3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$64.2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hoyts Cinemas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Circular Quay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ministry of Commerce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Howie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reuters</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Opera House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vice Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NDRC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US219</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fraser Howie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
