<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444998839774627</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/opinion/columnists/the-questions-that-ian-narev-has-to-be-asked-after-cba-atm-allegations-20170806-gxqlx6</url>
  <title>Three big questions that Ian Narev has to be asked </title>
  <content>
by
Dennis Gentillin

The word "litany" is almost an understatement when describing the various ethical failures that have besieged the banking and finance industry. This includes failures in financial planning, life insurance, interest rate fixing and now abetting money laundering (granted the latter two are still the subject of legal proceedings). By now, those of us questioning the efficacy a royal commission into the banks would be finding it extremely difficult to defend our positions.
At tomorrow's results announcement, Commonwealth Bank CEO Ian Narev will face questioning about the latest incident: money laundering through so-called smart ATMs. Analysts and journalists alike will want to get a view from Narev on the veracity of the allegations, the potential size of the liability, and how CBA's systems, processes and procedures failed to pick up the range of failures detailed in .
More important will be getting to  that incubate and sustain these types of incidents. I would like to propose a series of questions that try and unpack three of these issues.
First, the role of targets. In all these scandals, a focus on hitting targets and making profit seemingly takes precedence over all else. An obsessive focus on targets doesn't just result in people cutting corners to achieve goals, but can literally blind people to other more important concerns, such as legal and ethical obligations.

David Rowe

Mr Narev, were the targets associated with the roll-out of Intelligent Deposit Machines (IDMs) aggressive? Were they strictly enforced? What happened to people who hit their targets? Missed their targets? Did local leaders make hitting targets a priority, creating an 'at any cost' approach? And which people were promoted and held out to be champions of the business? Were they those who consistently hit targets but compromised their ethical and legal responsibilities?

Second, the role of the executive and other senior leaders. It is rarely the case in these incidents that executives are duplicitous and knowingly engage in, condone or turn a blind eye to unethical conduct. Rather, it is their failure to act when there is even the slightest suggestion of wrongdoing that sends a powerful message. In the words of Professor Max Bazerman from the Harvard Business School, executives need to be "first class noticers". And unfortunately for executives, hindsight is a savage judge.

Mr Narev, were you or your team aware that CBA was receiving and was slow to respond to requests for information from law enforcement agencies about suspected money laundering activities? If so, how did you respond? Also, was your executive team tracking the bank's adherence to its AML program? Were they aware of the significant growth in deposit volumes through IDMs? Was this questioned? Were there any concerns raised?

Finally, the failure to listen to those who speak up. An unfortunate repercussion associated with systemic ethical failures is that people who have raised concerns are not listened to. Worse still, they are shunned, and made to feel that their opinions are not valued. Alternatively some who harbour concerns remain silent, feeling that speaking up is a futile exercise.

Mr Narev, were there any concerns raised about the way the CBA was dealing with suspicious or threshold transactions through the internal whistleblower program? Or through local leaders in the retail business? How were these concerns addressed? If you or your team were not aware of the issues that AUSTRAC have documented, doesn't this say something about the willingness of CBA employees to speak up?

It is these types of questions that are rarely posed in the post-mortem of an ethical failure. Fixing any shortcomings in processes and procedures is unquestionably important, but it is the response to these questions that provide a far richer picture of the environment that encouraged and supported the conduct.
Indeed, these are questions that bank executives should be asking on an ongoing basis. By doing so and addressing the issues that invariably surface, they will go a long way towards creating environments that are more resilient to ethical failure.
Dennis Gentilin is the author of The Origins of Ethical Failures (Routledge, 2016) and founder of Human Systems Advisory. He was publicly named as a whistleblower in the NAB FX scandal in 2004.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dennis Gentilin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAB FX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Intelligent Deposit Machines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Human Systems Advisory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Origins of Ethical</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Routledge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUSTRAC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Narev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Narev</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ATMs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dennis Gentillin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harvard Business School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Rowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iDMS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Bank CEO Ian Narev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Max Bazerman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Narev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AML</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBA</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
