<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445303782458992</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/business/workplace-relations/lack-of-sleep-is-costs-the-economy-more-than-66-million-20170807-gxqrew.html</url>
  <title>Our lack of sleep taking its toll on economy</title>
  <content>
James Young is among four in 10 Australians who go to work each day without getting enough sleep.
New research to be released on Tuesday shows sleep deprivation cost the economy an estimated $66.3 billion in health bills, lost productivity and wellbeing.

Up Next

Avoiding an Australia opioid crisis

01:42

More Health and Fitness Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Five reasons sleep deprivation effects your health

Five surprising ways sleep deprivation can harm your mind and body. Video copyright Health Media Ventures, Inc 2017

Mr Young, a 41-year-old business consultant based in Canberra, has had mild sleep apnoea for about three years. It means he often needs to take an afternoon nap for an hour and a half about four days a week.
He can't remember the last time he woke up feeling refreshed.Photo: Supplied
"I feel tired during the day," he said.
"After 10 hours of sleep I wake up feeling tired and have to pull myself out of bed.

"A sleep study I had showed that I was not in a deep sleep for very much of the time."
He has been taking medication for the past six weeks which has dramatically improved his sleep quality.Photo: Peter Casolino / Alamy Stock Photo
A Deloitte Access Economics health survey to be released on Tuesday shows that 39.8 per cent of Australians don't get enough sleep.
It estimates that sleep deprivation costs the health system $1.8 billion or $246 per person and productivity losses of $17.9 billion or $2418 per person. The costs to overall wellbeing were estimated at $40.1 billion and costs overall at $66.3 billion in 2016-17.Photo: Bradley Cummings
The study found that 39.8 per cent of Australian adults experience some form of inadequate sleep including disorders such as sleep apnoea.
The report estimated that 7.4 million Australian adults did not regularly get the sleep they needed in 2016-17.
The cost of sleep deprivation is utterly alarming and confirms we need to take urgent action to put sleep on the national agenda.
Professor Dorothy Bruck, Chair of the Sleep Health Foundation

The report says 394 Australians die each year as a result of falling asleep at the wheel of a vehicle or industrial accidents due to lack of sleep.
Professor Dorothy Bruck, chairwoman of the Sleep Health Foundation, which commissioned the Deloitte report, said the lack of sleep affected millions of Australians.
She said sleep deprivation had the potential to contribute to health conditions including heart disease, stroke, diabetes and depression in tens of thousands of Australians.
"The cost of sleep deprivation is utterly alarming and confirms we need to take urgent action to put sleep on the national agenda," she said.
"Sleep - or rather the lack of it - is a substantial burden on our economy and the livelihood of Australians, dampening mood, exacerbating health problems, dulling our productivity and making us a danger on the roads and in workplaces around the country".
The report recommends that Work Health and Safety authorities tighten regulations in jobs where sleep is irregular but responsibility is high, such as defence, transport and health.
It also recommends that shift workers have body clock-sensitive rostering and well-timed exposure to dark and light to ensure they feel alert on the job and sleepy at bedtime. It said regulations were also needed to limit excessive work hours.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deloitte Access Economics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-11</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fitness Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deloitte</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Dorothy Bruck</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sleep Health Foundation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bradley Cummings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Health Media Ventures</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alamy Stock Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Young</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Inc 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Work Health</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chair of the Sleep</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Casolino</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Health Foundation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Young</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
