<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445260832784985</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/north/overweight-mother-of-two-outrunning-expectations-and-taking-on-a-fun-run/news-story/9c6661e9790a7a61c93bfccd089e52b2</url>
  <title>Mum losing weight on the run</title>
  <content>
THANKS to the power of high-fives and Instagram, a Mernda mother is inspiring many and running through expectations.
In January, mother-of-two Jessica Hay decided she wasn't getting anywhere in the gym and weighing in at 198kg, decided to put out feelers on social media about whether she could join a running group.
She was warmly received and after her first attempt, the improvements came rapidly.

"I went for my first run and I took a really, really long time but the next run I shaved a fair bit of time off and from there I thought, I really want to keep going and aim higher," Ms Hay said.
Ms Hay has since taken part in a 10km run and has her eyes set on completing a marathon.
While she is focusing on improving her running times rather than the weight loss, Ms Hay says she has "dropped two sizes" and up to 15kg so far.
Her Instagram, @thelongweighdownwithjess, is rapidly approaching 20,000 followers and she is preparing for the YMCA Father's Day Fun Run - not just as a runner but also an ambassador.
Ms Hay said while her posts on social media were well received, it was the love at home that drove her on.
"My four year old gives me high-fives when I come back from a run and asks if I ran really fast and I say I tried," she said.
"I wouldn't say I wasn't a good role model before but now I am putting out real goals and following through on them and I think that is rubbing off on the kids."
The  is held on September 3.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>YMCA Father's Day Fun Run</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jessica Hay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mernda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Hay</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
