<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444758321601479</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:13</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/queensland/queensland-economy-growing-as-coal-beef-and-wheat-boom/news-story/ad38a837333bf0f87fb1f29b9a65d9b1</url>
  <title>Export boom puts us back on top</title>
  <content>
Turnbull says coal opponents are 'delusional'

AN export boom has helped Queensland reclaim its mantle as the nation™s economic powerhouse.

The Courier-Mail can reveal today's state account figures will show that Queensland's economy grew by more than three times the national average in the 12 months to the end of March.

Surging coal prices, the subdued Australian dollar and demand for Queensland's agriculture products, including beef and wheat, ensured the state's exports grew by 10.2 per cent over the period compared to 3.1 per cent nationwide.

The economic growth figures were the best Queensland had recorded in five years.

Treasurer Curtis Pitt last night claimed credit for the result.

"What the latest Queensland State Accounts figures show is our economic plan is on the right track and has reinjected growth into the Queensland economy," he said.

"Before Labor took office the growth under the LNP was just 0.8 per cent in the four quarters to the December quarter 2014, the lowest since the Global Financial Crisis.

"The QSA figures also expose the previous criticisms by (Federal Treasurer) Scott Morrison that Queensland was somehow a drag on the national economy.

Should we not export coal?

"The facts are there in black and white. If Queensland's growth wasn't as strong as it is, Australia's would be much lower."

However, Queensland exports, which surged to a record $65.9 billion in the past 12 months, have masked ongoing doldrums in the domestic economy.

Dwelling investment shrunk by 6.8 per cent in the 12 months to March after the high-rise apartment boom in and around Brisbane contracted.

Queensland's public final demand figure - a key indicator of the Government's investment in infrastructure - was also half the rest of Australia with the Palaszczuk administration forced to limit capital spending as the State Budget remained mired in debt.

While Queensland's household consumption remained slightly below the national average, the state avoided the slump in business investment that occurred throughout the rest of Australia.

However, the state's boom condition will be short lived with the impact of Cyclone Debbie to wash through the next quarterly figures.

About 0.75 per cent is forecast to be wiped from the state's growth figures after 10 million tonnes of coal exports were lost during the category four storm.

Like this:

Like Loading...

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LNP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cyclone Debbie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treasurer Curtis Pitt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palaszczuk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Global Financial Crisis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QSA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Morrison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland State Accounts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Treasurer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Budget</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Courier-Mail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
