<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444822746112425</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:28</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Radio Australia</source>
  <url>http://www.radioaustralia.net.au/international/2017-08-07/australia-us-japan-call-for-south-china-sea-code-to-be-legally-binding/1691964</url>
  <title>Australia, US, Japan call for South China Sea code to be legally binding</title>
  <content>
Australia, the United States and Japan have urged South-East Asia and China to ensure that a code of conduct on the South China Sea they have committed to draw up will be legally binding, and said they strongly opposed "coercive unilateral actions".
The statement came after a meeting between Australia's Foreign Minister Julie Bishop, US Secretary of State Rex Tillerson and Japanese Foreign Minister Taro Kono, on the sidelines of a South-East Asian political forum in the Philippines.
The Association of South-East Asian Nations (ASEAN) and China should establish a set of rules that is "legally binding, meaningful, effective, and consistent with international law", the foreign ministers said.
Foreign ministers of ASEAN and China adopted a negotiating framework for a code of conduct over the weekend, a move they hailed as progress but seen by critics as a tactic to buy China time to consolidate its maritime power.
Australia, the United States and Japan also "voiced their strong opposition to coercive unilateral actions that could alter the status quo and increase tensions".
They urged claimants to refrain from land reclamation, construction of outposts and militarisation of disputed features, in a veiled reference to .
The three countries are not claimants but have long been vocal on the issue, arguing their interest is in ensuring freedom of navigation and overflight.
They urged China and the Philippines to abide by , where more than $3 trillion ($AU3.8 trillion) worth of sea-borne goods pass every year.
Brunei, Malaysia, the Philippines, Taiwan and Vietnam also have competing claims there.
Code may become 'gentlemen's agreement'

The code framework is an outline for what China and ASEAN call "consultations" on a formal agreement, which could start later this year.
China's Foreign Minister Wang Yi said that hinged on whether the situation was stable, and if there was no "major interference" from outsiders.
Several ASEAN countries want the code to be legally binding, enforceable and have a dispute resolution mechanism.
However experts say China will not allow that, and ASEAN may end up acquiescing to what amounts to a gentlemen's agreement.
Singapore's Foreign Minister Vivian Balakrishnan said it was still premature to conclude the outcome of the negotiations for the code of conduct, which will be done by lawyers.
"One key issue is the question of legally binding," he told reporters late on Sunday.
"Surely when we move into the [Code of Conduct], it has got to have some additional or significant legal effect."
Philippine Foreign Secretary Alan Peter Cayetano said he preferred a legally binding agreement, which other countries, like Vietnam, supported.
Jay Batongbacal, an expert on the South China Sea at the University of the Philippines, told news channel ANC the adoption of the framework gave China "the absolute upper hand" in terms of strategy, because it would be able to decide when the negotiating process could start.

Reuters

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asean</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philippines</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japanese Foreign Minister Taro Kono</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South-East Asian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Secretary of State</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taiwan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vietnam</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of the Philippines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philippine Foreign Secretary Alan Peter Cayetano</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East Asian Nations</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AU3.8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.67</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia's Foreign Minister Julie Bishop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Singapore's Foreign Minister Vivian Balakrishnan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brunei</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China's Foreign Minister Wang Yi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Association of South</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South-east Asia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reuters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jay Batongbacal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malaysia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rex Tillerson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Code of Conduct</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South China Sea</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
