<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444998839774653</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/news/politics/samesex-battle-goes-back-to-the-senate-20170807-gxr7gb</url>
  <title>Same-sex battle goes back to the Senate</title>
  <content>
The Coalition's same-sex marriage saga will continue until Christmas at least, after a clear majority of Liberal MPs and Senators argued to either stick with the current policy of holding a plebiscite or conduct a postal ballot to test the public mood before a Parliamentary vote.
The final policy position is likely to involve trying once again to pass legislation in the Senate for a plebiscite and, if that fails, conduct a postal plebiscite followed by a free vote if the 'Yes' vote is carried.
The issue should be resolved on Tuesday when the Liberals and Nationals meet for their joint party room meeting to adopt a formal Coalition policy.
Either way, there is no prospect of moving directly to a free vote in Parliament as has been pushed publicly for the past week by . One rebel, Warren Entsch, signalled he was still prepared to cross the floor if a bill was put forward.

Marriage equality: Liberals retain plebiscite

On Monday, a meeting of Liberal MPs and Senators agreed by a ratio of four-to-one to support in principle a cabinet proposal in which the government would put to the Senate once more legislation to establish a national, compulsory plebiscite. Late last year, the Senate rejected such legislation.

In the likely event this legislation is rejected again, the next step would be to have a postal plebiscite which the government believes does not need legislation and says it has legal advice to back this.
If the postal vote supports same-sex marriage, there would be a parliamentary vote either just before or after Christmas which would be a private members bill facilitated by the government.
If the postal vote fails to support a change, acting Special Minister of State Mathias Cormann said "the government will not be facilitating consideration of a private member's bill to change the law". This would mean the rebels would have to take matters into their own hands, as they threatened to do this week, or accept defeat.
There will be no public funding for the yes and no cases for either a plebiscite or a postal vote.

Sources said 27 or 28 Liberal MPs and Senators spoke in favour of either a plebiscite or postal ballot while just seven spoke in favour of a motion put by Senator Smith to abandon the plebiscite policy and moving straight to a free vote. These were the five rebels plus NSW MP John Alexander and Victorian MP Jason Wood.
The seven registered their support by a show of hands while there was no show of hands for those who wished to stick with some sort of plebiscite.
The Nationals are generally supportive of a postal vote rather than persisting with pushing the Senate for a plebiscite because, as one source said, "we just want it off the agenda".
who argued that a postal ballot would not be authoritative. Signalling a split with key conservatives Peter Dutton and Mathias Cormann who developed the cabinet compromise, Mr Abbott contended the Coalition should stick with a plebiscite and persist for years if necessary.

David Rowe

In a move designed to stall for more time, Mr Abbott likened the situation to the Howard government trying more than 40 times over several years to have the Senate water down unfair dismissal protections for workers before finally doing so after it won control of the Senate at the 2004 election.
"We should have another go and if that fails, we should have another go," he before the meeting.
He was backed by fellow conservatives Kevin Andrews and Craig Kelly while moderates Julian Leeser and Russell Broadbent argued against a postal vote on the basis it may not survive a challenge by same-sex marriage advocates who say it needs legislation to appropriate the money to fund it. Mr Kelly called it a second best option and also raised legal concerns.
But other conservatives said it was likely the Coalition would adopt the Cabinet proposal as long as "serious efforts" were made to secure Senate passage of the plebiscite legislation "rather than a step on the way to a postal vote".

Senator Cormann, the government's best Senate negotiator, told the party room meeting he would negotiate robustly with the Senate to try and effect a change of mind.
"The parliamentary Liberal Party party room maintained our commitment to give all Australians the opportunity to have a say on whether or not the definition of marriage should be changed to allow same-sex couples to marry and to do that through a plebiscite," Senator Cormann said after the meeting.
"Our preference is to do that through a compulsory attendance plebiscite and legislation to that effect. We'll come back before the Senate, we hope, this week.
"If that were to fail, the government believes that we have a legal and constitutional way forward to give the Australian people a say on whether or not the definition of marriage should be changed through a non-legislated, voluntary postal plebiscite."

One source inside the party room said a "reasonable number" of people who spoke in favour of a plebiscite were amenable to the cabinet proposal.
Labor, the Greens, the Nick Xenophon Team and Senator Derryn Hinch were among those who opposed the plebiscite legislation and they argue a postal vote would be even worse because it would not be at all representative or authoritive.
Senator Cormann said on that basis, they should change their mind and support the plebiscite.
"If there are concerns about a voluntary postal plebiscite, then I would encourage those Senators who are so concerned to consider supporting the government's bill for a compulsory attendance plebiscite," he said.
Opposition leader Bill Shorten, who is promising a free vote in Parliament within 100 days of being elected, was adamant on Monday Labor was not for turning.
"There is only one reason why this failure to deal with marriage equality has dragged on as long as it has. It is because of the complete failure of leadership and weakness of the Prime Minister of Australia to deal with this issue," he told his caucus.
"When you think about it, it is not just marriage equality, it is home ownership, it is energy prices, it's the NBN, the weakness and incompetence of this government is something to behold."
Senator Smith called the postal ballot "a D-grade response to a defining A-grade social issue"

-with Andrew Tillett

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senators</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Xenophon Team</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>D-grade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Dutton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Smith</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russell Broadbent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Abbott</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian MP Jason Wood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday Labor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW MP John Alexander</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Rowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Cormann</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Derryn Hinch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julian Leeser</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mathias Cormann</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MPs</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Tillett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Special Minister of State</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Howard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin Andrews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
