<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445003134741997</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/technology/rest-and-vest-the-silicon-valley-secret-aussie-startups-dont-want-to-take-on-20170803-gxomdw</url>
  <title>'Rest and vest' the Silicon Valley secret Aussie start-ups don't want to take on</title>
  <content>
"Damn, I worked hard this week towards the dream of becoming so senior that I'm no longer expected to contribute anything meaningful. #restandvest," someone drolly points out on Twitter.
Someone else announces: "Year 5 at Amazon starts with me rolling into work at 10:30 after raging to Diplo on a Sunday night. #restandvest."
It's enough to make the skin of anyone who even moderately works hard at their job and perhaps feels less-than-adequately compensated, crawl. 
"Rest and vest" is a  - where an employee, generally an engineer or a programmer, is handsomely compensated for doing very little work.

They are generally waiting for a healthy payday in the form of vesting stock interests they've accrued from an acquisition of their prior company or as part of a contract job that finished early.

The term "rest and vest" first bubbled up during Silicon Valley, where a group of "unassigned" employees spent their days drinking beer on the chic roof, waiting until they could fully vest their stock options.
And while the show is pretty funny, it is apparently a frequent occurrence in the United States. The likes of Google and Microsoft have more money than the Incas, acquire smaller businesses, along with their entrepreneurial founders and engineers and then park them in well-paid corners of their companies to "rest and vest".
It's also to stop them going to a rival firm and inventing something else awesome. 
Waste of talent

While the practice itself is a strange, open waste of otherwise excellent human talent, it's even more difficult to swallow knowing there's an entire hashtag devoted to these inflated individuals who openly flaunt their days presumably filled with table tennis and little responsibility. 
I did a ring around of some contacts in the Australian start-up scene to see if we have anything approaching "rest and vest" culture here.
Although they are a polite bunch, who avoided anything more scathing than an over-the-phone eye roll, there was a definite exasperated undertone at what was clearly a long-held practice in the Valley.
One lady told me rather flatly: "The idea of these fantastic skilled workers just hanging out, earning buckets of money is pretty gross. Especially when there are companies here desperately trying to source talent to actually grow to a point where they could even think about letting someone rest and vest. I don't know anyone that's resting in Startupland."

She had a point, all the founders I've spoken to are pouring every waking minute into their business and those that are acquired by larger corporates - a number you can count on two hands - tend to turn their attention to something bigger as soon as the handover occurs. 
There just isn't enough excessive money sloshing around in Australia to spend it keeping highly educated people idle.
Something I suppose the Australian start-up community can simultaneously high-five about, in a perverse way.
As one venture capitalist put it; these are arguably the most vital years of your life and it's entirely possible you'll just waste them, bunkering down in a token role accumulating dollars.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Microsoft</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Year 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diplo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Valley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Silicon Valley</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Google</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Inca</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
