<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445213588143733</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/queensland/high-court-to-consider-fate-of-senator-matt-canavan-after-citizenship-scandal/news-story/f557c930decd06b2d97b685014e2f034</url>
  <title>Canavan's fate heads to High Court</title>
  <content>
THE fate of Queensland Senator Matt Canavan will be referred to the High Court this morning when the Senate meets for the first time since the.
Senator Canavan resigned from Cabinet after revealing his mother had signed him up for Italian citizenship without his knowledge in 2006, potentially making him a dual citizen and not eligible to stand for federal parliament.
The Senate will today refer Senator Canavan to the High Court to determine if he is eligible to keep his job, but the process could take months.
It is expected to ask the High Court to decide "if there is a vacancy in the representation of Queensland in the Senate" for Senator Canavan and if so, how that vacancy should be filled.
Former Greens Senators Larissa Waters and Scott Ludlum resigned from the Senate last month after revealing they were unwittingly dual citizens.
The Greens will today refer the cases to the High Court to determine how their Senate spots should be filled.

Herald Sun Columnist Rita Panahi discusses if dual-citizen Matt Canavan should be allowed to stay in his role as a Federal Politician on Sunrise.

Should dual-citizen Matt Canavan be allowed to stay in his role as a Federal Politician?
Victorian Senator Derryn Hinch is working with the Greens on a motion seeking a broader inquiry into eligibility due to citizenship, seeking revocation documentation of any Senators born overseas.
While Senator Canavan will provide his own legal representation in the High Court, Attorney-General George Brandis is able to intervene on behalf of the government to put forward its interpretation of the law.
Senator Canavan has kept a low profile since standing down from the Cabinet, but previously said he had received legal advice that he was not in breach of section 44 of the constitution.
"It's important that we leave that process run now and let the court make its decision," he said.
"It's not just about my circumstance, it's going to establish principles which go to the heart of eligibility of many Australians to stand for the Australian parliament."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senators</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Senator Derryn Hinch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herald Sun Columnist Rita Panahi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canavan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Canavan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Politician</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Attorney-General George Brandis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Senator Matt Canavan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>High Court</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Ludlum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greens Senator Larissa Waters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Canavan</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
