<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445265127752432</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/south-east/seven-oaks-farmhouse-merricks-north-brewing-ciders-from-traditional-apples-and-methods/news-story/2407375d540f55affe9d5c88031e134c</url>
  <title>Old school cider rules at peninsula orchard</title>
  <content>
LISA Cresswell wants cider drinkers to give brews created with old-school apples a go.
And she's hoping a new cellar door at her family's third-generation apple orchard will help introduce traditional ciders to customers.
"We don't really have the set-up at the moment to offer proper tastings, but we hope to open one soon," Ms Cresswell said.
"If we had a cellar door, we could do that and sell eating apples and other produce from the farm."
Ms Cresswell said ciders made from traditional English or French apple varieties had greater complexity and depth of flavour.
"A lot of commercial ciders available today are made with imported concentrates and are just sweet and fizzy, there's nothing much to them," she said.
Seven Oaks Farmhouse cider is made from apples grown on site and hand processed and pressed using the traditional methods.
The boutique single varietal and blended ciders are created without added sugars, concentrates or pesticides.
The Pink Lady was the most popular and regularly sold out, Ms Cresswell said.
"Everyone loves Pink Lady apples and the cider is absolutely delicious," she said.
"I'd like to see some of our other traditional varieties, like the Kingston Black, get more love."
The Kingston Black has won critical acclaim in the past, taking out the Traditional Sweet Cider class at the 2015 Australian Cider Awards.
Seven Oaks' Bramley Seedling cider took out the same category in 2014.
Ms Cresswell has high hopes for her Lady William cider at this year's awards, to be held next month. "It's the best cider I have ever made," she said.
''When we first bottled it, we all got drunk because we couldn't stop tasting it. That hasn't happened for a long time!
"I have 200 litres of the Lady William ready to go (the Best in Show cider is served at the Australian Cider Awards Dinner)."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>LISA Cresswell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kingston Black</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oaks Farmhouse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lady William</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Cresswell</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Cider Awards Dinner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Cider Awards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oaks' Bramley Seedling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pink Lady</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Traditional Sweet Cider</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
