<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445170638469885</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/news/policy/industrial-relations/miners-want-new-round-of-ir-reforms-before-election-20170807-gxqt68</url>
  <title>'Time to take IR out of deep freezer': Miners want 'new round of IR reforms' before election</title>
  <content>
Former Australian Council of Trade Unions boss Martin Ferguson has called on the Turnbull government to enact a "new round" of , backing a resource industry push for new employee rights to opt out of collective agreements and move to individual agreements, restrictions on legal strikes, and a higher bar to prove unlawful employer actions.
The ex-Labor resources minister will launch the  on Tuesday night as short-term priorities for reform" to implement during this Parliament ahead of developing "a wider set of of agreement options".
In a speech to the Sydney Institute, Mr Ferguson will argue the economy needs to "get back on the pathway of sensible reform" before the "extremes" of WorkChoices and pursue changes "from within the system".
"Neither side of politics helps Australia's employees or its employers by running scare campaigns on workplace relations - nor by running scared of workplace relations reforms.

"It's time to take workplace relations reform out of the deep freezer."

'Reinstate individual agreements'

Mr Ferguson will emphasise that the mining industry has used individual agreements extensively for many years to facilitate flexible work practices.
However, when the Fair Work Act removed individual statutory agreements, it "restrict[ed] the choices available to employers and employers" and left no place for individual agreements.
He argues employees should be given the choice to opt out of enterprise agreements and instead enter "individual agreements" when they earn over a particular income, suggesting the current threshold for  of $142,000 a year, which is also the average salary in the resources industry.

While not specifically calling for a return of individual statutory agreements, Mr Ferguson will argue an opt-out provision "would reinstate individual agreements as a vehicle for achieving a flexible and motivated workforce, for boosting performance and productivity - and for rewarding employees with well-paid, individually tailored employment agreements".
The proposal is expected to be controversial with Labor outlawing "opt out" clauses in enterprise agreements in 2012 after a Fair Work Commission full bench ruled that such clauses undermined "bargaining certainty".
The bench, led by president Iain Ross, said the clauses could lead to employees opting out of an agreement to take protected industrial action.
Not 'upend' safety net

The Minerals Council, which includes BHP, Rio Tinto and , has worked with Mr Ferguson for the past nine months to develop the reform package, which also proposes limits on agreement content, restrictions on union right of entry and extension of greenfield agreements.
The industry's fresh push for reform clashes directly with Labor's announcement last week that it would move to overhaul the Fair Work Act if it won the next election so as to redress the "imbalance in bargaining power" favouring employers.
It also comes as the government is yet to respond to the Productivity Commission's report on workplace relations delivered more than 18 months ago, with the council frequently citing the commission's own recommendations to support its proposals.
Mr Ferguson will stress the council has not set out to "upend the existing system or to undermine the safety net".

"Rather we have identified the issues which are priorities for the mining industry and its workforce and made practical and realistic suggestions for reforms which will improve workplace relations and help the industry to continue to create well-paid, rewarding jobs into the future."
He said the Fair Work Act had expanded the scope of permitted agreement content beyond the direct employer and employee relationship into business decisions.
"This opens the way for protected industrial action over such issues, meaning that collective bargaining can go well beyond wages and conditions and into areas of everyday management and into matters concerning union business rather than direct employment matters."
He called for banning of restrictions on employers' use of contractors, requirements for employers to encourage union membership, and clauses that constrain an employer's ability to determine a suitable employment mix.

Workers would also lose the right to take protected industrial action over such claims.
'Refocus' adverse action

Protections from unlawful adverse action also needed "refocusing" so that they do not "interfere unreasonably" with management decision-making and performance management, Mr Ferguson said.
The council wants exemptions from adverse action claims for "legitimate actions", such as restructures, and to reinstate a "sole or dominant reason test" when proving actions were taken for a prohibited reason.
"The breadth of actions covered, coupled with a reverse onus of proof on employers, mean these provisions are being used to obstruct business decision-making and performance management processes."
Mr Ferguson will argue adverse action claims have jumped 50 per cent since 2012-13 and accuse unions of using "vague pleadings" to subject major employers, such as BHP, to "an extensive legal discovery exercise".
He said the government should move to end the historically no-costs jurisdiction and allow costs order to follow the results of a case to discourage unmeritorious claims.
Union officials' right of entry powers should also be "more balanced" by ensuring that employees can meet with their representatives while "minimising operational disruption" by removing default location requirements.

Employers would also be protected from the risk of industrial disruption on major projects through reforms that extend a greenfields agreement's term beyond its maximum four years to the life of a project.
Mr Ferguson will argue that the  in 2008 but that it needed to change to help attract investment.
"Let me make it clear - kick-starting industrial relations reform is once again not only in the national interest. It is very much in the interest of workers," he will say.
"Restricting the ability of companies to change work practices and adapt to changing market conditions restricts the ultimate capacity of companies to grow their businesses and employ more people."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BHP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Council of Trade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IR</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Institute</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin Ferguson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Productivity Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Tinto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Ferguson</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iain Ross</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fair Work Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WorkChoices</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minerals Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fair Work Act</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
