<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444277285255981</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-07/cats-accept-hawks-ban-may-appeal-mitchs</url>
  <title>Cats accept Hawk's ban, may appeal Mitch's</title>
  <content>
MRP hits Cats, Brown speaks, more
Monday Footy Feed with Matt Thompson and Nathan Schmook

Tom Hawkins has accepted a two-game suspension

GEELONG has accepted the two-game suspension handed to forward Tom Hawkins and is weighing up whether to challenge midfielder Mitch Duncan's one-match ban at the Tribunal. 

The Match Review Panel on Monday charged Hawkins with striking, assessing his jumper punch on Sydney defender Dane Rampe as intentional contact with low impact to the face. 

Cats football manager Steve Hocking said the club would not contest the Hawkins verdict.

"No, not that one. I don't think there is anywhere to go other than it was something that is disappointing," Hocking told Fox Footy on Monday night. 

Hawkins' bad record meant an extra week was added to the suspension, resulting in a two-game penalty with an early guilty plea. 

Hawkins was suspended for one game for a similar jumper punch on Adelaide onballer Matt Crouch in round 11 and served a one-match ban last year for a punch to the neck/jaw of Greater Western Sydney co-captain Phil Davis. 

Duncan, meanwhile, was offered a one-game ban for striking Swans small forward Tom Papley, with his punch graded as intentional conduct with medium impact to the body.

The MRP applied a two-match suspension with an early guilty plea reducing Duncan's penalty to one game. 

Hocking said the club was discussing whether to challenge the suspension at the Tribunal on Tuesday night. 

"The area (we'll consider) is the medium impact (and) whether or not there is an opportunity around that," Hocking said.

"I've had a conversation with Mitch and also our legal counsel, so we'll just sleep on that tonight and reconvene in the morning." 

The Cats have until 11am Tuesday to notify the AFL if they will fight the verdict. 

More to come 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dane Rampe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MRP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Schmook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Match Review Panel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.33</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greater Western Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Hocking</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Papley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Thompson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday Footy Feed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch Duncan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox Footy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phil Davis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hocking</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Duncan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawkins</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Hawkins</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Crouch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
