<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445003134741973</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/news/policy/education/after-gonski-funding-boost-australian-school-spending-will-be-near-oecd-norm-20170803-gxol9w</url>
  <title>After Gonski funding boost, Australian school spending will be near OECD norm</title>
  <content>
A new analysis overturns the conventional wisdom that Australia's school spending is high by international standards revealing that, even after the $24 billion funding boost to schools from the Turnbull government's Gonski 2.0 package, Australia's school spending remains in the middle of the pack of OECD nations.
The analysis, by the Grattan Institute, shows that after Australia's , the often-cited high level of Australian school spending as a proportion of GDP melts away.
FIgures from Grattan's school education program director Peter Goss, show that, even after the full implementation of Gonski 2.0, Australia will still spend less on school education as a percentage of GDP than Finland, Norway and New Zealand, all of which outperform Australia in a benchmark test of school achievement, the OECD's Programme of International School Assessment (PISA).
It also shows that Australia's school education spend is at a similar level to many other countries which outperform Australia in most parts of the PISA test, including Japan, Germany, Canada and South Korea.

The only two OECD countries whose school spending is well below Australia are Mexico and Turkey.

Adjust for numbers of school children

The key to the new analysis is taking into account Australia's outsized population of school age children which resulted from the baby boom of the early years of the century. With 166 school enrolments per 1000 population, Australia is above the OECD average of 147 per 1000 population.
As a result, the often-quoted statistic that, , Australia spent an additional 0.2 percentage points of GDP on schools compared to the OECD average, is explained by Australia's higher numbers of children in school.
Exactly where Australia's school spending lies in the future compared to other OECD countries, will depend on whether Gonski 2.0 spending is fully implemented to 100 per cent of the schooling resource standard (SRS).

State governments, which fund the bulk of public schools, will only be required to fund to 95 per cent of the SRS. If they stay at this level Australia's total school spending will be close to the OECD norm.
Not an outlier

Dr Goss said that his figures showed that Australia was not an outlier in the level of its school spending once the numbers of children enrolled in school were taken into account.
He said it was time to end the debate about the level of school spending and focus on how to ensure the money is spent well.

"Let's stop arguing about it. Given that our total spending is about right, let's make the best of it," he said.
Dr Goss also said that, because Australia would be close to the OECD norm after the injection of Gonski 2.0 school funding, any additional school spending would "need to be more strongly justified".
Because Australia has a high level of private spending on schooling compared to other countries, in order to give the fairest comparison the figures count both private and public spending on schooling.
However if only public spending on schooling is used in the comparison, Australia' school spending is well below the OECD norm, even after Gonski 2.0.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grattan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mexico</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turkey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Norway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canada</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Goss</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OECD</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>18</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gonski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OECD's Programme of International</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Finland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SRs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Goss</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gonski 2.0</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PISA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grattan Institute</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GDP</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Korea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>School Assessment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
