<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445711804360225</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>15:55</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>http://www.businessinsider.com.au/business-insider-is-hiring-a-tech-and-gadgets-intern-in-our-new-york-office-2017-8</url>
  <title>Business Insider is hiring a paid tech and gadgets intern in NYC</title>
  <content>
Business Insider is looking for a paid tech editorial intern for to join the Tech Insider team in NYC.

Our tech section covers everything from the hottest startups to big tech personalities to Apple earnings. We need someone who is as enthusiastic about social media as s/he is about staying on top of the latest product launches and what people in the tech scene are buzzing about.

We want someone who is curious about how certain companies dominate our lives while others crumble into dust.

We're looking for the following:

Excellent writing skills.

Someone who is psyched to work with text, photos, video, graphics, and audio - often all in the same story.

A basic knowledge of the tech industry.

Someone with good time-management skills who thrives in the fast-paced environment of a newsroom.

As an intern at Business Insider, there's no getting coffee, filing, or making copies.

Our interns are an integral part of our team. Many of our current writers and editors started as interns.

BI Interns spend their time doing meaningful work: researching, writing, producing, and promoting features and stories - even breaking news if the timing's right.

Interns are encouraged to work full-time (40 hours a week) if their schedule allows.

with a resume and cover letter if this sounds like your dream internship, and specify why you're interested in working on Tech.

NOW WATCH: Tech Insider videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NYC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insiders</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tech Insider</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Business Insider</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BI Interns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
