<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445153458600349</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:45</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>http://www.businessinsider.com.au/tandem-buys-harrods-bank-2017-8</url>
  <title>Startup bank Tandem is buying Harrods Bank</title>
  <content>
LONDON - Startup bank Tandem has agreed to buy Harrods Bank, four months after seeing a £29 million funding deal collapse.

Tandem, which is aiming to build a mobile-only bank, announced on Monday that it has signed a deal to buy the banking business of high-end department store Harrods. The financials of the deal have not been disclosed.

The bank will bring £80 million worth of capital to Tandem, a boost for the startup which lost its banking licence earlier this year after a funding setback.

Harrods Bank will bring a near-£200 million loan book and over £300 million of deposits, . Harrods Bank lost £8.4 million last year.

Tandem announced last December that it . However,  is owned by China's Sanpower and a crackdown from Beijing on capital flight led to .

The funding setback led Tandem to lose its banking licence as it no longer met capital requirements. The startup, founded in 2014, also .

The setback and licensing issue delayed the launch of its savings account, but Tandem said on Monday that the deal should help accelerate the launch, allowing it to happen by the end of the year.

Ricky Knox, Tandem's founder and CEO, said in a statement: "Tandem has been built from the ground-up with the help of over 11,000 co-founders, who have helped us shape products and services that really make a difference to their lives. This acquisition will allow us to scale the business and ensure we can introduce as many people as possible to a new way of banking."

Last month Tandem launched its app to its community of "co-founders." The app allows people to view all their bank accounts in one place and monitor spending. Tandem is also testing its credit cards internally, with plans to launch to the public later this year.

Tandem, founded in 2014, is one of a number of app-only banks set up in Britain in recent years. Others include Monzo, Atom, and Starling. Tandem has .

NOW WATCH: Money & Markets videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harrods Bank</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harrods</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China's Sanpower</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Starlings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Atom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ricky Knox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BEIJING</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
