<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445325257296032</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:25</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Australian</source>
  <url>http://www.theaustralian.com.au/business/technology/xero-spins-up-a-financial-web/news-story/051882ed5d79295a1d9df96b2bc47f2f</url>
  <title>Xero spins up a financial web</title>
  <content>
Cloud accountancy software provider Xero has signed up 100 Australian financial institutions as part of its strategy to make itself indispensable to Australian small businesses.
Extending its "financial web" allows Xero to leverage the direct relationships with the banks to open up a host of banking, lending, and growth opportunities for its customers.
According to Xero, its web connects to 95 per cent of all transaction accounts that its small business customers access every day, making it easier for them to connect their accounting dashboard directly to almost any bank or financial services provider in the country.
"That includes everything from a big four bank to a regional credit union, helping small businesses gain access to their financial data and make better business decisions," the company said.
Xero's Australia MD Trent Innes said the SMB sector still faced a number of challenges - from lack of financial transparency and managing cash flow to getting better access to appropriate lending.
"Through direct bank feeds, providing more payment options and opening up lending through two-way data sharing, Xero and our partners are creating growth opportunities for small businesses across Australia," Mr Innes said.
He said bringing the big banks and financial institutions on board was critical to Xero.
The news milestone for the dual-listed company comes as it crosses the half-a-million customer mark in Australia.
For Xero its continued success in the market, especially as a first mover in the cloud space, will depend on the strength of his platform. According to Mr Innes, the market continues to appreciate the offering in the market.
Xero recently picked up another gong from consumer ratings agency Canstar winning Australia's best accounting software for third straight year.
The company has also made a few changes to its Australian management team, with Ben Styles, formerly head of financial web at Xero, promoted to the role of APAC general manager to drive the strategy for growing Xero's financial web in Australia and across the region.
Additions to the Australian team also includes Ian Boyd, an eight-year veteran from Visa. He joins Xero as the new head of financial web in Australia.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Xero</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Styles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>APAC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SMB</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canstar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Xero's Australia MD Trent Innes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Boyd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Innes</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
