<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445325257295990</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:25</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/sport/local-sport/uni-games-bound-garbin-believes-flames-have-what-it-takes/news-story/9b39aec2ca4051c5e536e31ecdba4b1f</url>
  <title>Garbin believes Flames have what it takes</title>
  <content>
TOWNSVILLE Flames star Darcee Garbin made a bittersweet exit from the city last night with World University Games commitments meaning she will miss the QBL finals.
A championship winner with the Townsville Fire, Garbin has starred for the Flames in the WNBL off-season with impressive averages of 23.4 points and 10.2 rebounds per game making her a legitimate MVP candidate.
The 23-year-old will be sorely missed by the Flames in their finals opener against Gladstone this weekend but Garbin had full confidence in her teammates to get the job done without her.
"I always knew there was a chance I would miss QBL finals if I was selected for the Uni Games and I let the club know that before the season started," she said.
"Any chance to represent Australia always takes priority but I've got full faith in the girls for the Gladstone game.
"We've been playing great the last few weeks, we had three good wins on the weekend and the girls can go down there quite confident."
While Garbin was disappointed to miss the post-season with her Flames teammates the chance to pull on the green and gold against some of the world's top players was an opportunity she couldn't turn down.
Garbin is joined in the team by a host of the WNBL's top young players and after missing on a medal at the 2015 games she is determined to go improve on that result when the games kick on in Chinese Taipei later this month.
"I've been pretty happy with how consistent I've played throughout the QBL season and that gives me a lot of confidence going in to the next few weeks," she said.
"I really enjoyed the 2015 games but it was disappointing to not get a medal and the expectation on any Aussie team going in to a tournament is to be in those medal playoffs.
"A few of the girls on this team were in the under-19s Aussie team with me a few years ago and I know we're all looking forward to going over there and playing our best."
Coached by former Fire coach Chris Lucas, the team will spend the next few weeks in Japan for training and a warm-up tournament, before the games get underway in Chinese Taipei on August 21.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MVP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese Taipei</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World University Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Lucas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WNBL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QBL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TOWNSVILLE Fire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville Flames</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garbin</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 21</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darcee Garbin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uni Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gladstone</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
