<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445471286187156</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Australian</source>
  <url>http://www.theaustralian.com.au/higher-education/high-wired/high-wired-update-vcs-worth-a-packet/news-story/03d08fe9fd3a392915b6c28d75445c01</url>
  <title>VCs worth a packet</title>
  <content>
In today's High Wired, we admire vice-chancellors and stoop to humour studies
Refreshing empiricism
Maybe it's a compliment for vice-chancellors to join the ranks of bank bosses. The financial wizards of staff-slashing and fee-gouging are used to having their massive pay named and shamed in the public arena. It doesn't seem to do them any real harm, and may even bring them grudging admiration. And now it's the turn of . Sydney University's Michael Spence was top of the pops with his $1.4 million salary package, followed by Greg Craven at Australian Catholic University who took home $1.25m. The interesting outlier was Brian Schmidt, the physics Nobel laureate who runs the Australian National University. His package was a (modest by comparison) $618,000. Apparently he benchmarked his pay against similar roles overseas, as well as professorial salaries at ANU. Presumably he brings the same empirical approach to his spare time winemaking.
That's a bit rich
Did you know that the University of Melbs is Victoria's third biggest employer? The Nats' Bridget McKenzie certainly does now, if she didn't before. Sitting on the  into the government's higher education changes --- the report comes down on Wednesday --- McKenzie had asked Melbourne's Margaret Sheil for "a detailed summary of the remuneration structure for the vice-chancellor (Glyn Davis)". Sheil took the question on notice, and now have the answer. Yes, the university is the state's third largest employer and "one of Australia's biggest
research institutions. The vice-chancellor is the chief executive of a university ranked in the world's top 40. The organisation has an operating budget of over $2 billion, 8,000 staff and more than 48,000 students." So, running Melbs is a big deal. And the pay packet? McKenzie was told to check the annual report.
Great moments in marketing
McKenzie had also wondered aloud how much Melbs spent on marketing. The latest figure was $7.82 million in 2015. What's the budget of a metro newspaper these days? Anyway, apart from pointing out the giddy variety of things they do, the Melbs' marketeers offered a rationale nicely pitched for the present political moment: "In an educational sector in which the government is seeking to generate competition, choice and contestability, marketing will increasingly be an important communications tool through which to differentiate the education provided at various institutions in order to assist students make an informed choice".
Advances in diagnosis
HW has normally dealt with Glenn Atwell as media manager at Deakin University, and before that as a press secretary for former education minister Simon Crean and his Victorian state counterpart Bronwyn Pike. This morning, Atwell  about a very different matter - he and wife Laura's struggles to care for their little daughter Ivy, who has a devastating but as yet undiagnosed form of what is thought to be a mitochondrial disease. New research by Monash and Murdoch Children's Research Institute could boost diagnosis rates that have already been improved by the extraordinary recent progress in genomics. Here's hoping the latest advance gives the Atwells the answers they need.
But do they do home visits?
Today Macquarie University launches its new, rather pricey . It's a four-year graduate-entry program plugged in to Macquarie's own teaching hospital. Another special feature is clinical experience abroad at the Apolo Hospital in Hyderabad, India. Domestic students can expect to pay $64,000 a year with the fee for internationals being $70,000. No doubt conscious of the price ticket, Macquarie is at pains to say it will "offer the most generous scholarship fund of any Australian medical program, including scholarships for indigenous students and equity groups".
You had to be there
Ever tried to put overseas visitors at ease with a typical Aussie gag or two? And met with polite puzzlement? HW has just the conference for you - Humour: how does it travel? Organisers are on the lookout for work on "how humour travels, whether between times or places, genres or forms, from creator to recipient, from one hearer to another, as well as humour about travel". The  closes on Thursday. Keep your punch lines for the conference in Cairns next February.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon Crean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenn Atwell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Melbs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ivy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Atwell</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melb</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bronwyn Pike</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sheil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hyderabad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deakin University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VCs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian National University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brian Schmidt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>India</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macquarie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nobel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glyn Davis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macquarie University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laura</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney University's Michael Spence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>High Wired</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murdoch Children's Research Institute</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne's Margaret Sheil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Catholic University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Craven</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MONASH</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nats' Bridget McKenzie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McKenzie</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apolo Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
