<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445273717687197</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:13</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/south-east/mornington-peninsula-shire-council-calls-on-residents-to-join-campaign-against-residential-zone-changes/news-story/419b2b4e9bc80ad2b9f72c403077759e</url>
  <title>Peninsula 'under threat' from new laws</title>
  <content>
PLANNING changes that could allow three-storey buildings in residential streets are the "biggest threat" to the region's unique character, says Mornington Peninsula Mayor Bev Colomb.
The council is campaigning against changes to residential zones, which were introduced by the State Government in March "without consultation".
HAVE YOUR SAY: What do you think of the changes? Tell us below.
"We've hit it early and we've hit it hard," Cr Colomb said.
"It's the biggest threat to amenity on the Mornington Peninsula that I have seen in my 11 and a half years on the council."
The changes would mean developments could occur with no notification and no right of appeal.
"It was introduced without consultation with councils ... and the first residents will know a neighbour is adding a third storey to their house is when the work begins," Cr Colomb said.
The council has asked Planning Minister Richard Wynne to approve interim controls for the peninsula that would limit residential development to two storeys or 9m.
A spokesman for Mr Wynne, Patrick Lane, said the request had been received and would be "considered on its merits".
"The Mornington Peninsula is one of Victoria's most treasured destinations, which is why we're getting the planning right to ensure it retains its charm as our population grows," Mr Lane said.
"The Government's new residential zones protect neighbourhood character, capitalise on population growth and give developers and neighbourhoods certainty over what can and can't be built."
More than 400 people have attended a series of community meetings across the peninsula to find out what they can do to protect their towns.
"There was an overall agreement that people power is necessary to get the message across to the minister that the peninsula is not like metropolitan Melbourne," Cr Colomb said.
Areas most affected by the changes include Rosebud, Dromana, Capel Sound, Bittern, Hastings, Tyabb, Somerville, Baxter and Mornington East.
To get involved: Write to Planning Minister Richard Wynne at PO Box 1474, Collingwood VIC 3066, email richard.wynne@parliament.vic.gov.au, or sign the petition .

Future Melbourne editor Nick Richardson details the Herald Sun's in-depth investigation into what's next for Victoria's capital.

WHAT DOES THE FUTURE HOLD FOR MELBOURNE?
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mornington East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mornington Peninsula</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FUTURE HOLD FOR MELBOURNE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Lane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PO Box 1474</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tyabb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baxter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Colomb</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Richardson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood VIC 3066</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Planning Minister Richard Wynne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hastings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Wynne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Capel Sound</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Lane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herald Sun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bittern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Does</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rosebud</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dromana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peninsula</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mornington Peninsula Mayor Bev Colomb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Somerville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
