<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444998839774615</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/south-australia/postal-plebiscite-vote-looms-on-samesex-marriage-as-liberals-go-back-to-senate/news-story/bc59962c06a858d9eddbf1ed767dfd31</url>
  <title>Postal vote looms on gay marriage</title>
  <content>
A NATIONAL postal vote could deliver legal same-sex marriage to Australia by the end of the year, under a plan endorsed by federal Liberal MPs.
The Liberal party room on Monday in Parliament on marriage equality and instead backed a plebiscite.
The Senate is set to veto the plebiscite move and Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull will then push ahead with a national postal vote on same-sex marriage.
The Government has legal advice that the High Court is likely to dismiss an attempt by marriage-equality advocates to block a postal vote.
During a tense meeting, 28 Liberals spoke in favour of holding a plebiscite and seven called for a conscience vote.
After the meeting, Finance Minister Mathias Cormann said a plebiscite Bill would be introduced into Parliament this week. If it was defeated, the Government would move to hold a voluntary postal vote. If a majority of voters supported same-sex marriage at either a full plebiscite or postal vote, the Government would allow a conscience vote to proceed in Parliament.
"The Government is committed to giving the Australian people a say on whether or not the definition of marriage should be changed in the Marriage Act,'' Senator Cormann said. "Our preference is to do this through a compulsory attendance plebiscite.
"If that were not to be able to get through the Senate, the Government's view is that there is a legal and constitutional way forward - keeping faith with the commitment that we made - giving the Australian people a say through a voluntary postal plebiscite."
Key crossbench Senator Nick Xenophon said the Senate would reject a plebiscite and called on the Government to allow its members am immediate conscience vote on same-sex marriage.
"This reminds me of Groundhog Day. We just need a conscience vote,'' Senator Xenophon said.
Greens Senator Sarah Hanson-Young said a postal vote would be an "idiotic, stupid idea".
A conscience vote was backed in the party room by Senator Dean Smith and by MPs John Alexander, Warren Entsch, Trevor Evans, Tim Wilson, Jason Wood and Trent Zimmerman.
Mr Entsch reserved his right to cross the floor on same-sex marriage but said he was pleased the Government would attempt to resolve the issue through a popular vote.
Some conservatives, including former prime minister Tony Abbott, spoke against a postal vote and said the Government should keep pressuring the Senate to allow a plebiscite.
South Australian Liberal backbencher Tony Pasin used the party room meeting to take a swipe at Defence Minister Christopher Pyne, who supports marriage equality.
Mr Pasin said MPs who wanted the Government and Mr Turnbull to be in the "winners' circle" should stop "tackling colleagues from behind or kicking the ball in the other direction".

Hear Christopher Pyne tell a Sydney bar the government's plans for marriage equality. Audio courtesy Bolt Report, Sky News.

Pyne: Marriage equality may be "sooner than everyone thinks"
Australian Marriage Equality chair Alex Greenwich said pro-gay marriage groups would seek a High Court injunction to prevent a postal vote.
"There will be disappointment felt from coast to coast tonight ... as the Government has yet again decided to yet again delay, drag on and disappoint people with the decision,'' Mr Greenwich said.
Opposition Leader Bill Shorten said the Government's decision to hold a plebiscite or postal ballot was "ridiculous".
"I can't control what the Government does. But if Labor is elected, we'll legislate for marriage equality in our first 100 days,'' Mr Shorten said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Xenophon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marriage Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Pasin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Groundhog Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trent Zimmerman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greens Senator Sarah Hanson-Young</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Finance Minister Mathias Cormann</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leader Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pyne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Greenwich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christopher Pyne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Dean Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Nick Xenophon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Marriage Equality</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolt Report</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian Liberals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Cormann</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs John Alexander</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Greenwich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sky News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>High Court</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Wood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Defence Minister Christopher Pyne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Pasin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
