<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445260832785021</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/south-east/elsternwick-baker-frank-rieck-shares-the-500yearold-secret-of-his-success/news-story/74e686fc800663d514cdfd4942ea1f34</url>
  <title>Famous bread 500 years in the making</title>
  <content>
FRANK Rieck has made a crust out of baking bread for more than 50 years.
But it's not just any loaf - Mr Rieck creates what has been touted by some reviewers as the best sourdough in Australia.
He opened a Bavarian-style bakery in Elsternwick almost 50 years ago.
But the secret to his success is much, much older than that.
The key ingredient and sourdough culture in his loaves is actually about 500 years old.
"As long as you keep feeding it with more water and flour it never dies," Mr Rieck said.
"That's how you get the flavour. As the bacteria multiplies it creates little air bubbles which makes the bread rise."
He said loyal customers came for a slice of the action from as far away as Bendigo and Moe.
"People know this is the best bread," Mr Rieck said.
"They might move somewhere else but they keep coming back.
"Some people tell me: 'I'm going to Sydney, I better get some bread for my friends or they won't give me a bed to sleep in'."
Regular Jetti Levine has been coming in since she was a teenager.
"I come for the bread," she said, with a laugh, adding: "And also for Frank."
Mr Rieck is from a long line of bakers.
His parents owned a bakery in Germany, where bread is part of the culture and considered an art form.
His mother Maria was a master baker, having studied breadmaking for several years before setting up a bakery of her own.
Mr Rieck migrated to Australia as a youngster in 1959 without knowing a word of English.
And in his pants pockets - prior to today's strict Customs regulations - he carried his special ancient sourdough culture.
"It does all the work to make the bread rise, you don't use anything else," he said, opening a container of the culture which looks similar to porridge and smells vaguely like fermenting wine.
"This is sour dough, it's about 500 years old, it came from my parents in Germany," he said.
"You put water and flour, a little bit of salt, and it grows again."
His bread is made without yeast, preservatives or sugar, but requires more skill.
"When you're using sour dough you don't know how long it's going to take to grow," he said.
"When you buy yeast you know how much is in there, with the sour dough it's a bit more difficult."
"That's the skill of a baker, knowing when it's ready.
"I've got bread today that's been in the oven one and half hours, it's like a brick, it's gorgeous."
The smell of fermenting sourdough is thick in the air of the small Glen Huntly Rd bakery.
Mr Rieck said they hadn't changed much about the shop since day one, which still features the original wooden counter and bread display nailed on the wall.
Mr Rieck still uses a peel - a long wooden shovel - to put loaves in the old-school oven.
In keeping with the traditional theme, there is an old cash register with no Eftpos.
Their marketing strategy is equally simple.
They open whenever the bread is ready and close when it sells out.
5.45am is the busy time.
By 9.00am it is already quiet.
But there is plenty of love, with laughter echoing throughout the bakery.
Wife Elana admitted it was hard being a bakers' wife.
"You don't see them," she said.
"At night they're working, in the day they're sleeping."
The bakery is a happy place with their much-loved dog Izzy waiting patiently outside.
A pair of police officers stroll by and Mrs Rieck rushes out and gets Izzy to give them a "paw" shake.
There will be no loafing around for Mr Rieck.
Despite the 10.30pm starts and working into the wee hours of the morning, he refuses to retire.
"Frank's not doing it for money, he just loves it," Mrs Rieck said.
"He just wants to be here."
Details:  Frank's Elsternwick Bakery,  291 Glen Huntly Rd, Elsternwick.  Ph: 9528 2380
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bavarian-style</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MOE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Rieck</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frank's Elsternwick Bakery,  291 Glen Huntly Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jetti Levine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elsternwick</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germany</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glen Huntly Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bendigo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ph: 9528 2380</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Izzy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Rieck</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eftpos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frank</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FRANK Rieck</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
