<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445385386839459</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:39</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/lifestyle/real-life/news-life/police-hunt-accomplices-as-neighbours-describe-loner-in-alleged-model-kidnapping-case/news-story/6da7e31ee12dbda7cc25444d53305f28</url>
  <title>Police hunt accomplices as neighbours describe 'loner' in alleged model kidnapping case</title>
  <content>
Model kidnapped and offered for sale online
2:32

A UK model who was kidnapped and put up for sale on the dark web has spoken about the 'terrifying' ordeal.

August 7th 2017
17 hours ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/World/

A BRITISH model who was kidnapped by sex slavers told last night how she was drugged, handcuffed and stuffed in a suitcase. Mum Chloe Ayling, 20, was driven to a remote farmhouse and held captive for six days after being abducted by masked men. Pic Instagram @chloeayling

Share

THE man charged with abducting a British model has been described by neighbours as a "loner" as police hunt possible accomplices and release new pictures in the extraordinary case.
Polish man Lukasz Pawel Herba was arrested on July 18 and charged with abduction and illegal imprisonment by Italian police after UK model Chloe Ayling went missing for nearly a week.
The 20-year-old mother was dropped off at the UK consulate in Milan after being drugged and kidnapped at what she thought was a photoshoot that ended in a nightmare as she claims she was told she would be sold as a sex slave.
Neighbours of the young man have described Herba as a "loner" who lived quietly and kept to himself.
Sinead Boyce, 23, told  he had a pet rat that he walked around with on his shoulder and was very quiet in the neighbourhood he had lived in for more than four years.
"We'd see him from time-to-time carrying this rat on his shoulder. It must have been a pet or something," she said.
"He'd take it to the corner shop and all sorts. It was quite a big thing as well. It would sit fairly comfortably on his shoulder."
"One day, my mum asked him if she could see it. He came up close to her so that she could have a good look, but even then he wouldn't speak to her."

The fake studio where Ayling was lured to. Picture: Polizia di Stato.Source:AFP

A BRITISH model who was kidnapped by sex slavers told last night how she was drugged, handcuffed and stuffed in a suitcase. Picture: Instagram @chloeaylingSource:Instagram

Italian police have released a picture of the place where Chloe Ayling was held. Picture: Italian Police Photo via AP.Source:AP

Police have seized computer equipment from a home linked to Lukasz Pawel Herba.Source:Supplied
The UK's National Crime Agency and East Midlands Special Operations Police are using special kidnap and extortion units to uncover what happened in the case that has made headlines around the world.

"A house in the Oldbury area, linked to Lukasz Pawel Herba, was searched on 18 July by EMSOU officers with assistance from West Midlands Police. Computer equipment seized is being forensically examined," police said on Monday.
A note allegedly found on Herba's computer read "you are being released as a huge generosity from Black Death Group," according to media reports.
Meanwhile, details of the shadowy group from a 2015 investigation by , Joseph Cox have come to light. When approaching the "Black Death" on the dark web he found professional images of women with price tags and height and weight measurements listed. However one update to the story reports at least one of the women listed presented as "Nicole" appeared to use an image from a porn film.

The room where Ayling was held. Picture: Italian Police Photo via AP.Source:AP

Chloe Ayling said she was told she would be sold but later handed into authorities because she was a mother. Picture: Instagram @chloeaylingSource:Instagram
Over the weekend Ms Ayling told police of her horror at being drugged and kidnapped on July 11 after being lured to a Milan studio.
She said she was grabbed from behind by a man wearing a balaclava and gloves and injected before being thrown in the boot of a car and told she would be sold to men who would feed her to tigers if they grew bored.
"I've been through a terrifying experience. I've feared for my life, second by second, minute by minute, hour by hour," she said. "I woke up in a car's boot. My wrists and ankles were handcuffed, and there was adhesive tape on my mouth.
"I was inside a bag and was only able to breathe through a small hole."
"The girls are destined for Arab countries. At least three a week are sold and when the person gets bored of her he gives her to other people," she was told.

Italian police pictures show the home where the British-based Polish man allegedly held the model before reportedly planning to sell her on the dark web. Picture: AFP/ Polizia di Stato.Source:AFP

The car that Ayling was transported in by Herba, who claimed to be part of the "Black Death" web-based group. Picture: AFP PHOTO / Polizia di StatoSource:AFP
Italian police are now working to find another four men believed to be involved in the alleged plot. Herba's role remains unclear.
On Saturday Milan deputy prosecutor Paolo Storari said: "Fantasist or not, what is clear is that he is a very dangerous man who drugged his victim as soon as she was kidnapped and put her inside a large travel bag in the boot of a car."
"His version of events is barely credible but clearly he does not deny that he was with her for the time she was missing," Storari said.
Head of the Italian investigation Lorenzo Bucossi said it was unclear if he was a "disturbed individual or someone with a real plan" but he was "certainly a dangerous person and carried out a real kidnap."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/World</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Black Death</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>British-based Polish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP/Source</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Ayling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sinead Boyce, 23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Black Death Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian Police Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>chloeaylingSource</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oldbury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Midlands Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP PHOTO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EMSOU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chloe Ayling</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Polizia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arab</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Milan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joseph Cox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lukasz Pawel Herba.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ayling</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicole</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Polish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paolo Storari</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lukasz Pawel Herba</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stato.Source</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lorenzo Bucossi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herba</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK's National Crime Agency</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>StatoSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chloe Ayling, 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East Midlands Special Operations Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday Milan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
