<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445393976774228</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/business/helping-directors-keep-ahead-of-the-fast-pace-of-change-is-the-name-of-the-game-for-the-aicd-dr-roger-sexton-says/news-story/eb5e50432fd174a5a21ee926b2d7e03d</url>
  <title>Asia, digital focus for AICD</title>
  <content>
THE need to further engage with Asia and to stay abreast of technological developments are issues company directors need to keep top of mind, Australian Institute of Company Directors SA/NT president Roger Sexton says.
Dr Sexton, who is also the founder and chairman of listed South Australian exporter Beston Global Food Company, said there were great opportunities presented by both issues, and he was keen for the AICD locally to help directors navigate the inherent risks and opportunities.
"I said when I became president one of the things I wanted to do, given my background, was to have the local division of the AICD much more focused on Asia and broaden the skill base of directors here about how to operate in Asia, because that market's on our doorstep,'' Dr Sexton said.
"That's what we've done particularly with our Fellows' Dinner.''
Dr Sexton said last year David Chiem, founder of MindChamps, spoke at the Fellows' Dinner about what he was doing with early childcare centres in Singapore, the Middle East and the Philippines, and how he was educating children for the job market in 2030.
"The job market in 2030 is going to be very different from what it is now and companies are going to be very different, so that was fascinating stuff,'' Dr Sexton said.
"Not only did it open their minds to what's happening in Asia and what Asians are thinking, but also about saying 'you need to look at things a bit differently, because the world is changing rapidly'.
"Any business based in Adelaide and looking to expand needs to remain focused on what's happening in Asia.
"(More broadly) What we're doing is very much about making directors aware of the changing issues and problems - cyber risk and compliance processes - but also about stretching their mind and looking into nooks and crannies that they wouldn't otherwise do.''
Dr Sexton said membership was growing well, with the AICD's SA/NT division having just shy of 3000 members now.
"It's appealing to a broad range of people in a wide range of areas," he said.
ABC managing director Michelle Guthrie spoke at the AICD's most recent Fellows' Dinner in Adelaide last month.
Dr Sexton said while the event was off the record, Ms Guthrie spoke about the national broadcaster's ongoing digital transformation as well as the work it did it the regions.
"She made the point that in many areas the ABC has been leading Australia in the application of technology, such as iView, but she said her aim is to make the ABC even broader than what it is," he said.
Dr Sexton said he was also passionate about the application of new technology, with his own company, Beston, using virtual reality to help it expand its markets across Asia.
"You certainly need to be aware of what the trends are in the IT area, and how you can use it too. That's true from the consumer interface and how you use the digital world to sell your product, right through to your back offices and cyber security.''
Dr Sexton said it was important for directors to be aware of the seismic changes in the field.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Sexton</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fellows' Dinner</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roger Sexton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Directors SA/NT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beston Global Food Company</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Middle East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philippines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SINGAPORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michelle Guthrie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Institute of Company</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MindChamps</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AICD</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AICD's SA/NT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iView</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Guthrie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Chiem</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
