<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445346732132949</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/south-australia/julia-gillard-hails-bravery-in-new-book-by-former-port-adelaide-footballer-scott-hodges/news-story/91fd33c946c76d11fecc94e996da2ef8</url>
  <title>Be like Hodges: Get it off your chest</title>
  <content>
THAT there is life on the other side of depression is one of the most important lessons of the sometimes harrowing book of the life and times of former Port Adelaide footballer Scott Hodges, according to former Prime Minister Julia Gillard.
Ms Gillard, who is now chair of Beyond Blue, met with Hodges to talk about his biography Scott Hodges: Not all Black and White, where he opens up about his battle with depression which left him on the brink of suicide.
"I think we have got the conversation rolling in Australia (about mental health) but still I suspect people fear that being diagnosed with depression is like a never ending grim black cloud over your head for the rest of your life,'' Ms Gillard said.
"Whereas, as Scott shows, and as others have shown, (Sydney Swans footballer) Buddy Franklin and others, you can manage your health, you can get better.''
Hodges said he has been heartened by messages of support since the book was released last month and was hopeful it could help other people facing similar problems.

Those who played with Scott Hodges still marvel at his on-field exploits, especially his record-breaking season in 1990 when he kicked 153 goals. Courtesy: Seven News

Seven News: Scott Hodges' memorable career
"I just feel like I am 20 kilos lighter just by getting everything off my chest and that should give other people the same sort of feeling,'' he said.
Ms Gillard said it was vital people such as Hodges shared their story as it showed people, especially men, it was okay to talk about your problems.
"I am sure men must look at that and think if someone like him, strong, lived a life, football legend, if someone like Scott can have these issues and dilemmas that makes me more comfortable about talking about the pressures on me.''
She said, on average eight people a day take their own life, of which six were men.
"We suspect one of the reason is men are not used to reaching out for help,'' she said. "Men will talk to their mates about the football or have a joke, have a beer, but less likely to settle in with their mates and have a really deep and meaningful conversation.''
Anyone experiencing a crisis or thinking about suicide can contact on 131 114. Support for living with depression can be found at  on 1300 22 4636.

Ex Rugby League star Daniel Conn talks about his experience with mental health

Daniel Conn opens up about depression
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beyond Blue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Swans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Gillard</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ex Rugby League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Hodges</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Conn</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Julia Gillard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hodge</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buddy Franklin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seven News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
