<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445389681806873</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/business/fight-brewing-over-the-future-of-leigh-creek-mega-mining-machinery/news-story/fb9679472e1dd586c987342a8f0de23a</url>
  <title>Fight over mega mining machinery</title>
  <content>
A NOT-for-profit organisation is threatening legal action over the impending removal of iconic mining equipment based in Leigh Creek.
The William Light Foundation, via its lawyers at Clemens Haskin Legal, has sought assurances from SA Treasurer Tom Koutsantonis that the "cultural and economic impact on Leigh Creek's future will be properly assessed prior to removal of the machinery".
The 9W Drag line and Terex dump truck were sold for scrap at an auction late last year and will soon be removed from the Leigh Creek coal field. This has enraged WLF chairman Nigel Carney who said the items are "the last relics of the coal mining heritage of the region".
In its letter to Mr Koutsantonis, Clemens Haskin said: "To treat them as mere scrap does a severe disservice to the Government's own endorsement of the Leigh Creek Futures Report and the local community's proud heritage."
"Should the Minister not be willing to provide the assurances requested on an urgent basis, our client may have no option but to seek recourse through the courts, which may result in additional costs and adverse publicity," it said.
A Department of State Development spokesman yesterday said: "The Government understands the mine viewing site was closed off to the public for two years prior to the sale due to public safety concerns relating to the dragline and truck."
luke.griffiths@news.com.au
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>TEREX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leigh Creek</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leigh Creek Futures Report</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Koutsantonis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WLF</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>William Light Foundation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clemens Haskin Legal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clemens Haskin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nigel Carney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of State</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA Treasurer Tom Koutsantonis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>W Drag</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
