<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445312372393768</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:22</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/business/media-and-marketing/nine-southern-cross-fairfax-prime-rally-ahead-of-media-reform-debate-20170807-gxqmrz.html</url>
  <title>Potential targets rally ahead of media reform debate</title>
  <content>
Shares in media companies seen as potential merger targets have rallied to year highs just days before the Senate considers lifting Australia's 30-year-old ownership restrictions.
as media companies try to increase their reach, in a bid to win back advertising dollars from online search engines and social media.

Up Next

Who is Frank Madafferi?

09:40

More National News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Government's media reform agenda

In the wake of Channel Tens plunge into administration, Communications Minister Mitch Fifield says the government is seeking media reform.

However, not everyone is sharing in the surge, with Seven West Media and News Corp largely missing out (although Seven has lifted a little in recent weeks off a low base).
Their share prices have tracked along the broader market while Nine, Southern Cross Austereo, Fairfax and Prime Media have outperformed the ASX 200 in the past week.

Prime Media Group's share price is up 16.5 per cent in the past two weeks and was trading at 46¢ at the close on Monday, its highest price since March last year.
Prime has not updated the market since late June, when it revealed  as a result of the government's TV and radio licence fee cuts.

However, experts predict it is likely to be one of the first companies to be bought out by a metropolitan station if the Senate decides to lift restrictions on the reach rule, which currently prevents a single person or company controling a TV network with a licence area that exceeds more than 75 per cent of the Australian population.
"Prime Media is an obvious takeover target," Morningstar's media analyst Brian Han says.Photo: Alex Ellinghausen
"It is an obvious target because it is hanging out there by itself without anything else. It's an obvious target for Seven because there are a lot of synergies to be extracted. They have a long-term affiliation agreement  - they are basically sister companies."
The two other regional broadcasters, Southern Cross Austereo and WIN Television, are more complicated. Southern Cross also owns metropolitan radio stations around the country that broadcast Triple M and Hit Network, and has affiliates with both Nine and Ten around its regional television.Photo: Ben Rushton
Southern Cross would be much more expensive to buy with a market capitalisation of more than $1 billion, while Prime's is $180 million. Southern Cross has also enjoyed a rally in the past week, up 5.3 per cent to reach $1.39 on Monday.
WIN is a private company owned by billionaire Bruce Gordon, who is .
The crossbench and minor parties ... may propose additional measures, which the government is open to considering.
Senator Mitch Fifield

Fairfax's rally comes just weeks after  from potential takeover bids after completing their due diligence. Shares dived from a high of $1.26 to about 96¢ when that news broke, but have since risen back over $1 without any additional company news. Fairfax Media publishes BusinessDay.
Nine's shares are up 9 per cent in the past week and reached a 15-month high of $1.56 on Monday. Nine has the largest market capitalisation of the commercial broadcasters,  at $1.3 billion.Photo: Andrew Meares
Fairfax and Nine co-own streaming service Stan and have been . Nine's chief executive Hugh Marks last year said there was "nothing concrete" about that rumour.
"I am interested in quality content that I can make a business out of quality platforms," he explained, adding that print products were not a strategic asset for Nine.Photo: Daniel Munoz
The media bill's passage is far from certain, with key crossbenchers such as Nick Xenophon, the Greens and One Nation still concerned it may lead to more media concentration.
BusinessDay revealed last week the  could be enough to guarantee the support of crossbenchers. It is already supported within the Coalition.
Communications Minister Mitch Fifield told Fairfax Media it would not "contemplate splitting elements out of the existing package", which is well supported across the industry because both commercial and subscription broadcasters benefit as long as the package remains intact.
Tax benefits like not-for-profit status would help smaller news sources survive and could be added to the Broadcasting Legislation Amendment (Broadcasting Reform) Bill 2017 without splitting it.
"However, the crossbench and minor parties ... may propose additional measures, which the government is open to considering," Senator Fifield said.
He is also manager of government business in the Senate but has not listed his media reforms for debate until Wednesday. Amendments to Fair Work legislation and bills relating to gaming, telecommunications, competition and migration are listed ahead of media reforms.
If passed, the media reform bill would  and broadcast to 100 per cent of the population.
In anticipation of the changes, Mr Murdoch and Mr Gordon have laid the groundwork to purchase Ten, which is in administration. If their plan proceeds, it would give Mr Murdoch control of newspapers, radio and television in major metropolitan markets.
News Corp executive chairman for Australasia, Michael Miller, recently explained that his company needed  to compete against online sites such as Facebook and Google.
News Corp is already one of the largest media companies in Australia and publishes tabloid newspapers in every capital city and national broadsheet The Australian, and owns half of Foxtel.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Rushton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Gordon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill, 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morningstar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Media</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>One Nation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brian Han</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minister Mitch Fifield</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southern Cross</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Meares</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Xenophon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broadcasting Legislation Amendment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruce Gordon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Fifield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Munoz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Triple M</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WIN Television</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frank Madafferi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Murdoch</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fair Work</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Miller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seven West Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Mitch Fifield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxtel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel Ten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broadcasting Reform</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australasia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hugh Marks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southern Cross Austereo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BusinessDay</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX 200</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Google</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Ellinghausen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hit Network</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Media Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
