<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445329552263474</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:26</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/sport/mark-flanagan-to-fight-in-townsville-following-world-title-shot/news-story/056debdae4430eff0f1043c842f551d3</url>
  <title>Bam Bam confirms home fight</title>
  <content>
TOWNSVILLE's Mark Flanagan will use his hometown as the launch pad for another crack at the boxing big time.
Flanagan will fight Argentina's Pablo Matias Magrini (19 wins, 2 losses, 1 draw) on November 4 at the Townsville Entertainment and Convention Centre following his recent points loss against Russia's Denis Lebedev for the WBA cruiserweight title.
Magrini packs a powerful punch and - like Flanagan - has won most of his fights by knockout, having landed 15 stoppages.
"He's tough and definitely a respectable opponent," Flanagan's promoter Angelo Di Carlo said.
"But of course this all about getting Mark back in his hometown after the loss in Russia.
"He didn't take the opportunity but that's what happens, Lebedev has been the champion for a long time.
"Mark learned some lessons that night and he already knows where he went wrong."
Flanagan, now based in Brisbane, fought Lebedev in Siberia for the WBA belt last month, and was rated a solid chance of upsetting the gnarly Russian after winning his past 11 bouts.
But Flanagan struggled to find Lebedev's range and failed to land the heavy blow, with Lebedev dictating a slow pace and hitting on the counter-attack.
Flanagan, who returned home last week for a fight night held by his old club Upper Ross Hawks Boxing Gym, will now be on the hunt for another big opportunity.
"That next opportunity will come, but whether it's for a Commonwealth title or world title we just don't know," Di Carlo said.
"I think this fight in Townsville will be a great opportunity for his hometown supporters to see how far he's come."
An undercard featuring local fighters is also being put together, and could feature North Queensland talents such as Kolby Johnston and Liam Paro.
"Mark fighting an international fight here gives other fighters an opportunity," Flanagan's mentor and Hawks coach Dennis Clancy said.
"That was a big reason for him wanting to come back home, and he's looking forward to it after having a bit of down time.
"Angelo (Di Carlo) is coming up as well and that's a chance for some fighters to make an impression."
Flanagan last fought at the Townsville Entertainment and Convention Centre in 2014 for the Australian cruiserweight title, which he won with a unanimous decision over Newcastle's Daniel Ammann.
"This fight we'll help keep Mark's rating high and then he'll get his next shot," Clancy said.
"This also good for Townsville boxing, it's another cog in the wheel."
Ticketing information will be released in coming weeks.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Di Carlo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia's Denis Lebedev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Convention Centre</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Siberia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Angelo Di Carlo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WBA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Upper Ross Hawks Boxing Gym</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lebedev</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bam Bam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flanagan</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville Entertainment</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dennis Clancy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Angelo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liam Paro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magrini</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Argentina's Pablo Matias Magrini (19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kolby Johnston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clancys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle's Daniel Ammann</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TOWNSVILLE's Mark Flanagan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
