<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445557185534916</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>15:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/world/extreme-turbulence-on-american-airlines-flight-sends-10-to-hospital/news-story/9b6600f0f8e7f343bbb870c1896e8292</url>
  <title>Plane trip hell puts 10 in hospital</title>
  <content>
It was a flight from hell.
at least 10 people were hospitalised after an American Airlines flight from Athens to Philadelphia hit turbulence and became a case study in keeping your seatbelts buckled at all times.
"Thirty minutes out, they were giving us our drinks. The flight attendants were in the last couple rows when they said, 'Fasten your seat belts,'" Ian Smith of South Philadelphia told local news station, WPVI.
"And then they said for the flight attendants to get to their seats, and they didn't even have time. It started shaking, then it took a big drop. Babies screaming, people in front of us hitting the ceiling," Smith said.
Passenger Ervin Fang captured the resulting debris-strewn cabin, including drink stains on the bulkhead.
"Passengers disoriented and relieved," he tweeted along with the footage.
Flight 759 was carrying 287 passengers and 12 crew members on the weekend when it hit the severe turbulence.
"There was just very slight turbulence for about five seconds and then suddenly it felt like the whole plane was in free fall,"New Yorker Alex Ehmke told WPVI.
Another passenger, Jessica Huseman, tweeted: "They'd just handed out drinks. This plane (that I'm still on) is soaked. Soaked. They'll be hosing this out for hours."
She said one of the flight attendants had dislocated his shoulder.
After landing, three passengers and seven crew members were taken to a hospital.
Huseman praised the professionalism of the flight crew, saying, "Impressed w the attendants on this @AmericanAir flight from Athens."
American Airlines released the following statement:
"American Airlines flight 759 from Athens, Greece to Philadelphia International Airport briefly encountered severe turbulence shortly before landing safely in Philadelphia. The seat belt sign was on at the time. Three passengers and seven crew members were transported to a local hospital for evaluation. We are taking care of our passengers and our crew members at this time and want to thank our team members for keeping our passengers safe."
and is reprinted with permission.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Yorker Alex Ehmke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Athens</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jessica Huseman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greece</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>American Airlines</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AmericanAir</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Huseman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WPVI</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Smith of South</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ervin Fang</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philadelphia International Airport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philadelphia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
