<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445041789448617</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/business/banking-and-finance/david-morgan-blasts-bank-tax-as-revenue-grab-poor-policy-20170804-gxp5gw</url>
  <title>David Morgan blasts bank tax as revenue grab, poor policy</title>
  <content>
Banking elder statesman David Morgan has issued a scathing assessment of the federal government's bank levy, labelling it a "naked revenue grab" and a poor piece of tax policy.
Dr Morgan, who formerly ran Westpac Banking Corp and was also an international adviser to Australia's landmark Financial System Inquiry, said Treasurer Scott Morrison's argument that the tax compensated for the major bank's implicit government guarantee was "relatively weak".
"That bank tax fails any test of efficiency," he said in an interview from London, where he is now based. "It is just a naked revenue grab and a poor piece of tax policy.
"I continue to take an active interest in banking regulation and competition policy to ensure you get a competitive market."

Dr Morgan was equally critical of South Australia's own bank tax.

He declined to comment, however, on AUSTRAC's court action against the Commonwealth Bank of Australia, which alleges the bank  and took too long to close down suspicious accounts.
But Dr Morgan emphasised that capital ratios were just one of the which are to be implemented by 2020. He outlined other factors including strength of management, credit quality, risk management and liquidity as key measures of bank strength.
"I absolutely buy that Australia's major banks are heavily reliant on international capital markets and need to be unquestionably strong," Dr Morgan said, noting that on many measures the nation's banks "already met" the new benchmarks.
Dr Morgan, who is also Europe and Asia Pacific chairman at private equity group JC Flowers & Co and Chi-X Australia chairman, was commenting after the alternative exchange appointed former Deutsche Bank co-head of global markets Vic Jokovic as its new chief executive. He starts in January and replaces

Dr Morgan said locally Chi-X was now in the black after launching in Australia in 2011. He praised Mr Jokovic's suitability to the role and said he was confident Chi-X's share of Australian trading volumes would continue to increase.
"We've been building a market share ... that's now continuously increasing," he said.
Chi-X had a hard time gaining traction in Australia in its early years. Last month, the average daily market share for continuous trading was a record at just below 20 per cent, inclusive of on and off-market trades. The exchange has 45 trading participants in Australia.
Dr Morgan noted that following a long development stage, Chi-X would start offering "transferable custody receipts" (TRaCRs) to represent stocks from the New York Stock Exchange and NASDAQ on Chi-X before Christmas.

He said TRaCRs would make it "faster and cheaper" to trade those stocks but the exchange had to navigate a lot of "moving parts" including sign-off from a myriad of regulators and the Australian Tax Office.
Deutsche Bank is working with Chi-X on the introduction of TRaCRs to ensure there is a liquid market.
Dr Morgan also noted that under the leadership of Mr Jokovic, Chi-X wanted to have a constructive relationship with rival bourse the ASX while remaining a "rigorous competitor".
He was loathe to criticise the ASX on its investment in distributed ledger firm Digital Asset Holdings, saying industry players had to keep abreast of developments in blockchain technology.

"It is still unproven as yet but it is sufficiently interesting that one needs to stay across it."

Funds managed by JC Flowers own Chi-X Asia Pacific, which operates trading venues including in Australia and Japan.
Dr Morgan said the private equity firm was also on the look out for other acquisitions in the region, including in Australia.

"At JC Flowers we are very interested in Australia," he added, noting they had run a ruler over several local assets over the past two years.
Dr Morgan also plans to relocate back to Australia at the end of 2017 but no decisions have been made around whether JC Flowers will open an office here.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Digital Asset Holdings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deutsche Bank</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Morgan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JC Flowers</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUSTRAC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York Stock Exchange</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Tax Office</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chi-X</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chi-X Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Financial System Inquiry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vic Jokovic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Morgan</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Jokovic</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia Pacific</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westpac Banking Corp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Bank of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NASDAQ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treasurer Scott Morrison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TRaCRs</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chi-X Asia Pacific</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
