<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445303782458952</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/national/search-for-townsville-cbd-bomb-maker-after-homemade-devices-exploded/news-story/ca4d96a927a079a85184cbc9885f8549</url>
  <title>VIDEO: Townsville bomb caught on camera</title>
  <content>
UPDATE: A PERSON who placed a homemade bomb on Flinders Street is being hunted by police who warn there could be serious consequences for the offenders.
Police are scouring through CCTV footage from August 3 and have received dashcam footage of the explosion, which shows three people jumping back from a puff of smoke, which has been described by witnesses as "extremely loud."
Acting Senior Sergeant Damien Ahearn said someone could have been seriously hurt by flying shrapnel from the explosion.
"A device, which we believe was placed into a soft drink container, was set off in Flinders St," Sen-Sgt Ahearn said.
"The device that was placed on the traffic island has exploded and that's caught the attention of passers-by and they've contacted the police.
"That explosion has caused a lot of noise, there's potential for the shards of metal to have gone through the air, anyone in the general vicinity of that can at the wrong time would've been seriously hurt as a result of what's occurred."
Police are currently testing the remnants of the device to figure out what made the soft drink can explode.
"No cords, or wires were emitting from the can, ... even though inquiries are still being conducted, it's our opinion at the time, someone has placed some sort of chemical inside that has caused it to explode.
"We don't have any firm suspects at this time, we are monitoring some CCTV that has been recorded from the incident, and we're also asking people that may have been driving nearby or general vicinity to contact us with information."
Want breaking news delivered straight to your inbox?
EARLIER: BUSINESS owners and shoppers have been left shocked to learn a homemade bomb was set off in front of City Lane on Flinders Street.
Josh Koning from Sakana sushi bar told the Bulletin workers from his restaurant told him they heard an explosion on Thursday night, but had no idea it was an "improvised device".
"The two girls who were working heard a loud explosion, when the restaurant was fairly empty, I think there was one person left inside, they came out to have a bit of a look and see if they could see what it was," Mr Koning said.
"It's a bit concerning, they thought it might have been a street light exploding, or put it down to something else, that didn't see what it was at the time, but apparently it was a Red Bull can.
"I don't think there is anything to be concerned about, the first thing the police wanted to know was if we had sacked any staff recently or there might have been someone with a vendetta, but that's not the case.
"I would've just put it down to crazies pretty much."
David Williams said it was "ridiculous" to think someone would do this in Townsville.
"You don't want to see something like this happen here," Mr Williams said.
"Blowing up something on the main street, it can really get out of hand, it's not real good."

EARLIER: A SEARCH is underway for a person who allegedly blew up a homemade bomb in front of City Lane on Flinders Street.
Police are investigating the incident following reports of an "extremely loud explosion" on August 3 about 9.22pm near City Lane.
In a statement police said it will be alleged an unknown person has placed a tin can on the traffic island on Flinders St in front of City Lane, when a witness driving along the street heard the explosion.
"A witness has been driving along Flinders Street when he heard an extremely loud explosion and has seen a mist," the statement read.
The witness has observed a damaged tin can and smelt a gas in the air.
"No persons were injured," the statement read.
If you have any information or were in the area and can assist police, contact Crime Stoppers on 1800 333 000.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sen-Sgt Ahearn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flinders Street</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Koning</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Koning</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City Lane</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sakana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCTV</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flinders St</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Red Bull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senior Sergeant Damien Ahearn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crime Stoppers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 3</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
