<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444822746112441</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:28</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/afl/teams/gws/gws-giants-to-consider-challenging-shane-mumfords-onematch-ban/news-story/e652e7674cb75e8bb4473484b927868d</url>
  <title>Giants yet to rule out Mummy challenge</title>
  <content>
GWS is yet to rule out challenging Shane Mumford's one-match suspension at the AFL Tribunal, with the Giants desperate not to lose momentum on their charge to the finals.
In previous seasons the Giants have looked like shot ducks without Mumford's presence in the ruck and they can't afford to take their foot off the pedal in Friday night's blockbuster against the Western Bulldogs at Etihad Stadium.
Former greats Garry Lyon and Matthew Lloyd believe GWS kickstarted its premiership charge last week against Melbourne, but with Richmond and Geelong breathing down their neck, there is no room for another dip in form.
Mumford has been offered a one-week ban by the match review panel for engaging in rough conduct against his opposite number from the Demons, Max Gawn.
Many believe Mumford was lucky to only cop a week for making high contact with Gawn, but the Giants are adamant there is scope to earn their star leader a downgrade which would enable him to play against the Bulldogs.
GWS have until 11am this morning to make a decision and last night coach Leon Cameron and football manager Wayne Campbell were pouring over different video angles, weighing up whether it's worth risking a two-week ban for Mumford.
Last week's triumph over Melbourne came with big guns Jeremy Cameron, Toby Greene and Jon Patton all sidelined, but in the past Mumford has proved more irreplaceable than anyone.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Lloyd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toby Greene</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wayne Campbell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Demons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leon Cameron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garry Lyon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gawn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeremy Cameron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane Mumford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jon Patton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Max Gawn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GWS</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Tribunal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mumford</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
