<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445600135208656</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>15:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/news/world/michelle-carter-had-asked-for-conrad-roys-ashes-at-wake/news-story/9c471150b58d1a902ec1cb599a8f1ad6</url>
  <title>Family furious over Carter's ashes demand</title>
  <content>
A WOMAN who bullied her boyfriend into killing himself in a string of vile text messages also demanded to take home his ashes after the funeral.
Michelle Carter, 20, from Massachusetts, was jailed for two and a half years on Thursday after being convicted of involuntary manslaughter for her vile messages to then 18-year-old Conrad Roy III.
Roy was found dead from monoxide poisoning inside his truck in a car park in Fairhaven, Massachusetts in July 2014, reports The Sun.
The couple, who met in 2012, had only seen each other a handful of times despite living 34 miles apart - but investigators discovered hundreds of text messages from then 17-year-old Carter repeatedly urging her boyfriend to kill himself.
Speaking after Carter was found guilty, the victim's aunt, Kim Bozzi, told how immediately following her nephew's death, Carter had repeatedly contacted the family.
She told ABC News: "She wanted to go through his room and take some of his belongings."
Ms Bozzi also claimed Carter had even asked their family for some of Roy's ashes.
She added: "That's when things started to get a little weird. Yeah, you don't do that."
Ms Bozzi, who had hoped Carter would receive the maximum prison sentence of 20 years, said that Carter "has a damaged moral code".
She said: "I don't think she helped him kill himself. I think she forced him to kill himself.
"I think she was responsible for his death. I think if it wasn't for her, he'd still be here.
"She has to live as one of the most hated people in the country."
Massachusetts trial prosecutors alleged she wanted him to take his own life so she could win sympathy and attention that came with being the "grieving girlfriend".
The court was also played two video diaries found on Roy's computer in which he explained his inner turmoil. In one, he called himself a "minuscule, little particle on the face of this earth" and "no good trash."
Carter sent Roy, who reportedly battled depression, a list of various ways he could kill himself. She wrote: "Hang yourself, jump off a building, stab yourself idk there's a lot of ways."
In one text exchange, she chastised Roy for not going ahead with plans.
CARTER: "You're gonna have to prove me wrong because I just don't think you really want this. You just keeps pushing it off to another night and say you'll do it but you never do."
CARTER: "SEE THAT'S WHAT I MEAN. YOU KEEP PUSHING IT OFF! You just said you were gonna do it tonight and now you're saying eventually ..."
CARTER: "But I bet you're gonna be like 'Oh, it didn't work' ... I bet you're gonna say an excuse like that"
CARTER: "Do you have the generator?"
ROY: "not yet lol"
CARTER: "WELL WHEN ARE YOU GETTING IT"
When Roy texted Carter that "I keep regretting the past it's getting me upset," her response was: "Take your life?" and later added, "The time is right and you're ready, you just need to do it!"
In response to Roy expressing trepidation about killing himself, Carter sent him a series of texts appearing to encourage him.
"Don't be scared. You already made this decision and if you don't do it tonight you're gonna be thinking about it all the time and stuff all the rest of your life and be miserable," she wrote.
"You're finally going to be happy in heaven. No more pain. No more bad thought and worries. You'll be free.
"It's OK to be scared and it's normal. I mean, you're about to die.
"I would be concerned if you weren't scared, but I know how bad you want this and how bad you want to be happy. You have to face your fears for what you want."
Following Roy's death, Carter sent lots of texts messages to her friends expressing remorse.
"His death is my fault like honestly I could have stopped him," she wrote to one friend.
"I was on the phone with him and he got out of the [truck] because it was working and he got scared and I f***ing told him to get back in [redacted] because I knew he would do it all over again the next day and I couldn't have him live the way he was living anymore I couldn't do it I wouldn't let him."
Conrad left a heartbreaking suicide note thanking Carter for her "kindness".
The teen's handwritten suicide note read: "This life has been too challenging and troublesome to me but I'll forever be in your heart and we will meet up someway in Heaven."
He told Carter to "keep strong" and "hold her chin up", adding that he was "sorry about everything".
Carter had pleaded not guilty to the charges.
Her defence team argued that Conrad had planned his own suicide, and had gone so far as to secure the equipment that he used to take his own life.
They also said anti-depression medication that she was taking had affected her judgment.
This article
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairhaven</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SEE THAT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carters</name>
    <count>19</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KEEP PUSHING IT OFF</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roy</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Bozzi</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Conrad Roy III</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>13</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WELL WHEN ARE YOU GETTING IT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>S WHAT I MEAN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Conrad</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Massachusetts</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michelle Carter, 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kim Bozzi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
