<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445222178078461</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/queensland/sixyearold-chloe-knows-an-ekk-of-a-lot-about-cattle/news-story/5dd909b4d3dbbf145d0688411903ea23</url>
  <title>No bull, Chloe's an Ekka veteran</title>
  <content>
DON'T be fooled by her age, this aspiring young cattle handler is already an Ekka veteran.
Six-year-old Chloe Worgan has attended every show since she was a baby.
"I like coming to the show. I mostly like the rides but it's good helping with the cows too," she said.
Her family have travelled from Inverell in northern NSW to enter the annual cattle competitions.
Chloe isn't yet old enough to compete but she's completely at ease handling the newest member of the family, a six-week old Murray Grey calf.
"We haven't even decided what the name will be yet," Chloe said.
Mum Danelle said next year her daughter will be able to enter the junior parade division.
"Chloe and her sister also help to feed and look after the cattle when we're at home too, so it's not just about the glamour of coming to the show," she said.
The 2017 Ekka Beef Cattle competition has attracted 2889 entries - the most in the show's 140-year history.
This week thousands of cattle are descending on the RNA showgrounds in Brisbane with owners and handlers in tow to ensure each animal is groomed to perfection as they vie for one of the prestigious prizes.
Ekka-goers will be able to watch the stud beef judging finals take place in the main arena on Friday followed by an official awards ceremony the next day.

If you like animals, the Royal Queensland Show is the place for you.

EKKA: A place to meet animals
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ekka-goers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chloe</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Inverell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray Grey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Queensland Show</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ekka</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RNA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chloe Worgan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Danelle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ekka Beef Cattle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
