<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445170638469848</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/federal-politics/political-news/the-polite-rebellion-day-of-battle-arrives-for-liberal-mps-who-want-to-legalise-gay-marriage-in-australia-20170807-gxqsuk.html</url>
  <title>It's hard to imagine a more gentle group of guerrilla fighters than these five men</title>
  <content>
They've been called rebels and saboteurs, and accused of using "kamikaze tactics" to undermine their own party. One anonymous colleague even called them the "Balibo five" - a reference to five Australian journalists killed in East Timor in 1975.
Dean Smith, Trent Zimmerman, Tim Wilson, Trevor Evans and Warren Entsch are the five Liberal MPs who have been pushing for same-sex marriage to be legalised in Australia through a free vote in Parliament. On Monday their day of battle finally arrived.

Up Next

Who is Frank Madafferi?

09:40

More National News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Turnbull rallies the troops

PM Malcolm Turnbull has called a special Liberal party meeting to try and settle the divisive issue of same sex marriage.

Amid the hyped-up rhetoric, it's been easy to overlook what a polite and patient rebellion this has been. It would be hard to imagine a more gentle group of guerrilla fighters than these five men. Even Entsch - the ocker north Queensland crocodile catcher turned gay rights champion - has shown atypical restraint.
The group came together after the Senate rejected the plebiscite last year and have held regular telephone meetings over many months. They shared a common goal, but were not necessarily close friends. It took a long time to build up trust and there were tactical disagreements along the way. Each time a development leaked out to the media, the whole operation was at risk of blowing up. 

But they held together. 
As Monday afternoon's party room meeting approached, Smith, Zimmerman and Wilson gave interviews outlining their case. They didn't make threats or raise their voices. The strategy throughout has been to be disciplined, measured, practical. 

"I'm hoping for a process that can give some finality to this issue," Zimmerman told reporters outside Parliament House.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

'We've tried to get a plebiscite up but that simply hasn't happened so we need to look at another way for ensuring this issue doesn't dominate the government's agenda and that we can get on with allowing so many Australians who want to show their love for each other through marriage to do just that."Photo: Alex Ellinghausen
The raciest thing Smith said was to describe a plebiscite as a "D-grade response to a defining A-grade social issue".
For a group of men described by some colleagues as "self-interested", there's been remarkably little talk of themselves, their own relationships or their dreams to get married. (Smith, Zimmerman, Wilson and Evans are openly-gay.) Photo: Alex Ellinghausen
Instead, the rebels emphasised the religious protections in their bill and the long Liberal tradition of using conscience votes to resolve contentious social issues.
To those watching at home it probably all seemed rather arcane and uninspiring. For the rebels that was ok. Photo: Andrew Meares
Their interviews may have been beamed across the country, but persuading the public wasn't the point. This was all about narrowcasting to their own colleagues - many of whom are opposed to or ambivalent about same-sex marriage. 
By mid-afternoon, there was little evidence their carefully-crafted arguments had hit their target. Only two colleagues - Jason Wood and John Alexander - had publicly backed their call for a conscience vote. Many more were out supporting a plebiscite.
And that's how it played out in the party room. Just seven MPs supported a conscience vote compared to around 30 speaking in favour of a plebiscite - a colossal failure for the rebels. 
It was easy to forget that just weeks ago same-sex marriage was going nowhere. A resolution before the next election seemed a fantasy. Now there was hope of a resolution within months - either through a postal plebiscite or by the rebelscrossing the floor to force a parliamentary vote. 
As every guerilla fighter knows, sometimes you have to lose a battle to win the war. 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trent Zimmerman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>D-grade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smith</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wilson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Meares</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East Timor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frank Madafferi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Alexander</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Balibo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zimmerman</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Wood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Ellinghausen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parliament House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
