<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445385386839512</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/business/the-winnovation-awards-are-looking-for-businesswomen-with-an-innovative-edge/news-story/1f4c437ed6b69a19f11dc59f21d47cbb</url>
  <title>Innovative women wanted</title>
  <content>
SOUTH Australian businesswomen have until this Friday to nominate themself - or someone they know - for this year's Winnovation awards.
Since 2014, the awards have recognised and encouraged innovative women across a range of fields and interests.
Categories this year include science, technology, engineering, social impact, regional, and emerging innovator.
"We want anyone in SA who knows an trailblazing woman to nominate her for the Winnovation awards as soon as possible - please tell your colleagues, employers, family and friends," Women in Innovation vice president Tania Jolley said.
Nominees can work in any field, including government or self-employed.
"It might be someone you employ or have been inspired by, someone who has taken an innovative approach to a longstanding issue and overcome obstacles along the way," Ms Jolley said.
Among last year's winners were Inkling Women founder Gemma Munro, and Chloe Gardner from Kids Camera Action.
The Advertiser is media partner of the Winnovation awards, which forms part of the Open State festival that will be held in Adelaide from September 28 to October 8.
To apply, visit winnovation.com.au
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Jolley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Open State</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gemma Munro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chloe Gardner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kids Camera Action</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Winnovation</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tania Jolley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Inkling Women</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 28</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
