<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445428336513360</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Australian</source>
  <url>http://www.theaustralian.com.au/life/food-wine/pasta-perfect-joel-valvasori/news-story/d649f4e200feaed0c92534d2eea1396d</url>
  <title>Pasta perfect</title>
  <content>
Down a quiet pedestrian lane in genteel Subiaco, Joel Valvasori is making a noise. The chef - and now restaurateur - went out on a limb last year to open his first own place and he's not going to die wondering if Perth has an appetite for pasta. Not spaghetti marinara, or fettuccine with mushrooms or penne with creamy carbonara. No, we're talking tagliolini made with pig's blood and a "sauce" of chopped prawn meat, white vermouth and fennel seed.
And gargati in a sticky/sweet onion sauce with smoked pancetta and exceptional duck livers. We're talking challenging dishes that extend most of our preconceived ideas about what a pasta dish can be. They also challenge the chef, who makes everything himself. It makes Lulu La Delizia Australia's best pasta restaurant.
"I spent my formative years working through some of Melbourne's top restaurants," says Valvasori, "but a few years in, while I was working at a two-hat restaurant, I realised the style of cooking we were doing didn't gel with me. It was a very 'protein, garnish, jus' kind of situation.
"I wanted to cook with my heart, to cook on instinct. For me that meant cooking from my heritage." And that meant going "back to the source" travelling and -cooking in Friuli, in Italy's north, for a year.

The dish
Squid ink bigoli in salsa, smoked fish crumb, at Lulu La Delizia, -Subiaco.
The backstory
"I've always used tradition and technique as a basis for my creativity," says Valvasori, who built his reputation at Balzari in Melbourne and Lalla Rookh in Perth.
"For me, it is about reflecting on the past to have our food move forward with integrity and a sense of authenticity."
Bigoli is a hand-extruded pasta found in the northeast of Italy, between Venice and Istria in Croatia. A hand-wound brass press (torchio) is used to force the dough through a brass die, producing a long thick spaghettoni. Bigoli can be bought commercially made, but Lulu extrudes its own. Serving the bigoli in salsa is a style that's probably more synonymous with Venice, says Valvasori. "It is usually made with anchovies and onions. Very simple. Proper peasant food."
The produce
The two most important ingredients of the dish, says the chef, are the anchovies and the fish used for the smoked crumb.
"We always look for a high-quality anchovy to use in our cooking. We look for fillets that are pink in colour and have a sweetness to their flesh. Poor-quality anchovies on Australian pizzas are the reason why anchovies have such a bad reputation. It shouldn't be the case.
"For the smoked fish crumb we prefer to use wild Australian salmon when it's in season. Not only does the fish have great flavour for intensifying through dehydration, it also has a great balance of meatiness to fat that makes it a great fish to dry for floss or powders. People too often only look at the edibility of fish as a fillet. This is a great use for an under-utilised fish. Barramundi also works well."

The method
For the salsa, Valvasori likes to fry garlic and herbs first to really extract the natural oils and aromas before adding onions, which are sweated slowly with the addition of a little bit of butter to develop "some nice sweet golden characteristics".
"Only then do we add in the beautiful anchovies so as not to fry them heavily, which to my mind could change their flavour profile somewhat, and in a way could contribute to a loss of integrity if not careful.
"The pasta itself is quite a strong pasta dough made up of squid ink, pastured eggs and tipo 00 flour. We try to make a dough that is slightly elastic in feel, but not moist to touch. That means adjusting the balance of the egg whites to yolk ratio. It's an experience thing."
The twist
Valvasori says Lulu's version of the dish takes the sophistication up a few notches. "Firstly we increase the seafood richness and the visual intensity of the dish with the inclusion of squid ink in our dough. The sauce is kept relatively traditional to their Friulano style, using rosemary and sage, which is our typical herbal base for a lot of our dishes. That way it still tastes like home.
"The kicker on the dish is the hot-smoked fish powder that we sprinkle over the top to really increase the savoury deliciousness of the dish."
The price
"Our prices are generally a reflection not only of the produce we use, but hugely affected by the amount of labour involved in producing our pasta."
More: lululadelizia.com.au
DELICIOUS ALTERNATIVES
Like Perth's Lulu La Delizia, none of these restaurants should be called a "pasta restaurant". They do all Italian food very well. Nevertheless you'll find exceptional pasta at each one.
Tipo OO Melbourne
The hoo-ha right now is all about Tipo's new sibling, Osteria Ilaria, but don't forget this little gem two doors down the street. The name says it all, really: you don't make pasta with any other flour. Two things set Tipo apart: the quality of the pasta and the cooking skill, finesse and sense of adventure that goes into the sauces or accompaniments. Like saffron tagliolini with red chilli, lightly poached crabmeat and fish stock. Or casarecce with pork sausage and radicchio. Or squid ink tagliolini with squid and bottarga. Or ... stop it, I'm getting hungry.
tipo00.com.au
Lucio's Sydney
No, Lucio's is not an everyday proposition unless you're pretty well off, and let's face it, a lot of Lucio Galetto's regulars are. Good luck to 'em; this is a special place where standards are not compromised. As the menu says, and has done for more than 30 years: "All of Lucio's pastas are fresh & made daily in house." This is not a lie. Fazzoletti neri ai frutti di mare (black handkerchief pasta with cuttlefish, mussels, prawns and chilli) is something of a Lucio's signature and undoubtedly brilliant; last time we went there was fresh pici, a hand-rolled pasta made without eggs, with true Ligurian pesto made at the table. No wonder Matt Canavan has never been to Italy: he probably eats at Lucio's.
lucios.com.au
Osteria Oggi Adelaide
Never disappointing, always energetic and fizzing with social grace, Oggi is a one of several places we love for pasta in Adelaide, but since it's next door to Jonny Pisanelli's magnificent Italian pastries shop, this is what passes for an Italian-ish precinct in the city of churches. And the pasta? Well it's all made in house, and clever. Memories: tiny squid ink gnocchetti in a bisque-like crustacean sauce with flash-fried baby tentacles. And spaghetti - tight, tasty - plated as a new-wave carbonara with runny, cold-smoked egg yolk at the centre of the nest, lardons of speck and a dusting of pecorino adding to the DIY finishing at table. A glorious place to eat.
osteriaoggi.com.au
Bar Di Stasio Melbourne
In the dining room next door they serve - as they have for many years - a pasta called "bread maltagliati with calamari and radicchio". It is heaven. Sweet, bitter, slippery ... And you can have it in the Bar, if you wish. Often there will be their sublime version of angel hair pasta with crab, too. But if you want to keep it "humble", we like their take on cucina povera at a solid calacatta marble bar with an outrageously good martini: pillowy gnocchi alla Romana with a boar ragu; lasagne "Pasqualina" (named for the owner's late mum); and a classic spaghettone aglio olio. Your drinks bill will almost certainly exceed the food bill, but it is called a "bar", right?
distasio.com.au
Honourable mention
Yak Italian Kitchen Melbourne
A modest restaurant, Yak takes the "Italian Kitchen" bit of its name very seriously. The pasta is a highlight and if they have tortellini on a sweet/acidic balsamic reduction filled with bitter braised radicchio, smothered with an aerated chestnut and goat cheese sauce, order it.
yakitaliankitchen.com.au
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lalla Rookh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Subiaco</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italy</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Istria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Venice</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friuli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bigoli</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lulu La Delizia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oggi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Valvasori</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ligurian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lucio's Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonny Pisanelli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Osteria Ilaria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Canavan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Di Stasio Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Balzari</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friulano</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lulu La Delizia Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian-ish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lucio Galetto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lulu</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yak</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yak Italian Kitchen Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Osteria Oggi Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Romana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lucio</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian Kitchen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DIY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OO Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joel Valvasori</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fazzoletti</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth's Lulu La Delizia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Croatia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
