<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444784091405905</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/lifestyle/relationships/marriage/tori-johnsons-lindt-cafe-death-becomes-inspiration-for-marriage-equality-bill/news-story/0ed0fc88be566f1086c886bb4023c1f5</url>
  <title>Tori Johnson's Lindt Cafe death becomes inspiration for Marriage Equality bill</title>
  <content>
Liberal MPs won't rule out free vote motion
7:18

MPs calling for a free vote now on gay marriage are not ruling out supporting a motion to bring on the vote.

August 7th 2017
2 hours ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National/Politics/

Tori Johnson who was killed during the Lindt siege in 2014 Martin Place, Sydney. Four Corners. ABC

Victoria Craw & wiresAAP

Share

THE tragic death of Lindt Cafe manager Tori Johnson during the Sydney siege sparked the renewed push for marriage equality, Senator Dean Smith said.
Mr Smith drafted a private members' bill after being "particularly moved" by Mr Johnson's death when reading about it on a flight to Albany in Western Australia.
Mr Johnson was working in the Sydney cafe when lone gunman Man Haron Monis entered and held staff and customers hostage in a terrifying 17-hour ordeal. He sent terrified text messages to his loved ones before being forced to his knees and shot by Monis.
Mr Smith told the ABC while he didn't "know Tori's circumstance" the story galvanised his resolve.
"I came to the conclusion that had Tori and his partner been wanting to get married, or had been waiting to get married in the same way that so many gay and lesbian Australians are waiting to get married, and then his life was taken in such a tragic way, that moved me and it just reinforced my resolve and I came to the conclusion very quickly, with great clarity, that it is now time to legislate by Parliamentary vote same-sex marriage in Australia," he said.

Tori Johnson and Thomas Zinn.Source:Supplied
WHAT JUST HAPPENED?
On Monday, liberal backbenchers  for the second time. A plebiscite is a national vote to gain feedback on an idea. It differs to a referendum as it does not involve changing the constitution.

It's the second time the government will try to get a plebiscite through, after an initial attempt was voted down by Labor and crossbench senators in November.

If it fails, the Government wants to conduct a voluntary postal plebiscite through the Australian Electoral Commission, followed by a free vote in Parliament on the issue.

Supporters of same sex marriage carry banners and shout slogans as they march in Sydney on August 6, 2017. Picture: AFP/PHOTO / PETER PARKSSource:AFP
WHAT'S DIFFERENT THIS TIME?
Smith has described his current bill as "excellent" because it is the first of 15 incarnations to take into account same-sex marriage while supporting "community attitudes" that want religious freedom protected.
It means same-sex marriage will be legal, while still allowing religious ministers, civil celebrants and others to refuse to cater for same-sex couples on religious grounds.

It was backed by Smith's fellow representatives Trent Zimmerman, Tim Wilson, Trevor Evans and Warren Entsch who circulated it to members before Monday's meeting.
Labor leader Bill Shorten said the party had an "open mind" and the Government should get on with bigger issues like housing and electricity bills. However Marriage Equality campaigners said it was a "bloody stupid idea" that is "well beyond a joke".
More than 500 religious leaders from Anglican, Catholic, Uniting Church, Hindu, Buddhist, Jewish and Muslim faiths have signed a letter saying politicians should "show leadership" and legalise same-sex marriage.

Tiernan Brady, Alex Greenwich & Anna Brown of Australian Marriage Equality have said it is a "stupid" idea that could be subject to a legal challenge. Picture: Troy Snook/News Corp Australia.Source:News Corp Australia
WHAT HAPPENS NEXT?
The next step is for laws to allow a compulsory plebiscite go back to Parliament this week for a vote.
Key to its success will be the Nick Xenophon Team (NXT) changing its position and backing the Government. NXT opposes a plebiscite, but if the alternative is a voluntary postal vote it may put pressure on the party to back the compulsory plebiscite.
If it fails again, the Government will work on a voluntary postal vote.
WILL IT PASS?
If the issue does get to plebiscite stage and that is passed by a majority of Australians, a private members' bill to change the Marriage Act will be brought to Parliament and all MPs will have a free vote on it. The numbers are expected to be there for the law change to go through.
If the plebiscite vote is a majority "no", the Government won't support a marriage amendment bill to go forward, or another national vote.
If it goes to a postal vote, that would likely be held before the end of 2017 and, if passed, the Government would bring a private members' bill to Parliament to change marriage laws.

Lucy Wade and Kelly Delvin hope to win the right to marry at home. Picture: Brook Mitchell/Getty ImagesSource:Getty Images
LEGAL CHALLENGE ON THE CARDS
Same-sex marriage advocates claim they could legally challenge the Government against a postal plebiscite.
Australian Marriage Equality said it would be unconstitutional because of the money used to fund it. It claims the Government cannot spend money on a postal vote without passing laws to authorise taxpayer funds.
Modelling from  found a plebiscite could cost upwards of half a billion dollars, made up of $280 million of lost productivity, $158 million for the Australian Electoral Commission and the cost of impact on the community around $86 million.
Newspoll figures  show Australians support a popular vote on the issue by 46 per cent to 39 per cent with 15 per cent undecided.
An  found that 56 per cent of covers disagree that "marriage should only be between a man and a woman", up from 52 per cent in 2013.
Australia trails behind the UK, Canada, South Africa, France, New Zealand and the US who have already legislated in favour of same-sex marriage.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anna Brown of Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marriage Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moni</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>S DIFFERENT THIS TIME</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getty Images</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Electoral Commission</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Xenophon Team</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marriage Equality</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Johnson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NXT</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelly Delvin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trent Zimmerman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria Craw</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uniting Church</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tori</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Smith</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canada</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smith</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catholic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnson's Lindt Cafe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HAPPENS NEXT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anglican</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP PHOTO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jewish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lindt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brook Mitchell/Getty ImagesSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Dean Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Man Haron Monis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Marriage Equality</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newspolls</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muslim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CHALLENGE ON</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lucy Wade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Greenwich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin Place</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Africa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>wiresAAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buddhist</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Troy Snook/News Corp Australia.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tiernan Brady</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lindt Cafe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tori Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JUST HAPPENED</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National/Politics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PETER PARKSSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hindu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thomas Zinn.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
