<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445016019644181</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:13</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/technology/fuji-xerox-restructures-australia-and-new-zealand-leadership-after-accounting-scandal-20170806-gxqiel</url>
  <title>Fuji Xerox restructures Australia and New Zealand leadership after accounting scandal</title>
  <content>
The President of Japanese printing giant Fuji Xerox has pledged to rein in the independence of its rogue Australian and New Zealand subsidiaries, with new board appointments made to keep watch on the operations after an accounting scandal in which ANZ revenues were .
The joint venture formed in 1962 between Fujifilm and US-based Xerox Corporation, Fuji Xerox has previously been run with a "light touch" locally, according to Fujifilm president Shigetaka Komori, but the parent will now appoint its own chairmen and directors to the Australian and New Zealand subsidiaries for the first time.
In an exclusive interview with The Australian Financial Review, Fuji Xerox President and chairman Hiroshi Kurihara said Tokyo will be keeping a much closer eye on its Sydney and Wellington operations. Its accounting and audit operations will be merged with Fujifilm's by September, and legal departments will also be integrated.
The company, which recently suspended itself from government tenders in New Zealand, where the scandal had become politically divisive, is seeking to remedy a "sales at any cost" culture that Fujifilm's  found had developed in the two subsidiaries.

Former Fuji Xerox New Zealand Boss Neil Whittaker, who ran the NZ business from 2004 to April 2015, lasted only 15 months after taking over the Australian operations before resigning in 2016. A whistleblower had reported widespread booking of fictitious revenue, or booking of revenue inappropriately early, as well as exorbitant salaries and profligate expenses claims.

Four executives from Fuji Xerox's Tokyo c-suite have been sacked for turning a blind eye to the false profits, including former chairman Tadahito Yamamoto, and the 2016-17 annual report has been delayed while the faked numbers are rectified.
Mr Kurihara, who along with most remaining executives has had his pay docked 20 per cent for the next three months and will lose 30 per cent of his next bonus, told the Financial Review he was "deeply apologetic" for the scandal and was determined it would not happen again.
Fujifilm has not yet confirmed whether it will pursue Mr Whittaker or any other executive in the courts, he said.
Mr Kurihara said remuneration policy had been rewritten and that sales would now only form part of executive bonus calculations. Customer satisfaction and employee satisfaction now also being measured.

He declined to reveal the identity of the inaugural chairman of Fuji Xerox Australia, but said they would "build a bridge between Sydney and Tokyo".
Fuji Xerox New Zealand had, by mutual agreement with the government, barred itself from new tenders as the scandal broke earlier this year.
The smaller scale of the fraud at Fuji Xerox Australia - which was responsible for $148 million of the $451 million having to be re-accounted for - made a similar move unnecessary here, according to its Asia Pacific chief Isamu Sekine.
No Australian government official had requested Fuji Xerox stand down from tenders, added Mr Whittaker's successor as chief executive of Australia, Sunil Gupta.

Mr Gupta said he has created a "sales university" to re-train Fuji Xerox Australia staff in light of the scandal. The course includes a module on the Trade Practices Act.
Only 60 per cent of Fuji Xerox's Australian revenue now comes from sales of printers, Mr Gupta said. He said he preferred to call them "multi-function devices" and said they were now the hub of a "cloud-based solution allowing clients' staff to be more productive wherever they are".

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NZ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tadahito Yamamoto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fuji Xerox President</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fuji Xerox's Tokyo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fuji Xerox New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President of Japanese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tokyo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunil Gupta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Kurihara</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shigetaka Komori</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fuji Xerox</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Gupta</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia Pacific</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fuji Xerox Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fujifilm</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fuji Xerox New Zealand Boss Neil Whittaker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trade Practices Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US-based Xerox Corporation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fuji Xerox's Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Isamu Sekine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Whittaker</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANZ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wellington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hiroshi Kurihara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
