<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445033199513893</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:17</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/printer-ive-group-heads-into-escrow-expiry-with-disclosure-confusion-20170807-gxqmm2</url>
  <title>Printer IVE Group heads into escrow expiry with disclosure confusion</title>
  <content>
Investors are awaiting the release of acquisitive print and marketing company IVE Group's annual results after it took the unusual step of quietly disclosing $20 million of additional purchase payments.
Those payments, it appears, were not detailed  in December last year. The omission has come to light at a critical time for IVE, which has expanded rapidly in its short time as a listed entity from private equity-backed origins, just as the escrow periods imposed on its remaining pre-IPO shareholders expire.
IVE has become one of the two dominant players in the fiercely competitive retail catalogue production market, also known as the large format web offset sector. Its larger rival, , has been closing production sites following the merger of its operations with IPMG.
The ASX-listed IVE's full-year results are expected soon. The final escrow restrictions applying to early backers the Selig family and IVE's management shareholders ends the next day.

In December 2016, the business acquired the Sunshine-based catalogue producer The Franklin Printing Group, and AIW, for $116 million, partially funded by a $40 million capital raising. A further $6.5 million was allocated to cover general transaction costs, taking total acquisition spending to $122.5 million. Around half that, or $62.2 million, came from debt.

The Franklin purchase was agreed for cash of $95.7 million and IVE shares worth $4.3 million. The Springvale-based AIW was acquired for $16 million in shares.
The deals would be earnings per share accretive, shareholders were told, in the first full year after the businesses were combined, according to the retail entitlement offer booklet. The retail component of the raising, which raised $4.7 million at $2 a share, was underwritten by Bell Potter and Evans and Partners.
However, at IVE's first-half results released in February, where the company said its acquisitions were "very well received by all key stakeholders", something changed.
Capex, which was initially flagged at $18 million, became $30 million "as a result of securing the Coles contract", referring to Franklin winning the Coles catalogue printing services contract effective July 1, 2017.

The bigger surprise was Franklin suddenly had a further $14.9 million of deferred consideration allocated to it, taking its purchase price to $114.9 million instead of the $100 million initially flagged in cash and shares.
And AIW had a further $4.4 million allocated in deferred consideration, taking its price to $20 million instead of $16 million in shares.
One day later, two large shareholders reduced their stakes at $2.40 apiece: Wolseley Private Equity sold all of its remaining 14.2 per cent stake (Wolseley's escrow restrictions expired in August 2016) and the Selig family sold 4 million shares, equivalent to 3.4 per cent of the company.
The Seligs, including  is still one of IVE's largest investors via an entity called Caxton; roughly 6 million of their remaining 10 million shares (valued at $22 million or 8.4 per cent of the company) are escrowed.

When IVE was floated at $2 a share, raising $75.6 million, Wolseley Private Equity reduced its interest to 38 per cent from 69.5 per cent and the Selig family interest went to 15 per cent from 21.9 per cent. The stock last traded at $2.23.
In 2006, the Blue Star Print assets were acquired by CHAMP Private Equity, which in 2012 sold the Australian operations to Wolseley and the Seligs. IVE had no large format web offset business at the time it floated.
The Australian Financial Review sought comment from IVE on Monday.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caxton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CHAMP Private Equity</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ive</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IPO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX-listed IVE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IPMG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IVE Group</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wolseley</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coles</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Franklin Printing Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Franklin</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Selig</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wolseley Private Equity</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blue Star Print</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AIW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Springvale-based AIW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bell Potter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
