<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445080444154941</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:28</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/business/accounting/inside-story-of-the-alex-malleys-final-days-at-cpa-australia-20170727-gxjr73</url>
  <title>Inside story: How Malley's CPA sacking unfolded</title>
  <content>
The final capitulation of the CPA Australia board came without warning last Friday afternoon. After weeks of resistance and arguing that resignations of the entire board was unnecessary and counterproductive, the five remaining "old guard" directors of the nation's largest accounting body suddenly announced they would all do just that - by the year's end.
The current board members, having purged former Naked CEO Alex Malley from CPA's website and its ubiquitous promotional material, will now follow him out the door.
In typically defiant fashion, CPA chairman Jim Dickson dressed up last Friday's announcement of the early retirement of himself and two other board members as part of an "orderly succession of directors". But in truth it was an almost complete surrender. Just two days earlier, a CPA representative told an unimpressed Senate committee that "".
But questions remain about aspects of the announcement, particularly the plan by Dickson to sit on the committee that helps select the new board, and how any new board members can be selected at all while an internal inquiry is ongoing. That made Friday's announcement a classic of the current CPA board's oeuvre - solve one problem, create a few more.

The member rebellion that began in February as a  sent to about 1000 public practice members by accountant Brett Stevenson had finally succeeded in a clean-out of the top of the organisation six months later.

Stevenson's initial 1400-word email had highlighted his long-brewing concerns about the way CPA Australia was being run and what he considered excessive spending on a promotional strategy based primarily around Malley, the body's high-profile CEO. The Armidale-based accountant's curiosity and then frustration with CPA had been first triggered by reading The Australian Financial Review's Rear Window columns on CPA's spending habits. Those initial pieces by columnist Joe Aston asked questions of the , part of which was used to promote Malley's autobiography The Naked CEO and billboards spruiking the book in places as far away as New York's Times Square.
The accounting body reacted swiftly to Stevenson's email. It shut down the "Find a CPA" function on its website so the rebel member could no longer search for other members to contact (the function has since been restored). CPA felt it was the rantings of a few unhappy accountants, and best ignored. But the email publicly brought to light complaints that had until that point only been aired in private. And Stevenson just kept writing and writing.
An uninvited guest

The February email set in motion a chain of events that, by mid-June, had resulted in seven directors resigning from the CPA board - three in a single day - over the inability, or unwillingness, of the remaining board members to take action to deal with an unfolding governance crisis.

The turning point was an eight-day period in June when the CPA board, led by Dickson, went from effusively supporting Malley and announcing a so-called "independent review" led by former defence chief Angus Houston, to firing Malley with a $4.9 million payout.
That endgame began on Wednesday, June 21, when a surprise visitor turned up at the regular 4.30pm meeting of members of the CPA NSW Divisional Council.
The council is elected by NSW CPA members and represents the largest group of CPAs nationally, around 41,000 members. Every week, the council held its meeting in a third-floor conference room at CPA's Sydney office in Harrington Street, overlooking the back of the Four Seasons hotel.
The uninvited guest was director Graeme Wade, a Victorian 11-year CPA board veteran and fierce supporter of Malley and the CPA's direction. Wade had been in the Sydney office and wanted to discuss the future of the organisation with the councillors.

DEAN LEWINS

In the lead-up to the meeting, Wade and the remaining CPA board members had been tapping their networks to get a feel for the mood of members. Another board member, Sharon Portelli, also attended the meeting. The difference was that she had been invited.
The discussion between Wade and the councillors was described by all sides as robust.
Some councillors, unhappy at what they saw as Wade's intrusion into their regular meeting, say that Wade proceeded to lecture the group about the strength of the CPA designation and the achievements of Malley and the board. Wade told the group that the rebel members causing all the noise should be ignored. He also allegedly made the point that before he and Malley came on to the scene accounting had been a boring profession. Wade was certain that The Naked CEO strategy, centred on Malley, had made the profession exciting, especially with younger members.
A more generous version of events has it that Wade made a passionate defence of the CPA during which he described it as our "beautiful organisation" with a rich tradition and history. In that telling, he never referred to the profession as boring. He was instead highlighting that technological change meant the old way of working would no longer cut it.

Glen McCurtayne

Asked to comment on the NSW Divisional Council meeting, CPA cited the need for actions of the board to be confidential and declined to comment on this and other events described in this story.
The NSW letter

After Wade left, the council held their "in camera", or private, meeting. The next day, Thursday June 22, the NSW council sent the board a letter. It's contents were extraordinary. The councillors demanded nothing less than a complete renewal of the board and the CEO. They made it clear they had no confidence in the board and Malley.
It was a forceful move from a council that represents the largest group of CPAs. But it also illustrated that the group had no real power to force the board to take action. The board acknowledged the letter and promised a renewal, not a complete renewal. The long-term directors were planning to hold on as long as possible.

DEAN LEWINS

The board had formed the view, one it continued to hold until last Friday, that it was not in the interest of members to have a complete spill of the board. Their thinking was that too much corporate knowledge would be lost - and they were best placed to rebuild the organisation.
That defiant attitude highlighted what many long-term board members continued to believe: they and Malley had done nothing wrong. They felt that Malley had been doing an excellent job and, when pressed, pointed to the growth of the organisation under his leadership. In 2009, the year Malley was appointed CEO, CPA reported a membership of 129,000 and by 2016 the membership had grown to 160,000 with one-third working and living outside of Australia. In addition to going global, he had also moved the focus from accounting to leadership to encourage younger members to sign on.
The remaining board felt that the review they had announced was the proper way to deal with member complaints and that Malley was entitled to stay on.
But by this stage there were so many aspects of the way CPA was being run under Malley that irked members that it is hard to know where to start or finish.
Members were upset at Malley's $1.79 million pay packet and the level of pay given to senior executives and board members. They were furious at the vast sums spent marketing Malley's book The Naked CEO and his television show In Conversation with Alex Malley. They were dismayed that the body's financial advice arm was losing millions and had also led to a conflict of interest that meant public practice accountants would soon lose their legal shield against multimillion-dollar lawsuits.  Then there were the unproven allegations of staff bullying against Malley and transactions such as the CPA's $756,000 sponsorship of the National Basketball League while Wade was both a CPA director and chair of the NBL. (CPA has previously said the NBL sponsorship was done at arm's length). 
Most of all, they were especially upset at finding out much of this information in the media, mainly in regular front page Financial Review stories and Rear Window columns. Many members expressed sadness, and even embarrassment, at how their once-proud qualification was now viewed in the market.
Decision day

The NSW Divisional Council sent its letter on Thursday, June 22. CPA chairman Dickson had called fellow director Wade to attend a pre-meeting of the board that evening. Wade was given just 20 minutes' notice. The directors were already set to meet most of Friday - now they were going to make what would turn out to be a momentous decision.

Wade asked what he should tell his long-time friend and CPA CEO Alex Malley about the board meeting. Dickson said that Malley should be told nothing.
The next day, Friday, June 23, the remaining CPA board worked throughout the day and into the evening out of the 20th floor of CPA's Melbourne Southbank office. The boardroom, which overlooks the Yarra, features a long rectangular table that became strewn with paper. Directors and other staff were moving in and out of the main boardroom and various breakout rooms.
There were now six board members. The five "old guard" directors - Wade, Portelli, chairman Dickson, Richard Petty and Michele Dolin - and a newcomer, Tim Youngberry. Youngberry had been unilaterally appointed by the board after seven of their number had resigned.
Early in the day, the directors made the decision to fire Malley. It is still unclear why the board didn't just use the standard governance protocol of standing Malley aside on full pay until the inquiry, announced the previous week, ran its course.
To pay out or not to pay out

The board's view was that Malley had become such a focus of member anger that if he were to go, the anger might also dissipate. It would allow the remaining board to focus on rebuilding the organisation. Having decided that Malley had to go, the discussion then became focused on what was described as CPA's financial obligations to their leader in the event he was fired.
Some directors argued that the board had to give Malley a payout if he was fired. Others wondered aloud at the member reaction to firing Malley and giving him a big payout at the same time. The board called in external counsel for advice on the payment. But there are conflicting versions about what the advice received actually was.
Some time in the afternoon one of the options canvassed was that Wade, seen as deeply connected to Malley by many members, should also be asked to resign. It wasn't followed through. There were already rumblings from the rebel members that the appointment of the sixth director, Youngberry, might be invalid. The board needed six members to make decisions. Losing Wade would mean the board would lose the quorum required for it to act.

It remains unclear if the obligation to make the termination payment to Malley was contractual or not, and if it was contractual, when this stipulation had been inserted into the contract.
Either way Malley ended up with $4.9 million on termination, the equivalent of three years' worth of base pay. If the CPA was a public company, the golden handshake would breach Corporation Act changes which limit payouts to CEOs to one year's base pay.
Member email

Around 10pm on Friday, June 23, a message was sent to members with the subject line "Announcement in relation to the Chief Executive".
The email, from chairman Dickson, read in part: "At its meeting today, the Board decided to terminate Alex's contract in order to allow CPA Australia, CPA Australia staff and Alex to move forward. In the interests of full disclosure, CPA Australia has made a payment of $4.9 million in accordance with our obligations."
Dickson added: "On behalf of the Board, I wish to thank Alex for the significant contribution he has made over the past seven and a half years. He has guided CPA Australia through a period of sustained growth. He brought an ambitious vision for our profession and was dedicated to supporting students and young leaders. Alex's legacy is an organisation with a global footprint and an ambitious outlook. We know that he will be very much missed by his colleagues and friends at CPA Australia."
An apologetic CPA spokesman, Stuart Dignam, then emailed out the announcement separately to various journalists he had come to know over the past month.
His note read: "I am sorry for the lateness of this communication but the CPA Australia Board met today and proceedings have only just concluded. Please see attached a statement we are distributing this evening."

Fix one problem, create two

Malley's reign was over but the payout, and kind words for a sacked CEO, further enraged rebel members. Solve one problem, create a few more.
By Sunday, June 25, the feeling was the position of the rest of the board was now untenable. Stevenson, the original rebel CPA, summed up the thoughts of many: "This is an outrageous amount to pay. The board need to go, to have approved this, let alone allow CPA to fall into such a sorry state."
The Monday, June 26, edition of the Financial Review featured a shot of Malley, in a rugby top, cap and sunglasses above the bold headline "CPA unrest erupts after sacking".
Sir Angus resigned from the inquiry on that Monday, although this was not revealed to CPA members for another week. His resignation letter read: "I accepted chairmanship of the independent review of the CPA 10 days ago because I thought I could work with [former Commonwealth auditor-general] Ian McPhee to help the association and its members put their current problems behind them. The developments over the last week demonstrate that a deep, comprehensive and time-consuming independent review of CPA is required."
Senate hearing

Until Friday, the board had maintained its defiant stance since Malley was fired. The remaining directors vowed they would not leave early but would stay to help to rebuild their organisation.
They were seemingly unperturbed by an ongoing investigation by the Australian Securities and Investments Commission into potential breaches of director duties and the reconfigured internal inquiry, now led by McPhee and due to issue a preliminary report by mid-September.

What may have broken through the board's recalcitrance is the prospect they will now have to front up to a Senate committee to explain their actions.
The committee, which includes Senator Nick Xenophon and Labor Senator Sam Dastyari, had been holding public hearings in Sydney last Wednesday into a CPA-inspired change to the Corporations Act around storing and releasing email addresses.
The senators became increasingly incensed as CPA representatives tried to explain the board's decision to hold the CPA annual general meeting in Singapore in April and the board's resistance to sending out a message on behalf of 16 past leaders of the organisation calling for a spill.
Committee chair Liberal Senator Jane Hume expressed this bewilderment, inadvertently channelling frustrated CPA members everywhere, about the actions of the CPA board.
"My greatest frustration ... is that the reason why we are needing to have this discussion is the extraordinary behaviour of your organisation," she says during the questioning of CPA general manager of policy and spokesman Stuart Dignam and CPA senior legal counsel Kerrell Ma.
"[The] opacity and obfuscation is just mind-blowing. There are plenty of global organisations listed on the ASX and none of them have their AGM overseas. I cannot understand why on earth you would deny your members a say at the very forum that is created for that purpose."
Two days later, the CPA board announced they would all be leaving by the end of the year. But, rebel CPA Stevenson and frustrated members across the country hope, not before they first explain themselves to the senators in Canberra.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CPA Stevenson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday June 22</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CPA CEO Alex Malley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Investments Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Angus Houston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Naked CEO Alex Malley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CPAs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Financial Review</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sir Angus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Petty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review's Rear Window</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stuart Dignam</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Armidale-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CPA 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CPA's Melbourne Southbank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rear Window</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CPA Australia Board</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dickson</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian McPhee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wade</name>
    <count>16</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York's Times Square</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CPA NSW Divisional Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chief Executive</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SINGAPORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malley's CPA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graeme Wade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CPA Australia</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CPA's Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Nick Xenophon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corporations Act</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Four Seasons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kerrell Ma</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Youngberry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CPA-inspired</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Basketball League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Securities</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Senator Jane Hume</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brett Stevenson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Portelli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jim Dickson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CPA's $756,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Malley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McPhee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harrington Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Divisional Council</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 23</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 22</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 21</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEOs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malley</name>
    <count>29</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sharon Portelli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW CPA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michele Dolin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stevenson</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Aston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AGM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Youngberry</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Naked CEO</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malley's $1.79</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CPA</name>
    <count>37</count>
    <score>13</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labor's Senator Sam Dastyari</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Lewins</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glen McCurtayne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
