<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445342437165599</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:29</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/travel/travel-updates/incidents/horror-stories-from-the-high-seas/news-story/0bc740d53a67e478f6e45c4311b9b0a5</url>
  <title>Horror stories from the high seas</title>
  <content>
Cruise Ship tragedies: Murders, disappearances and more
1:08

Cruise Ship tragedies: Murders, disappearances and more

August 7th 2017
6 hours ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Travel - News.com.au/

Kristy and Kenneth Manzanares were said by friends and relatives to have had the 'perfect marriage'.

Share

MINUTES after Kenneth Manzanares allegedly bludgeoned his wife Kristy to death on an Alaskan family cruise last month, one of their children was heard to sob: "I knew my dad would do this".
Passenger Jens Larsen said the teenage girl had run for help after violence exploded inside her parents' cabin on the Emerald Princess on July 25.
"She was saying to my sister-in-law: 'I knew my dad would do this. I knew he would do this'," he  WMUR9 from the ship.
Mr Larsen account suggests the couple did not have the "perfect marriage" described by friends and relatives in the wake of the glamorous Utah real estate agent's untimely death.
The childhood sweethearts, both 39, had reportedly booked a week on the ship to celebrate their wedding anniversary with a large group that included three daughters aged from 13 to 22.
However, relations between the couple quickly deteriorated. On the second night, Kenneth became "belligerent" at dinner, with his behaviour escalating to the point that his wife asked him for a divorce.

Kristy Manzanares, 39, was allegedly murdered by husband Kenneth on a cruise to celebrate their wedding anniversary.Source:Facebook

Kenneth and Kristy Manzanares, both 39, were childhood sweethearts.Source:Facebook
Fellow passengers who responded to the screaming inside cabin D726 before the arrival of security and medical staff described the horrific crime scene in documents tendered to court.
One witness told of seeing Ms Mazanares lying on the floor covered in blood and her husband with blood on his hands and clothing.
When he asked him what happened, Manzanares replied, "She would not stop laughing at me."

A gruesome tug of war ensued when Manzanares allegedly dragged his wife's body towards the cabin balcony in an apparent bid to toss her overboard and the witness grabbed the victim's ankles and pulled her back inside the cabin.
Later, when Kenneth Manzanares was being processed during an FBI evidence search, "he spontaneously stated, 'My life is over,'" according to documents tendered to court.
to the affidavit said.
Manzanares was due to appear at a preliminary hearing on August 10 but that session has been postponed for at least two weeks.
Kristy Manzanares' death is the latest in a string of cruise ship tragedies.

Kristy Manzanares was on a cruise with her family when her husband allegedly 'snapped' and killed herSource:Facebook

Kristy Manzanares was described as the 'light of her daughters' lives'.Source:Facebook
Li Yinglei
Li Yinglei disappeared in February while on a Mediterranean cruise with husband Daniel Belling and their two young sons.
Authorities arrested Belling on suspicion of murder at Rome airport on February 17, a day after he disembarked the MSC Magnifica with the boys, aged four and six, without their mother.
The 46-year-old German born IT consultant was awaiting a flight to Dublin, where the family was based. He remains in custody and the children have been placed in Italian state care as authorities continue to search for Ms Li, 36.
In a macabre twist, the body of an Asian woman found stuffed in a suitcase floating in the sea in an Italian port several days later was ruled out as that of Ms Li, who remains missing.
Staff on the cruise ship reported Belling to police after they noticed his wife was not with her family as they left the ship and he had not reported her missing.
Defence lawyer Luigi Conti claims Belling had not reported his wife missing because she had a history of leaving family holidays early.
He said that on the night that the ship sailed from La Valletta in Malta to Katakolon in Greece, his wife had told him that she was tired of the cruise, that she was not enjoying it and that she wanted to get off the ship.

Daniel Belling is accused of murdering his wife Li Yinglei on an Italian cruise in February.Source:Supplied

In a bizarre twist authorities searching for Ms Li's body recovered the remains of another Asian woman stuffed in a suitcase. The cases are not related.Source:Supplied
When the ship stopped at Katakolon, she had chosen to remain on board while Belling took their children for a day of sightseeing, Mr Conti told the court.
He said when the trio returned to the ship that evening, Belling discovered that his wife had left, taking her own clothes and luggage with her.
Belling claimed that he had not immediately reported her as missing because in the past she had behaved similarly, walking off during a family holiday.
He claimed that he thought she had probably returned to Dublin.
Not only was he not worried by her departure but he had so accepted it that he told the ship's chambermaids to make up three beds rather than four because his wife had abandoned the cruise.
Mr Conti claims that at least one chambermaid has confirmed that the man did indeed issue that instruction to her.
He said Belling repeatedly tried to call his wife on her mobile the following day, only for it to ring out. In the meantime, no ship's official had asked about the disappearance of his wife since he himself had already explained it to the personnel, Mr Conti told the court.
Belling is scheduled to front court in Rome later this year. Meanwhile, Ms Li's body has yet to be found.

An FBI agent leads Robert McGill from the Carnival Elation in 2009. McGill was arrested after he told another couple on the cruise that he had just murdered his wife.Source:Supplied
Shirley McGill
Shirley McGill was found dead on a Carnival Elation cruise just a few days after celebrating her 55th birthday.
Her strangled and badly beaten body was found in a pool of blood in the bathroom of their cabin on July 14, 2009.
Her husband and childhood sweetheart Robert John McGill later told police he had killed her "with his bare hands".
McGill reportedly consumed a lot of alcohol before strangling and beating his wife. Afterwards, he changed his clothes and met up with another couple to smoke a cigar and drink some more. When the couple inquired about his wife, McGill said he had killed her, according to the San Diego Tribune.
The couple alerted the ship's security and McGill was arrested.
McGill was sentenced to life in prison in 2011.

George Smith and his wife Jennifer Hagel Smith on their wedding day. Mr Smith vanished during the couple's honeymoon cruise in 2005.Source:Facebook

George Smith was captured on CCTV in the ship's casino hours before he is believed to have been pushed or fallen overboard.Source:Facebook
George Smith
George Smith was just 26 when he vanished while on a honeymoon cruise on a Royal Caribbean ship called the Brilliance of the Seas with new wife Jennifer Hagel Smith in 2005.
The ship was just off the Turkish port of Kusadasi when George disappeared in the early hours of July 5 after a night of partying at the casino with Jennifer.
His 25-year-old bride was found passed out drunk in a corridor the following morning but there was no sign of Mr Smith.
Authorities later found a large blood stain beneath the couple's cabin balcony and concluded it was the spot Mr Smith had hit before going overboard. Witnesses told police they had seen four men along with Mr Smith's wife inside the cabin on the night he disappeared.

George Smith and his wife Jennifer Hagel Smith, who has since remarried.Source:Facebook
One witnesses claimed to have heard arguing and a loud thud between 4am and 5am.
Mr Smith's family have always believed he was murdered and that Jennifer and the men know more than they told investigators.
The FBI investigated for ten years before closing the case in January this year, telling the victim's family there was insufficient evidence to prove his death was a homicide and not an accident.
The decision has "outraged and disgusted" Mr Smith's relatives, who have vowed to continue their quest for justice.
His body has never been found.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cruise Ships</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-12</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>herSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>D726</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George Smith</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MSC Magnifica</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brilliance of the Seas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alaskan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jens Larsen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Smith</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Conti</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 14</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGill</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>La Valletta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shirley McGill</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert McGill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>San Diego Tribune</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emerald Princess</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greece</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Travel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert John McGill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dublin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turkish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Utah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katakolon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luigi Conti</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms. Li</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WMUR9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Mazanares</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kristy Manzanares</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCTV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rome</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carnival Elation</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kristy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kenneth</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Larsen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kusadasi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manzanares</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jennifer</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mediterranean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jennifer Hagel Smith</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Belling</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FBI</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Caribbean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kristy Manzanares, 39</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kenneth Manzanares</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Li Yinglei</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belling</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
