<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445037494481291</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:18</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/leadership/risk-culture-and-complexity-cba-board-must-investigate-lapse-in-controls-20170807-gxqpw1</url>
  <title>Risk, culture and complexity: CBA board must investigate lapse in controls </title>
  <content>
The Commonwealth Bank board will have to move swiftly to get the full facts of its systematic failure to report money laundering, and assess if non-compliance with regulation is a wider problem in the bank, said Ian Ramsay, Professor of corporate law at the University of Melbourne.
The Australian Transaction Reports and Analysis Centre has taken action against CBA in a Federal Court action which alleges the bank "exposed the Australian community to serious and ongoing crime".
Professor Ramsay said one of the most critical issues for the board, which has been chaired by Catherine Livingstone since January this year, is to ascertain whether the AUSTRAC action and the bank's acknowledgment that it failed to report 53,700 transactions points to a more deep-seated malaise at the bank.
"There is a big issue about the allegations that the bank was put on notice and didn't respond. When a prominent regulator puts the bank on notice of poor systems, that's a really big issue," he said.

The board, which is meeting for three days this week, must also decide . "Given the magnitude of this, the finalisation of the legal strategy would I think come to the board. As part of that, settlement issues loom large," he said. "You , where executives are dragged before talented QCs to show they didn't know what was going on."

Media strategy is also crucial, as it looked like the bank was taken unaware by the AUSTRAC action, based on an initial press release that stated the bank was reviewing the situation and more information would be forthcoming. "It is an issue of such magnitude that the board has to be satisfied that it is on the front foot with an effective media strategy."
Media strategy

There would be questions about whether the board was happy with the media strategy that unfolded in the first few days, he said. But perhaps the most important issue for the board is whether compliance is an issue more generally at the bank.
CBA has been hit with multiple scandals involving financial planning and insurance claims since Ian Narev was appointed as chief executive.

In June 2014, . In September 2014 CBA tried to fix it, but the process wasn't complete until November 30, 2015. I
AUSTRAC alleges that $8.91 billion was deposited in CBA's Intelligent Deposit Machines before CBA conducted any risk assessment for money laundering and financing terrorism. It also alleges that CBA repeatedly failed to report transactions to the agency as required by legislation, and that it "adopted a policy not to report" if similar transactions had been reported within three months.
. In September 2014 it tried to fix it, but the process wasn't complete until November 30, 2015.
Mr Narev told the AFR in an interview on Sunday that a . He did not address AUSTRAC's allegations of slow response, or the policy of non-compliance. CBA has yet to lodge its defence.

There was no mention of any AUSTRAC issues in CBA annual reports for 2015 or 2016. ASX corporate governance principles say the board is responsible for ensuring that there is an appropriate system of risk management in place.
Cultural insights

The board should appoint a senior person "specifically dedicated to sorting this out ... who reports directly to the risk committee," said governance expert Julie Garland McLellan.
Rebecca Davies, governance lecturer and non-executive director, said "it can be hard to get a handle on what is really going on inside mega companies", so "directors need to be confident they are being told the whole story, regardless of the implications for individuals".

"Directors should be getting information about complaints (particularly complaints that might indicate systemic problems), cultural insights from staff surveys, feedback from any whistleblower systems, and feedback from shareholders, customers, suppliers and the press. This can't be sugar coated and directors need to encourage truth telling.
"Any director would want to know about how they are seen by their regulators ... Management need to be very clear that the board requires to be told immediately about any significant issue raised by a regulator or enforcement agency. For me, hearing about something for the first time when a prosecution is launched or regulatory action is taken is not acceptable.
"Longer-term issues will be understanding how this situation occurred, how the board can be confident it would not happen again, and assessing the culture of compliance and communication within the bank."
She said "the cultural piece will be key and the AUSTRAC case can't be taken in isolation ...The common issues of dealing with problems, complaints and bad news seem to be systemic."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Ramsay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rebecca Davies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julie Garland McLellan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUSTRAC</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Narev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Narev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QCs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catherine Livingstone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 30, 2015</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Transaction Reports</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBA's Intelligent Deposit Machines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Analysis Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 2014 CBA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Ramsay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBA</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
