<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445011724676737</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/lifestyle/this-ceos-road-bike-may-have-cost-more-than-i-told-my-wife-20170731-gxmjf3</url>
  <title>This CEO's road bike 'may have cost a little more than I told my wife'</title>
  <content>
A crash just days before being interviewed for the top job at safety footwear manufacturer Steel Blue had an unexpected bonus for Garry Johnson. He answers our Time Out Q&A.
First memory of riding a bike
My first bike was a purple single-speed Malvern Star, which I got when I was eight years old. It was a pity I had to wait another year before I could reach the pedals.
How many bikes and how do you know when you have too many?

I have two: a Pinarello road bike and a Fuji track bike, but as we all know, you can never have too many bikes.

How much did they cost?
Track bikes are very basic machines, so it was a reasonable spend. As for the road bike, it may have cost a little more than I told my wife.
Dream bike and equipment
I have my eye on a Specialised S-works Roubaix for my next purchase, but I'm also thinking about going retro with a custom-built titanium frame.

Kind of riding
Mostly leisure cycling for fitness. I also enjoy doing charity rides like the  for Youth Focus. The ride provides a fantastic opportunity to meet some great people, get fit and help raise community awareness about youth suicide and depression.
Tips to become a better rider
When the alarm goes off, get out of bed and don't hit the snooze button. Ride in a group as it keeps you accountable and the team competitiveness will push you harder.

Kilometres a week
Depending on work commitments, it varies between 150 and 200 kilometres and I will do more if I'm training for a longer charity ride.
Hills or the flat
As I get older I seem to be enjoying the flat more than the big climbs, but you cannot beat the sense of achievement after conquering a big climb.

Love most about cycling
Getting out with good friends and seeing some amazing sunrises and, of course, solving the world's problems while enjoying a post-ride coffee.
Dislike about cycling
Cold and dark winter mornings make it a challenge to get out of bed, but with the right kit you can make it more comfortable. My biggest dislike is changing punctures on my rear wheel.

Most like to go on a long ride with
I missed an opportunity to ride with Cadel Evans some time back, so I would love the opportunity again. His achievements with the Tour de France are truly remarkable.
Will you ever be too old to ride?
Hopefully not - it will just become a case of adjusting the ride circuits to make sure the coffee stops are more frequent.
Favourite refuel station
, Perth, is long-favoured by our Steel Blue TBR [Tough as Boots Riding] team.
Favourite cycling gear
My waterproof winter gilet helps keep me warm and dry on winter mornings.

Favourite ride
Living in Perth, it is hard to go past a river loop. You can ride either a 50-kilometre or 70-kilometre circuit, with mostly river or coastal outlooks.
Dream bike holiday
In July, my TBR team went to Italy to ride the hills around Lake Como.
If you take long rides at the weekend, how does your partner feel about it?
I am fortunate to have a very supportive wife who can see the physical and mental health benefits, but sometimes isn't as impressed with my afternoon naps.
Crashes? Catastrophes?
The Sunday before my initial interview for the CEO role at Steel Blue, I stopped for a coffee fix and as I was rolling off decided to put on my gloves. I hit a small pothole, went over the top and smashed the humerus bone in my right shoulder, which was not so funny. The painkillers certainly helped me be very relaxed for the interview. The big lesson was to always keep one hand on the handlebar.

Ever felt scared on a bike?
I have had a few close calls with cars pulling out in front of me, so I have invested in quality lights and always assume that the driver has not seen me.
lifeandleisure@afr.com.au

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boots Riding</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake Como</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Specialised S-works Roubaix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malvern Star</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TBR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fuji</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garry Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cadel Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pinarello</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steel Blue TBR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steel Blue</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Time Out Q</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Youth Focus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
