<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445655969784384</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>15:42</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>http://www.businessinsider.com.au/aziz-ansari-money-and-work-2017-8</url>
  <title>Aziz Ansari says having more money than he 'ever imagined' has changed the way he looks at his work</title>
  <content>
Aziz Ansari doesn't have immediate plans for a third season of 'Master of None,' his hit Netflix show.

"I mean, those two seasons are really personal, and it's a lot of content, a lot of ideas," he told Mark Anthony Green in an . "Now I need a minute to refill my notebook. My life has not progressed enough for me to write season three yet."

Prodded by Green, Ansari went on to talk about how financial success has affected his willingness and ability to work. Here's Ansari:

"I was talking to a friend of mine the other day. We both have more money than we ever imagined. And I was like, Can you imagine if someone called us a few years ago and said, 'All right, you're going to have this much money when you're this age. What are you gonna do with it?' You would say all sorts of fantastical things, right? No one would say, Oh, I would figure out how to make more money and keep working all the time. Everyone just buys into this, like, Oh, I need to keep making stuff, I need to go make more money. I don't need to make more stuff. I've made a lot of stuff! I'm financially ok. I'm not gonna make stuff just for the sake of making stuff. I want to make stuff 'cause I'm inspired. Right now I don't really feel inspired."

Ansari has been travelling the world lately - Japan, France, Italy - taking time to recharge. He said removing himself from the urgency of his life in the US, full of meetings with other successful people who are moving on to the next thing, has lessened anxiety he might feel about taking a break, however temporary.

"I hope more people get very successful and then quit," Ansari told Green. "Shouldn't that be the game? That you make a bunch of money and just move to Italy and live a quiet life?" He continued: "No one who does what I do - or anywhere related in my world - is ever like, I'm done."

NOW WATCH: Ideas videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master of None</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ansari</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aziz Ansari</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Anthony Green</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
