<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445312372393804</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:22</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/news/helping-families-in-time-of-great-need/news-story/5e2a0efc8825ebad789ecf5d02314ba8</url>
  <title>Helping families in time of great need</title>
  <content>
EIGHTEEN cyclists have begun a gruelling journey over 660km from Airlie Beach to Cairns to help families in their time of greatest need.
The Ride for Sick Kids started yesterday and participants hope to raise more than $150,000 for Ronald McDonald House Charities in Queensland.
The group will arrive in Townsville about noon today and head to Ronald McDonald House in Douglas about 12.30pm.
The event has gained the support of NRL Cowboy Lachlan Coote who last week hosted a special warm-up and spin class at the -Ronald McDonald House to launch the event.
He also met with children and families staying at Ronald McDonald House.
Scott Campbell, McDonald's licensee and Ride for Sick Kids Queensland founder, is taking part in his tenth ride this year.
"I'm honoured to be out there again for such a great cause," he said.
"The challenges on the ride are at times difficult, however knowing how much of an impact the donations raised make on the lives of families makes each kilometre worth it."
Ronald McDonald Houses allow families to stay close to their children while they receive treatment in nearby hospitals.
Since January 1 last year Ronald McDonald Houses in Queensland provided over 22,158 nights of accommodation to families.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL Cowboy Lachlan Coote</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Airlie Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ronald McDonald House</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDonald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sick Kids Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Campbell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ronald McDonald House Charities</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Douglas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sick Kids</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
