<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445269422719840</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/north/whittlesea-multicar-homes-behind-growing-congestion/news-story/155b96f2a0de7705b287acf109cb0af2</url>
  <title>Four-car homes behind traffic chaos</title>
  <content>
AN INFLUX of traffic on Whittlesea roads is being driven by the rise of four-car homes.
New Census data shows that Whittlesea properties are among the state's leaders for multi-car dwellings, with 4569 households owning four or more vehicles, trailing only Casey, Yarra Ranges, Hume and Geelong.
Almost 40,000 households in the municipality have more than one car, while just 2910 homes are without any vehicles.
Unsurprisingly, houses in the outer suburbs of Melbourne typically contained more cars, due to the greater commute and a lack of access to public transport.
A rise in the number of cars has been labelled as one of the main reasons behind increased congestion.
Epping Rd and Plenty Rd - both listed as the worst roads in Whittlesea for congestion in last year's RACV Redspot Survey - are regularly reduced to a crawl during morning and afternoon peaks, while others such as Cooper St, Yan Yean Rd and Bridge Inn Rd are a continued source of frustration.
About 500,000 new vehicles have hit Victorian roads in the past five years, including 33,000 in Whittlesea.
A total of 139,509 vehicles were registered in the municipality in 2016.
Mernda driver Teresa de Jesus said busier roads meant members of her four-car family often struggled to park at their own home.
Ms de Jesus said her husband got up at 4.30am to catch a train, only to find parking already full at the station.
"I had to drive into the city the other day and I was just stuck in traffic," she said.
Wollert's Spilios Alexopoulos said the crush was heavily impacting life.
"It's a nightmare, it's getting worse in terms of numbers of cars and the roads don't change," Mr Alexopoulos said.
Whittlesea Mayor Ricky Kirkham said the outer suburbs were falling behind because of congestion.
"Outer Melbourne is at risk of becoming the Third World in a first-world country," he said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yan Yean Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bridge Inn Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Plenty Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whittlesea Mayor Ricky Kirkham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RACV Redspot Survey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Third World</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Epping Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hume</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Alexopoulos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Casey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Teresa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mernda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jesus</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yarra Ranges</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Census</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollert's Spilios Alexopoulos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3.3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whittlesea</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cooper St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
