<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445303782458941</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/sport/running-the-gauntlet/news-story/a481fe35420b7a1f342a89e9e49fb076</url>
  <title>Running the gauntlet</title>
  <content>
HAD someone said at the start of the season that Matt Scott would play just two games and Johnathan Thurston seven, most would have run a red pen through the Cowboys.
But despite the injury hardships which continue to hound them, especially up front, the Cowboys have shown plenty of grit to stay in the finals hunt.
Entering the final month of the season on the back of consecutive losses to top two teams, the injury-ravaged outfit can still make the top four, but can also miss the top eight altogether.
The Cowboys must win at least one more game to cement their place in September, and given they're in the midst of the toughest six week stretch in the NRL, they'll have to do it the hard way.
THE DRAW
Panthers (away), Sharks (home), Tigers (away), Broncos (home)
There's no gimmes here, even against the lowly Tigers who have proven a bogey team recently. The Tigers have won their past two clashes against the Cowboys, and a trip to Campbelltown is no picnic.
The Cowboys have won seven of their past eight games against Penrith, the latest a last gasp win in round 16 where a late Kyle Feldt try sealed a 14-12 win in Townsville. This weekend's trip to Penrith is a mini final. If the Panthers win they will draw level with the Cowboys on points, and they have an easier run home.
North Queensland has lost its last three games against Cronulla, including last year's preliminary final. The Sharks are starting to signs of looking old, especially in the forwards, but the Cowboys' front row has been weakened by several injuries.
Then there's the derby against the Broncos to finish, which always takes plenty of gas out of the tank of both teams.
They'll earn everything they get, but the Cowboys have shown they've got the effort and desire needed to overcome the challenge.
INJURIES
With Thurston and Scott already out, the last thing the Cowboys needed was injuries to more experienced players. However the footy gods have been ruthless with Gavin Cooper (calf) and Antonio Winterstein (hamstring) both going down early in last week's loss to Melbourne. Cooper suffered his injury in a non contact situation, similar to what Thurston did earlier this year, and if that's any guide he could be out for around a month. Cooper is the stand-in captain in the team and also the biggest talker. Someone will need to adopt that role with him out and Michael Morgan and Scott Bolton look the frontrunners to vie for the captaincy reins. Props Ben Spina (pectoral) and Patrick Kaufusi (ankle) are both out for the year, putting an enormous strain on Bolton to continue to step up.
WHICH TEAMS SHOULD COWBOYS FANS SUPPORT?
The Panthers, after this week of course. Following their clash with the Cowboys, Penrith faces the Raiders, Dragons and Sea Eagles. All of these sides are around North Queensland on the table and battling them for spots in the bottom half of the eight. It may mean Penrith overtakes North Queensland, but they can help to ensure the Cowboys make the top eight at minimum. The Warriors are also set to play Manly and Canberra at home, but must lift on current form. The Bulldogs meet Manly and the Dragons in round 24 and 26 respectively, but are also in a massive slump.
WHO NEEDS TO LEAD THE WAY?
Michael Morgan and Scott Bolton have lifted their games to another level for most of the season, and they will have to continue to do so. Morgan registered 11 tackle breaks against Melbourne last week and has made it a focus to take on the defensive line. His set plays with fullback Lachlan Coote are getting better each week as he adjusts to life without Thurston. Bolton has taken on a leadership role on and off the field with Scott out, and he has been in near career best form. For the Cowboys to go far into September, the fringe forwards who have been thrown into the deep end like Corey Jensen and Sam Hoare need to at least break even with their rivals when they come off the bench.
WHO NEEDS TO LIFT?
It's been a case of rocks or diamonds for the Cowboys' right edge. At times they've been suspect in defence but in other games, they've been rock solid and destroyed other teams in attack. Winger Kyle Feldt is a case in point. He didn't score a try in his first nine games, but then crossed seven times in the next six games. He has been wobbly under the high ball in some games too and that will be tested in the big matches. Representative centre Justin O'Neill has been solid enough recently, but has only found the try line once all year.
THE KEY GAMES
Round 23
Saturday: Panthers v Cowboys at Pepper Stadium, 7.30pm
Round 24
Saturday: North Queensland v Cronulla at 1300SMILES Stadium, 7.30pm
Sunday: Canberra v Penrith at GIO Stadium, 2pm
Round 25
Sunday: Penrith v St George Illawarra at Pepper Stadium, 4pm
Round 26:
Saturday: Manly v Penrith at Lottoland, 5.30pm
PREDICTED LADDER AT END OF REGULAR SEASON
We forecast the Cowboys will win two of their remaining four games and finish in seventh spot, booking an elimination final at Cronulla in week one of September.
1. Storm, 44 points (+216)
2. Broncos, 38 points (+170)
3. Roosters, 38 points (+85)
4. Sea Eagles, 36 points (+69)
5. Eels, 34 points (+36)
6. Sharks, 32 points (+71)
7. Cowboys, 32 points (+48)
8. Panthers, 30 points (+43)
.....................................
9. Raiders, 28 points (+81)
10. Dragons, 28 points (+69)
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>SMILES Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raiders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Storm, 44</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Queensland</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sea Eagles, 36</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Antonio Winterstein</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Spina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Bolton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eels, 34</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin O'Neill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morgan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broncos, 38</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KEY GAMES</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thurston</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnathan Thurston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Hoare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dragons</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Panther</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St George Illawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pepper Stadium</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TEAMS SHOULD COWBOYS FANS SUPPORT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broncos</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sharks, 32</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kyle Feldt</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sea Eagles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Penrith</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lottoland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raiders, 28</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Campbelltown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NEEDS TO LIFT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Scott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LADDER AT END OF REGULAR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GIO Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NEEDS TO LEAD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Kaufusi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roosters, 38</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Morgan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cooper</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dragons, 28</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gavin Cooper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cronulla</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corey Jensen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manly</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Panthers, 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lachlan Coote</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
