<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445527120763081</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>15:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/mitch-mcconnell-hillary-clinton-senate-health-care-bill-failure-2017-8</url>
  <title>Mitch McConnell: My first thought when the Republican healthcare bill died was, 'Feel better, Hillary Clinton could be president'</title>
  <content>
Senate Majority Leader Mitch McConnell said he thought of one person when the long-held Republican promise to repeal and replace Obamacare went up in flames: Hillary Clinton.

The  reported McConnell told attendees of Fancy Farm - an annual Kentucky event - that he took solace in the fact that Clinton wasn't president following the stunning defeat of the Senate plan to repeal Obamacare.

"I choose not to dwell on situations where we come up a little bit short," McConnell said, according to WFPL.

"Even on the night when we came up one vote short of our dream to repeal and replace Obamacare, here's the first thing I thought about: Feel better, Hillary Clinton could be president."

Despite controlling the House, Senate, and White House, the GOP failed to deliver on the "dream" after months of debate on a variety of plans that formed serious divides within the party.

The final blow came from Republicans in the Senate, who came up short on various healthcare proposals. Following the defeat of a full-blown repeal-and-replace plan and a wholesale repeal-only bill, three GOP senators - Susan Collins, Lisa Murkowski, and,  - all voted against the so-called "skinny repeal" plan that would have eliminated certain aspects of Obamacare.

The failure appears to be the death blow for the GOP's aspirations of passing a repeal-and-replace bill. Most senators have moved on discussing possible bipartisan fixes for Obamacare or shifted to other issues, like tax reform, the budget, and the debt ceiling.

Clinton had  during her tenure as first lady, when she took the lead on reform efforts but saw her proposal was defeated by Republicans in Congress.

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lisa Murkowski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WFPL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Susan Collins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hillary Clinton</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McConnell</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kentucky</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clinton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Republicans</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch McConnell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate Majority Leader Mitch McConnell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GOP</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Obamacare</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FANCY FARM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
