<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445522825795681</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>15:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/game-of-thrones-fans-ask-why-podrick-is-so-bad-at-fighting-2017-8</url>
  <title>'Game of Thrones' fans can't understand why Podrick is still so bad at fighting</title>
  <content>
Warning: Minor Spoilers if you have not seen "Game of Thrones" season seven, episode four.
In this week's episode of "Game of Thrones," Brienne and Podrick have a bit of sparring time with swords in Winterfell - and it turns out Pod is still truly terrible.

Fans noticed that poor Podrick hasn't seemed to pick up anything after all of his time spent training with Brienne, and are roasting him for it on Twitter.

It's not that Podrick needs to beat Brienne. She's an amazing warrior, and will likely be forever out of his reach. But he could at least learn a bit about form, instead of lunging all over the place.

Podrick and Brienne have been travelling together since season four, and within that time Podrick's fighting abilities haven't made much of an improvement. Time to step it up, Pod.

Here are some of the best tweets about Podrick's shortcomings:

I don't think we talk enough about how bad at fighting Pod is. Dude gets trained every single day by Brienne and falls down in seconds.
- Brendan Darr-A-Lago (@BrendanDarr)

Yo Pod straight up has just not gotten any better at fighting. It's a bonafide miracle that he's lasted seven seasons
- Kid Cruddy (Malcolm) (@Marvelous_Mal)

Has Pod's fighting progressed since Blackwater? Or in general? Love the guy, but you'd think he's be better at sparring by now.
- Matt Armstrong (@MArmstrongest)

I'm concerned with Pod's lack of improvement in sword fighting over the past two seasons.
- Ed Fujawa (@edfujawa)

If Pod hasn't learned how to use a sword by now, I don't think he'll ever learn
- Joe ???? (@Ravenclaw1991)

How does Pod never get any better? Like even a little?
- adam. (@AdamCGoering)

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ravenclaw1991</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AdamCGoering</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Winterfell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yo Pod</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blackwater</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MArmstrongest</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marvelous_Mal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Podrick</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minor Spoilers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brendan Darr-A-Lago</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brienne</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ed Fujawa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BrendanDarr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Armstrong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
