<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444741141731933</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/news/national/defiant-lauren-huxley-tells-monster-he-wont-win-as-robert-farmer-launches-appeal-over-attack/news-story/ba8f6355ec9597a63905239a99025e16</url>
  <title>Lauren Huxley declares</title>
  <content>
Man jailed for farmer attack prepares appeal

EXCLUSIVE

A defiant Lauren Huxley declared the "monster" who tried to destroy her life will never win as messages of support from across the nation flooded the family's social media account amid reports her attacker was trying to launch an extraordinary appeal.

Ms Huxley was 18 in 2005 when 39-year-old career criminal Robert Farmer entered her home, assaulted and bashed her repeatedly with fibro cutters before dousing her in petrol and setting the house alight.

She spent 23 days on life support and has been left permanently partially brain damaged.

Farmer was sentenced to more than 24 years jail.

But as revealed exclusively by News Corp Australia yesterday, Farmer has been using Queensland's Griffith University's Innocence Project team hoping that advances in DNA technology can show he was not responsible.

He was convicted on the basis that his DNA was found in Ms Huxley's room and on the fuel can: a court heard it was a one billion to one DNA match.

Ms Huxley did not want to comment on Farmer's push now for an extraordinary appeal and give him any idea she was thinking about it.

"This monster tried to destroy my life, let me tell you he never will," she said yesterday.

"I choose to only move forward and will never go back to the past."

Ms Huxley's sister Simone Gibson who with their parents were by her side through the whole court case and her rehabilitation, said yesterday it was a disgrace he could even contemplate such a move.

"I'm so protective of my family and particularly my sister and we've been through hell and back, particularly Lauren and I just think how this absolute mongrel thinks he can rehash this again, haven't we been through enough?" Mrs Gibson said.

"We don't need to go through this again ... it's just rehashing bad, hurtful things and its stressful for us as a family.

"Lauren doesn't really have anything to do with it, she doesn't think about it but none us need to go through this again. He's convinced himself he didn't do it, he's delusional."

The story of Lauren Huxley

She said her local MP had already written to the Attorney-General Mark Speakman to urge him to ensure frivolous appeals cannot be launched and on Facebook she had received immense support declaring "all of Australia" would ensure his case was not heard.

"He (Farmer) was on bail when he attacked my sister and so many others out there, something has to be done before anyone else gets hurt, no one should experience what Lauren and my family did," she said.

The DPP is yet to receive any notification of anyone seeking leave to appeal the conviction.

As revealed in an extraordinary series of letters written last year from his cell in Wellington Correctional Centre near Dubbo to a pen pal, the now 48-year-old Farmer detailed how he and his family were preparing to mount an appeal.

"I cannot wait for my day in court," he wrote as he detailed how he was working with the Innocence Project looking to build a case.

The pro bono group pulls together students from its Gold Coast law school campus, lawyers and academics to probe DNA-based cases once all legal avenues of appeal are exhausted.

"I'm OK just a little impatient but that is only normal under the current situation, proceedings take time so I'm just holding on for the ride?" Farmer wrote in September last year of his case.

He was sure of early release.

"So hopefully soon there will be a bit of normality in our lives and my life can finally take some positive, constructive direction," he wrote of his anticipated judicial success.

His then lawyer Ben Archbold yesterday could not be reached for comment.

Farmer's notice of intention to appeal expired on 29 May 2009 and an application in May 2009 for a further extension was rejected by the courts.

The Innocence Project director Lynne Weathered declined to comment on Farmer.

"We have reviewed hundreds of applications in the past 15 years and in accordance with project policy, treat all our cases with strict confidence and therefore make no comment in regard to any particular case," she said.

The project is operated from university funds and probono.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lauren Huxley</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Gibson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Huxley</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lauren</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dubbo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Innocence Project</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simone Gibson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Farmer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Attorney-General Mark Speakman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Archbold</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 2009</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wellington Correctional Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DPP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DNA</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DNA-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland's Griffith University Innocence Project</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lynne Weathered</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
