<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445643084882239</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>15:39</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/lifestyle/relationships/marriage/russian-billionaire-roman-abramovich-splits-from-third-wife-dasha-zhukova/news-story/bc6ccf10ee47f5c9047e28de5b0e4e1e</url>
  <title>Russian billionaire Roman Abramovich splits from third wife Dasha Zhukova</title>
  <content>
Dasha Zhukova has announced an amicable split with her husband, Roman Abramovich. Picture: AP Photo/Pavel Golovkin, FILE.

Share

A DIVORCE between a Russian billionaire and darling of the art world was never going to involve small change.
But Chelsea football club owner Roman Abramovich and his wife, gallerist and fashion editor Dasha Zhukova, are set to raise eyebrows with a settlement that could involve billions after announcing their split on Monday.
Abramovich and Zhukova said they had separated after a decade together in a joint statement.
"After 10 years together, the two of us have made the difficult decision to separate, but we remain close friends, parents, and partners in the projects we developed together," they said.
"We are committed to jointly raising our two children. We will also continue to work together as co-founders of the Garage Museum of Contemporary Art in Moscow and the New Holland Island cultural centre in Saint Petersburg."

Roman Abramovich will split with his third wife Dasha Zhukova in an amicable divorce.Source:Supplied

Chelsea Soccer Club owner Roman Abramovich thinks nothing of racking up a $47,000 restaurant billSource:Supplied

Russian billionaire oligarch Roman Abramovich's super yacht Eclipse.Source:News Limited
Abramovich is estimated to be worth $11.5 billion and is famous for his high-profile assets including Chelsea Football Club and a string of luxury properties and yachts around the world.
He's reportedly dropped more than $1.5 billion on "toys and homes" including ones in Colorado ski village, a jet, and celebrity laden parties where Beyonce and Gwen Stefani would perform.
Zhukova, 36, is no stranger to the high life herself. The daughter of a Russian oligarch Alexander Zhukov, who has made a small fortune in oil, metals and banking, she has been lauded by the New York fashion and arts scene for her daring art projects.
She previously ran her own label and edited magazine POP before launching her own project with a picture of a

Dasha Zhukova, the founder of the Garage Museum of Contemporary Art, is the daughter of an oligarch herself. Picture: AP Photo/Pavel Golovkin, FILE.Source:AP

Sad face. Chelsea's Russian owner Roman Abramovich is getting divorced for the third time. Picture: GLYN KIRK/AFP/Getty Images.Source:Supplied
The split could be costly enterprise for Abramovich as Zhukova is his third wife. He previously divorced Irina Malandina in 2007 after 16 year marriage and five children together.
The settlement was reported to include $1.65 in cash and four homes in what was described at the time as the "world's costliest divorce".
The "quickie" agreement was never made public due to Russia's secretive court system but it's to have been sparked after Irina saw pictures of Abramovic with Zhukova who was 24 at the time. Abramovich's first marriage was brief, from 1987 to 1991 with Olga Lysova.
Abramovich and Zhukova married in secret nine years ago and have two children together.

Roman Abramovich with second wife Irina Malandina.Source:AP
Abramovich's biographer Chris Hutchins said at the time Russian President Putin - who is said to be a close friend of Abramovich - told him to "get his act cleaned up".
"Putin is a real family man and did not approve of Roman's relationship with Daria or the publicity it has generated," .
"He sees Abramovich as something of an ambassador for Russia and made it clear Abramovich should settle his personal affairs.
"Abramovich tends to do what Putin tells him, in business and in his personal life, and Putin's intervention would certainly have influenced his decision to grant his wife an uncontested divorce."
The news comes after the whopping $9 billion divorce battle between  - and James Stunt.
The ugly parting between the pair played out in court with claims of drug abuse, foul language and having to "slum it" in a $42 million townhouse were made public.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moscow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FILE.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dasha Zhukova</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olga Lysova</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abramovic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Irina Malandina.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chelsea's Russian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colorado</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chelsea Soccer Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chelsea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Romans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GLYN KIRK/AFP/Getty Images.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eclipse.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Irina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abramovich</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Hutchins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roman Abramovich</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garage Museum of Contemporary</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Putin</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian President Putin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zhukova, 36</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zhukova</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Limited</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>billSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gwen Stefani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beyonce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Irina Malandina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP Photo/Pavel Golovkin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chelsea Football Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Holland Island</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexander Zhukov</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Stunt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saint Petersburg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
