<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445256537817621</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/opinion/columnists/why-workplace-reform-will-remain-in-the-deep-freeze-20170807-gxqzlw</url>
  <title>Why workplace reform will remain in the deep freeze</title>
  <content>
Martin Ferguson insists it's time to take workplace relations reform out of the deep freezer. He's likely to spend a long while waiting for any thaw.
Modern Labor certainly doesn't want the sort of reform advocated by Ferguson, a former ACTU president and federal Labor minister. Quite the reverse.
Opposition spokesman Brendan O'Connor is promising increased regulation of labour-hire companies and a focus on "sham" contracting.
And, of course, restoring full Sunday penalty rates after the Fair Work Commission, following a protracted investigation, ruled some rates in the retail and fast-food sectors should be reduced.

It's true the Turnbull government has restored the Australian Building and Construction Commission to try to remove some of the corruption, inefficiency and unnecessary costs in the construction industry.

This should belatedly improve conduct in that sector, particularly given the additional need for companies to comply with the code in order to win federal government building contracts from next month.
Beyond that, however, the Turnbull government is not too interested in pushing broader industrial relations reform.
That's not only because of the hostile numbers in the Senate - or even the lingering Coalition fear about Labor's ability to continue to exploit the unpopularity of the Howard government's Work Choices policy.
The new political reality is that it is now more likely to be business leaders rather union leaders who are regularly tried in the court of public opinion.

Berating big business

So even a Coalition government spends more time berating big business, especially the banks, for bad behaviour and not responding quickly enough to community concerns. (More privately, complaints include the Coalition's own concerns about not getting enough money and support from the business community.)
How sentiment has changed. The furore over the repeated failures of the  - and questions about the future of its well-paid chief executive Ian Narev - reflect that dramatic shift.
Anna Bligh from the Australian Bankers' Association candidly concedes the CBA case puts a further dent in the big banks' already tarnished image.

But the issue is much bigger even than this spectacular lapse and public relations disaster - yet another one - damaging Australia's biggest bank.
It's about how a union movement that now represents less than 10 per cent of private sector workers remains such a powerful player in most Australian workplaces as well as the Labor Party and key sectors of the Australian economy.
It's about how apprehensive ordinary people are about the loss of jobs, pay and conditions in a period of extended low wages growth.
It's about how employees are resentful about executive salaries and accountability when they seem blocked from the sort of financial prospects they previously took almost for granted.

That also helps explain why ministers have also been almost mute on expressing support for the commission ruling in favour of a cut in certain Sunday penalty rates, for example.
So instead of unions being seen as a hindrance to necessary flexibility and productivity improvement, they are seen by many non-union members as providing a form of community protection in tough times.
The relative union strength in trusted professions like nursing, teaching and policing add to that appeal.
Partly this is also because the era when strikes in the transport sector or power industry directly affected many people's daily lives has largely vanished. Who remembers the trauma of beer strikes any more?

In contrast, industrial thuggery on building sites by the Construction, Mining, Forestry and Energy Union or at ports by the Maritime Union are rarely visible to those outside the industry. The true costs to the economy and to projects are effectively hidden in inflated budgets and delays.
So even the prospect of those two unions merging into an even more powerful blockade has yet to stir much public alarm.
But the resource industries are still trying to remind politicians and the community that there is still a compelling case for targeted industrial relations reform as a way of lifting productivity in a sector crucial to the economy.
While the resources construction boom may have largely ended, the industry is arguing improved productivity remains vital to competitiveness and any prospect of attracting new investment in what should be Australia's area of comparative advantage.
National productivity agenda

Ferguson has become persona non grata with the union movement and Labor but has taken on several resources related roles, including as strategic adviser to the Minerals Council of Australia.
He is speaking at The Sydney Institute on Tuesday evening to coincide with the  and to argue this must again be placed at the centre of the national productivity agenda.
The paper lists five priority areas. These include limiting unions' ability to take protected industrial action while restricting the range of issues covered by enterprise agreements.

Ferguson says the Fair Work Act has now extended collective bargaining well beyond wages and conditions into areas of everyday management and the ability to respond to changing market conditions.
Other urgent reforms advocated involve "more balanced" right of entry laws for union representatives to curb operational disruption; liberalising greenfield agreements to help get new investment projects off the ground; letting high-income employees choose between enterprise agreements and individual agreements in an industry where the average income is $140,000 a year; and tightening "adverse action" provisions meant to protect employees' rights in the workplace but often used to obstruct business decision making.
Such concerns might sound almost old-fashioned given how much work, technology and global competition have changed.
That they are still considered so significant to Australia's mighty mining industry shows how much the industrial relations "reform" agenda has gone into reverse over the past decade.
Political interest? Close to zero.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Forestry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACTU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anna Bligh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minerals Council of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Institute</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Narev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin Ferguson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Energy Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ferguson</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Construction Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Bankers' Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fair Work Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fair Work Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Howard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maritime Unions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Building</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brendan O'Connor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Work Choices</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
