<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444955890100825</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/114649/timber-hut-trappings-an-irresistible-lure/?cs=4173</url>
  <title>Timber hut trappings an irresistible lure</title>
  <content>
Timber hut trappings an irresistible lure

The farmhouse where Naden was captured.

A pile of food outside the house

Inside the farmhouse, a pile of potatoes on the floor.

exit

IN the end it was a desire for shelter and warmth that was Malcolm Naden's undoing.
The stark timber hut where Naden was captured contains only the barest of essentials, but Naden would have considered it luxury as darkness descended on Wednesday evening.
A freshly disturbed mud patch at the door, a pile of rotting meat and eggs dumped in the grass and a bag of potatoes left on the floor just inside the cabin were the only clues yesterday to dramatic events that unfolded there hours earlier.
The hut's owner, Ken Rumbel of Dungog, said police notified him yesterday morning they had arrested Naden at his property.
Mr Rumbel's property includes a farm equipment storage shed but he mainly resides in the hut when he visits.
''I was there [Wednesday] morning. They had told me they had put bugs on the fridge and a haversack, and asked me to tell them when I was going up there,'' he said.
It is thought police had put similar bugs in other properties Naden had previously targeted.
Mr Rumbel said he was surprised Naden had returned to the residence after stealing a semi-automatic firearm from the hut recently.
''He liked his tucker, but he didn't like baked beans. He opened eight tins of them and just left them there,'' he said.
It is easy to understand why Naden targeted the remote hut.
Nestled on a  hillside overlooking a stream, the dwelling is invisible from nearby Moppy Road. Locals said it was not unusual for more than a week to go by without anyone going near it.
What Naden wasn't counting on was the electronic sensors that had been installed since his last visit, which alerted his captors.
''I think he was running out of options in the end,'' Peter Bignell, who lives on an adjoining property, said yesterday. ''I'm surprised he was hanging around here actually. I thought he would have been around one of the less-populated areas.''
As much as they were relieved he was behind bars, several residents near where Naden had been hiding out acknowledged his supreme bush and survival skills.
''He must have been pretty tough,'' Rawdon Vale resident  Dave Bignell said.  ''I'd say his tucker would have been getting thin because the goannas have gone into hibernation now.''
Naden's arrest also meant Mr Bignell's children could once again go swimming in the nearby creek.
''He was probably up there spying on us,'' Mr Bignell said.
For another neighbour, Kylie Hall, life would be more relaxed with Naden behind bars.
''People are out working all day.  It was always a worry that someone was going to run into him,'' she said.
''I was here by myself for a week recently. It felt a little bit funny, but  I had the dogs so it was OK.''
After years on the run, news of Naden's capture filled Gloucester's main street yesterday.
''It's the talk of the town all right. Everyone is happy that they have finally got him,'' shopkeeper Jill Laurie said. ''If he was still out there during Easter, a lot of people who come up here to go camping would have stayed away.''

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Bignell</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rawdon Vale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moppy Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Bignell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Naden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ken Rumbel of Dungog</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Naden</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Easter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gloucester</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Rumbel</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dave Bignell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jill Laurie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kylie Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
