<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445256537817633</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4838190/keyless-entry-just-wave-your-smartphone/?cs=12&utm_source=latestnews&utm_medium=cpc&utm_campaign=Latest%20news%20traffic</url>
  <title>Keyless entry, just wave your smartphone</title>
  <content>
NEW TECHNOLOGY: Crowne Plaza Hunter Valley general manager Lachlan Walker demonstrates the hotel's keyless entry via smartphone. Picture: Krystal Sellars

Guests at Crowne Plaza Hunter Valley's villas no longer have to worry about losing their room key.
The Lovedale hotel has introduced a ground-breaking guest mobile platform that enables guests to access their rooms from the convenience of their smartphone.

Mobile keys are digitally generated by hotel staff and, once created, guests simply need to open the app and wave their smartphone in front of the door for keyless entry.
Crowne Plaza Hunter Valley is the first hotel in Australasia to implement this technology, and general manager Lachlan Walker said the hotel is honoured to have been chosen to lead the charge within the Schwartz Family Company portfolio.

"We are thrilled to be embracing this cutting-edge technology," Mr Walker said.

"The hospitality industry has shown tremendous growth in technologies aimed at enhancing the guest experience.

"Recent studies have shown that over 64 percent of travellers want engagement with their hotels via mobile devices including the ability to use their device as a room key.

"We are meeting our guests' needs in the way that matters most to them."

INNOVATIVE: The Crowne Plaza Hunter Valley app includes keyless room entry.
The technology will bring added benefits to staff and management at Crowne Plaza Hunter Valley, such as improving efficiency at the concierge, easing check-in queues at peak times, and reducing plastic and paper usage, which is in line with SFC's historical commitment to sustainability and the environment.
Schwartz Family Company director Dr Jerry Schwartz said he has a passion about using technology to benefit travellers.

"Technology is now an increasingly important component in travel and I'm aiming to establish my NSW hotels as technology leaders, ensuring that travellers make the most of their precious holiday time," Dr Schwartz said.
"The Hunter Valley is one of Australia's most celebrated tourist destinations. I have always been passionate about promoting the region, so investing in revolutionary technology will be yet another drawcard for Hunter Valley.

"As we continue to experience a strong influx of both local and overseas guests, there is no reason we shouldn't provide a state-of-the-art guest experience, even in a regional location."
The story  first appeared on .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter Valley</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Krystal Sellars</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crowne Plaza Hunter Valley</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2.8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SFC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Technologies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Jerry Schwartz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Walker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lachlan Walker</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Schwartz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australasia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lovedale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Schwartz Family Company</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
