<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445325257296064</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:25</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/sport/townsville-warriors-closing-in-on-finals/news-story/ba57061e76461f5fde61578de11ea0c5</url>
  <title>Warriors fight on</title>
  <content>
TOWNSVILLE Warriors have almost booked their place in the North Queensland Football premier league finals after scoring a drought breaking 2-0 win over Saints Eagles Souths.
Battling through injury and going winless from their past seven games, Warriors again played a handful of reserve grade players in the must win Round 17 encounter.
But Warriors pushed hard to earn the win and as a result leapfrog Burdekin into fourth.
Win again this weekend and Warriors coach Graeme Bonato believes his team will secure its berth in the upcoming finals.
"We've really been struggling with depth during the last 3-4 weeks," Bonato said.
"Injuries have hit us hard, including Justin Rawlins (hamstring) and we've had to bring a lot of reserves through.
"Things haven't gone to plan and we're not in the best situation, but we got an important win.
"The way we got it was great as well, it will do us a lot of good and it puts us back into the top four because other results went our way."
Burdekin lost to MA Olympic 3-1 and ladder leaders Brothers thumped third placed Rebels 4-0.
This weekend's catch-up will see teams play the same opponent again, meaning Warriors will aim to repeat its matchwinning performance against SES and possibly leap another win clear of Burdekin.
"If results repeat themselves that should guarantee us finals," Bonato said.
"Whether we finish near the top or scrape in, I'm confident we can go a long way through finals.
"We've shown throughout the season that we can beat the top sides and on our day we can beat anyone."
Rawlins could soon return to action in a positive coup for Warriors, with Bonato saying the team linchpin should be back for finals.
Brothers 4 (Sean Howe 2, Anthony Roulston, Mick Eisenhutt) Rebels 0
Saints Eagles Souths 0 Townsville Warriors 2 (Scorers unknown)
MA Olympic 3 (Ashley Goldfinch 2, Stephen Blackburn) Burdekin FC 1 (Joshua Valle)
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bonato</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burdekin FC 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin Rawlins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Roulston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ashley Goldfinch 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rebels 0</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TOWNSVILLE Warriors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sean Howe 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rawlins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burdekin</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Queensland Football</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saints Eagles Souths 0 Townsville Warriors 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saints Eagles Souths</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SES</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mick Eisenhutt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Blackburn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graeme Bonato</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Round 17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joshua Valle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MA Olympic 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
