<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445260832784980</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/opinion/talking-point-woeful-record-of-staterun-businesses-key-to-taswater-stand/news-story/e75041279f29df178ba760906405952b</url>
  <title>Woeful record of state-run businesses key to TasWater stand</title>
  <content>
THE hostile takeover bid by Treasurer Peter Gutwein and the State Government to seize control of TasWater will likely reach something of a conclusion in coming weeks when the Tasmanian Parliament considers the ill-conceived legislation to mount the asset grab.
Of course, the issue may not end there, with legal advice casting severe doubt over the Government's ability to take over a corporation owned by 29 local government shareholders, prompting speculation of a future court challenge should legislation pass through the Parliament.
But the next step is Parliament's consideration of the legislation and while the Government has the numbers in the House of Assembly, its fate in the Legislative Council is not so certain. Premier Will Hodgman has signalled that he will attempt to do a "selling job" on MLCs, and the Treasurer will probably resort to bluff and bluster in an attempt to get his way.
Although his latest public mutterings have taken a less adversarial tone. He is now effectively saying "trust us as we know best", while offering nothing new and not backing up any of his claims.
The big issue remains. Can we trust the State Government to run TasWater and deliver on its promises, considering its history of managing other Government Business Enterprises such as Hydro, TasNetworks and Aurora?
It is interesting and a little ironic that the Treasurer is now attempting to paint the Government as being unfairly attacked and complaining about the name-calling and misinformation, when it is he who is most guilty of these protestations.
Rather than a true change in Mr Gutwein's attitude, this is probably more a reflection of feedback the Government is receiving regarding the Treasurer's past behaviour and aggressiveness on this issue.
No doubt the Legislative Council will closely examine the Government's plan for TasWater and how it plans to deliver on its pricing and infrastructure promise.
It will see that at best, Mr Gutwein's plan will deliver just 0.5 per cent reduction in consumers' future water and sewerage charges in exchange for an added and unnecessary $600 million in debt. In fact, this could be much worse, given the impact of rushed projects leading to poor outcomes having to be fixed by future governments and paid for by future generations of customers.
There's also the impact of starting a new company, further compressing the Government's timeframe for acceleration of infrastructure upgrades that could see as much as two years' of momentum lost.
Then there is the promised $140 million pay-off to councils.
The reality is this money must come from somewhere in the budget and, in essence, it is a raid on badly needed funds for hospitals, schools and other essential community services.
Apart from the new-found hypocrisy, the Government's performance on this issue has been characterised by a lack of transparency regarding its legal position and advice, a lack of any coherent financial model, and a "yes minister" report from Infrastructure Tasmania, which has been roundly debunked.
The disappointment for Tasmania must be the Government's folly in putting all its energy into a matter that the public does not regard as a major issue rather than focusing on failures in hospital and health administration, education, traffic management and roads, planning and expressing a clear vision of our state. Overwhelmingly, TasWater's owner councils do not trust the State Government to run TasWater, nor should Tasmanians.
David Downie is the Northern Midlands Council Mayor and TasWater's Chief Owners' Representative.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Infrastructure Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treasurer</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Gutwein</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aurora</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TasWater's Chief Owners' Representative</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Downie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TasNetworks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Midlands Council Mayor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TasWater</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hydro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Legislative Council</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>House of Assembly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treasurer Peter Gutwein</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Government Business Enterprise</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian Parliament</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Will Hodgman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MLCs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
