<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445346732133000</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/comment/smh-editorial/untrusting-voters-demand-tangible-action-20170807-gxr3wp.html</url>
  <title>Untrusting voters demand tangible action </title>
  <content>
There is much to trouble Malcolm Turnbull and Bill Shorten in the findings of focus groups conducted for Fairfax Media in recent days, but more for their dispirited constituency.
The research found a consensus that Malcolm Turnbull lacks the political strength or will to prosecute his agenda. Voters could not name a single achievement of his government that had positively and demonstrably affected their lives. "Do something," lamented one voter over the government's impasse over same sex marriage. "Just do something."Photo: Andrew Meares
The research revealed an hostility at the government for failing to address housing affordability, particularly in key western Sydney seats, but also in suburban Melbourne.
But the perceived failure of the Turnbull government to act on behalf of voters did not translate to support for Bill Shorten. Though Labor has announced policies designed to cool the housing market -including a pledge to limit negative gearing - the focus groups remained unaware of Labor's stance and unimpressed with its leader.Photo: Andrew Meares
"They agreed that Shorten is not an appealing alternative, even amongst 2016 Labor voters, who believed he could not be the leader they were looking for - but had no idea who could,"  a researcher observed.
But one finding did stand out, so much that it shocked the researchers observing the groups. Some voters, particularly young voters, believe the government is exaggerating the threat of terrorism for political ends.

"It's like smoke and mirrors - 'look over here while we ruin your lives over there'," said one younger western Sydney voter. Another remarked, "One person a year dies of terrorism, less."

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

The comments are revelatory. They suggest that just as Kevin Rudd was unable to politically profit from what was his government's greatest achievement - action to prevent a recession in Australia in the midst of a global financial meltdown - Turnbull is not being rewarded for his government's achievement in preventing a mass casualty terrorist attack on Australian soil under his watch.
There are two lessons in this. It reminds us that fairly or unfairly voters will reward tangible action over intangible prevention. More significantly, though, it starkly reveals that trust between the electorate and the political class has been thoroughly broken over years of intra-party political warfare.
This loss of trust goes some way towards explaining another revelation of the research: that many voters are beginning to see crossbenchers such as Pauline Hanson and Derryn Hinch as more effective than their major party counterparts.
If this drift from the major parties towards independents was to be replicated at a coming federal election, it is not inconceivable that One Nation or a collection of minor parties could gain seats in the lower house, perhaps even the balance of power.
This could open the door in Australia to the sort of disruptive populism that swept through Britain and much of Europe, and which is now threatening the international stature of the United States.
The result for an already despondent Australian electorate would be even more political uncertainty and obstruction at a time when it craves clarity of vision by an activist government. Some politicians appear to already understand this.
"If there is one lesson that MPs and political parties should surely have learnt over the past few years it is that you don't break promises," Tony Abbott wrote in an opinion piece addressing same-sex marriage for The Australian newspaper on Monday.
"Say what you mean and do what you say has to be the cardinal rule and is the only way to keep faith with the electorate."
Given how determined Mr Abbott is to destabilise his own party and derail its policymaking processes, he is perhaps not the right messenger.
'A note from the editor' - to have Sydney Morning Herald editor Lisa Davies' exclusive weekly newsletter delivered to your inbox sign up here:
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin Rudd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>One Nation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Meares</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lisa Davies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Derryn Hinch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Morning Herald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Untrusting</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
