<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444736846764545</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/real-estate/the-salvation-army-buys-new-digs-on-church-street-parramatta-20170807-gxqn5q</url>
  <title>The Salvation Army buys new digs on Church Street, Parramatta</title>
  <content>
The Salvation Army has beaten 100 developers to buy a sought-after two-storey commercial building on a substantial site at 426 Church Street, Parramatta in Sydney's west.
It is understood bids of $30 million were made for the deal.
The Salvation Army will relocate its Parramatta place of worship and community services to the property, following the sale of its three buildings on the corner of 93-95 Phillip Street and 32 Smith Street in 2016.
The site is popular with developers because of its corner profile and its big 90-space car park. The property is  occupied by office and retail tenants.

It is understood also that Sydney west developer Dyldam was also considering the site.

"We've been in Parramatta since 1884 ... We believe that the purchase of 426 Church Street will enable us to continue, and indeed grow, our ministry in Western Sydney," the Salvation Army's Major Grant Sandercock-Brown said.
CBRE's Peter Vines, Frank Oliveri and Victor Sheu managed the marketing campaign of the property for a private family based in Gordon in Sydney's north, but declined to comment on the deal.
Parramatta is shaping up quickly to become Sydney's next CBD, with big players like GPT Group, and Walker Corporation taking a stake in the suburb, about 20 kilometres from the Sydney CBD.
The Salvation Army's previous site can yield a hotel or office tower for GPT, providing about 28,000sq m in new space.

is developing three stages of the $2 billion Parramatta Square commercial precinct which are two commercial A-grade mixed-use towers and the 700-unit residential project and the tallest residential tower in the southern hemisphere, Aspial Tower.
Western Sydney University will also move into Parramatta Square occupying a future 14-storey, 26,500sq m A-grade building developed by Charter Hall and constructed by John Holland.
is also confirmed to move to the old David Jones car park site on Church Street.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Church Street</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charter Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phillip Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victor Sheu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frank Oliveri</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aspial Tower</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walker Corporation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salvation Army</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parramatta</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gordon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salvation Army's Major Grant Sandercock-Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GPT Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parramatta Square</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Holland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Sydney University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smith Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GPT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBRE's Peter Vines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
