<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445170638469845</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/finance/work/leaders/martin-place-tent-city-leader-vows-to-stay-in-place-despite-clover-moores-move-on/news-story/1ef08578916e253b7794c34b571159fb</url>
  <title>Martin Place tent city leader vows to stay in place, despite Clover Moore's move on</title>
  <content>
'Political games' over Sydney's tent city
0:28

Gladys Berejiklian says the state government would take action on Sydney's tent city if the council doesn't.

August 6th 2017
a day ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National/

Chris Hook, Jason Tin & Christopher Harris

Share

THE man described as the "mayor" of Martin Place's tent city last night issued a defiant rejection of the supposed "deal" to pack up the homeless camp - just moments after it was announced by Sydney Lord Mayor Clover Moore.
Ms Moore had declared to a media pack on the steps of Town Hall that she had "negotiated an outcome with Lanz Priestley", claiming that he had agreed to pack up the camp of roughly 47 tents when council trucks arrived at the CBD landmark pedestrian mall today to collect material following a guarantee a "safe space" would be provided - although one without beds.

The so-called "Mayor of Tent City" Lanz Priestly had a very different message to the Lord Mayor. Picture: Richard DobsonSource:News Corp Australia

Sydney Lord Mayor Clover Moore arrives for yesterday's press conference at Town Hall. Picture: AAPSource:AAP
"He's agreed to this because accommodation has been offered to people and they realise that pressure is mounting and the crisis was really developing," she said.

The Daily Telegraph he and the Lord Mayor had conflicting definitions of what that "safe space" should look like and that he was prepared to "spend months if necessary" hashing out a deal.
"I don't think we will accept it without accommodation ... we want people to be able to sleep communally in a building - effectively a big hall with a lot of mattresses in it," he said.
"It'll be open in the sense that there won't be closed off rooms."

Lanz Priestly stands at Martin Place. Picture: AAPSource:AAP
, who earlier vowed to step in and use powers available to the state to move on the camp if council didn't resolve the issue, saying: "Don't think that banning me from here or from Sydney is going to stop this ... we will be back with me or without me."

NSW Premier Gladys Berejiklian ordered council to clear the public space. Picture: AAPSource:News Corp Australia
Mr Priestley, a New Zealand-born father of 12 who has become the public face of the tent city homeless crisis, said that if the state issues a "banning order to 30 or 40 people here, this will still come back".
It remains unclear whether Ms Moore will be able to salvage the so-called deal before council trucks arrive today to cart away property, with Mr Priestley

Tent City residents have vowed to rebuild in the CBD or surrounds. Picture: Dylan RobinsonSource:News Corp Australia
"Clover at her press conference indicated there wouldn't be any sleeping space there," he said.
"My definition is what we have here, which clearly has a sleeping aspect - I think we are entitled to ownership of that definition."
While Ms Moore spoke of an agreement to have the camp packed up, Mr Priestley said the tent city was simply "going to let the council take away some of our surplus stuff".
"If they come back to us with a building people can move to, (that) they can sleep in and have a 24/7 safe space, then we will take the tents down," he said.

The City of Sydney has committed to moving the homeless on. Picture: Dylan RobinsonSource:News Corp Australia
Ms Moore last week said she would only use council's power to confiscate property if a list of demands was met by the state government, which included the reopening of the Sirius building for homeless people.

Ms Moore said she expected to have the homeless moved on by morning. Picture: AAPSource:AAP

Martin Place remained full of tents on Monday night. Picture: AAPSource:AAP
She then declared that more discussion was needed when the state fell short of meeting those demands.
But when an optimistic Lord Mayor was yesterday asked when the tent city would move, she said: "As soon as our first truck arrives there ... so I think that will be tomorrow morning."
Mr Priestley has just had his 12th child. The most recent is with 20-year-old Nina Wilson, who is from Nowra.

Priestly addresses the homeless in Martin Place. Picture: AAPSource:AAP
A self-taught project manager originally from Wellington in New Zealand, he told The Daily Telegraph he is a permanent resident who refuses to collect taxpayer-funded benefits.
"I think it might be a little hypocritical to criticise what government does and stick my hand out," he said.
He first set up camp in the financial heart of Sydney in 1991.
Mr Priestley sold his own home in the eastern suburbs 20 years ago so he could give his own children, the eldest 47 years old, deposits to buy houses.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lanz Priestley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christopher Harris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Moore</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nowra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sirius</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nina Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard DobsonSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lord Mayor</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clover Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lanz Priestly</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clover</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JASON TIN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAPSource</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Lord Mayor Clover Moore</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Hook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Priestley</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin Place</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand-born</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City of Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Town Hall</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dylan RobinsonSource</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mayor of Tent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gladys Berejiklian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wellington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Telegraph</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Premier Gladys Berejiklian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1.8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
