<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445213588143718</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:59</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/messenger/west-beaches/push-for-major-renovation-for-thebarton-theatre/news-story/74fb55fb39c4a42f3090a1023f89ad94</url>
  <title>Thebarton Theatre needs a major revamp</title>
  <content>
THE historic Thebarton Theatre may be in line for a major makeover as it nears its centenary.
Weslo Holdings, the theatre's operators, have asked West Torrens Council to fund a master plan for the makeover.
The plan and project cost estimate would then be used to seek external funding from state and federal governments.
The council's community facilities committee last week recommended councillors vote to proceed with the master plan at their August meeting.
The council's chief executive officer, Terry Buss, said plans could cost up to $137,000 to produce - and would take about six months.
He described the theatre as "iconic and important".
In a letter to the council, Weslo Holdings director Bob Lott said ideally the building should be renovated before its centenary in 2028.
The aim was to achieve the "highest level of compliance possible", making the old theatre "more competitive".
"The age of the Thebarton Theatre building and its heritage status provides challenges for redevelopment," Mr Lott said.
"We are heartened by the successful revitalisation of the similar Empire Theatre in Toowoomba and we envisage being able to achieve as good an outcome for Thebarton Theatre."
His letter calls for repairs to the ceiling, replacing seats, new lighting, upgrades to the bar and installation of solar panels.
The Thebarton Theatre was built in 1926 for £30,000 - about $2.3 million in today's figures - and opened its doors two years later.
Metallica, Hunters & Collectors, Sex Pistols, Billy Bragg and Cold Chisel are some of the artists that have performed there.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Torrens Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Billy Bragg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cold Chisel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thebarton Theatre</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Metallica</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Lott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sex Pistols</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bob Lott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Weslo Holdings</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toowoomba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terry Buss</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Empire Theatre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
