<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445389681806876</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4840094/more-than-half-of-floated-companies-are-underwater-a-decade-later/?cs=2373</url>
  <title>More than half of floated companies are underwater a decade later</title>
  <content>
You've heard the hype. You've felt the hope. That company with the promising technology. The new mine. The biotechnology breakthrough just on the cusp. Or you've been offered shares in some big government company that's being privatised and all of the brokers are spruiking it.

You get a chance to play with the big end of town. Get yourself some of those fantastic "stag" profits we all hear about.
It's a seductive sell. This could be the next Facebook. Or Google. Heck, even the next CBA, which was privatised at just $5.40 per share (it's now over $80) in 1991.
And for the brokers and those selling their shares as part of each new initial public offering (IPO) or float, the marketing almost writes itself. You allude to past successes. You tell people that the offer is only open for a short time, and that there is a limited number of shares available ??? FOMO - the fear of missing out - does the rest.
Some people do make money with IPOs, but it's not who you think.
I was reminded of this fact last week when my colleague Mike King shared some stunning facts on Twitter. From his , there have been around 280 IPOs on the ASX since January 2015. And more than half are currently underwater. Not only that, but over the , only 50 per cent of new floats are trading above their first day closing price.
In other words, far from being the promise of new riches, your chances of success have been indistinguishable from a coin toss. And remember, I'm not comparing those returns with the index - a vastly tougher, but more appropriate target - but simply whether or not those shares are positive or negative.
And there have been some themes. According to Mike:
"Chinese companies floated on the ASX have probably been the biggest disappointment with several examples down as much or even more than 90 per cent including Sunbridge (ASX: SBB) and XPD Soccer Gear (ASX: XPD). Several have been delisted, including some over alleged fraudulent activity. Tech stocks were also disappointing with NewZulu (ASX: NWZ) losing virtually 100 per cent of its value since listing in January 2015."
But he was also careful to note that there have been some big winners, too:
"On the other side of the ledger, a2Milk (ASX: A2M) is up more than 630 per cent since listing in March 2015. Pot stock Zelda Therapeutics (ASX: ZLD) has seen its share price soar 200 per cent. It remains to be seen whether those gains can be maintained, once the hype dies down and reality sets in."
That last sentence might well be the disclaimer on every IPO that comes to market.
You know who does reliably make money from IPOs? The sellers and their hangers-on. After all, just think about it. A stockmarket float is one of the only times the buyers are convinced the opportunity is really about them. When you buy a house, you know the seller and the agent want to get the best price possible. As they should. Ditto buying a car.

Foolish takeaway

Those selling shares into an IPO want the best price possible. And the investment banks, lawyers and stockbrokers work for the seller. Which is as it should be.
But remember that next time you're offered the chance to buy shares in an IPO. No one is out to do you a favour - they're trying to create a market for the sellers. Remember the glossy Myer prospectus with more pages of models than financials? Or the Dick Smith ""?
There are some great IPOs. But choose carefully, making sure you buy quality and value ??? not hype.
New report: The "blue chips" of tomorrow aren't the blue chips of yesterday. If you want to look forward rather than backward, we've released our three best ideas for 2017. .
Scott Phillips is the 's director of research. You can follow Scott on Twitter . The Motley Fool's purpose is to educate, amuse and enrich investors. ???

The story  first appeared on .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>XPD Soccer Gear</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dick Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NWZ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Phillips</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ditto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IPO</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IPOs</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Myers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zelda Therapeutics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBB</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Motley Fool</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NewZulu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>XPD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ZLD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mike King</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mike</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FOMO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Google</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunbridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 2015</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
