<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445432631480684</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Australian</source>
  <url>http://www.theaustralian.com.au/life/food-wine/complete-set-of-penfolds-grange-goes-to-the-highest-bidder/news-story/3c2ad72aacce48a4d9a7d16274e46076</url>
  <title>Not a drink, it's an investment</title>
  <content>
I'm not the usual habitue of the regular auctions conducted by the venerable house of du Plessis, specialists, says the catalogue, in the "fine art of fine living".
I can't pull off a poloneck with anywhere near the panache of some of the others in the room, and all of my hair is my own.
But on a bleak and foul Sunday in Adelaide, I take my seat shortly after an auction has started. It's only when someone asks me to stand so they can inspect the chair's underside that I realise I've parked my backside on Lot 47.
The room is filled with a whole lot of furniture that makes Menzies look edgy, most of it drawn from a single home in the Adelaide Hills where the television played Midsomer Murders on repeat.
There was a Streeton that attracted some interest despite clearly coming from his "sentimental pictures of flowers that should be on a chocolate box", period, and some rather lovely Chinese pieces from the Qing dynasty.
One hundred and sixty-six lots before the one item that had lured me in. Lot 167 was a complete set of Penfolds Grange from 1951 to 2012, the penultimate lot for the day, the only thing to sell after it the wine fridge the auctioneers had to buy to display it.
I wasn't a potential bidder, there were three too many zeros on the estimate for me, but I was curious to see what sort of interest might be aroused by the set. These things are getting pretty rare. Probably a number nearing single figures. News reports had said the vendor of this set was a prominent figure in the South Australian building industry who still had another one stashed away.
I spoke to someone fitting that description a couple of days before the auction. "Nah, it's not mine, mate. I sold mine back to Penfolds three years ago. I took it to one of the re-corking clinics they do every few years and Peter Gago told me about how some of those early bottles were all hand-blown glass so you never knew where the fracture points might be. Knowing my luck, I'd just have to touch one and the bottom would fall out. Don't need the stress, so I got rid of it."
I asked several people who should know who the vendor might be and they each gave me a different answer. Two-thirds of the way through the auction, the TV news crews started setting up. Penfolds Grange stands alone in Australian wine terms for its ability to break free from niches like this column and splash out into general news.
I'd scoped the room a bunch of times but still couldn't see anyone that stood out as a potential buyer. There was one prominent restaurateur in the crowd, but surely his famously large cellar needed no more adornment? There didn't seem to be anyone from Penfolds, always an interested party when old bottles of Grange become available. But there had been plenty of interest before the sale, with auctioneer Marc du Plessis telling of inspection appointments at all sorts of odd hours from buyers trying to see the goods without being seen themselves.
When the time finally came, it came quickly. An internet bid got the ball rolling at $200,000. The room was quiet. A phone bid pushed it to $215,000. And the room stayed quiet. Then a man in a black leather jacket, sitting there with his wife the whole time, put up his hand and it was done, at $230,000. It went once. It went twice. And it went third time, into the possession of a semi-retired earthmoving contractor who wanted to buy it as an investment for his grandkids. What is it with construction types and Grange?
John Davison got his first bottle of Grange, the 1993, as a birthday present from his wife.
"I think it was one of those years where she couldn't think of anything to get me," he laughed, the day after joining the very small club of people owning a complete collection of Australia's most famous wine. That started him collecting and he already has most of a set assembled singly residing in a cellar that's about to get some upgraded security.
A man with such a collection must really love the wine then? "I've drunk Grange once," says Davison. "I'm a keen cyclist and when I did the Three Peaks ride in Victoria a couple of years ago I took a bottle of 1998 and promised myself I'd drink it if I finished." So how was it?
"I don't really know. I was so buggered after the ride I couldn't really taste it."
The collection will be given to his four grandchildren when the youngest turns 21.
Sure beats the overnight bag I got for mine.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Midsomer Murders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grange</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Streeton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marc</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Gago</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Hills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Plessis</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Menzies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Davison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Penfolds Grange</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Davison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lot 47</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Three Peaks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
