<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651446592272670937</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/they-said-we-were-crazy-to-set-up-away-from-the-ci/3208438/</url>
  <title>They said we were crazy to set up away from the city</title>
  <content>
WHEN I first arrived on the Sunshine Coast in 1979, the only large manufacturing industries I can recall were those processing local agricultural products.
The main processors were the Buderim Ginger Factory, which was in Buderim at that time, and the Moreton Central Sugar Mill in Nambour, which closed in 2003. The sugar industry supported many smaller engineering companies and other local suppliers.
The main industries on the Coast at the time were tourism and construction, which of course went hand-in-hand. 
It was while working in the construction industry as a solid plastering contractor that I recognised the need for better coating systems to brighten up the dull face brick buildings that were common at the time.
The challenge was to develop coating systems that had colour and style and would stand up to the harsh, variable coastal climate. This was achieved by working closely with designers, builders, architects and tradespeople to produce a range of coatings that would come to influence Sunshine Coast style. 
I built a factory in the backyard of our property at Yandina and was able to leave the contracting business by 1987 to focus solely on manufacturing.
The business grew and Rockcote moved to the Yandina industrial estate in 1992. We continued to build extra space and production capacity as demand increased, with the factory eventually running 24 hours a day.
In 2008, Rockcote opened a state-of-the-art dry mix cement render plant on the same site, enabling us to manufacture more in an hour than we could produce in an entire shift with the old equipment. The new plant also allowed us to produce renders more economically and with higher quality and greater product consistency.
Industry experts said we were crazy building such a plant on the Sunshine Coast. Now this plant is running 24 hours a day, Rockcote supplies our quality products across the country, employing over 80 people and has an annual turnover approaching $30 million. 
I recall having a chief executive from one of our major suppliers visit once and ask why we based the business on the Sunshine Coast.
I suspect he expected to hear the business case outlining demographics etc but my simple answer was "because this is where we live".
Another time, I had left work a little early one Friday afternoon to pick up our daughter Jessie from school and go fishing at the mouth of the Noosa River.
We were returning home just on dusk with four nice size fish in the bag when the phone rang. It was a colleague from one of the major paint companies based in Sydney who had decided to use his time stuck in the Friday afternoon traffic to catch up on some business calls.
He said he had at least another two hours travel time ahead of him. We were 10 minutes from home. Why base our selves on the Sunshine Coast indeed? 
One of the unique features of the Sunshine Coast that helped us in the early days and throughout the development of our business is the wealth of knowledge of the people who move to our area. From retired business people to others with marketing and technical experience, we have gained greatly by tapping into this knowledge. 
In the early days we recognised that it was difficult to get the talent we needed to leave the big cities. Now we find the opposite is true and that the Sunshine Coast is a great drawcard in sourcing the best people. 
Perhaps our greatest advantage has come from the vibrant construction industry that exists on the Sunshine Coast. Rockcote has benefited greatly from our close association with local architects, building designers, builders and tradespeople who use and endorse our products. Many of these are renowned far beyond the Sunshine Coast and have played a significant part in the demand for our products in the southern states.
The wider community and Sunshine Coast lifestyle have contributed much to our clean, green ethos. We live here for the beautiful environment so we do not want to contribute to its degradation. And members of the local community are generally the early adopters of our latest products, like our range of beautiful natural materials based on clay and lime.
These products provide an attractive natural finish and contain no Volatile Organic Compounds (VOCs) or harmful chemicals, improving the indoor air quality.  
Looking to the future, I believe the days of huge, centralised, polluting factories are numbered, not only for the Sunshine Coast but also around the world.
We believe that the future lies with smaller, distributed, high-tech production facilities closer to the markets they serve, supported by centralised technical and research and development.
The Sunshine Coast is the ideal base for the knowledge workers while much of the work is actually carried out within the communities where the products are to be used.
Hyundai unveils its only fully-electric model in Australia
Work on next stage of redevelopment due to start next April
Coast's $18m rescue chopper has been shifted by Lifeflight
LIFESTYLE lure was stronger than a high-flying accountancy career.
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
A NATIONAL exhibition of ceramic art has been launched on the Coast
BREAKING: New festival coming to the Sunshine Coast
ONE of Hollywood's most adorable couples is over.
New celebrity cooking show fails to fire for Seven.
The legendary creator isn't so sure about how Netflix works.
*WARNING this story contains spoilers*
Make way for Mackay's newest tech start up
Planning documents lodged on behalf of site owners
Education, student accommodation, bars and music all key to future
Five dates through August for community to have its say on rock wall
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jessie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VOCs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast's $18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LifeFlight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moreton Central Sugar Mill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Volatile Organic Compounds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>13</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rockcote</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa River</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yandina</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hyundai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim Ginger Factory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
