<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651446566502866677</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:14</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/i-was-ready-to-give-up-on-my-dream/3208451/</url>
  <title>'I was ready to give up on my dream'</title>
  <content>
THE idea for COYO announced itself, like all great ideas, at three o'clock in the morning.
I had been retired for a year, filling my days with home renovations and gardening. But that just wasn't enough.
Once the idea was planted, I was in the kitchen every day experimenting with different recipes.
Our kitchen was often filled with home-made yoghurt machines churning out coconut yoghurt.
I worked for six months to perfect the original recipe before we were ready to take the idea commercial.
It still brings tears to my eyes when I talk about the day the first commercial batch of COYO was created.
Things weren't going as planned and I was on the verge of giving up and tipping my dream down the drain, but I persevered. It was lucky I did as just after my dream started slipping away, I looked down into the yoghurt vat and saw the creation of the very first coconut yoghurt in Australasia. The rest is history.
Of course, with all new products there was a lot of initial feedback for the product. We welcomed this feedback and used it to improve our original recipe.
Our customers opinions have always been important to us, it was one of the reasons we become ACO organic.
We started out as a very small-scale family business.
We have always been a very family-run company. Even now, years later we still have our son and daughter working in the company.
Along with our family values we are also very conscious of the impact manufacturing has on the wider community. We pride ourselves on sourcing sustainable and fair-trade ingredients and make sure to visit our plantations to ensure standards are upheld.
In fact, one of our initiatives we set up for our plantation workers is to continue supporting them into retirement.
Manufacturing COYO on the Sunshine Coast has been a pleasure. We have always had wonderful staff, easy access to major transport routes and a supportive community.
The journey of COYO has been one Sandra and I couldn't imagine living without.
Hyundai unveils its only fully-electric model in Australia
Work on next stage of redevelopment due to start next April
Coast's $18m rescue chopper has been shifted by Lifeflight
LIFESTYLE lure was stronger than a high-flying accountancy career.
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
A NATIONAL exhibition of ceramic art has been launched on the Coast
BREAKING: New festival coming to the Sunshine Coast
ONE of Hollywood's most adorable couples is over.
New celebrity cooking show fails to fire for Seven.
The legendary creator isn't so sure about how Netflix works.
*WARNING this story contains spoilers*
Make way for Mackay's newest tech start up
Planning documents lodged on behalf of site owners
Education, student accommodation, bars and music all key to future
Five dates through August for community to have its say on rock wall
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>COYO</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sandra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast's $18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LifeFlight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hyundai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australasia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
