<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445303782458968</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/news/castle-hill-goat-track-upgrade-starts/news-story/8c2d7be9dbabf9f0b01fbf6bf86a88b3</url>
  <title>Castle Hill Goat Track upgrade starts</title>
  <content>
UPGRADES are under way on two of Castle Hill's most popular walking tracks, with more than $800,000 in funding to ensure they are in pristine condition for walkers.
Work on the Goat and Cudtheringa tracks is funded under the Townsville City Council and State Government Works for Queensland package, with upgrades expected to be complete by November 30.
The work includes track widening, erosion control and new steps, drains and landing areas.
The council's Infrastructure Committee chair Cr Mark Mola-chino said safety was the priority with more than 8000 walkers using the tracks every week.
"While we will endeavour to keep the tracks open to the public, it may be necessary to close the tracks at various stages," he said.
"We ask that the public remain vigilant for updates regarding closures."
Townsville MP Scott Stewart said Castle Hill was an iconic destination and the upgrades would deliver a great experience for walkers.
Pedestrian management will be in place to advise users of detours.
Want breaking news delivered straight to your inbox?
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville MP Scott Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville City Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NOVEMBER 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Infrastructure Committee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Castle Hill</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Mark Mola-chino</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government Works</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Castle Hill Goat Track</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cudtheringa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
