<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651446562207899337</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:13</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/roy-family-were-citrus-pioneers/3208421/</url>
  <title>Roy family were citrus pioneers</title>
  <content>
ALTHOUGH the citrus industry was never the largest agricultural industry on the Sunshine Coast, it has played a major role over the past 50 years.
The Roy family was a pioneer of citrus growing in the region and four generations were involved in the largest citrus farm industry in the Palmwoods district from 1908 until 1984.
Their land is now a part of residential land estates and many families live on their old orchards.
Roys Rd at Palmwoods is named after the family and a memorial cairn in Palmwoods pays tribute to their efforts and acknowledges how they were the original founders of the Golden Ripe Citrus orchards and in 1980 opened the Suncoast juice factory in 1980 - at that time the only privately-owned juice factory outside the capital cities.
Farming has all but disappeared in Palmwoods but many people who worked in the Suncoast juice factory or in the fruit packing sheds on Roy's citrus farms have happy memories of the time.
A large farm on Roys Rd, off Landershute Rd, was owned by orchardist Charlie Roy. Roy's farms included the areas of the Old Orchard Estate and extended up towards the Palmwoods School.
The family was also very community-minded.
Gordon Roy was a councillor for Maroochy Shire and Jessie Roy was acknowledged in Maroochy Shire Centenary celebrations with an award for her contributions to the shire which was met with a standing ovation by the community.
Young brothers Harry, Gordon and Jack Roy moved to the Coochin Creek district in the early 1930s, arriving on horseback. Later, they managed a 37,000 citrus tree orchard on 248ha as well as a turf farm.
The Roy family of Coochin Creek worked hard and grew lemons and Washington naval oranges for three generations. They also had a jetty in the lower reaches of Coochin Creek with frontage to Pumicestone Passage where the packed fruit could be picked up from Roy's Jetty and taken by boat down Pumicestone Passage to the markets in Brisbane.
Today, tourist boats pull up to that same jetty.
The industrious Roy brothers made a road from their property at Coochin Creek to Beerwah. This dirt road crossed creeks through isolated low-lying, rough mulga scrub to reach Beerwah on the main highway.
The Roys built spider bridges to traverse the creeks and waterways so they could transport the fruit by rail to Brisbane.
The Coochin Creek Fruit Co-Operative, established in Beerwah in 1936, was adjacent to the Beerwah Railway Station and it was there fruit was loaded on to the goods trains.
Today, Roys Rd crosses the Bruce Hwy near Beerwah.
A little cemetery closer to Beerwah on Roys Rd is where early members of the Roy's pioneering family rest. The three Roy brothers contributed to the building of Roys Rd, which bears their name.
In 1998, the Roy family's homestead burnt down. A year later, the Roys lost three years' worth of fruit in a single hailstorm on the Coochin Creek holdings.
Today, land sale signs alongside the Bruce Hwy show development is coming ever closer to the Coochin Creek and Bells Creek areas.
But the name Roys Rd and the signs on the highway remind us of days gone by, when things were very different on the Sunshine Coast.
Thanks to Sunshine Coast Council's Heritage Library officers for the words and images.
Hyundai unveils its only fully-electric model in Australia
Work on next stage of redevelopment due to start next April
Coast's $18m rescue chopper has been shifted by Lifeflight
LIFESTYLE lure was stronger than a high-flying accountancy career.
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
A NATIONAL exhibition of ceramic art has been launched on the Coast
BREAKING: New festival coming to the Sunshine Coast
ONE of Hollywood's most adorable couples is over.
New celebrity cooking show fails to fire for Seven.
The legendary creator isn't so sure about how Netflix works.
*WARNING this story contains spoilers*
Make way for Mackay's newest tech start up
Planning documents lodged on behalf of site owners
Education, student accommodation, bars and music all key to future
Five dates through August for community to have its say on rock wall
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palmwoods</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jessie Roy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gordon Roy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beerwah Railway Station</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy Shire Centenary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast's $18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LifeFlight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beerwah</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Council's Heritage Library</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SUNCOAST</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coochin Creek</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roys Rd</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coochin Creek Fruit Co-Operative</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roy</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Roy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy Shire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roys</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palmwoods School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bells Creek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gordon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlie Roy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hyundai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Golden Ripe Citrus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pumicestone Passage</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roy's Jetty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruce Hwy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Old Orchard Estate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Landershute Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
