<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651446502078356281</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>18:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/469357/goannas-win-on-the-bell/?cs=4173</url>
  <title>Goannas win on the bell</title>
  <content>
Goannas win on the bell

CLASH: Rosellas second-rower Ed Barber takes on Cessnock's Brad Grant at Harker Oval yesterday. - Pictures by Phil Hearne

exit

CESSNOCK winger Jack Fitzgibbon became a Goannas hero in his first-grade debut yesterday when he scored the match-winning try in the club's 20-18 victory over Western Suburbs at Harker Oval.
A charge down in the middle of the field gave Cessnock one last set to produce an unlikely win with a minute on the clock.
Cessnock spun the ball wide and Beau Ryan beautifully positioned Fitzgibbon - the son of federal Hunter MP Joel Fitzgibbon - to dive over in the corner.
Wests, who fielded a new-look forward pack, had led from the 21st minute of the match and paid for taking several poor options in the final stages.
"It was there for us to win but we threw it away with ill discipline," Rosellas coach Craig Miller said.
"They love getting in that grind and handled it better than us in the final five."
The Rosellas have lost a wealth of experience over the off-season and have focused on promoting juniors.
"It'll take a few more of those losses to learn," Miller said. "We've got to learn from that and move on as quick as we can and try and get better.
"They're a young side and need to learn the hard knocks of rugby league."
Goannas coach Craig Thomas said defence forged the victory and praised the forward pack, who were led by props Brendan Hlad and Adam Withyman.
Both put plenty of sting in their tackles and new hooker Darcy Etrich provided the spark from dummy-half as he toyed with the Wests defence.
"Young Darcy Etrich is dynamic and he's still got footy under his belt," Thomas said. "He's probably around 80 per cent at this stage.
"He's a little schemer and if you sit down and talk footy with him he's got a great footy head."
Cessnock five-eighth Joby Patten scored in the opening minutes after successive penalties but tries to outside backs David Pangai and Steve Gordon from a bomb and a grubber kick gave Wests an 8-4 advantage.
Rosellas captain Jermaine Ale made Goannas centre Sean Driver pay for a fumble near half-time to give Wests a 14-4 lead at the break.
A penalty goal extended the scoreline to 16-4 before the Goannas fought back through tries to two of their new recruits from Wests - fullback Sam Wooden and centre Brock Harmer.
At Tomaree yesterday, Wyong thrashed the Northern Blues 56-0 as Roos hooker Mitch Williams carved up the home side.
Maitland's match against Lakes United at Maitland Sportsground was abandoned on Saturday due to rain.
Central co-coach David van Buuren said yesterday his club would not lodge a complaint with the Newcastle Rugby League concerning an incredible incident in the Butcher Boys' 16-14 loss to Kurri Kurri at Kurri Sportsground on Saturday.
English halfback John Schofield sprinted away to apparently score his second intercept try of the match with Central leading 10-0.
Van Buuren said Schofield, the son of England and Balmain star Garry Schofield, put the ball over the line one-handed but it rolled back into the field of play.
When referee Tom Aylett caught up to the play he ruled no try and Kurri picked up the loose ball and scored two tackles later.
Also on Saturday, the new-look South Newcastle won a spiteful match 16-8 over Macquarie at Peacock Field.
Scorpions substitute Josh Schmiedel was sent off for hitting Macquarie hooker Joe Cudmore, who required stitches in his mouth.
The Lions' victory came at a cost with Ainsley Coxsedge (suspected torn biceps) and Kurt Gudgeon (broken arm) suffering injuries.
Meanwhile, the Newcastle Rebels under-18 side made an impressive start to the defense of their regional championship title over the weekend with wins over the Northern Thunderbolts (26-12) and Oxley Pioneers (46-6) at Mittagong.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Wooden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rosellas</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurt Gudgeon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Miller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brendan Hlad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Suburbs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joby Patten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garry Schofield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phil Hearne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maitland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jermaine Ale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Schofield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Pangai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beau Ryan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Rugby League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Withyman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sean Driver</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wyong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fitzgibbon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peacock Field</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Rebels</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Schmiedel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Miller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurri Sportsground</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thomas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macquarie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Balmain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buuren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tomaree</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Van Buuren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurri</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Schofield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter MP Joel Fitzgibbon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ed Barber</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Gordon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cessnock's Brad Grant</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lakes United</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Fitzgibbon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Cudmore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brock Harmer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goannas</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Aylett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mittagong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harker Oval</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurri Kurri</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darcy Etrich</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cessnock</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ainsley Coxsedge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maitland Sportsground</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Thomas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
