<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651446115531293937</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>17:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/technology/netflix-leads-the-way-as-streamers-set-to-take-down-pay-tv-20170803-gxolpa</url>
  <title>Netflix leads the way as streamers set to take down pay TV</title>
  <content>
The number of Australians paying for subscription video on-demand (SVOD) services is set to leapfrog pay television in 2018, with Netflix leading the charge, followed by Stan and a growing long-tail of niche players.
According to an annual study of the local SVOD market by research firm Telsyte, total paid uptake of SVOD services in Australia is expected to hit 3.8 million as early as June next year, overtaking the 3.3 million who pay for subscription TV services including Foxtel and Fetch.
The 3.8 million forecast SVOD subscriptions by mid-next year includes . In October last year, it.
The study found there were 3.7 million SVOD subscriptions in June 2017, of which 78 per cent were being paid for and the rest were either complimentary or on free trials, a 30 per cent increase from the end of June 2016.

Netflix is dominating the market with a 55 per cent share of subscriptions while Stan, which is 50-50 owned by Nine Entertainment and Fairfax Media, publisher of The Australian Financial Review, has 24 per cent.

The remaining 21 per cent of SVOD subscribers were spread across a range of services including Amazon and a number of niche players, mainly sport, including NBA League Pass, UFC, AFL, NRL and Cricket Australia products.
Amazon to boost subscribers

The is expected to increase its number of SVOD subscribers in Australia because the US e-commerce giant offers its streaming service for free when customers sign up to a $99 per year Prime offering, where purchased goods are delivered for free.
The ease of use and growing number of devices that support SVOD services - mobiles, tablets, set top boxes and smart TVs - is also helping subscriber growth, Telsyte managing director Foad Fadaghi said.

"SVOD is becoming the go-to instant gratification that people are looking for with regard to their content consumption," he said.
The survey found 49 per cent of Australia households were paying for either SVOD or subscription TV, and 11 per cent have both.
"I think the appetite for paid content is increasing across the Australia population," Mr Fadaghi said.
"A confluence of forces is driving that; availability of content; the only way you can get certain content legally is via paid offerings, prices have come down for some offers, and the arrival of some offers...just being available."

Mr Fadaghi said Netflix's shift to be more heavily reliant on its original content means there will be a number of players with a range of content.
"We continue to think this is not a winner takes all market. Stan is proving that the market can sustain two more generalist type players, possibly even more," he said.
"Foxtel Now's arrival is a vindication of streaming business model and will probably continue to grow if the content offering appeals to the consumer - I think sports might have a large part of that going forward."
Sporting selections

Telecommunications providers offering sport subscriptions such as Optus Sport with English Premier League and cricket and Telstra with the AFL and NRL were up 55 per cent in the year to June 2017 at 477,000.
A major boost came from , which Telsyte estimates has surged past the 100,000 subscriber mark.
Mr Fadaghi said bundling is playing an increasingly important role for telcos, especially as the equal playing field that is the National Broadband Network plays out.
Bundle offers help telcos differentiate themselves from rivals and make customers less likely to leave the provider. Mr Fadaghi said bundling services such as Netflix and Stan on unmetered data service - when the data used by those services isn't counted towards the user's overall data limit - is important for telcos to win over customers.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foad Fadaghi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>English Premier League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Broadband Network</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBA League Pass</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UFC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TVs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Telstra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Fadaghi</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxtel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SVOD</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cricket Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 2017</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stan</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Entertainment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Optus Sport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxtel Now</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Telsyte</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
