<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445016019644229</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:13</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/personal-finance/superannuation-and-smsfs/millennial-super-funds-should-be-raising-red-flags-for-apra-20170807-gxqzy2</url>
  <title>Millennial super needs more APRA oversight</title>
  <content>
Members of the $2 trillion superannuation sector are calling on the prudential regulator to better oversee the growing plethora of niche, youth-oriented superannuation offerings over concerns about their heavy use of outsourcing.
A rush of super funds marketing themselves towards the traditionally disengaged millennial market have sprung up and some have been criticised for The most well-known is the Atlassian-backed Spaceship, but others such as Grow Super, Zuper, Human Super and Mobi Super are also gaining attention.
Common to these newer outfits is propensity towards outsourcing key elements of the fund's functions, including investment and trusteeship to different providers. Companies such as ASX-listed Onevue's Diversa and Trustee Partners with its related entity Tidswell Financial are the trustees behind many of the new funds.
'Opportunistic' 

For Phil Vernon, managing director of ASX-listed super and managed fund provider Australian Ethical, the move towards outsourcing amounts to a  "dispersion of accountability" and he believes  the newer funds are being "opportunistic" in targeting millennial disengagement.
He said the Australian Prudential Regulation Authority must investigate.

"I don't know if they [APRA] are, but we believe that they should. We believe that superannuation is a complex long-term business and we believe that accountability is a very important thing," he said.
"The Superannuation Industry (Supervision) Act places responsibility on the trustee [to look after member's retirement funds] and what we have an issue with is where the promoters of the product aren't the trustee. We believe that the person promoting the product should be the person that has long-term accountability for what they are representing."
Under the SIS Act, super funds are allowed to outsource the functions of the trustee. They are also allowed to provide their trustee services to sub-funds and products that are set up underneath their prudential structure.
Alex Dunnin, Rainmaker's executive director of research and compliance, said this was how many of the newer superannuation products were being set up. It might be a technical point but it means these newer outfits should not be referred to as funds that report to APRA but instead as sub-funds or products, he explained.

"For it all to work properly you need to know you can trust the people running these products, they need to have investment credentials, the insurance needs to sharply priced, and you need to know who to call if something goes wrong,"  Mr Dunnin said.
Risks to the system

"For APRA ... this is one of the biggest risks to the system. Who is running these funds and products is more important than ever."
Tn. He was previously involved in Good Super, an ethical offering that saw ASIC fine the trustee $20,000 for a misleading website.

Zuper's founders come from Tyro Payments and
Allens Linklaters partner Michelle Levy said the outsourced structure presented challenges to APRA from an oversight perspective, challenges she also doesn't believe the regulator has looked at yet.
"APRA is so busy looking at industry funds, I don't think they are looking at these sorts of funds that are providing 'badged' products," she said.
"'In short, they are nothing more than a branding exercise and clever marketing and branding is no substitute for good trusteeship and is a poor basis upon which to decide to contribute to a superannuation fund (or rollover).

"The greatest risk with these sorts of products where the trustee is effectively an outsourced provider to the promoter is that the trustee doesn't have proper oversight and control of the product."
An APRA spokesman said he could not comment on specific funds or investigations.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>TN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trustee Partners</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zuper</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Superannuation Industry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grow Super</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Human Super</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Atlassian-backed Spaceship</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mobi Super</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>APRA</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Dunnin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Prudential Regulation Authority</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michelle Levy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX-listed Onevue's Diversa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phil Vernon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASIC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Good Super</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tyro Payments</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Allens Linklaters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Ethical</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX-listed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tidswell Financial</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SIS Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Dunnin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
