<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651446592272670953</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/trump-attacks-blumenthals-military-service-heres-the-real-story-2017-8</url>
  <title>Trump is again attacking Sen. Richard Blumenthal over his military service  --  here's the real story</title>
  <content>
President Donald Trump unleashed a series of  Monday morning blasting Democratic Sen. Richard Blumenthal about his Vietnam War record.

The tweets came just minutes after the senator  Trump for "politicizing" the Justice Department and saying that any collusion between Russia and Trump campaign "must be pursued."

"Interesting to watch Senator Richard Blumenthal of Connecticut talking about hoax Russian collusion when he was a phony Vietnam con artist!" Trump .

"He told stories about his Vietnam battles and conquests, how brave he was, and it was all a lie," Trump added. "He cried like a baby and begged for forgiveness like a child. Now he judges collusion?"

But the truth about Blumenthal's military record might be a little more nuanced than Trump let on.

During Blumenthal's senate campaign in 2010, The New York Times  that some of his past statements about his military service were misleading.

"I served during the Vietnam era," Blumenthal  in 2008. "I remember the taunts, the insults, sometimes even physical abuse."

"We have learned something important since the days that I served in Vietnam," the senator also  in 2008.

In truth, between 1965 and 1970, Blumenthal did  at least five military deferments, and in April 1970, when his last deferment was in jeopardy, he got assigned to the Marine Corps Reserves.

"The Reserves were not being activated for Vietnam and were seen as a shelter for young privileged men," David Curry, a professor at the University of Missouri at St. Louis,  the Times in 2010.

Despite his successful attempts to avoid combat, Blumenthal did  for six years in the Marine Reserves, where he was stationed at Parris Island for six months and then later in Washington, DC.

Blumenthal has not always been misleading about his military service.

"Although I did not serve in Vietnam, I have seen first hand the effects of military action," Blumenthal  in a speech before the 2010 Times article came out. Some even  the misleading statements he made were taken out of context.

Still, the day after the 2010 New York Times article was released, Blumenthal  for any past misleading statements.

"On a few occasions I have misspoken about my service and I regret that, and I will take full responsibility," Blumenthal  at a press conference the day after the article was published. "But I will not allow anyone to take a few misplaced words and impugn my record of service to this country."

In any event, there appears to be  of Blumenthal ever crying "like a baby and begged for forgiveness like a child," as Trump tweeted.

Trump, like Blumenthal, also  five military deferments during the Vietnam War for bone spurs and never saw any combat.

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Curry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Richard Blumenthal of Connecticut</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2.2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ST. LOUIS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marine Corps Reserve</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Missouri</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marine Reserve</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blumenthal</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vietnam</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parris Island</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reserves</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York Times</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justice Department</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sen. Richard Blumenthal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vietnam War</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Democratic Sen. Richard Blumenthal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 1970</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
