<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651446575092801485</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:16</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/casey-joins-birdsville-races-volunteer-workforce/3209733/</url>
  <title>Casey joins Birdsville Races' volunteer workforce</title>
  <content>
BEERWAH'S Casey Bourke is gearing up for a taste of outback adventure as she prepares to travel more than 25 hours and 1584km to volunteer at this year's Birdsville Races.
Australia's oldest and most remote thoroughbred racing carnival is running on September 1 and 2 this year - the 135th edition of the event.
The two-day meet sees the small township of Birdsville - with a regular population of 115 - swell to about 7000 as thousands of racegoers flock from across Australian to revel in an outback experience like no other.
Not just a dusty good-time in the bush, the races present an opportunity to give back to the community, with the event raising funds for the Royal Flying Doctor Service of Australia - a vital charity that provides help to remote areas often cut off from medical services, as well as inter-hospital transfer services between metropolitan areas.
A colourful character - and one of Birdsville's youngest volunteers - Casey, 32, has been working in the hospitality industry for seven years.
Starting off as a waitress at a local restaurant in Year 10, Casey has continued to pursue her career in hospitality, catering for large events - at one point serving up to 800 guests in one night.
At Birdsville, Casey will be volunteering on the hospitality team, using her experience in waiting and cleaning.
Volunteer registrations are still open at www.birdsvilleraces. com/Volunteer, with all volunteers required to be 18 or over.
Hyundai unveils its only fully-electric model in Australia
Work on next stage of redevelopment due to start next April
Coast's $18m rescue chopper has been shifted by Lifeflight
LIFESTYLE lure was stronger than a high-flying accountancy career.
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
A NATIONAL exhibition of ceramic art has been launched on the Coast
BREAKING: New festival coming to the Sunshine Coast
ONE of Hollywood's most adorable couples is over.
New celebrity cooking show fails to fire for Seven.
The legendary creator isn't so sure about how Netflix works.
*WARNING this story contains spoilers*
Make way for Mackay's newest tech start up
Planning documents lodged on behalf of site owners
Education, student accommodation, bars and music all key to future
Five dates through August for community to have its say on rock wall
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Birdsville Races</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BEERWAH'S Casey Bourke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast's $18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LifeFlight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Birdsville</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Casey</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hyundai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Flying Doctor Service of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Year 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
