<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445273717687237</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:13</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/outer-east/ringwood-east-cctv-not-switched-on-three-months-after-installation/news-story/3750f99d72a4ec1801012e09355fbaeb</url>
  <title>Camera red tape hinders sex attack probe</title>
  <content>
NEW security cameras at Ringwood East are still not operating three months after they were installed.
Police investigating a sex attack tried to gain CCTV footage from the Railway Ave cameras but discovered they were not even switched on.
Victoria Police sexual crime investigation unit Sergeant Phil Drews confirmed police were investigating an incident in the area but could not disclose further details.

Cafe Emjay owner Bill Buchanan, 75, who was punched in the face near the IGA supermarket in September last year, said the delay in switching on the cameras was crazy.

The Federal Government handed over $400,000 to install the cameras in Ringwood and Ringwood East in November 2014 but the council did nothing until Leader launched a campaign to get them installed.
In April this year the council confirmed security cameras would finally be installed and blamed Metro Trains and VicTrack for delays.
Mr Buchanan said police came around a couple of weeks ago asking traders if they had any footage of an incident that happened some time ago.
"Of course we didn't because our private cameras have a much shorter backlog, and the quality wouldn't be as good as the hi-tech ones installed by the council," he said.
Maroondah Council confirmed only one camera was working and the others were to be installed on Metro Trains and VicTrack land.
The council's planning and community director Phil Turner said the council had been "working closely" with Metro Trains and a contractor to finalise the project, which he said would be completed by the end of this month.
Mayor Tony Dib did not respond to a request for comment on why it was taking so long. Metro said it was working to have the cameras installed as soon as possible.

We explain the procedures involved in a criminal trial in Victoria

WHAT HAPPENS IN A CRIMINAL TRIAL?
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ringwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iGA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Metro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sergeant Phil Drews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ringwood East</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Buchanan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phil Turner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroondah Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCTV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VicTrack</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Buchanan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mayor Tony Dib</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Railway Ave</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Metro Trains</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HAPPENS IN A CRIMINAL TRIAL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cafe Emjay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
