<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651444741141731860</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Australian</source>
  <url>http://www.theaustralian.com.au/news/latest-news/kerobokan-prisoners-feel-heat-of-escape/news-story/04b39161f46220e6c5a10ad7ca43c656</url>
  <title>Kerobokan prisoners feel heat of escape</title>
  <content>
Prisoners at Bali's Kerobokan jail are facing more sweeps and an earlier lockdown, as Indonesian officials continue to be taunted on social media over the escape of Australian man Shaun Davidson.
In the most recent Facebook post purporting to belong to the Western Australian, the 33-year-old posted a photo of an airline seat on Friday, stating: "Another day another country and check out my leg room hahaha enjoy life".
Since Davidson's escape on June 19, Interpol and Bali authorities have been the target of constant jibes over his ability to remain on the run.
Prison guard Wayan Mudastra told AAP they were all "shocked" when the escape of Davidson and three other inmates became known.
"I pity those who were on shift that time. (They are) the ones being questioned the most."
One inmate at Kerobokan told AAP said they used to be locked down at 1am, now it is 11pm.
"Then at the morning ceremony - now, we must all come. (The inmates can) no longer be represented by the head of room only."
The inmate also said there were no more hand phones as they "were swept in (last month's) searching".
Prison governor, Tonny Nainggolan confirmed the increased sweeps and that Kerobokan had boosted staff by two people - 10 guards and two staff doing security.
In July Kerobokan housed about 1400 prisoners when it has a capacity of 325.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kerobokan</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indonesian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tonny Nainggolan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Davidson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Interpol</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bali's Kerobokan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bali</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wayan Mudastra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July Kerobokan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shaun Davidson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
