<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445767638936120</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>16:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/entertainment/tv-and-radio/new-doctor-who-jodie-whittaker-hopes-fans-dont-fear-a-female-time-lord-20170807-gxrbe9.html</url>
  <title>New Doctor Who Jodie Whittaker hopes fans don't fear a female time lord</title>
  <content>
London: Jodie Whittaker, the first woman cast as the lead role of the BBC's iconic sci-fi programme Doctor Who, expressed hopes on Monday that fans will embrace her role as a symbol of diversity rather than fear the shift from a man.
Whittaker, 35, breaks a tradition back to the start of the television series in 1963 that the Doctor is a man, travelling the universe as a "time lord" in a telephone box to protect the weak and combat evil aliens.

Up Next

Clip:
Sharknado 5

01:23

More Entertainment News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

01:23
Clip: Sharknado 5

Clip:
Sharknado 5

Showing off their acting skills, Karl Stefanovic and Lisa Wilkinson make an appearance in Sharknado 5, set in Sydney.

Up Next

Entertainment news highlights

02:09

02:09
Entertainment news highlights

Entertainment news highlights

Karl Stefanovic's new show, The Bachelor gets an RSPCA enquiry, Laurie Oaks retires, HBO gets hacked, ABC gets petitioned,and Elisabeth Moss doesn't nail the Aussie drawl.

Up Next
Australian Survivor 2017:
Tarzan moves on

01:20

01:20
Australian Survivor 2017: Tarzan moves on

Australian Survivor 2017:
Tarzan moves on

Saying he has no regrets the 51-year-old contestant who was affectionately dubbed Tarzan leaves the competition. Vision courtesy Australian Survivor facebook page

Up Next
Home and Away
legend defends Sam Frost

01:28

01:28
Home and Away legend defends Sam Frost

Home and Away
legend defends Sam Frost

'Get over it', Debra Lawrance, who played Pippa Ross on the long running soap bites back at critics who are unhappy with The Bachelorette moving into Summer Bay.

Up Next

Bachelorette Sam Frost chooses Sasha

00:42

00:42
Bachelorette Sam Frost chooses Sasha

Bachelorette Sam Frost chooses Sasha

Sam Frost picks builder Sasha Mielczarek during the first season of the Australian Bachelorette in 2015.

Up Next

Private Sydney: Roxy Jacenko chapter #3452

01:58

01:58
Private Sydney: Roxy Jacenko chapter #3452

Private Sydney: Roxy Jacenko chapter #3452

Things move fast on Planet Roxy. The troubles with her marriage, second weddings and diamond rings. Andrew Hornery investigates

Up Next

Al Gore: 'We are going to win' over climate change

01:27

It's a girl! The new
Doctor Who
is born

After intense speculation the new Doctor Who is revealed, and will be played by Jodie Whittaker.

"I hope, you know, my gender isn't a fearful thing for the fans," Whittaker told the BBC in her first broadcast interview since her casting was announced last month.
"In this world particularly -- there aren't rules and that's a great thing, you know, so hopefully, hopefully everyone is excited, as excited as I am."

Her casting was largely viewed positively by fans and commentators but some on social media argued that the role of the Doctor should not be played by a woman.
Whittaker said that she had missed the reactions as she was not a social media user.

Ultimately, Whittaker hopes that her casting will help fans of the programme to embrace diversity.
"Now we can say to young boys and young girls that the people that you potentially look up to or the characters that you love don't necessarily have to look the same as before -- you know, we can celebrate the fact of differences," she said.Photo: BBC
She told the BBC that she believed getting the role would be "a blessing and a curse", and expressed the hope that media interest in her personal life would die down: "It's not very exciting", she said.
Doctor Who is one of the BBC's most popular scripted programmes, and has inspired a devoted fanbase in several countries, with clubs, conventions and fan publications. She will be the 13th Doctor.
Whittaker replaces actor Peter Capaldi, who has played the programme's lead role since 2014. She has previously appeared in British crime drama Broadchurch, and British cult film Attack the Block, among other roles.
Her casting comes as the BBC deals with the public relations fallout from revelations that it pays its highest profile female on-air talent significantly less than men in comparable positions. 
Reuters
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BBC</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karl Stefanovic</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Debra Lawrance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Survivor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Frost</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HBO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lisa Wilkinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Bachelorette</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Capaldi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whittaker, 35</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sasha</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tarzans</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elisabeth Moss</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Planet Roxy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bachelorette Sam Frost</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whittaker</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bachelorette</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laurie Oaks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Hornery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broadchurch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Summer Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sharknado 5</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roxy Jacenko</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RSPCA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sasha Mielczarek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jodie Whittaker</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pippa Ross</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reuters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Survivor 2017</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Doctor Who Jodie Whittaker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Al Gore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
