<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651446596567638319</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:21</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/coast-electric-car-bays-on-the-charge/3209755/</url>
  <title>Coast electric car bays on the charge</title>
  <content>
ELECTRIC car charging stations are popping up on the Coast with drivers set for up to 150 more as demand increases.

A section of 10 charging points servicing up to 20 parking bays for the new breed of vehicles was launched at Sunshine Coast University Hospital on Monday by a touring team including representatives from ChargePoint and Hyundai.

ChargePoint Australia and New Zealand national manager Roy Unny said electric cars could be charged for free at most sites.

"ChargePoint is involved in the global roll out of electric vehicle charging infrastructure," Mr Unny said.

He said the hospital site was designed to eventually hold 180 electrical charging bays.

"We also have a charging location at Aura, with Stockland for their development."

He said they were set up in places such as shopping centres and hospitals where users could remain occupied while they waited for up to a couple of hours for full charge.

"The significance of having electric vehicle charging infrastructure is to ensure that the uptake of electric vehicles is easy for anybody who makes the decision to buy an electric vehicle."

He said his company wanted to expand to other sites on the Sunshine Coast.

"Whether it be workplaces, shopping centres, at home or on the go."

Hyundai Australia northern region business sales manager Louise Andrews took the opportunity to show off the only fully electric Hyundai car in Australia.

Miss Andrews said the Ioniq would be built in hybrid, plug-in hybrid or fully electric models.

At least one of those variations is expected to be launched in Australia at the end of the year.

Seqwater facing massive shortfall because we are waterwise
University of the Sunshine Coast turns over a new leaf
Work on next stage of redevelopment due to start next April
LIFESTYLE lure was stronger than a high-flying accountancy career.
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
A NATIONAL exhibition of ceramic art has been launched on the Coast
BREAKING: New festival coming to the Sunshine Coast
ONE of Hollywood's most adorable couples is over.
New celebrity cooking show fails to fire for Seven.
The legendary creator isn't so sure about how Netflix works.
*WARNING this story contains spoilers*
Make way for Mackay's newest tech start up
Planning documents lodged on behalf of site owners
Education, student accommodation, bars and music all key to future
Five dates through August for community to have its say on rock wall
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of the Sunshine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ChargePoint Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louise Andrews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seqwater</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Unny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ioniq</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast University Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hyundai</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stockland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ChargePoint</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hyundai Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roy Unny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
