<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445011724676785</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/accounting/battle-weary-cpa-members-cautious-on-board-moves-20170807-gxqvlz</url>
  <title>Battle weary CPA members cautious on board moves </title>
  <content>
Rebel CPA Australia members have cautiously welcomed moves by the "old guard" board to retire early but still have questions about how a new board will be chosen at the nation's largest accounting body.
The remaining CPA directors announced their early retirement on Friday in a move to appease members angry at their continued presence. Another  was that the body's Nomination and Remuneration Committee will now include external members Rhonda O'Donnell, Leanne Rowe and Geoff Rees, along with chairman Jim Dickson and another current director, Tim Youngberry.
Members have been calling for the current CPA directors to all go after they oversaw a period at the body where seven of their number resigned and former .
CPA member Glen Hasselman welcomed the announcement but questioned how the members of the next CPA could be selected while an inquiry, led by former auditor general Ian McPhee, was still ongoing.

"The [existing] directors seem to have recognised that it is wrong for them to control the selection process for [the new] directors so they have given up some control, but they gave it to external non-members. These non-members are simply not accountable to members and neither are the directors they appoint," he said.

Mr Hasselman is part of a group of members that has put together a board spill petition, which now has two-thirds, or 3790, of the required 6000 members required to call an emergency meeting.
Another outspoken member, Greg Angelo, was against having the two existing directors on the nomination committee.
"Dickson and Youngberry will wield undue influence and should resile from any decision-making whatsoever. The current rump and the board should [also] have no say whatsoever in the search for new CEO because of their appalling mismanagement of the old one," Mr Angelo said.
CPA spokesman Stuart Dignam said the early retirement of the current directors and the new committee members struck "a prudent balance between providing business continuity and delivering orderly succession."

"Mr Dickson brings invaluable knowledge and experience of the membership to the process but his will be one voice in five," Mr Dignam said, adding that the CPA director recruitment process was "well advanced" with two separate rounds of applications for nine director positions and more than 200 applications in total received.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leanne Rowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Angelo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Dickson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stuart Dignam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glen Hasselman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dickson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian McPhee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Remuneration Committees</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CPA Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Angelo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Youngberry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Dignam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jim Dickson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hasselman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rhonda O'Donnell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Youngberry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CPA</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geoff Rees</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
