<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651446338869596745</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>18:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/us-employment-gains-have-been-unusually-steady-in-recent-years-2017-8</url>
  <title>There's one remarkable trend in the jobs numbers that few people are noticing</title>
  <content>
Trump's view of US job numbers has changed now that he's in office and wants credit

One remarkable trend in US employment has been the stability of monthly gains

Weak wages, low inflation suggest things could still get a lot better

Donald Trump was quick to take credit for a solid July employment report, despite  when it happened to point to strength under former President Barack Obama

The president took to his preferred medium, Twitter, to sing his own praises:

However, as my colleague Bob Bryan noted,  looks very much like it did under Obama.

Indeed, one remarkable trend of the recent economic recovery, , has been the incredibly steady pace of job-market gains, which once fluctuated much more drastically from month to month.

"To our mind what is truly remarkable is the stability of this jobs growth, not solely its headline strength," said Rick Rieder, BlackRock's chief investment officer, in a statement following the employment report.

"Not only is the persistence of this hiring incredible, but the simultaneous evolution and growth of a more service-oriented economy was once again on display with today's numbers, with service jobs making up 88% of July new jobs, close to in-line with the five year average." 

"To put that data into context, since 1970, or for virtually the past 50 years, the U.S. economy has had less than a 4.3% unemployment rate for only 4.0% of the time, with virtually all of that taking place between 1999 and 2001, so this underscores the strength of the current labour market recovery," Rieder said.

"The stability of hiring during this cycle has been nothing short of remarkable. It is not just that the system has created 16.8 million jobs since 2010, during a period of rapid implementation of automation and job-replacement software, but the stability and sustainability of this job recovery is truly historic," Rieder argues. 

Still, many economists say the headline jobless rate , reflecting  that continue to plague the job market.

That softness has made Federal Reserve officials reluctant to continue raising interest rates, with most investors . In the meantime, the Fed is expected to announced the timing of its plans  

Excellent Jobs Numbers just released - and I have only just begun. Many job stifling regulations continue to fall. Movement back to USA!
- Donald J. Trump (@realDonaldTrump)

The US labour market under Trump (so far) looks... almost exactly the same as the US labour market under Obama
- Bob Bryan (@RobertBryan4)

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>RobertBryan4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Reserve</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>U.S</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Obama</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jobs Numbers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rick Rieder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bob Bryan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Barack Obama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rieder</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BlackRock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald J. Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>realDonaldTrump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
