<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651446570797834129</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:15</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/lyns-getting-a-run-on-with-marathon-fundraising-ef/3209721/</url>
  <title>Lyn's getting a run on with marathon fundraising effort</title>
  <content>
ANYONE who sees Lyn Mills pounding the pavement and braving the hills near Nambour Hospital could be forgiven for thinking she is a "spring chicken".
But at 65, Lyn shows that age has no bounds as she tackles the tough path of a marathon runner.
Showcasing a clear determination and a contagious enthusiasm, she is ready to take on the half marathon in the Sunshine Coast Marathon and Community Run Festival on August 20.
Having done the five kilometres successfully last year, Lyn is stepping up a level this year.
"What the heck, I've got to give it a go," she said.
"I'll be finishing it.
"I am only 65. I can do it.
"I am only competing against myself and there is something about knowing that all my training has been worthwhile.
"There is something I have found that I enjoy about running: just like paddling, it helps me clear my head and add to the fact that I am helping a charity and I am there."
Braving the elements and pushing her body to the edge isn't new for Lyn who regularly competes in outrigging canoe events.
She decided to try running for something different in the off-season.
But Lyn isn't just doing the marathon to see if how far she can push her body.
She is fundraising for Orange Sky Laundry.
Asked why she chose this charity, Lyn said people usually took for granted their ability to do the washing or have a shower, but some didn't have that "luxury".
"We all can be up high one day and then down there tomorrow so it is good to see an organisation like Orange Sky Laundry is providing this valuable service for homeless people," she said.
"It costs the organisation $6 per load.
"And they also offer the homeless a shower facility which also costs Orange Sky $3 per shower.
"So if I can help in some small way, then I am happy."
To donate to this much-needed service and help Lyn reach her $800 goal, visit  and type in Lyn Mills.
Hyundai unveils its only fully-electric model in Australia
Work on next stage of redevelopment due to start next April
Coast's $18m rescue chopper has been shifted by Lifeflight
LIFESTYLE lure was stronger than a high-flying accountancy career.
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
A NATIONAL exhibition of ceramic art has been launched on the Coast
BREAKING: New festival coming to the Sunshine Coast
ONE of Hollywood's most adorable couples is over.
New celebrity cooking show fails to fire for Seven.
The legendary creator isn't so sure about how Netflix works.
*WARNING this story contains spoilers*
Make way for Mackay's newest tech start up
Planning documents lodged on behalf of site owners
Education, student accommodation, bars and music all key to future
Five dates through August for community to have its say on rock wall
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Marathon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lyn</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lyn Mills</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast's $18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LifeFlight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Orange Sky Laundry</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Community Run Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hyundai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Orange Sky $3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
