<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651446575092801537</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:16</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/the-last-cane-train-into-nambour/3208312/</url>
  <title>The last cane train into Nambour</title>
  <content>
NAMBOUR'S Peter Hayward recalls starting work at Moreton Sugar Mill in 1989. His first position was a "navie" in a gang that replaced sleepers and handled derailments.
"It was hard work, as it was only pick and shovels back then and mobile air compressors we towed with the Melcomore loco," he said.
"We used jack hammers to beat the crusher dust under the sleeper to form a hard footing."
Later, Peter took up a position as fireman, loco driver's assistant.
"The fireman was back in the steam train days: the assistant shovels coal, and that's where the fireman name came into it."
In his career, he drove "Coolum", "Bli Bli", "Jamaica", "Dunethin", "Petrie", "Valdora" and "Maroochy" but says his favourite was "Coolum".
"It was a bigger loco and it just floated as it was bogie driven," he explained.
While working for the mill, Peter's uniform consisted of green King Gee shorts and shirt.
He has fond memories of his dad Charlie Hayward. He also drove the cane trains, and let his son drive them when he was a youngster.
"You wouldn't get away with that today," Peter laughed.
He remembers the day he went for his train ticket in the '90s.
"I had James Attewell and Darrel Woods observe me drive "Moreton" that day: top blokes and friends of my dad's."
He said the closure of the mill was sad.
"It was very upsetting to find out it was my last year in 2003, as I wanted to retire at the mill," Peter said.
"It was a great place to work and great blokes I worked with. It was like a happy family.
"I was on midnight shift the last night in December 2003 and I missed out seeing the other workers as they were down at the pub while I finished my shift.
"It was a sad day.
"I remember someone stole the whistle on the roof that night and the Coolum name plate was also taken."
Before dark, the loco crews lined up for photos. The final run was to be special with large signs attached to the last bin.
They assembled at Howard St, in the dark with headlights and amber flashing warning lights on, providing a sad scene in the falling rain.
For one last time, about 9.45pm, "Bli Bli" led a loaded cane rake down Howard St, with "Coolum" banking and "Moreton" and "Petrie" behind.
The locomotive's horns were blown continuously so everyone in Nambour knew that an era had ended as the train entered the mill yard.
Hyundai unveils its only fully-electric model in Australia
Work on next stage of redevelopment due to start next April
Coast's $18m rescue chopper has been shifted by Lifeflight
LIFESTYLE lure was stronger than a high-flying accountancy career.
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
A NATIONAL exhibition of ceramic art has been launched on the Coast
BREAKING: New festival coming to the Sunshine Coast
ONE of Hollywood's most adorable couples is over.
New celebrity cooking show fails to fire for Seven.
The legendary creator isn't so sure about how Netflix works.
*WARNING this story contains spoilers*
Make way for Mackay's newest tech start up
Planning documents lodged on behalf of site owners
Education, student accommodation, bars and music all key to future
Five dates through August for community to have its say on rock wall
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dunethin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlie Hayward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melcomore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAMBOUR'S Peter Hayward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bli Bli</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast's $18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LifeFlight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coolum</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Attewell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moreton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moreton Sugar Mill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King Gee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Howard St</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2003</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamaica</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hyundai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Petrie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Valdora</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darrel Woods</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
