<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651446287329988457</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>18:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/questnews/southwest/australian-ninja-warrior-mum-launches-first-state-competition/news-story/c4c693488246b0bd904b49a2e360ea04</url>
  <title>Queensland gets own Ninja warrior comp</title>
  <content>
IF you sat on your couch watching Australian Ninja Warrior sure you could blitz some of the muscle-busting obstacles then it's time to put your muscle where your mouth is.
This weekend is round one of the inaugural Queensland Ninja Cup tri-series, and the courses are designed and owned by three Ninja alumni.
Round one is August 12 at Centenary Play Ground, Darra, owned and operated by Australian Ninja Warrior and kick-ass mum of two Emma Teede, 41.
Three years ago the gym owner celebrated lifting one kilogram after a brutal CrossFit shoulder injury threatened to squash her fitness career.
Upon meeting her, it is instantly obvious that this Wonder Woman's strength is as much in her "never say die" attitude as it is in her biceps.
"I don't want to be Australia's whinger, I want to be Australia's Ninja," she said after recounting the 2015 injury.
She said she would have been happy to simply lift the weight of her arm after the surgery.
Emma Teede, Australian Ninja Warrior

But she did, and two years later she was the women's national masters weightlifting champion.
Fast forward to the Channel 9 smash hit  and Ms Teede, dubbed Mumma Bear by her fellow ninjas, was flying through obstacles that had Mr Universe wiping out.
She had never watched a full episode before she was selected from about 10,000 applicants as one of 200 to compete on the world-class Sydney obstacle course.
In fact, she learned the rules only when she arrived.
"I was so crazy raw," she laughed.
"It blew my mind, but I just had to be like, 'Alright, bring it on'."
She blitzed some of the hardest obstacles, in particular the Bomb Slider, but splashed out before completing the course.

Confusion reigned as Australian Ninja Warrior's grand final wrapped up without actually crowning anyone Australia's Ninja Warrior. Courtesy: Nine

Who actually won Australian Ninja Warrior?
"I was absolutely stoked with where I got to and it gave me confidence in what I can do," Ms Teede said.
"I'm a person who never wanted to be the rock star. I always wanted to be the coach and help other people become the rock star," she said.
Ms Teede had teamed up with fellow ninjas and gym owners Lachlan Fyfe and Shane Elisara, to host the inaugural Queensland Ninja Cup.
Anyone can give it a shot, but ninjas must compete in all three rounds, scheduled at three separate gyms on August 12, September 16 and October 22, to be crowned the state's first ninja champion
Among the Ninja warrior obstacles ready to test Queensland's best are the five step, flying fox, tramp to cargo net, cannonball alley and the towering warp wall.
The second round will be held in north Brisbane, and the third on the Gold Coast.
For more information and to register, visit  or call Emma on 0419 592 777.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ninjas</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane Elisara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia's Ninja</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wonder Woman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Teede</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Universe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lachlan Fyfe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emma</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emma Teede</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Ninja Warrior</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Ninja Cup</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CrossFit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 16</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 22</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bomb Slider</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 12</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia's Ninja Warrior</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Centenary Play Ground</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mumma Bear</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
