<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651446579387768845</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:17</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/it-was-harvest-time-when-the-skies-turned-red/3208305/</url>
  <title>It was harvest time when the skies turned red</title>
  <content>
LEX Campbell is probably the oldest born-and-bred Bli Bli cane farmer still living in the area.
His family ties with Bli Bli started in 1912 when his grandfather bought land there and began farming citrus and pineapples (including setting up their own cannery) and working an oyster lease in the Maroochy River, south of the David Low Bridge.
His father Donald bought land between Petrie Creek and Eudlo Creek in 1920 and established the family cane farm which Lex started working on after leaving school in 1947, at the age of 14.
Some of his memories of Bli Bli over the last 50 years include: 
In 1967 there were many changes happening in Bli Bli. It was still a small, quiet rural community but was now more accessible from other areas due to Petrie Creek bridge being constructed in 1962 and Eudlo Creek bridge soon after. The David Low Bridge across the Maroochy River had been built in 1959.
Lex was living with wife Fay and two young sons in the cane barracks north of Petrie Creek. For the safety of the boys, he thought it best to build a low fence around the barracks because of the "heavy" traffic appearing on David Low Way.
He was now share-farming the family's Petrie Creek property as well as two smaller farms nearer the castle. Soon after he also bought 10 hectares off Diddillibah Rd and later took a lease on the Mill farm in Fisherman's Rd.
This meant driving tractors and harvesters on the roads between farms which was quite manageable in those days because of the light traffic - it would be virtually impossible to do it now.
The Bli Bli State School was continuing to grow slowly - there was still only one building with a shelter shed and tennis court but it was now a two-teacher school. It has since expanded significantly in numbers with many new buildings and additional sports field areas across the road.  
The only shop in Bli Bli for many years had been Mcbride's General Store (now the Quirky Circle cafe) at David Low Bridge - a far cry from the large shopping centre of today.
A new landmark appeared in 1973 when the Fairytale Castle was built. It was quite imposing - standing on a knoll looking out over the river and canefields.
It is said it attracted one million visitors in the first three years of operation. Several extensions and renovations occurred over the following years.
The local sugar industry (which had started officially in Bli Bli in 1897) was also going through major changes. Mechanical harvesters had replaced the gangs of handcutters in the late 1950s.
The early harvesters were "whole stick" cutters - stalks were cut in whole lengths, bundled and then loaded onto the back of trucks.

By the late 1970s, harvesters had progressed to "choppers", which cut each stalk into 30cm pieces and spat them into bins being towed by tractors beside the harvester.
The crop had to be burnt to remove the thrash and make it easier to cut. These fires were impressive - always a drawcard and many stopped to watch. In the '80s and '90s it wasn't unusual to have 30 cars pulled over on the side of the road.
Not everyone was impressed, however, as some newcomers to the area complained about the black ash from fires settling on their clean washing or in their pools.
Later improvements to harvesters meant that the cane could be cut green and fires were phased out.
Lex also had some humorous moments with onlookers - a Victorian couple once came up to him and asked if he could cut a stalk in half and show them how the sugar poured out.
Locomotives collected the bins from each farm and hauled them to the mill in Nambour. This usually worked well but there were the occasional derailments.
The locos also had to cross roads on the way and there were some bingles involving cars. At night the long line of bins were not always well lit and cars would run into them.
Two sections of the track remain - in Nambour from the Howard marshalling yards to the old mill site (now Coles) and from Coolum to the Maroochy River rail bridge at Dunethin Rock. 
The Nambour and District Show was always a highlight on the calendar and attracted big crowds. The cane displays were a feature and there was intense rivalry between the Bli Bli and Maroochy River district growers to see who could present the best displays and win the prizes for longest stalk, thickest stalk and highest sugar content.
Farmers would spend several days before the show scouring their fields for winning stalks.
The closure of the Moreton Mill in Nambour in 2003 came as a bit of a shock and essentially meant the end of the industry on the coast. The closure came not long after the Belgian company Finasucre had purchased Bundaberg Sugar.
A combination of factors lead to the closure - world sugar prices were very low and, nearly 1000 hectares of cane growing land had been lost to development or other purposes.
Moreton Mill had been crushing cane since the turn of last century and when it closed it had reached an annual crush of approximately 660,000 tonnes. During the six months from July to December the mill operated 24/7 - the thick brown sweet smoke coming out of the tall stack was a feature of Nambour during the season.
There were only two major breakdowns - firstly when a boiler blew up and stopped the mill for a couple of weeks and secondly when the bagasse (dried cane skin/pith) loft caught fire.
A Coles supermarket now occupies the mill site.
Some cane is still grown for baling as mulch or for transport to the Maryborough mill for processing. A consortium of farmers also tried to establish a stock fodder enterprise ("cow candy") using sugar cane and aimed at the Asian market. This unfortunately was quashed when Chinese backers withdrew their funding for the project.
The sugar industry was very important to the economy of the Sunshine Coast. Residential development has occurred on some of the farms, the Maroochy River Golf Course has been constructed on another, but it is good that the majority of the green belt has been preserved to maintain some of the rural feel of Bli Bli.
Hyundai unveils its only fully-electric model in Australia
Work on next stage of redevelopment due to start next April
Coast's $18m rescue chopper has been shifted by Lifeflight
LIFESTYLE lure was stronger than a high-flying accountancy career.
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
A NATIONAL exhibition of ceramic art has been launched on the Coast
BREAKING: New festival coming to the Sunshine Coast
ONE of Hollywood's most adorable couples is over.
New celebrity cooking show fails to fire for Seven.
The legendary creator isn't so sure about how Netflix works.
*WARNING this story contains spoilers*
Make way for Mackay's newest tech start up
Planning documents lodged on behalf of site owners
Education, student accommodation, bars and music all key to future
Five dates through August for community to have its say on rock wall
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fisherman's Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lex</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eudlo Creek</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mcbride's General Store</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Petrie Creek</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dunethin Rock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bli Bli</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diddillibah Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast's $18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bundaberg Sugar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Finasucre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LifeFlight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coolum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quirky Circle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Low Bridge</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1.3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maryborough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coles</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy River Golf Course</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>District Show</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy River</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LEX Campbell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bli Bli State School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Low Way</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hyundai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belgian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Howard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairytale Castle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moreton Mill</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
