<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445771933903524</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>16:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/world/donald-trump-insists-support-for-him-is-stronger-than-ever-while-lashing-out-at-democratic-rival/news-story/fd5909ee72ff2b7d7bbd129448e33b7d</url>
  <title>Trump lashes out at rival on Twitter</title>
  <content>
DONALD Trump is insisting his support is stronger than ever, despite a report that some Republicans are weighing a 2020 presidential run without him.
In a flurry of early morning tweets, Mr Trump said "the Trump base far bigger & stronger than ever before (despite some phony Fake News polling)."
He specifically criticised the "failing nytimes."
The New York Times detailed efforts by some Republicans looking ahead to 2020, including Vice President Mike Pence. Pence called the report false.
Mr Trump also tweeted that he is "working hard" from his private golf club in central New Jersey, while the White House heating and cooling system is repaired, and plans to head to New York next week for "more meetings."
White House spokeswoman Lindsay Walters said Monday that Mr Trump will return to his hometown for part of the first half of next week. She did not provide more details.
The president has not spent a night at his residence in Trump Tower since his inauguration in January.
He also reiterated his personal attacks on Democratic Senator Richard Blumenthal, calling him a "phony Vietnam con artist" after the politician expressed concerns about the Justice Department's pursuit of leakers and embraced a special counsel's probe of Russia meddling in the election and possible collusion with Trump campaign officials.

The failing , which has made every wrong prediction about me including my big election win (apologized), is totally inept!

The Trump base is far bigger &  stronger than ever before (despite some phony Fake News polling). Look at rallies in Penn, Iowa, Ohio.......

...and West Virginia. The fact is the Fake News Russian collusion story, record Stock Market, border security, military strength, jobs.....

... Supreme Court pick, economic enthusiasm, deregulation & so much more have driven the Trump base even closer together. Will never change!

Hard to believe that with 24/7  News on CNN, ABC, NBC, CBS, NYTIMES & WAPO, the Trump base is getting stronger!

In a series of tweets from his holiday in New Jersey, Mr Trump dismissed the "hoax Russian collusion" and revived a 2010 embarrassment for Mr Blumenthal.
The Connecticut politician, a Marine Corps reservist during Vietnam, had to apologise for saying he had served in the war.
"Interesting to watch Senator Richard Blumenthal of Connecticut talking about hoax Russian collusion when he was a phony Vietnam con artist!" Mr Trump tweeted. "Never in US history has anyone lied or defrauded voters like Senator Richard Blumenthal. He told stories about his Vietnam battles and ... conquests, how brave he was, and it was all a lie. He cried like a baby and begged for forgiveness like a child. Now he judges collusion?"
Mr Blumenthal later responded to Mr Trump on Twitter, saying: "Mr. President: Your bullying hasn't worked before and it won't work now. No one is above the law." And adding, "This issue isn't about me - it's about the Special Counsel's independence and integrity."
Mr Trump's criticism overnight came shortly after Mr Blumenthal, a member of the Senate Judiciary Committee, was interviewed on CNN.
The senator discussed several topics, including the Justice Department's crackdown on leakers, new sanctions on North Korea and reports that special counsel Robert Mueller has empaneled a grand jury in his inquiry into Russia meddling and potential ties to the Trump campaign.
"I'm very concerned that the Department of Justice is weaponising these laws for its personal and political ends, and specifically for the White House's purposes," Mr Blumenthal said.
He warned of a "chilling effect on the press and whistleblowers." The two-term Connecticut senator and former state Attorney-General credited the media for its reporting on the Trump administration. He said Mueller's investigation must be pursued.

Working hard from New Jersey while White House goes through long planned renovation. Going to New York next week for more meetings.

Interesting to watch Senator Richard Blumenthal of Connecticut talking about hoax Russian collusion when he was a  phony Vietnam con artist!

Interesting to watch Senator Richard Blumenthal of Connecticut talking about hoax Russian collusion when he was a  phony Vietnam con artist!

Interesting to watch Senator Richard Blumenthal of Connecticut talking about hoax Russian collusion when he was a  phony Vietnam con artist!

"The impanelment of the grand jury shows that Bob Mueller is pursuing this potential wrongdoing by the Russians, the attack on our democracy, seriously and diligently. There is no minimising ... that attack by the Russians," Mr Blumenthal said, before pointing out the "potential collusion by the Trump campaign and then obstruction of justice."
He said "that investigation must be pursued." It wasn't the first time that Trump had raised the issue of Mr Blumenthal and Vietnam. Earlier this year, Mr Trump accused Mr Blumenthal of misrepresenting Neil Gorsuch's comments from a private meeting. Mr Blumenthal said Mr Gorsuch, who was confirmed to the Supreme Court, had told him that he found the president's attacks on the judiciary "disheartening" and "demoralising."
In response, Mr Trump said during a lunch with senators that Mr Blumenthal had misrepresented Mr Gorsuch. "His comments were misrepresented. And what you should do is ask Senator Blumenthal about his Vietnam record that didn't exist after years of saying it did," he said.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marine Corps</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Special Counsel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vice President Mike Pence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fake News Russian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Attorney-General</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stock Market</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump Tower</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OHIO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Richard Blumenthal of Connecticut</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Justice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Virginia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Blumenthal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Richard Blumenthal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neil Gorsuch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WaPo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. President</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mueller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Gorsuch</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NYTimes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vietnam</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Republicans</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lindsay Walters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>11</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Trump</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Mueller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York Times</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justice Department</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Democratic Senator Richard Blumenthal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bob Mueller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Blumenthal</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate Judiciary Committee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Jersey</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Penn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Supreme Court</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CNN</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Connecticut</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fake News</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iowa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
