<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651446248675282321</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>18:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/unc-footballs-new-practice-uniforms-appear-to-be-giant-ads-for-nike-2017-8</url>
  <title>UNC Football's new practice uniforms appear to be giant ads for Nike</title>
  <content>
Uniform advertisements are nothing new in sports, but the University of North Carolina football team is taking the concept to a new level with their practice uniforms.

The Tar Heels football team have revealed new practice uniforms for the 2017 season, and it looks like the folks at Jordan Brand , the Nike-owned subsidiary buoyed by one of the greatest basketball players of all time, will get some nice publicity out of them.

Take a look:

Taking on a uniform sponsor isn't such a big deal in and of itself, but this is an extreme case. Jordan's famous Jumpman insignia completely replaces any kind of UNC logo - the chin strap is the school's lone identifying mark.

The program's regular home and away uniforms will continue to prominently display UNC's logo, though the Jumpman will remain in a smaller capacity. All team sneakers and apparel are provided by Jordan Brand.

"I'm so excited about bringing UNC football into the Jordan,"  Larry Fedora, the team's head coach. "It doesn't get any better than that, really. If you think about it, I promise you, when our guys run out of that tunnel onto that field, wearing that Jumpman logo, they're gonna be jacked. Wearing that Jordan brand on your chest is like wearing a badge of honour."

Michael Jordan, a proud alumnus of UNC, averaged 17.7 points and 5.0 rebounds in three seasons for the Tar Heels. He led them to an NCAA Championship in 1982, and it seems his influence on the school's athletic programs hasn't gone away yet.

The Tar Heels will kick off their season on September 2 against the California Golden Bears.

New practice helmet for .
- UNC Equipment (@UNCEquipment)

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nike</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jordan Brand</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UNC Football</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nike-owned</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Larry Fedora</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UNC</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of North</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UNC Equipment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Jordan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jordan</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NCAA Championships</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UNCEquipment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tar Heels</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carolinas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California Golden Bears</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
