<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651446545028029857</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/real-estate/queensland/gen-y-buyer-wins-innercity-bargain-in-one-of-brisbanes-hottest-suburbs/news-story/965c7b6e7e338e9a835ae9a5060e4f4d</url>
  <title>Gen Y buyer wins inner-city bargain in one of Brisbane's hottest suburbs - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
A unit in this building that generated strong public feedback has sold to a millennial investor. Picture: Realestate.com.au

A GEN Y investor has beat hundreds of interested parties to win a property that was billed Brisbane's best inner-city bargain.
Over 350 people were interested in the studio apartment at 902/188 Shafston Avenue in Kangaroo Point, which was listed at offers over $130,000.
The property deal went unconditional at $150,000, with the millennial buyer making just the one offer.

The view from the rooftop gym. Picture: Realestate.com.au

The property is in high demand Kangaroo Point, a suburb that's just a hop across the river to the CBD. Picture: Realestate.com.au

The building has common chill zones. Picture: Realestate.com.au

It's believed the millennial buyer intends to continue to have the property rented out.
It currently fetches around $250 a week, which equates to a rental return of just over 8 per cent.
Real estate agent Solomon Michael of Coronis Coorparoo sealed the deal within three weeks of marketing the property as an urgent sale.
"This owner needs it sold as soon as possible," he had said.

The studio kitchen is functional. Picture: Realestate.com.au

The property is perfect as an inner-city base. Picture: Realestate.com.au

It's almost like a large hotel room with a fully functioning kitchen. Picture: Realestate.com.au

With no car accommodation but located just across the river from the Brisbane CBD, the property was said to be great for investors or those who wanted a cost effective inner city base.
The 21sq m unit was in a complex with two shared gyms - one indoor, one outdoor, and across the river from the bustling Fortitude Valley entertainment precinct.
*</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Realestate</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gen Y</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Solomon Michael of Coronis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kangaroo Point</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fortitude Valley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shafston Avenue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coorparoo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
