<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445265127752388</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/opinion/editorial-gutwein-has-only-one-option/news-story/39cbe9a4f2624cc24c86b52f795b3bb6</url>
  <title>Gutwein has only one option</title>
  <content>
TODAY, Local Government Minister Peter Gutwein is again expected to suspend Glenorchy City Council aldermen for the next six months.
Mr Gutwein has but one option. The elected members cannot be allowed to return. The board of inquiry report is yet to be publicly released and deep divisions remain. The matter is still before the courts as key players seek to prevent having details released publicly and the whole process continues to burn a hole in the pockets of ratepayers.
Commissioner Sue Smith must stay where she is until the report is released, resolutions reached and a pathway forward determined.
This is not a process which can be rushed.
The claims in the board of inquiry report, even if they are only partially true, beggar belief.
There is one paragraph which stands out above many others: "Council's lack of an appropriate oversight of its operations has contributed to the loss of experienced and valuable senior managers through termination, redundancy and resignation. Additionally this lack of oversight has contributed to the council's failure to finish the KGV development, despite having an original finishing date of December 2014; council's failure to progress the development at Wilkinsons Point; and council's failure to progress the CBD revitalisation projects."
It goes on to list similar serious concerns about tendering processes, the use of consultants and lawyers.
And then we move on to the "animosity, defiance, distrust and lack of willingness to work together for the good of the council and the community ..."
It is a damning indictment on many, many levels.
Mrs Smith and her new senior team need to be given time and space to clean up this mess. That work can only start once the possibility of this council being returned is erased, once and for all.
Adelaide link a step in right direction
THE return of direct flights between Hobart and Adelaide for the first time in seven years is to be welcomed.
Jetstar on Monday announced flights between the two state capitals three times a week would start in mid-November.
This came after fellow budget carrier Tiger canned its service due to a lack of demand in 2010.
And Premier Will Hodgman did not miss the chance to push for a return of Australian Federal Police officers to the airport, following their withdrawal for budgetary reasons by the Commonwealth in 2014.
It is something which the Government - and all sides of politics - must not let up on.
We live in increasingly complex times and it is important, with tourism numbers rising and the state's profile increasing, that Tasmania is viewed as a world-class tourism destination and treated as a legitimate capital city with all the bells, whistles and, dare we say it, risks that entails.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hobart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Gutwein</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jetstar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gutwein</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KGV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wilkinsons Point</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenorchy City Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Local Government Minister Peter Gutwein</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commissioner Sue Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Federal Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Will Hodgman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
