<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651446630927377244</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/1412468/topics-pindimar-city-now-figment-of-google/?cs=4173</url>
  <title>TOPICS: Pindimar City now figment of Google</title>
  <content>
TOPICS: Pindimar City now figment of Google

ONLINE: Walter Burley Griffin's vision has been overlayed by reader Daniel Alexander on Google Maps.

exit
THE vision of a sprawling metropolis on the Myall River (Herald, April 2) predates the city in the Judge Dredd comics.

In fact, it's way cooler than that. Think Canberra, and the guy who designed it. He planned almost a century ago to build Pindimar City and make it the state's major seaport, the ''New York of Australia''. 
In 1919, the Chicago architect Walter Burley Griffin envisioned his city on the northern shores of Port Stephens, about eight kilometres east of Karuah.
''Get in early!'' screamed an early investment prospectus. 
''Decentralise! Demobilise! Develop!''
But Pindimar City never got off the ground. The company that Burley Griffin worked for went into liquidation. 
Fast forward 95years, and one who dares to dream is tech-savvy reader Daniel. He's overlayed the original Pindimar City plans onto a map on Google Earth.
Sadly, the Pindimartians will never open their shutters, or peer out the windows of their skyscrapers, or wring their hands over the crime on Burley Griffin Boulevard, except in our imaginations.
A whale of a name
NORM Skellams, who wrote this column in 1988, has an addition to Names That Suit Occupations, which he calls Horses For Courses. We'll steal that, thanks Norm. Now go ahead.
''The editor of Modern Fishing magazine,'' reports Norm, ''is Shaun Whale.''
Money for old rope.
Busy chasing MILFs
OUR bid to bring the cast of Geordie Shore to Newcastle is fading faster than a Tan in a Can.
Topics' hopes of meeting the Newcastle (UK) stars of the reality hit had soared with the news in February that they'd bunkered down in Coogee to film a series Down Under.
But fan favourites Ricci and Dan have left the show, and won't be coming to Australia for the latest incarnation of the MTV show.
''I've decided not to head to Australia with the rest of the crew and am staying in Newcastle where I intend to pursue some exciting personal projects and to continue to chase MILFs,'' said Dan in a statement.
The MILFs of Newcastle, NSW, sadly, will miss out on being chased.
Sworn to good cause
WE've been forwarded an email. It's from a Maitland rugby type, to an administrator.
 ''Could you please circulate to all clubs, referees and officials?'' it reads.
''At Maitland Rugby Club this year we are trying to promote a friendly and sporting atmosphere for all to enjoy. 
This year we have implemented a swear jar. Anyone caught swearing or yelling abuse at referees will be asked to donate a gold coin, if not more, to the Swear Jar. 
Please understand that this applies not only to the Maitland Rugby club but to all who visit Maitland Rugby Club grounds.
If they are caught, and do not wish to hand over a gold coin, they will be asked to leave the premises. 
If they fail to do so I will call the police, who will escort them out for good.''
The money left in the swear jar would be donated to a local family struggling with medical expenses.
Topics approves. They should put a jar at Civic Station. The Hunter's sick would be the envy of the world.
Have you ever used a swear jar? What was the result?

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MTV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Modern Fishing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burley Griffin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swear Jar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maitland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maitland Rugby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shaun Whale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maitland Rugby Club</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Civic Station</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Alexander</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Google Map</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Google Earth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karuah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ricci</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judge Dredd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geordie Shore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coogee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MILFs of Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Myall River</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chicago</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walter Burley Griffin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Horses For Courses</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Skellams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Names That Suit Occupations</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burley Griffin Boulevard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MILF</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Stephens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Google</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pindimartians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pindimar City</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
