<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651446978819734024</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/national/rush-hour-stories-you-need-to-know-today/news-story/cb7f51f7cfe34d9fdb26d24cc38551b3</url>
  <title>RUSH HOUR: Stories you need to know today</title>
  <content>
Live: Rush Hour
Good morning! Doctors believe a Melbourne teen who was bleeding profusely after emerging from the water at one of the city's beaches was ravaged by sea fleas. Homeless people camped in Sydney's CBD have rejected a deal to move to a safe space, and two men who streaked across the field at a Big Bash game are being treated like sex offenders.
6:30am
Streakers could be deemed sex offenders
Two cousins who streaked across the Sydney Cricket Ground during a Big Bash game face being treated as sex offenders over the incident.
Carpenters Chad Sharp, 27, and Josh Hudson, 24, faced court on Monday and pleaded guilty to entering the playing field, which carries a $5500 fine.
They were also charged with wilful and obscene exposure after they were arrested at the game between the Sydney Sixers and Sydney Thunder in January.
A key issue for the magistrate is the fact the incident was witnessed by a number of young boys and girls in the crowd and on television.
"This is a case ultimately over whether streaking on the SCG or anywhere else is by today's contemporary standards obscene," defence barrister Peter Strain told the court.
"Does the court seriously think that a couple of jokers running across the SCG depraved and corrupted people at the ground?"
6:05am
Sydney's tough new "mayor" rejects deal
The man described as the "mayor" of a tent city in the middle of Sydney's CBD has defiantly rejected a deal to pack up the homeless camp - just moments after it was announced by the city's Lord Mayor, Clover Moore.
Ms Moore had declared to a media pack on the steps of Town Hall that she had "negotiated an outcome with Lanz Priestley", claiming that he had agreed to pack up the camp of roughly 47 tents when council trucks arrived at the CBD landmark pedestrian mall today to collect material following a guarantee a "safe space" would be provided.
"He's agreed to this because accommodation has been offered to people and they realise that pressure is mounting and the crisis was really developing," she said.
But just a short time later, Mr Priestley told The Daily Telegraph he and the Lord Mayor had conflicting definitions of what that "safe space" should look like and that he was prepared to "spend months if necessary" hashing out a deal.
Mr Priestly is a New Zealand-born father of 12, who has become the face of Sydney's homeless crisis.
-  to read more

5:45am
Why Melbourne teen didn't stop bleeding
Brave locals have got back in the water at a Melbourne beach where a teen was left bleeding profusely from both legs, after he was believed to have been ravaged by sea fleas.
The critters are about a centimetre long and are commonly found in shallow water, where they tend to clean up fish carcasses on the sea floor.
Sam Kanizay, 16, emerged from the water at Dendy Street Beach in Brighton covered in what his family said were tiny marine creatures eating his legs.
Doctors later struggled to stem the bleeding from scores of what looked like tiny pink-prick bites due to the anticoagulant the fleas release to stop blood from clotting.
- to read more

Melbourne teen Sam Kanizay stood in the water for 30 minutes at a Brighton beach before emerging with blood all over his feet from an unknown sea creature. Courtesy: Sunrise/Channel 7

Melbourne teen left bleeding after mystery sea creature attack
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Sixers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lanz Priestley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dendy Street Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big Bash</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rush Hour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Streaker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Hudson, 24</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lord Mayor</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clover Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carpenters Chad Sharp, 27</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Strain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SCG</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Cricket Ground</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Priestley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Kanizay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand-born</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Priestly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Town Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunrise/Channel 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Does</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brighton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney CBD</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Thunder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Telegraph</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Kanizay, 16</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
