<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651446768366332765</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Ipswich Queensland Times</source>
  <url>http://www.qt.com.au/news/suicide-survivor-i-was-surprised-wake-er/3209838/</url>
  <title>Suicide survivor: 'I was surprised to wake up in ER'</title>
  <content>
DONNA Thistlethwaite walked across the bridge twice, her mind cluttered with thoughts of "all my shortcomings".
She'd spent the night before convinced her family - husband Greg and son Matthew - would be better off without her.

She'd left their home that morning, saying she was heading out for groceries, but actually thinking "I need to end my life. It seemed to me to be the only solution".

Now, atop Brisbane's iconic Story Bridge twice, 40 metres above the water, she quietly took off her shoes and dropped her bag.

"And then I just climbed over the fence ... and then I fell," Donna tells tonight's Australian Story on ABC.

"And then I remember just panicking for a minute. I was little bit scared.

"Years ago I had this dream a big wave came and it grabbed me. And I remember being frightened and then just going 'just relax, just relax'.

"It felt a bit like that feeling - 'oh my gosh', and then 'shh, it's OK'.

"And then I remember I was so released and I wasn't scared."

She remembers hitting the water: the sharp, icy sting and the pain in her body.

She remembers resurfacing, looking up at the bridge, seeing people "When I resurfaced I looked up at the bridge and I could see people standing there and sort of gathering around.

And then, for a while, she doesn't remember anything.

That Sunday afternoon in August 2012, was the day Donna had decided to die.

Instead she miraculously survived the 40 metre drop into wintry waters which should have killed her: stunning experts as well as herself.

"I was surprised to wake up in the ER because, you know, to me you jump off that bridge and you're dead. That's the only outcome I had conceived as possible," she says.

Thankfully, it wasn't. Some call it fate or a miracle. For three years, Donna called it her "big dirty secret".

But now she shares her survival story of "the bridge incident" in the hope it might help "Somebody. Some day.

Somewhere" to realise there is hope in darkness and that suicidal crisis can be overcome.

TEN DAYS TO DISINTEGRATE

It came out of the blue. Now, even Donna can't quite understand how her life took just "seven to ten days" to unravel from accomplished wife, mum and work over-achiever with no history of mental illness to a mental state in which she tried to take her own life.

That, says her psychiatrist George Blair-West, is "what made her case so perplexing. "But it speaks to how the human mind can move from being well and functioning to in this state that we think of around this word 'suicidal'."

Donna had just returned form maternity leave to the much-loved career in Human Resources she'd spent 17 years building, when the self-doubt surfaced. As she led a team and grappled with the introduction of a new IT system the flickers of lost confidence deteriorated into a confidence crisis.

"I started to feel like I was stupid and that people would know I had no idea what I was doing," she tells Australian Story

Despite assurances form colleagues she was doing fine, she convinced herself she was on the verge of bring sacked.
She had no history of the mental illnesses that are commonly associated with risk of suicide.

But she "could see all of my shortcomings and felt that was all anyone else could see", and felt all would be better off if she wasn't around.

"It seems like another person now," she says.

"I had a great life and awesome partner a beautiful child and a great job and it was really just this not coping at work".

"My thoughts were irrational. I couldn't see any way out of the situation."

She wasn't sleeping. She couldn't "switch my head off". She was "embarrassed" to tell her husband.

It's a sad reality, Dr Blair-West says, that people who think about suicide are "about to make the most important decision in their life, but are lacking the mental capacity to do so".

"It's literally the most important decision in your life - with the greatest amount of cognitive impairment you could have," he says.

"When people are suicidal they have this cognitive narrowing.

"When they try to access parts of their own mind to work out what to do, how to help themselves, they can't," he said.

"They really need the mind of somebody else at those times."

SURVIVAL

It's a miracle the fall from the Story Bridge alone didn't kill Donna, experts say.

And then a miracle again that she didn't drown after it.

"Hitting the water is like hitting concrete. Normally people who fall 40 metres will actually die on impact and they suffer multiple catastrophic injuries," says Queensland Ambulance Service medical director Dr Steve Rashford.

In 2012, 15 people lost their lives falling from there Story Bridge.

It's believed Donna was the only one who survived.

She was picked up from the water by a Brisbane ferry crew on a boat full of passengers.

Stuss Read saw her lying facedown in the water.

"She was going down," he says. As eh dragged her up and she gasped to life, he was "surprised she was alive".

She sat silently in the ambulance, head down, wet, shaking. Wordless.

She busted five vertebrae and a rib, lacerate her liver, and was bruised all over.

Barriers were erected on the Story Bridge in 2015 to stop similar incidents.

"And I was so pleased to see that they did," Donna says.

"I believe it would have made a difference (for me) because it would have been harder and that was one of the factors that I thought of."

FINDING HER VOICE

For three years Donna and close family guarded her "big dirty secret".

"It was very difficult, that stage of our lives. Our whole lives were turned upside down," she says.

"I wish I didn't put them through all of that. I feel bad that I put them through that experience."

The discovery she was one of 65,000 Australians who attempt suicide a year, and being told had she completed suicide, her son would be at 50 per cent greater risk of suicide in his lifetime kicked her into gear.

"Something just clicked in that made me think no matter how bad anything ever gets, I can't let that happen," she says

"Matthew deserves a mother. Flaws and all. It doesn't matter that I'm not perfect. I'm still his mother and he needs me in his life. "

She didn't tell people what had happened for a long time - "I didn't want people to feel they should have known and should have helped me - and she feared she would be judged.

"I had a little two-year-old. What mother abandons her two-year-old? But 18 months later I had an urge to talk about that," she says.

"It felt good to me to put it out there. People would see that your life can be different from that really dark place that you find yourself in," she says.

"I would say to anyone not to give up. It is possible to feel different to how you feel right now. And there is hope."

She is now a career coach, and also does telephone crisis support for Lifeline.

"I felt it was a way I could use this experience to help others. A way I could make sense of it as well," she says.

As Lifeline's Alan Woodward says: "There is a remarkable power in hearing from people who have survived a suicide attempt our suicide crisis in their lives. It's a story of living and hope.

Almost five years on, Donna has "never had that thought again".

"I'm in a better place than I have ever been. Life is great."

If you or anyone you know needs help: Lifeline 13 11 14, Beyond Blue 1300 224 636, or Kids Helpline 1800 5511 800

Australian Story airs at 8pm Monday on ABCTV and ABCiview

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>George Blair-West</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lifeline's Alan Woodward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stuss Read</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TEN DAYS TO DISINTEGRATE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2012</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABCiview</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Steve Rashford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Blair-West</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Story</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donna</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABCTV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beyond Blue 1300 224 636</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Human Resources</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donna Thistlethwaite</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Ambulance Services</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kids Helpline 1800 5511 800</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Story Bridge</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
