<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651446605157573027</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:23</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/streetscape-concerns-make-shop-owner-wary/3209699/</url>
  <title>Streetscape concerns make shop owner wary</title>
  <content>
GUITAR shop owner Brad Moore hopes changes to his end of Caloundra's Bulcock St will encourage more foot traffic past his front door.
But he is worried Sunshine Coast Council's next stage of development will drive away custom, at least during construction.
The council plans to release the design for the section between Minchinton St and Knox Ave next week.
It will be the fourth stage of redevelopment work that started at the western end.
Mr Moore has run The Guitar Den in Bulcock St since 1999.
"The way I look at it, if they do exactly what they did down the bottom end it is going to be a bit disastrous," Mr Moore said.
He said unexpected delays had serious affects on some traders, particularly those in the food industry.
"Retail is getting tougher for me every year as it is.
"I think it is going to be hard."
Mr Moore said he would have liked to have seen Bulcock St turned into a one-way thoroughfare, with wider footpaths to accommodate a mall setting.
"I think it is going to be a reproduction of what is down the bottom.
"There is no big wow factor."
But he said something needed to be done.
"We need to upgrade the street.
"I just think it could have been thought out a bit more."
Cr Tim Dwyer said work on the $2 milllion section of upgrade was expected to start in April next year.
"Some eight months after major construction was completed for stage three, I've enjoyed seeing how the upgrade has further enhanced downtown Caloundra," Cr Dwyer said.
Plans for the next section will be on display at Caloundra Library from August 15 to 24.
Seqwater facing massive shortfall because we are waterwise
University of the Sunshine Coast turns over a new leaf
Hyundai unveils its only fully-electric model in Australia
LIFESTYLE lure was stronger than a high-flying accountancy career.
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
A NATIONAL exhibition of ceramic art has been launched on the Coast
BREAKING: New festival coming to the Sunshine Coast
ONE of Hollywood's most adorable couples is over.
New celebrity cooking show fails to fire for Seven.
The legendary creator isn't so sure about how Netflix works.
*WARNING this story contains spoilers*
Make way for Mackay's newest tech start up
Planning documents lodged on behalf of site owners
Education, student accommodation, bars and music all key to future
Five dates through August for community to have its say on rock wall
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Moore</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Library</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of the Sunshine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra's Bulcock St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minchinton St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seqwater</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulcock St</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Guitar Den</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hyundai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 15</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Knox Ave</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Tim Dwyer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Dwyer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
