<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651446987409668793</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:52</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Ipswich Queensland Times</source>
  <url>http://www.qt.com.au/news/there-is-human-suffering-in-mackay-streets-every-d/3209805/</url>
  <title>'There is human suffering in Mackay streets every day'</title>
  <content>
CLOSE to 900 people are homeless in Mackay right now and that figure continues to grow each day.

More and more people are reduced to living on the streets, couch hopping, living from their cars and without a place to call their own - living without the basic human right of having a roof over his or her heads.

Worse yet, not enough is being done to curb this figure and to help those blatantly suffering in the community.

Anglicare Mackay/Whitsundays regional director John Langford said the issue is only getting worse and community members and the government are turning a blind eye.

"The reality of homelessness in our community is very very real," Mr Langford said.

"It's often hidden to the average person but not to organisations such as ours, CASA and St Vincent De Paul, where people come in each day because they can't afford to pay their way, their rent, accommodation and are stuck in that ongoing cycle.

"And it's not that we are uncaring as a community, but often people are not quite as aware of the plight of the needy around us, we need to do something about that."

Mr Langford said more government support was needed it addition to more resource, facilities, workers and volunteers.

"We also don't have an emergency centre for every homeless person to attend," he said.

"We have several groups who can offer accommodation for a low cost and I believe there is a women's emergency shelter, but nothing at all for men or those suffering with mental illness.

"Something needs to be done, and that begins with a change of attitude and change of heart by the community and the government to want to extend a helping hand."

Mr Langford said Anglicare alone has new people coming in each day suffering from homelessness and unable to get a leg up.

"Men, women, families, kids, all in different circumstance and all needing help," he said.

"One major issue is the connection between community service providers and the government, it needs to be better we need to get our system right, it's not there at all yet.

"The poor are always with us, if we forget them for a minute we are neglecting our own people, they have no voice, there is human suffering in Mackay streets every day ."

In a bid to raise awareness about the issue of homelessness in the region, CASA is hosting a 'sleep out' at Blue Water Quay on Wednesday August 9.

Members of the community are invited to sleep like the homeless for a night, to better understand their situation, sleeping with only a sleeping bag and cardboard.

Tara Cassidy

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anglicare Mackay/Whitsundays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Langford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Vincent De Paul</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Langford</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tara Cassidy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blue Water Quay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackay</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CASA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday August 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anglicare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
