<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651446974524766682</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:49</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/victoria/melbourne-express-tuesday-august-8-2017-20170807-gxrbmg.html</url>
  <title>Melbourne Express: Tuesday, August 8, 2017</title>
  <content>
Lord Mayor Robert Doyle's home has been damaged in an early morning paint bomb attack, the second time the South Melbourne property has been targeted in six months, reports Ebony Bowden.

Anarchist group Street Artists for Doyle Collective have claimed responsibility for the attack which occurred about 1.30am on Monday morning.

A police spokesman confirmed Port Phillip Crime Investigation Unit detectives were investigating.

In a Facebook post, the group made threats toward Mr Doyle and other politicians.

"Our intention was to send a message to Doyle and his wealthy politico-scum colleagues, that we have the ability to identify their homes and make their lives uncomfortable anytime we choose," the post read.

The same group staged an early morning protest outside Mr Doyle's home in February after council officers dismantled makeshift homeless camps on Flinders Street.
Six train lines have minor delays, says PTV

Due to earlier obstructed track between Burnley and Camberwell, services on the Alamein, Belgrave, Glen Waverley and Lilydale lines are delayed by up to 10 minutes.

Werribee: Minor Delays to 10 min : to City

Frankston: Minor Delays to 10 min : to Frankston

Heavy snowfall has sparked avalanches in the Victorian Alpine region, with emergency services issuing a stern warning to tourists to steer clear of remote areas, .

Ski resorts conducted controlled avalanches after incidents on Monday to reduce risk before warmer weather forecast and strong winds forecast for Tuesday.

Vic Emergency said warmer weather and strong winds heightened the risk of avalanches. 

"You should avoid activities such as skiing, snowboarding, or hiking in remote areas of the Alps as there is an increased risk of avalanches," the organisation's advice message said.
Our front-page story today: Victorian Opposition Leader Matthew Guy attended a secret dinner earlier this year with the alleged head of Melbourne's Mafia over several bottles of Penfolds Grange at a lobster restaurant in Melbourne's south-east, report Nick McKenzie, Richard Baker, and Richard Willingham.

Mr Guy dined with Tony Madafferi, a wealthy market gardener and the owner of the La Porchetta pizza chain, even though Mr Madafferi has repeatedly been accused by police in court of being a high-ranking member of Melbourne's Mafia.

3AW, meanwhile, are chasing the key question about this story this morning:

Wine expert Christopher Barnes says, no, Matthew Guy should't have drunk Penfolds Grange with lobster, shoulda been a Vic wine anyway!

There was a partial lunar eclipse in the wee hours of this morning - did you see it? Make sure you send us your photos.

A partial eclipse happens when the earth's orbit takes it between the sun and the moon, leading to it casting a slight shadow on the moon.

Seven houses have now been condemned in Land O'Lakes, Florida, thanks to the county's largest sinkhole in 30 years.

Two homes were destroyed when the ground gave way July 14, but the sinkhole has since expanded and now stretches 260 feet (80 metres) at its widest point, The Tampa Bay Times reported. Two more houses along its edge were condemned on Saturday, followed by three Sunday, according to a Pasco County news release.

Sinkholes are the culmination of a process that can occur over centuries or even millenniums. When rainwater seeps into the ground, the acids in it gradually erode particular types of bedrock -- limestone or sandstone, for example. Natural cracks and cavities in the bedrock slowly expand, and the soil above it begins to fall through. At first, the upper layers can still bear the weight of the buildings above them. But eventually, as the sediment slips through the cracks like sand through an hourglass, the ground gives way. Heavy rainfall can contribute to a sudden collapse.
Lord mayor Robert Doyle's home was paintbombed again Monday night, 3AW are reporting.

The lord mayor's house has been regularly targeted by homelessness activists over the city council's homelessness policies. In Febuary he called police after a large protest erupted outside his house in the early hours of the morning.

A post on Insurrection News, claiming to be from the protesters, said the paintbombing came with the following note:

Hence, in appreciation for your support of Melbourne's vibrant and internationally street art culture, we felt it was both our civic and creative duty to bestow upon you a personalised gift. We genuinely hope that you will forever enjoy your own priceless piece of street art. We presume our contribution will result in an increase of your property value, which, after your sad demise your child-bride and tender-aged offspring will capitalise upon.
Top of 15 in Melbourne today with a 40 per cent chance of showers in the late afternoon in the southeast suburbs.

How's this for a simple crime: a woman strolled into the change rooms at a leisure centre on Williams Road in Templestowe Lower, nicked another woman's set of keys, and drove off in her BMW.

The woman walked into the change rooms about 12.20pm on July 22 and grabbed the keys and a mobile phone from the victim's handbag. She then used the keys to steal a  2016 BMW coupe from the car park.

The car was later recovered, but police are still hunting the woman, and have released images of her in the hope a member of the public recognises her. Anyone with information is asked to call Crime Stoppers on 1800 333 000.
Good morning and welcome to Melbourne Express. Liam Mannix with you behind the wheel today. Let's hope for an easy run on the transport network.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BMW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flinders Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belgrave</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vic Emergency</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tampa Bay Times</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minor Delays</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Florida</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Guy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne's Mafia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Land O'Lakes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alamein</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Werribee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liam Mannix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lilydale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 14</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 22</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frankston</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 8, 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Street Artists</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Febuary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick McKenzie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Express</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Williams Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PTV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insurrection News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Madafferi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Penfolds Grange</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Madafferi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Baker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Templestowe Lower</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burnley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lord Mayor Robert Doyle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Guy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Phillip Crime Investigation Unit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crime Stoppers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Doyle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pasco County</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Alpine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doyle Collective</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>La Porchetta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Opposition Leader Matthew Guy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lord</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ebony Bowden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alps</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christopher Barnes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doyle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Willingham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Camberwell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glen Waverley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Doyle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
