<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651446768366332662</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:01</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/queensland/working-for-queensland-survey-show-one-in-four-public-sector-workers-witness-bullying-or-harassment-20170807-gxqn1i.html</url>
  <title>One in four Qld public sector workers witness bullying or harassment</title>
  <content>
More than one in four Queensland public servants have witnessed bullying or sexual harassment at work.
The latest Working for Queensland survey reveals 27 per cent public sector employees said they had witnessed bullying or sexual harassment in the workplace in the past 12 months.Photo: Andrew Quilty
The report showed 16 per cent of public sector workers said they were themselves subjected to bullying and 1 per cent were sexually harassed.
Verbal abuse was the most common type of bullying across the public sector at 60 per cent, followed by inappropriate and unfair application of work policies or rules at 41 per cent.
Across the public sector, fellow workers were the most common perpetrators of bullying at 43 per cent, followed by the victim's immediate manager or supervisor at 35 per cent.

Of those workers who were bullied, 57 per cent did not report the incident, with more than half of those saying they did not bother to report it because they did not think any action would be taken.
A Fairfax Media analysis reveals hospital and health services made up nine out of 10 of the agencies with the highest percentage of people who had witnessed bullying or sexual harassment.

You will now receive updates from

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Out of the departments, Justice and Attorney General (29.7 per cent) had the highest percentage of people who said they witnessed bullying or sexual harassment, followed by Communities, Child Safety and Disability Services (25.7 per cent) and Health (24.8 per cent).
Across the public sector, 37 per cent felt overloaded with work, while 28 per cent felt burned out by their work.
Queensland Public Service Commission chief executive Robert Setter said the recently released 2016 results showed bullying was less prevalent in the Queensland public sector than in previous years.
In 2013, witnessing of bullying and harassment was at 36 per cent compared with 27 per cent in 2016.
Mr Setter said the proportion of people being subjected to bullying or harassment had also declined from 21 per cent in 2013. 
And the proportion of people reporting overload and burnout had decreased - by 9 per cent and 7 per cent respectively - since 2013. 
Mr Setter said that in response to the survey results, individual departments and agencies took action to address areas in need of improvement.
He said the Public Service Commission also co-ordinated leadership and management training, and would soon introduce a health, safety and wellbeing framework and a new workload management guide would help guide workload discussions, planning and issues resolution.
"All of these elements seek to positively impact on employees' workplace experiences," Mr Setter said.
"The Public Service Commission works with departments and agencies to brief on results, and actively develop strategies to lift individual results where needed."
A Liberal National Party spokeswoman bullying and sexual harassment was unacceptable in any workplace and appropriate actions needed to be taken to stop workplace harassment. 
The spokeswoman pointed to its plan to create a public service of excellence policy.
"Our plan will empower public servants with the training, skills and leadership to deliver better outcomes for Queenslanders," she said.
The 2016 survey had a response rate of 38 per cent across the public sector - or 89,033 surveys - and was conducted from mid-April to early May 2016. 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Health (24.8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Setter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spencer Howson AM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Public Service Commission</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Attorney General (29.7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qld</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queenslanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Setter</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Disability Services (25.7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Child Safety</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal National Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Quilty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Public Service Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
