<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651446244380314941</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>17:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/925204/ivy-piano-room-rape-charges-expected-to-be-dropped/?cs=4173</url>
  <title>Ivy, Piano Room rape charges expected to be dropped</title>
  <content>
Ivy, Piano Room rape charges expected to be dropped

Chris Corben, covering his face and head,  runs from Surry Hills Police Station in an attempt to flee the waiting media in 2009.

exit

ONE of two rape charges against a man accused of sexually assaulting two women in separate attacks at exclusive Sydney nightclubs is expected to be dropped, police and legal sources have told The Sun-Herald.
It is also understood the defence team for accused Bondi accountant   Christopher Scott Corben, 31, will apply to have the second charge dropped when the case comes before Downing Centre Local Court tomorrow.
Mr Corben's solicitor, Nick Boyden, was not available for comment but it is understood he has briefed Winston Terracini, SC, to make the application for the Director of Public Prosecutions to dismiss a charge against his client of having allegedly raped a well-known fashion designer in a change room cubicle at the exclusive Ivy bar in October 2009.
The application will be made at the same time as the DPP is expected to formally withdraw a charge against Mr Corben of having  raped another woman in an unconnected attack in  the Piano Room, Kings Cross, a year earlier.
The alleged victim in the Ivy  case told prosecutors early last month that she would not be available to give evidence at tomorrow's hearing because of her commitments at  Australian Fashion week in Sydney.
The DPP had sought unsuccessfully to vacate the hearing because it clashed with fashion week.
Late last year magistrate Caleb Franklin found ''a number of inconsistencies'' in the two complainants' versions, saying ''special reasons'' gave rise to an order that both alleged victims be required for cross-examination ''in the interests of justice''.
Mr Corben is   on strict bail conditions.  He  must live at his parents' Lilli Pilli home, abide by a strict curfew, and not drink alcohol or visit licensed premises.
In October 2009, Mr Corben was charged with aggravated sexual assault and deprivation of liberty of a woman, 34, in a toilet at the Ivy nightclub in George Street, Sydney.
Two months later he was charged with sexual intercourse without consent, taking and detaining a person with the intention to obtain advantage and two counts of assault with an act of indecency against a woman, 25, in a toilet at the Piano Room bar in Kings Cross in October 2008.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Fashion</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Piano Room</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ivy</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Director of Public</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bondi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christopher Scott Corben</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Corben</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kings Cross</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 2009</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 2008</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sun Herald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Corben</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surry Hills Police Station</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Boyden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DPP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lilli Pilli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Winston Terracini</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Downing Centre Local Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caleb Franklin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
