<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651446570797834077</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:15</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/from-little-things-big-marketing-ideas-grow/3208462/</url>
  <title>From little things, big marketing ideas grow</title>
  <content>
WHAT a roller-coaster ride it has been.
In the late 1980s, two Australian brothers (both food scientists) frustrated with the short life of culinary herbs developed the Eva Fresh technology which extended the natural shelf life of fresh herbs, without the need of heat treatment or acidification which can destroy delicate flavours.
In the early 1990s, the Department of Primary Industries was working on a project to help Central Queensland cotton growers change their crops from cotton to herbs, as cotton is a high water-consumption plant with low yields and herbs are lower water-consumption and high yield.
The farmers began trials of growing culinary herbs and in the late 1990s, Berri, which had purchased the Eva Fresh technology, and the Biloela farmers joined forces and the first seed (coriander) was planted on March 1, 1998.
The Gourmet Garden brand was launched in late 1998 with a range of 10 stir-in herbs and spice pastes. It operated out of the Suncoast juice facility in Palmwoods. Suncoast Juice had been around since the 1970s and during the 1990s was a juice- processing facility for Berri Ltd.
All the major supermarkets in Australia at the time sold Gourmet Garden. The Botanical Food Company saw the brand as a product range with global capability and appeal.
The brand was quickly launched into the UK with a joint- venture partner in 2000, with New Zealand following in 2001.
The biggest distribution opportunity was the North American market.
The first potential customer we engaged with in the US thought we had rocks in our heads for coming up with the concept. We had a plan to launch in 1000 supermarkets through multiple retailers on the west coast of the US late in 2002. That way we could control our production capabilities.
After we presented the Gourmet Garden concept to the first customer, he said he could put us in 1000 stores but we would have to stretch further than just the west coast.
This distribution expansion continued to move east with Gourmet Garden's production capabilities building in Palmwoods. The expansion of the North American market continued, with distribution into Canada in 2003 and a legal entity was established in the US state of California in October 2007 with a small team of dedicated people.
Distribution continued to build to the point where Gourmet Garden was being sold in more than 20,000 supermarkets across North America.
The project to build a new facility started in early 2006 and was operational in October 2006. This new facility has enabled us to process enough product to expand into additional countries around the globe and continue to supply the ever-increasing demand in existing markets.
Craig Smith is Gourmet Garden's Head of Sales in Asia.
Hyundai unveils its only fully-electric model in Australia
Work on next stage of redevelopment due to start next April
Coast's $18m rescue chopper has been shifted by Lifeflight
THE idea for COYO announced itself at three o'clock in the morning.
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
A NATIONAL exhibition of ceramic art has been launched on the Coast
BREAKING: New festival coming to the Sunshine Coast
ONE of Hollywood's most adorable couples is over.
New celebrity cooking show fails to fire for Seven.
The legendary creator isn't so sure about how Netflix works.
*WARNING this story contains spoilers*
Make way for Mackay's newest tech start up
Planning documents lodged on behalf of site owners
Education, student accommodation, bars and music all key to future
Five dates through August for community to have its say on rock wall
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palmwoods</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Biloela</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>COYO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CENTRAL Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast's $18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canada</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Botanical Food Company</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North America</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LifeFlight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berri Ltd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North American</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suncoast Juice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 2007</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 2006</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SUNCOAST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gourmet Garden's Head of Sales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hyundai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gourmet Garden</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Primary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eva Fresh</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berri</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
