<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651446811316006546</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:11</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/i-did-nothing-mum-tells-torture-trial/3209804/</url>
  <title>'I did nothing', mum tells torture trial</title>
  <content>
FIRST, the door of the girl's room was kept open.
Soon, she was kept inside with the door closed, handle removed and no way out.
That was the evidence of the girl's mother on Monday, at the trial of a 58-year-old man who has pleaded not guilty to torture.
The mother told Brisbane District Court the man on trial advised her to smack the girl, "put her in a naughty chair, or put her in her room".
The jury heard the mother was herself jailed in relation to the child's treatment.
The mother admitted she and another adult also put the girl in the room to punish her.
"She wouldn't go in. She screamed and yelled every time," she told the court.
The mother said her daughter had "attitude problems" which included screaming, not listening and throwing clean clothes around.
The man facing trial twice used a cup to pour water on the girl's head when she was on the naughty chair, the witness said.
"She would freak out. She would start crying, that she had water poured on her," the mother said.
Crown Prosecutor Victoria Trafford-Walker asked the mother why she went along with it.
"I just don't know," she said. "I did nothing. I felt scared and intimidated that if I said something I would be abused myself."
Defence barrister Simon Hamlyn-Harris earlier told the court his client provided parenting advice and bought the girl a bed.
He said his client "never suggested" the girl be locked up for a long time.
Mr Hamlyn-Harris said a desire to help the parents with their troubled child motivated his client.
The trial continues. -NewsRegional
Coast's $18m rescue chopper has been shifted by Lifeflight
Seqwater facing massive shortfall because we are waterwise
University of the Sunshine Coast turns over a new leaf
LIFESTYLE lure was stronger than a high-flying accountancy career.
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
A NATIONAL exhibition of ceramic art has been launched on the Coast
BREAKING: New festival coming to the Sunshine Coast
ONE of Hollywood's most adorable couples is over.
New celebrity cooking show fails to fire for Seven.
The legendary creator isn't so sure about how Netflix works.
*WARNING this story contains spoilers*
Make way for Mackay's newest tech start up
Two of three estates sold after hitting the market.
Planning documents lodged on behalf of site owners
Education, student accommodation, bars and music all key to future
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane District Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown Prosecutor Victoria Trafford-Walker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of the Sunshine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast's $18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hamlyn-Harris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LifeFlight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seqwater</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NewsRegional</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon Hamlyn-Harris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
