<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651446931575093051</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:39</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/entertainment/celebrity-life/hook-ups-break-ups/chris-pratt-anna-faris-split-could-be-financial-nightmare/news-story/ff82592af03ed7369d404903fa39f6e9</url>
  <title>Chris Pratt, Anna Faris split could be financial nightmare</title>
  <content>
BREAKING: Chris Pratt &amp; Anna Faris SPLIT; Was Jennifer Lawrence the Reason!?
2:18

Sadly, Chris Pratt and Ana Faris are legally separating after 8 years of marriage. Chris himself broke the news directly to his fans via Facebook late last night. Fans pretty much flipped out in sadness over this news. They also noted a possible reason for their split - an affair with another hollywood actress. Were you surprised by this adorable couple separating, and do you think Jennifer Lawrence had anything to do with it? Let us know in the comments below.

August 8th 2017
3 hours ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment - syndicated/

The couple's fortune could be difficult to divide. Picture: AP

Diana FalzoneFox News

Share

CHRIS Pratt and Anna Farris announced yesterday via social media that they are legally separating after eight years of marriage.
Over the , the A-listers' careers have boomed with Pratt being ranked by Forbes as one of Hollywood's highest-paid actors in 2016, raking in $US26 million with his two film franchises, Guardians of the Galaxy and Jurassic Park.
Meanwhile Farris reportedly makes $US125,000 per episode for her sitcom, Mom, which currently wrapped it's fourth 22-episode season.

The couple kiss on the red carpet in April this year. Picture: AFPSource:AFP
It was not immediately clear if the couple had a prenup in place. They wed in Bali in 2009.
If they didn't sign on the dotted line before their union, legal experts say a divorce for the pair could be a financial disaster.
"I find that it's interesting that the announcement is that they are 'legally separating' ... versus [a] dissolution [of their marriage]," said Lynda Sheridan, a Los Angeles-based divorce lawyer.
She said if the couple doesn't have a prenup they may divide their fortune in half.

"As for their assets, absent a prenup or other written agreement, they should expect to determine what they have, whether held jointly or separately, and divide by two," Sheridan explained.
Jason Hopper, a practice manager at Cordell & Cordell law firm, said Pratt may lose some of his recent earnings if the couple didn't have a prenup. He noted most of Pratt's success came in recent years.

Pratt's career has skyrocketed in recent years as he's gone from sitcom actor to action hero. Picture: APSource:AP
"While both Mr. Pratt and Ms. Faris had Hollywood successes before their marriage and likely brought significant assets into the marriage, Mr. Pratt has enjoyed his greatest box office paydays during the ... marriage, which could likely lead to Ms. Faris having a very strong claim to a portion of Mr. Pratt's earnings incurred during their marriage," he said.
He added Faris would likely be able to ask for child support for their 4-year-old son, Jack, if Pratt is earning more than she is.
In a January 2016 interview with , Faris reflected on her marriage and what she had learned from it.
The actress advised, "Be selfish in love ... because ... we tend to put a man's needs first or sort of identify ourselves through our relationship more than men do sometimes."
She added, "Make sure that you find a partner who really, really loves you and respects you and cares for you, and I feel like Chris is all those things, but it just took a minute."
Fox News reached out to Pratt and Faris' reps who confirmed the couple's separation, but did not comment further.
This story originally appeared on  and is republished here with permission.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Pratt</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ana Faris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diana FalzoneFox News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anna Faris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Guardians Of The Galaxy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anna Farris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Hopper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Los Angeles-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Pratt</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cordell</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jurassic Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>APSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms. Faris</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFPSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Farris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sheridan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$125,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bali</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JENNIFER LAWRENCE</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anna Faris SPLIT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lynda Sheridan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Forbes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pratt</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FARIS</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
