<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651446686761952848</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:42</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/three-gladstone-estate-developments-flop-in-three-/3209830/</url>
  <title>Three Gladstone estate developments flop in three months</title>
  <content>
THE 31-lot Bradford Rd subdivision was the third failed Gladstone region development in three months to return to the property market for sale.

The first, and largest, in the spate of unfinished developments was Brookview Estate, which was put on the market in March.

The once $90 million housing estate in Glen Eden is believed to have sold late July.

Brookview Estate was a project of Latitude Development Group's, which was placed in the hands of receivers McGrath Nicol early last year.

The buyer would receive 23 residential lots, and the additional 123 approved residential lots which are in the second stage of the development.

In June Gladstone Green followed suit - with 23 blocks up for sale for between $49,000 - $68,000.

The 23 blocks off Lorikeet Ave for sale were once part of Gladstone Green, a planned 36 home suburb that promised family-friendly living in New Auckland.

The developer behind Gladstone Green, Moreton Bay Developments No 8 Pty Ltd, is in administration and its assets are being handled by a private lender.

An auction sale was attempted for the remaining blocks, however none sold.

Only 13 of the house and land packages at Gladstone Green were sold about four years ago.

Coast's $18m rescue chopper has been shifted by Lifeflight
Seqwater facing massive shortfall because we are waterwise
University of the Sunshine Coast turns over a new leaf
LIFESTYLE lure was stronger than a high-flying accountancy career.
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
A NATIONAL exhibition of ceramic art has been launched on the Coast
BREAKING: New festival coming to the Sunshine Coast
ONE of Hollywood's most adorable couples is over.
New celebrity cooking show fails to fire for Seven.
The legendary creator isn't so sure about how Netflix works.
*WARNING this story contains spoilers*
Make way for Mackay's newest tech start up
Planning documents lodged on behalf of site owners
Education, student accommodation, bars and music all key to future
Five dates through August for community to have its say on rock wall
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glen Eden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gladstone Green</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of the Sunshine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lorikeet Ave</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast's $18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moreton Bay Developments No 8 Pty Ltd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Latitude Development Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June Gladstone Green</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LifeFlight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brookview Estate</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seqwater</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGrath Nicol</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Auckland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bradford Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gladstone</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
