<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651446764071365268</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/breaking-news/wa-mans-escape-keeps-kerobokan-on-alert/news-story/7a6aab5bcfede93a2610ea62899e61c9</url>
  <title>WA man's escape keeps Kerobokan on alert</title>
  <content>
Prisoners at Bali's Kerobokan jail are facing more sweeps and earlier lock-down, as Indonesian officials continue to be taunted on social media over the escape of Australian man Shaun Davidson.
If the recent Facebook post purporting to belong to the Western Australian is to be believed, the 33-year-old has been off jet-setting once again.
"Another day another country and check out my leg room hahaha enjoy life," the post accompanying a photo of an airline seat stated on Friday.
Since Davidson's escape on June 19, Interpol and Bali authorities have been the target of constant jibes over his ability to remain on the run.
But for those who have been left behind, it isn't so funny.
"I pity those who were on shift that time, the ones being questioned the most," prison guard Wayan Mudastra told AAP.
He said the guards were "shocked" when the escape of Davidson and three other inmates became known.
The four men are believed to have spent hours digging out dirt and water from a hole, before escaping through a tunnel on to Bali's streets.
"Can you imagine? We, are 10 people, supervising thousands of troubled people. And each one of them is different from another. It's not easy," Mr Mudastra said.
"It's a job. We have to be uplifted. But we can say that we are (feeling) numb."
Prison governor, Tonny Nainggolan said the concern that it might happen again has is "always there".
He has increased sweeps of the prison and boosted the number of staff by two people - up to 12.
Last month, during a raid on cells police uncovered a "sharp weapon", drugs, including ecstasy pills and dozens of mobile phones.
One inmate at Kerobokan told AAP said they used to be locked down at 1am, now it is 11pm.
"Then at the morning ceremony, now we must all come." They could no longer be represented by the head of room only.
"There are no more hand phones. All were swept in last month searching."
Like many prisons across Indonesia, Kerobokan is beyond capacity - housing about 1400 prisoners last month, despite being build for 325.
The prison system has come under increasing scrutiny following Davidson's escape and last month's discovery of 1.2 million ecstasy tablets, linked to a prisoner inside Central Java island jail Nusakambangan.
Kerobokan is expected to receive an injection of 28 staff members next year, as part of a nation-wide effort to recruit 14,000 people to staff Indonesia's chronically overpopulated jails and get rid of those who had been "corrupted".
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kerobokan</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indonesian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tonny Nainggolan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Davidson</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Mudastra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indonesia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Interpol</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bali's Kerobokan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bali</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wayan Mudastra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central Java</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nusakambangan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shaun Davidson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
