<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651446609452540345</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:24</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/our-fishermen-are-a-tough-breed/3208353/</url>
  <title>Our fishermen are a tough breed</title>
  <content>
PRAWNING off the North Coast, as it was known then, in the late 1950s saw the trawlers come from as far south as Iluka and Brunswick Heads, and also from Moreton Bay.
The most we ever had tied to our wharf was 26 boats. With this many trawlers using the Caloundra Bar daily, it was always deep.
The seafood was unloaded at our wharf and trucked to Brisbane fish market.
This was the first time I had seen a spanner crab.
Most of the trawlers went to Mooloolaba around 1971 when the new boat harbour was opened.
In 1961, on New Year's Eve, Caloundra was hit by a cyclone.
It sunk two trawlers: the Bris-cal a small cargo boat, and Tom Maloney's Water Hen (she went down next to Tom's wharf where La Promenade is at the Bulcock Beach boardwalk).
Tom used the Water Hen to bring fuel and stores from Brisbane by water to Caloundra and to backload with shell grit from Moffat Beach, where he bagged it, loaded a sled which was pulled along the beach by his draught horse and up to his truck which was parked on the road.
It was a Thornycroft truck, with hard rubber wheels. It did not have a starter motor: you had to crank it.
The shell grit was used in chook pens in Brisbane.
I took over from my father in 1989 and continued to fish with Heather and the Chaplin boys in the winter for sea mullet on the beach.
In 1995, the Pumicestone Passage was closed to net fishing and around the same time fishing zones were introduced.
Over the years, the Caloundra area has produced on average about 60 to 80 tonnes of mullet a year.
It depends on the weather: if you get a lot of west to south-west wind, you could have a good season.
However, if heavy south-eastlies prevail, the fish can go wide of the beach and you cannot catch them.
The biggest lot of mullet ever caught at Caloundra was 42 tonnes in one shot. It was at Kings Beach in 2004. We shot them in at 7am and finished handling them at 10pm that night.
After 45 years of fishing, I have worked in the pawning, mullet, spanner crab, reef fish, barramundi and beche-de-mer industries.
In 2007, I retired and now live on my 55ft ex-government pilot boat, which I bought in 1997. My wife and I have been married for 51 years this November, and we have three children and six grandchildren.
Seqwater facing massive shortfall because we are waterwise
University of the Sunshine Coast turns over a new leaf
Hyundai unveils its only fully-electric model in Australia
LIFESTYLE lure was stronger than a high-flying accountancy career.
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
A NATIONAL exhibition of ceramic art has been launched on the Coast
BREAKING: New festival coming to the Sunshine Coast
ONE of Hollywood's most adorable couples is over.
New celebrity cooking show fails to fire for Seven.
The legendary creator isn't so sure about how Netflix works.
*WARNING this story contains spoilers*
Make way for Mackay's newest tech start up
Planning documents lodged on behalf of site owners
Education, student accommodation, bars and music all key to future
Five dates through August for community to have its say on rock wall
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moffat Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Water Hen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of the Sunshine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kings Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moreton Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brunswick Heads</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bris-cal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heather</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seqwater</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mooloolaba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thornycroft</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PRAWNING</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Bar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulcock Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hyundai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chaplin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>La Promenade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Year's Eve</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pumicestone Passage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iluka</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Maloney's Water Hen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
