<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651446587977703556</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/queensland/city-park-and-laneway-to-honour-carol-lloyd-for-expo-88-and-rock-career-20170806-gxg37r.html</url>
  <title>City park and laneway to honour Carol Lloyd for Expo 88 and rock career</title>
  <content>
Another famous Brisbane musician, iconic singer-songwriter Carol Lloyd, is set to have both a park and a Fortitude Valley laneway named after her to honour her achievements as a singer, advertising executive and her role in World Expo 88.
The honour is being investigated by Brisbane's Expo 88 commemoration committee because Carol Lloyd wrote and sang the Expo 88 theme song, Together We'll Show the World, as well as developing much of its advertising themes.Photo: Tony Moore
The idea has already been discussed with Brisbane's lord mayor Graham Quirk, who is enthusiastic about the proposal.
As well as being one of Brisbane's most powerful and influential musicians, Carol Lloyd was one of Queensland's leading advertising executives.Photo: Supplied
With her Railroad Gin songwriting partner Frank Millward, she wrote Together We'll Show the World around the campaign line she had developed.
Ms Lloyd also wrote and performed the theme song used in the Queensland Pavilion at Expo 88, Come Join the Spirit.

The acting chairman of Brisbane's Expo 88 People's Committee, Peter Rasey, is investigating projects to mark the transition in Brisbane over 30 years since World Expo 88 after Brisbane City Council allocated $555,000 to get the city ready to remember the famous event.

You will now receive updates from

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

He said a triangular piece of established parkland opposite Brisbane's Centenary Pool on Gregory Terrace at Spring Hill is proposed to become Carol Lloyd Place.Photo: Tony Moore
"One of Brisbane's exciting and influential people, who tragically passed away earlier this year and who had a really important role in the story of World Expo 88, was Carol Lloyd," Mr Rasey said.
"We think that few people today realise she had such an important role in World Expo 88, as well as successes in her career as a musician with Railroad Gin and her own bands," he said.Photo: Heather Faulkner
"We've had very fruitful discussions with the lord mayor about it and in those discussions we've agreed to name it Carol Lloyd Place."
Central Ward councillor Vicki Howard - who manages the Fortitude Valley region - said that while Council was always happy to receive further suggestions to honour icons of our city's history, Council already had plans afoot to honour Carol Lloyd.
"I am currently working with businesses and property owners in the Fortitude Valley to name a laneway after Carol Lloyd," Cr Howard said.
"The Valley was where Carol made her name and she was one of the few who helped shape Brisbane's rock'n'roll scene," she said.
"Carol's influence on '70s and '80s music has been seen both here and internationally, and will continue to be remembered for decades.
"Everyone I have spoken to has been extremely supportive of this idea and I look forward getting plans in place to celebrate the naming in time for the 30th anniversary of Expo 88."
Brisbane City Council plans to shift a large sculpture called Showdown from the front of the Boondall Entertainment Centre to the small parkland on Gregory Terrace to make the site more symbolic.
Showdown by Chris Beecroft, was one of the World Expo 88 sculptures that was shifted around the city after the event finished.
Mr Rasey said the city's then-lord mayor Sallyanne Atkinson moved Showdown to Boondall in 1992 to impress delegates assessing Brisbane's bid to host an Olympics.
"We think it is time Showdown comes back to the CBD," Mr Rasey said.
It will become part of
He said the idea was to landscape Carol Lloyd Place in the same way  to honour Queensland's famous women's tennis champion.
Carol Lloyd
South-east Queensland has been slow to acknowledge its musical heritage, to honour the co-songwriter of hugely-influential Brisbane band The Saints.
It has already acknowledged Brisbane band the Go-Betweens with the Go Between Bridge between Milton and South Brisbane in 2010, while Redcliffe has the Bee Gees Way.
There is also a collection of plaques on the ground of the Fortitude Valley mall, recognising other bands including Powderfinger, Regurgitator and earlier musicians.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Railroad Gin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carol Lloyd</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane City Council</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spring Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carol Lloyd Place</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spencer Howson AM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane's Expo 88 People's Committee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Expo 88</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Expo 88</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graham Quirk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boondall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Together We</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>12</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Valley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Powderfinger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane's Centenary Pool</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sallyanne Atkinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Redcliffe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Lloyd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fortitude Valley</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gregory Terrace</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Pavilion</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South East Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.67</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saints</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Regurgitator</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boondall Entertainment Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central Ward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Beecroft</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carol</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Moore</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frank Millward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Go-Betweens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Rasey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Milton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane's Expo 88</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heather Faulkner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bee Gees Way</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Howard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vicki Howard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carol Lloyd Place.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Rasey</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Go Between Bridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
