<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651446566502866733</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:14</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/i-chose-the-sunshine-coast-over-a-big-six-career/3208454/</url>
  <title>I chose the Sunshine Coast over a Big Six career</title>
  <content>
I WAS working as a graduate accountant for Ernst & Young in Brisbane in 1994, when I was sent to work on an audit for a client: Buderim Ginger.
I grew up in Noosa and Pomona and was so excited to be back in my old stomping ground.
Greg Tuer, the CEO, mentioned that they had a job for a marketing officer going. I threw my hat in the ring and got it.
My colleagues in Brisbane thought I was completely mad throwing away a city accounting career with a Big Six firm to move to a regional area.
Buderim Ginger sponsored me to go back to university part-time and I completed my marketing subjects at QUT. I had no idea I was meant to be in marketing and innovation but I had found my niche.
It was an exciting time for Buderim Ginger. It was in the midst of a strong innovation cycle and I got to be a part of this.
We did things like taking the jams and marmalades out of the niche health food aisle in Woolworths and re-positioned the brand in the mainstream jam category.
Tony van Alphen was in charge of sales and I was fortunate to have a mentor in marketing consultant Deborah Looseley.
I also loved the tourism and worked closely with Joy Varney who ran that part of the business.
In 1997, I left Buderim Ginger to go travelling in Europe and ended up staying for nine years, building a career in food and wine. In 2007, I returned with a young family. The lure of home was strong and instead of heading to the city, we decided to go back to the Sunshine Coast and see if it would work.
I worked as a consultant for a few years and had some great clients.  I met the CEO of Gourmet Garden, Nick White. He was recruiting for a head of marketing and innovation and I applied for the job and was successful.
The team at Gourmet Garden like to approach innovation collaboratively and with the consumer at the heart of decision- making. This way of working feels natural to me as I like to bounce ideas off other people: colleagues or consumers.
This approach was solidified in our business through our mentor, Dr Sam Buculo, a Professor of Design Innovation at University of Technology Sydney. Thanks to a State Government-funded innovation program, he came to the company to teach us the principles of design-led thinking, where the consumer is at the heart of everything we do.
He aligned our approach and as a team we went on to innovate and launch the successful lightly dried herb range in 2014.
We are currently piloting a new innovation with chilled finishing drizzles: a range of healthy sauces to drizzle over barbecue meats, made with Queensland-grown herbs and spices, cold blended with olive oil and no nasties.
In 2015, motivated by the Sunshine Coast regional development strategy, I co-founded the Food and Agribusiness Network (FAN) with Gourmet Garden colleague Andrew Eves-Brown and Sara Bucher, from Maleny Cheese.
FAN is not-for-profit organisation that is about creating connections and facilitating opportunities for its members.
This is a voluntary role but is so closely aligned with my day job that it helps Gourmet Garden, too.
And, selfishly, I would like to see the Sunshine Coast economy continue to prosper so that my children can have careers here one day, too.
Hyundai unveils its only fully-electric model in Australia
Work on next stage of redevelopment due to start next April
Coast's $18m rescue chopper has been shifted by Lifeflight
THE idea for COYO announced itself at three o'clock in the morning.
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
A NATIONAL exhibition of ceramic art has been launched on the Coast
BREAKING: New festival coming to the Sunshine Coast
ONE of Hollywood's most adorable couples is over.
New celebrity cooking show fails to fire for Seven.
The legendary creator isn't so sure about how Netflix works.
*WARNING this story contains spoilers*
Make way for Mackay's newest tech start up
Planning documents lodged on behalf of site owners
Education, student accommodation, bars and music all key to future
Five dates through August for community to have its say on rock wall
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>COYO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Eves-Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government-funded</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast's $18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LifeFlight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ernst</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny Cheese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland-grown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Technology</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woolworths</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big Six</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QUT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Sam Buculo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO of Gourmet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim Ginger</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sara Bucher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hyundai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alphen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Tuer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joy Varney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deborah Looseley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gourmet Garden</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor of Design</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pomona</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Agribusiness Network</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
