<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651446600862605681</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:22</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/the-show-is-a-day-out-for-the-entire-family/3208396/</url>
  <title>The show is a day out for the entire family</title>
  <content>
DESPITE being held in Nambour since 1909, the local show probably reached its peak as an agricultural showpiece in the 1960s.
Agriculture was the backbone of the area and primary to who had the biggest and the best.
The hub for exhibitors was the main pavilion. The upper level was taken by trade displays and the lower level by fruit and produce, cooking, crafts and flowers, with the displays often following a theme for that year.
Outside was the sugar cane display and machinery.
The grand parade was a must-see, as were other ring events such as the woodchop, showjumping and sideshow alley.
Until recently, parking was permitted in the showgrounds.
Smart families would bring their cars in at dawn then get a lift back home for a bit more sleep before returning later. There was nothing better than settling into your car on the hill as the sun set to eat show food and watch the evening's ring events and entertainment, culminating in the fireworks.
Since those days, agricultural pursuits have gradually diminished on the Sunshine Coast and sideshows and trade displays are now taking up proportionately more of the show area.
Many locals have had long associations with the show. One example is the late Fay Campbell, of Bli Bli, who started putting entries in the copybook section while at primary school in the 1940s.
For over 60 years, she has continued entering the cooking and flower sections, taking many prizes including grand champion camellia. She was also involved as a steward and sponsored prizes in the primary school writing and kidscraft sections.
Fashion was always important and it was common for Fay to be completing her new outfit at midnight the night before the show.
Over the years, the showgrounds area has undergone many improvements with better facilities and additional covered areas for exhibitors and the show is now experiencing a resurgence.
Seqwater facing massive shortfall because we are waterwise
University of the Sunshine Coast turns over a new leaf
Hyundai unveils its only fully-electric model in Australia
LIFESTYLE lure was stronger than a high-flying accountancy career.
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
A NATIONAL exhibition of ceramic art has been launched on the Coast
BREAKING: New festival coming to the Sunshine Coast
ONE of Hollywood's most adorable couples is over.
New celebrity cooking show fails to fire for Seven.
The legendary creator isn't so sure about how Netflix works.
*WARNING this story contains spoilers*
Make way for Mackay's newest tech start up
Planning documents lodged on behalf of site owners
Education, student accommodation, bars and music all key to future
Five dates through August for community to have its say on rock wall
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of the Sunshine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bli Bli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seqwater</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fay Campbell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hyundai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
