<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651446931575093065</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-08/more-boat-collisions-likely-thousands-whales-migrate-qld-coast/8782478</url>
  <title>More boat collisions likely as thousands more whales migrate up Queensland coast: expert</title>
  <content>
Dangerous collisions between boats and whales are likely to increase, as 30,000 of the mammals migrate up the Queensland coast this year, an expert has said.
Six men are lucky to be alive .
Two of the men were knocked unconscious, with one of them suffering severe facial injuries when they were thrown around the boat.
Maritime Safety Queensland said just 11 whale strikes were officially reported between 2012 and 2016.
There have been two serious incidents in the past fortnight, but only one officially reported to Maritime Safety Queensland this year.
In the second recent incident, three men had a lucky escape after a whale became tangled in their anchor rope off Magnetic Island, also in north Queensland, dragging the boat and almost pulling it under before the rope snapped.

Boat strikes 'are under-reported'

University of Queensland whale expert Associate Professor Michael Noad said such incidents were likely more common than first thought.
"We think the number of boat strikes is under-reported," he said.
"Recreational vessels, fishing vessels, hit whales from time to time but people rarely report it - for one thing, they're scared of getting in trouble - it probably is becoming more common as the number of whales increases."
Associate Professor Noad said the men on the A-One Fishing Charter in the Whitsundays on Saturday were very lucky.
"If a smaller vessel runs into a whale it's not just a problem for the whale, it's a problem for the people on board," he said.
"It could also cause boats to sink and that could cause loss of life."
In Queensland, boats must keep a 300-metre 'caution zone' around a whale.
But Associate Professor Noad said there was not much an angler or boatie could do if a whale decided to breach near them.
"There's probably nothing that anybody was doing wrong - it's just an unfortunate incident," he said.
"We need to really understand how whales move and behave around vessels so we can better predict what's going to happen and so we can develop proper mitigation measures before there's too much loss of life."

Swelling whale numbers fuel near-misses

The incident is one of several close encounters and near-misses in Queensland waters as whale numbers swell.
A humpback whale became entangled in a fishing boat anchor rope near Magnetic Island off Townsville a fortnight ago, dragging the boat and its stunned passengers for several metres before dunking them.
Steve Crespin said he and two friends were on the fishing boat when the incident happened.
"I honestly thought we were gone," Mr Crespin said in a video posted on Facebook.
He said the whale smashed two fishing rods hanging over the boat before gliding underneath their boat.
"As it's turned beside the boat and I've seen the under carriage of the whale ... I reckon the tail was as big as the boat," Mr Crespin said.
"Then it gets in front of us - we were going for a ride like Orca.
"I was about to grab a knife, run up the front and cut the rope ... then the boat went under the water and snapped the line."
He said the boat's anchor was ripped off and never seen again.
"There's a whale out there that's got an anchor and he's spoiled our fishing trip," Mr Crespin said.
In a statement, the Queensland Environment Department said collisions with whales should be reported to Maritime Safety Queensland.
"Even if skippers avoid cutting across the path of a whale or going within the approach limits, humpbacks may approach or nudge boats," the statement said.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Environment Department</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>One Fishing Charters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maritime Safety Queensland</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magnetic Island</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Associate Professor Michael Noad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Crespin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Crespin</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whitsundays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Associate Professor Noad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Noad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
