<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651446377524303041</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>18:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/police-doubling-down-on-a-dunkin-donuts-boycott-2017-8</url>
  <title>'I don't serve cops': People are calling for a Dunkin' Doughnuts boycott after police officers were reportedly refused service</title>
  <content>
Police are boycotting  after two cops were reportedly refused service. 

According to the  a cashier ignored two officers attempting to order at a Dunkin' Doughnuts in Brooklyn last week. The Dunkin' Doughnuts employee reportedly told another customer "I don't serve cops."

After the news broke, the New York City Detectives' Endowment Association, a local police union, encouraged members to

Dunkin' Doughnuts employees said that the issue was simply a mix-up as to where to order. Additionally, the company apologised for the incident - but it seems as though the damage is done.

that a police office refused to give directions to a Dunkin' Doughnuts on Sunday, and that police unions have called Dunkin's explanation "an insult." 

"No D&D in the 7-3," said a sergeant carrying a tray of generic, non-Dunkin' Doughnuts coffee into the 73rd Precinct station house, according to the Post. 

Boycott threats have also continued to swirl online. 

"I am never going to Dunkin Doughnuts again," reads one of many angry comments on  "What you did to those policemen was terrible, how dare you." 

"Your organisation should be ashamed of themselves!!!"  "Refusing to serve ANYONE is inexcusable. WHY would you refuse to serve police officers???"

"Dunkin' Doughnuts sincerely regrets this situation, and we apologise to the two police officers who were left unattended in the store," the company responded to one Facebook comment.

"We have a long history of supporting the NYPD and we take great pride in the number of officers our restaurants serve every day," Dunkin' Doughnuts' comment continued. "We continue to have conversations with the parties involved and we are hopeful for a satisfactory conclusion."

Dunkin' Doughnuts must apologise until that I buy my coffee at 7:11 boycott Dunkin' Doughnuts????????????????
- Fred (@sickNdisgusted)

NYPD Cops Launch Boycott Against Dunkin' Doughnuts. McDonalds coffee is CHEAPER and MUCH BETTER.
- Dennis Skea (@codekeyguy2)

Let's all Boycott, Dunkin Doughnuts...
I'm all in....Let's do it...It's the right thing to do, regardless of your political views.
- I'm a born Viking (@BklynThor)

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NYPD Cops Launch Boycott Against Dunkin' Doughnuts. McDonalds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dunkin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BROOKLYN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BklynThor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fred</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NYPD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York City Detectives' Endowment Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dunkin' Donuts</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vikings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dennis Skea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>sickNdisgusted</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MUCH BETTER</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
