<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651446592272670961</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/cane-was-king-before-the-tourists-came/3208289/</url>
  <title>Cane was king before the tourists came</title>
  <content>
LONG before the Sunshine Coast became a tourism hotspot - even before we were known as the Sunshine Coast - agriculture was the backbone of our economy.
And there is no argument that sugar cane was king.
As recently as 10 years ago there were fields of cane as far as the eye could see and cane fires lit the night sky before each harvest.
Cane trains rumbled through Nambour, taking their sweet loads to the mill in the centre of town, and generations of local families were proud to say they grew cane.
The Campbells, the Apps, the Suosaaris and many others could never imagine it would one day come to an end, with the closure of the mill in 2003 leaving the industry on its knees and the fields lying bare.
But while cane was the mainstay of agriculture in the region, pineapples, avocados, ginger, dairying and citrus have all played a role.
The fishing industry has also been through some tough times but still survives, with large prawn and tuna fleets still based on the Coast and the mackeral fishremen a regular sight along our beaches.
The Kuskopfs, Mackays, Cannons, Tuckers, Clarkes, Durbidges nd Radcliffes were just some of the families who made the industry what it is today.
But times have changed - they had to - and we've diversified into business aand manufacturing with several major industries now based on the Coast and taking advantage of the modern technology that enables manufacturing bases to set up and prosper in regional centres.
Things have certainly changed since 1967 and while they will never go back to the way they were, it will be interesting to look back in another 50 years and see how they have continued to evolve.
Hyundai unveils its only fully-electric model in Australia
Work on next stage of redevelopment due to start next April
Coast's $18m rescue chopper has been shifted by Lifeflight
LIFESTYLE lure was stronger than a high-flying accountancy career.
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
A NATIONAL exhibition of ceramic art has been launched on the Coast
BREAKING: New festival coming to the Sunshine Coast
ONE of Hollywood's most adorable couples is over.
New celebrity cooking show fails to fire for Seven.
The legendary creator isn't so sure about how Netflix works.
*WARNING this story contains spoilers*
Make way for Mackay's newest tech start up
Planning documents lodged on behalf of site owners
Education, student accommodation, bars and music all key to future
Five dates through August for community to have its say on rock wall
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Durbidges</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clarke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suosaaris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast's $18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Campbell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LifeFlight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cannon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Radcliffe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackay</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tucker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hyundai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kuskopfs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
