<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651446888625419341</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/08/05/45/sydney-tent-city-to-move-after-mayors-deal</url>
  <title>'Tent City' looks to remain at Martin Place as proclaimed mayor casts doubt on deal</title>
  <content>
Doubts have been cast on a deal which may see Martin Place's tent city dismantled this morning.
Lord Mayor of Sydney, Clover Moore, announced an agreement had been made between the city and proclaimed "mayor" of the tent city, Lanz Priestly, to help residents relocate to a "safe space" and then onto more permanent housing.
Sydney City Council trucks are expected to roll into the area this morning to help residents dismantle the city, which includes a make-shift 24-hour kitchen.
However, the long term solution sorely sought by Ms Moore and Mr Priestly seems no closer.

Ms Moore claimed yesterday the council would help pack the camp and transfer the approximately 70 residents to a "communal safe space" until temporary and permanent accommodation was found.
However, the location, facilities, and design of the space have still not been announced. 
Mr Priestley cast doubt on the deal, claiming the proposed safe space did not include beds.

Related Articles

Mr Priestley formally agreed to the proposal last night, but would not relinquish his push for people to be able to sleep at the space, AAP understands.
Speaking to 9NEWS this morning Mr Priestly said the tent city will not be moving if beds aren't part of the deal.
"Our intention is to stay here and transition seamlessly to that space," he said.
"It's absurd to think that the people staying here should just have nowhere to go in the interim."
People living at the tent city told 9NEWS this morning they would not be leaving the area until they're told where they're being moved to.
The Department of Family and Community Services has offered the residents of tent city temporary accommodation on numerous instances, and council expects the relocated individuals to accept those offers where suitable, a spokeswoman for Ms Moore told AAP.
However, if suitable accommodation was not found and the facility was able to house sleepers, people would not be forced to sleep on the street, she said.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Moore</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clover Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lanz Priestly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Priestley</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin Place</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Priestly</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Community Services</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lord Mayor of Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney City Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Family</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
