<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651446643812279353</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:32</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/seafaring-pioneers-paved-way/3208343/</url>
  <title>Seafaring pioneers paved way</title>
  <content>
IN THE late 1960s, Mooloolaba's fishing fleet consisted of 20 to 30 boats, mainly mackerel and reef boats with a few prawning vessels.
But the area's fishing history dates back to well before then.
My great, great uncle Alma "Butcher" Tucker had been fishing from Mooloolaba Beach since 1917 and had his maiden voyage on his new boat "Meridian" in June 1930.
In the mid-1930s, my grandfather Dudley Cannon, Bob Gunlack and Bob Durbidge, all based in Mooloolaba, bought a pearling boat with sails and engine and started fishing Swains Reef for mackerel.
Lloyd Clarke told my dad Kevin Cannon that grandad and crew were the first to fish the Swains. They had three small boats they would take out on the reef after anchoring the larger boat. Once they had 15,000 pound of mackerel on board, they would sail over 700km to Brisbane to unload their catch.
In the 1950s, my grandfather started prawning from Mooloolaba with Eddie Kuskopf. Bub Evans and Eddie Radcliffe soon followed. The Kuskopf family was well known in the Maroochydore district for their fishing and building skills.
Harry, Bill and Eddie Kuskopf were three of nine sons of Harry Kuskopf senior. The three brothers lived at Mooloolaba and had a slipway on the Spit.
Eddie became a professional fishermen and Harry, who also fished, constructed a number of buildings in the area and designed and built a wide range of boats.
Other early fishing families from Mooloolaba included the Durbidges, Wicks, Radcliffes, Evans, Carruthers, Wilsons and later the Flahertys.
In 1969, my dad Kevin Cannon and my uncle Jake Cannon bought the 13.72m wooden trawler "The Margaret Rose" for $9500, to be used for prawning. Previously, dad had been skippering for Jack Carr on "The Trump" and receiving a good pay of 25% of the catch.
He has told me stories of trawling up war items such as phosphorous flares, 120kg bombs and other assorted bombs, ammunition and land mines. He said the old phosphorous flares had a gel-like substance which leaked from them and would ignite when it dried on the deck.
It would ignite and dad recalled many times he had to wash the deck down.
The Durbidges, Kuskopfs and my grandfather Dudley Cannon had the netting rights to Mooloolaba and Mudjimba beaches, which are still held by Kevin Cannon and the Durbidge brothers, Frankie and Tom.
From the 1940s to 1960s, they hauled mullet on to Mooloolaba Beach by net, then packed the fish in crates and loaded them on to a truck which took them to the markets.
The original receiving depot was at Tom Durbidge's ice works at the corner of Parkyn Pde and River Esp, where the fish were packed in ice and transported to Brisbane by road.
In the late 1950s, a Queensland Government Fish Board building and jetty was established. The fish board was where The Wharf is today. Jack Clark owned Markwell's Fisheries and the old fish board was managed by Ken Smith.
Alan Scott had the old slipway next to the fishboard and also had hire boats for day fishing for visitors and an old steel barge he built himself that he used in a contract he held to re-fuel the local trawlers.
My dad helped launch the barge at Clarke's Jetty - the old jetty that was at Clarke Park, Mooloolaba. Alan was also in charge of keeping the lead lights, oil lamps, lit. Kevin said there was one on Point Cartwright side and one in the Mooloolah River mouth.
Jim Pickering had the slipway after Alan Scott. Before Mooloolaba Harbour was dredged the trawlers were often packed up and anchored out the front of Mooloolaba, as when the tide was low the sandbars that far up Mooloolah River were quite shallow, making it impossible to pass.
The crews would then row a dinghy out to the trawler, sometimes sinking on the way. Kevin remembers losing his dinghy and supplies on a few occasions.
Mooloolaba was considered a safe harbour, even though the sandbar and rocks in the mouth made it difficult. The rocks inside the Mooloolah River mouth, where the pilot station was built, were blasted out.
Dad says they would sound a siren to stop boats entering or exiting the mouth and then blow the rocks up using a fertiliser mix. An old crane was used to pick the rocks up and place them into barges to be taken out and dumped in deeper water.
The Port of Brisbane Pilot Station was opened on August 9, 1968.
The rock walls in Mooloolah River were started in 1967 and completed in 1968, giving easier entrance into the river.
The New Fishboard in Mooloolaba is situated between the old public wharf and the Mooloolaba Yacht Club and was opened in 1970. Ken Smith continues to manage the new fishboard.
Athol Sargood remembers his dad, Bob Sargood, building the family's trawlers - "The Leprechaun" and "The Delamekyl" - in the 1970s, at home at Broadmeadows Rd, Maroochydore.
Both were designed by Terry Burt and launched at the old fishboard.
Bob Sargood was instrumental in forming the Mooloolaba Co-Op. He wanted all of the trawler men to understand they were businessmen and wanted everyone to do well.
It was a big family back in the late 1960s, through the 1970s and 1980s. Everyone worked and played together.
I remember a "sea wives' club" whose members visited my mum when I was young, helping out whenever they could.
The prawning industry was booming in the 1970s and the Rotary Club of Mooloolaba staged the annual Prawn Festival from 1974-1984. "Norm the Prawn" was a big favourite and led the festival parade.
Raft races for the kids was a fun part of the festival. We all enjoyed making rafts from different materials, with most sinking not far from the starting line.
The Rotary club stopped holding the festival in the mid-1980s because it had grown too big for the location at The Spit. It was later downsized, moved to Kawana and called The Harvest of the Sea Festival.
A modern version of the Prawn Festival was The Mooloolaba Seafood Festival, which was held on The Spit in Mooloolaba for a couple years from 2005.
In late 2015 the Mooloolaba Slipway was dismantled. It had begun operation in late 1969 and was built by Pat Vansliev. According to Barry Apps, his father's vessel was the first to go onto the new slip.
The hull of the "Sea Pearl" was towed up from Caloundra and completed at the slipway. Racovolus took over the operation when they owned the adjoining factory, then Les Brown in the early '80s took over the wharf factory fuel and the slipway.
Les Brown leased the slipway to Les and Barry Apps in the early 2000s. Then Rockcliffs bought out Browns complex and continued to run it until 2014.
Mooloolaba Co-Op was bought by Dennis Poulos and about the same time Raptis bought all the Qld Fish Boards and soon after started shedding all of them except Colmslie. He had the slipway for some 20 years and it was a godsend for trawler operators. Peter Ashworth managed the slipway.
In 1967, the year the Sunshine Coast was named, a kerosene taint had spread through the fishing industry affecting many families, especiaally those who fished for mullet.
For 13 years when the migration run came through Moreton Bay and the fish moved north, they were considered polluted with kerosene taint due to them feeding off the sea grass where hydrocarbons had settled.
It was coming from the fallout from the sewage of the Pine River from the Australian Paper Mills or the Brisbane Sewerage System, which was polluting the waters of Moreton Bay.
Today, Mooloolaba Harbour is home to a large fleet of fishing vessels and is the northern base for the pilot vessels that control shipping through Moreton Bay and the Port of Brisbane.
Mooloolah River Fisheries Marina, on Parkyn Pde, services Mooloolaba's commercial fishing vessel fleet.
It was established by Tony Pinzone, a local fisherman, and Beverly Atkins and Murray Scott, and completed in 2002.
Mooloolah River Fisheries has evolved from a small operation to the largest operating seafood company on the Sunshine Coast and is one of the leading operators servicing the seafood and fishing industries in Australia.
Mooloolah River is a river of contrasts compared to 1967.
Ocean-going fishing trawlers come and go, the river shelters pleasure cruises and high-rise developments while homes and resorts sit along its banks.
When the ships head into and out of the Port of Brisbane it is up to Mooloolaba's Pilot Station crew to make sure all runs smoothly
A memorial dedicated to the fishermen and women lost at sea, and in honour of the fishing industry's heritage on the Sunshine Coast, is located at Mooloolaba Spit.
The 2.7m bronze sculpture by a local artist contains plaques with the names of seven fishermen lost off the Coast.
While there is anger at Queensland Government regulations which are strangling the industry, my dad says the best thing about working in the fishing industry is the lifestyle.
"It's not really a job when you enjoy what you do," he said.
Hyundai unveils its only fully-electric model in Australia
Work on next stage of redevelopment due to start next April
Coast's $18m rescue chopper has been shifted by Lifeflight
LIFESTYLE lure was stronger than a high-flying accountancy career.
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
A NATIONAL exhibition of ceramic art has been launched on the Coast
BREAKING: New festival coming to the Sunshine Coast
ONE of Hollywood's most adorable couples is over.
New celebrity cooking show fails to fire for Seven.
The legendary creator isn't so sure about how Netflix works.
*WARNING this story contains spoilers*
Make way for Mackay's newest tech start up
Planning documents lodged on behalf of site owners
Education, student accommodation, bars and music all key to future
Five dates through August for community to have its say on rock wall
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Durbidges</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mooloolah River Fisheries Marina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin Cannon</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frankie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Athol Sargood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bub Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rockcliffs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Clark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wharf</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rapti</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 1930</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bob Sargood</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flaherty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swains Reef</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotary Club of Mooloolaba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Government Fish Board</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Racovolus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Durbidge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harvest of the Sea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pine Rivers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake Cannon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast's $18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alan Scott</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port of Brisbane</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les Brown</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moreton Bay</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LifeFlight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ocean-going</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sea Pearl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Margaret Rose</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bob Durbidge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mooloolaba Seafood Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parkyn Pde</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kawana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meridian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colmslie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ken Smith</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Pinzone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mooloolaba Spit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Markwell's Fisheries</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mooloolaba Harbour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Radcliffe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mooloolah River Fisheries</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Carr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qld Fish Boards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mooloolaba</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tucker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pat Vansliev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carruthers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mudjimba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mooloolah River</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harry</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eddie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Sewerage System</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mooloolaba Co-Op</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dudley Cannon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mooloolaba Slipway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hyundai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kuskopfs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broadmeadows Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clarke Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prawn Festival</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terry Burt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eddie Radcliffe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bob Gunlack</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Fishboard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harry Kuskopf</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pilot Station</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dennis Poulos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eddie Kuskopf</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray Scott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>River Esp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mooloolaba Yacht Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lloyd Clarke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jim Pickering</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Point Cartwright</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clarke's Jetty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Paper Mills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mooloolaba's Pilot Station</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mooloolaba Beach</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barry Apps</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Delamekyl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beverly Atkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Ashworth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
