<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651446557912932000</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/drink-company-has-a-sweet-spot-in-our-history/3208441/</url>
  <title>Drink company has a sweet spot in our history</title>
  <content>
THE Wimmers soft drink name had been around for more than half a century when the Sunshine Coast was named in 1967.
Both it and Cooroy Mountain Spring Water came up as a business opportunity five years ago when both operations went into receivership during the GFC.
We had no experience in the beverage game but knew we wanted to keep these iconic Queensland businesses alive and running in their home town of Cooroy.
After the dust had settled, we amalgamated the businesses to create Noosa Beverages, which manufactures well-established brands Wimmers Premium Softdrinks, Cafe Earth, Noosa Natural Spring Water and Cooroy Mountain Spring Water.
With financial backing, good basic business management and significant commitment from our hard-working staff, we quickly turned both businesses back to being profitable.
With customers again demanding our products, we could see ourselves outgrowing the small manufacturing facility and so took the opportunity to purchase the old CSR brickworks site on Lake Macdonald Dr at Cooroy.
Major construction works took place over two years to develop the site into the massive 9000sqm building that is now home to our for best practice beverage manufacturing, warehousing, distribution and administration.
Using as many remaining materials as possible from the old brickworks plant, we carefully ensured the link to this long-time Cooroy factory was kept alive. The original old bricks feature prominently in our new foyer.
The facility has enough room for four bottling lines plus additional storage and has an expansive office space, while the land area can accommodate another 6000sqm building when required.
A brand new carbonated bottling line purchased from America to advance and broaden our beverage opportunities has both PET and glass capabilities.
This line has diversified our potential product range and increased significantly the speed at which we can bottle.
It gives us the opportunity to have our natural spring water used in our traditional Wimmers soft drinks and low sugar Cafe Earth flavored mineral waters as well as producing our own sparkling mineral water, which we are developing at present on request from a major grocer.
Not only have we made improvements to the carbonated side of the business but we also installed modern infrastructure at our Natural Spring Water site at the base of Cooroy Mountain, with an upgrade of high-flow water supply that can pump out 50 litres of our high quality natural spring water every second.
The future is now endless for Noosa Beverages as we have positioned the company to competitively explore opportunities for new beverage products with both natural spring water and carbonated components.
This has seen us maintain our long-time customers and attract new ones including overseas buyers who place a high value on quality and credible products of regional manufacturers like us.
Hyundai unveils its only fully-electric model in Australia
Work on next stage of redevelopment due to start next April
Coast's $18m rescue chopper has been shifted by Lifeflight
LIFESTYLE lure was stronger than a high-flying accountancy career.
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
A NATIONAL exhibition of ceramic art has been launched on the Coast
BREAKING: New festival coming to the Sunshine Coast
ONE of Hollywood's most adorable couples is over.
New celebrity cooking show fails to fire for Seven.
The legendary creator isn't so sure about how Netflix works.
*WARNING this story contains spoilers*
Make way for Mackay's newest tech start up
Planning documents lodged on behalf of site owners
Education, student accommodation, bars and music all key to future
Five dates through August for community to have its say on rock wall
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast's $18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LifeFlight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa Beverages</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Natural Spring Water</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cafe Earth</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cooroy Mountain Spring Water</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa Natural Spring Water</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wimmers Premium Softdrinks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hyundai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake Macdonald Dr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GFC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wimmer</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cooroy Mountain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CSR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cooroy</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
