<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651446545028029860</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/world/how-the-donald-trumps-washington-hotel-is-filling-the-presidents-coffers-20170807-gxrbh9.html</url>
  <title>How the Donald Trump's Washington hotel is filling the President's coffers</title>
  <content>
Washington: On a June morning, Romanian President Klaus Iohannis and his wife enjoyed croissants in the lounge of an opulent hotel, a day before joining US President Donald Trump a few blocks away at the White House for a Rose Garden news conference.
Downstairs that same day in the grand ballroom, hundreds of bankers discussed their industry's future under Treasury Secretary Steven Mnuchin, who lived in the hotel for six months at his own expense after Trump picked him for the job.

Up Next

Clip:
Sharknado 5

01:23

More Entertainment News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

02:50
Q&A: Could Trump destabilise US-Australia ...

Q&A: Could Trump destabilise US-Australia relationship?

Despite the historically strongA relationship, is it possible theA current US administration could change relationsA between Australia and the US?

Up Next

Clip:
Sharknado 5

01:23

01:23
Clip: Sharknado 5

Clip:
Sharknado 5

Showing off their acting skills, Karl Stefanovic and Lisa Wilkinson make an appearance in Sharknado 5, set in Sydney.

Up Next

Entertainment news highlights

02:09

02:09
Entertainment news highlights

Entertainment news highlights

Karl Stefanovic's new show, The Bachelor gets an RSPCA enquiry, Laurie Oaks retires, HBO gets hacked, ABC gets petitioned,and Elisabeth Moss doesn't nail the Aussie drawl.

Up Next
Australian Survivor 2017:
Tarzan moves on

01:20

01:20
Australian Survivor 2017: Tarzan moves on

Australian Survivor 2017:
Tarzan moves on

Saying he has no regrets the 51-year-old contestant who was affectionately dubbed Tarzan leaves the competition. Vision courtesy Australian Survivor facebook page

Up Next
Home and Away
legend defends Sam Frost

01:28

01:28
Home and Away legend defends Sam Frost

Home and Away
legend defends Sam Frost

'Get over it', Debra Lawrance, who played Pippa Ross on the long running soap bites back at critics who are unhappy with The Bachelorette moving into Summer Bay.

Up Next

Bachelorette Sam Frost chooses Sasha

00:42

00:42
Bachelorette Sam Frost chooses Sasha

Bachelorette Sam Frost chooses Sasha

Sam Frost picks builder Sasha Mielczarek during the first season of the Australian Bachelorette in 2015.

Up Next

Private Sydney: Roxy Jacenko chapter #3452

01:58

01:58
Private Sydney: Roxy Jacenko chapter #3452

Private Sydney: Roxy Jacenko chapter #3452

Things move fast on Planet Roxy. The troubles with her marriage, second weddings and diamond rings. Andrew Hornery investigates

Up Next

Al Gore: 'We are going to win' over climate change

01:27

Q&A: Could Trump destabilise US-Australia relationship?

Despite the historically strongA relationship, is it possible theA current US administration could change relationsA between Australia and the US?

The scenes illustrate a daily spectacle of Washington influence at 1100 Pennsylvania Avenue, the city's newest luxury hotel that has quickly become a kind of White House annex.
Since Trump's election, the Trump International Hotel has emerged as a Republican Party power centre where on a good day - such as July 28 around 8pm - excited visitors can watch the President share intimate dinner conversation with his just-named chief of staff, John Kelly, and be the first to brag about it on social media.

This is nothing Washington has ever seen before.
For the first time in presidential history, a profit-making venture touts the name of a US president in its gold signage. And every cup of coffee served, every fundraiser scheduled, every filet mignon ordered feeds the revenue of the Trump family's private business.

In conversations with The Washington Post, the hotel's management described its strategy to capitalise on the President's popularity.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

It markets the hotel to Republican and conservative groups that embrace Trump's politics, but takes care not to solicit business from fringe groups that would embarrass the President.Photo: AP
Trump supporters in red "Make America Great Again" caps get a chance to rub elbows with White House officials against an American flag backdrop at the Benjamin Bar, where a signature concoction of winter wheat vodka, oysters and caviar goes for $126.
"While we can't quantify how much business we have received because of politics, neither can we quantify how much we have lost," Patricia Tang, director of sales and marketing, said in an interview.Photo: AP
It is difficult to see comings and goings at the hotel. There are no signs in the lobby to direct guests to daily events, velvet ropes block the public from meeting areas, and some groups holding conventions and banquets omit references to Trump's name in their promotional materials. Many decline to answer questions about why they chose the Trump hotel from the many similar luxury Washington venues.
The Washington Post spent part of every day in May in the hotel's bars, restaurants and lobby. What reporters saw ranged from events hosted by foreign groups with policy priorities to Republican glitterati - Rudolph Giuliani posing for selfies at the bar the night Trump fired FBI director James Comey; White House aide Omarosa Manigault conferring with the former producer of The Apprentice; former Trump campaign adviser Corey Lewandowski plopping into a black leather chair marked "Reserved"; then-press secretary Sean Spicer scrolling through his phone on a plush blue sofa in the lobby.Photo: AP
The parade included out-of-town tourists gawking in the lobby; bartenders hawking bottles of Champagne for $3150; a light artist at nightfall projecting a protest message on the gray stone facade that read "Pay Trump Bribes Here."
Trump, as titular leader of the Republican Party, has showcased the hotel as a destination of choice for GOP loyalists.
In July, about 300 Republican donors, paying $44,100 apiece, gathered at the hotel for a fundraiser headlined by the President. The event raised an estimated $12.6 million for Trump's campaign, the Republican National Committee and other GOP groups, according to news reports at the time.
Money also has poured in from other Republican political committees that have chosen the Trump hotel as a venue for receptions. The hotel has hosted events for Dana Rohrabacher, Bill Shuster and nine other Republican members of Congress, according to campaign spending disclosures.
No one has yet calculated how much taxpayer money is being spent at the hotel, though a Texas newspaper is seeking records of state expenditures there.
In Maine, the Portland Press Herald dug into Republican Governor Paul LePage's spending at the hotel when in Washington for White House meetings. LePage's spokesman defended the expenditures, telling the newspaper that the governor was meeting with federal officials "in an effort to benefit the Maine people."
Business from foreign customers is brisk, the hotel says, but as an ethical precaution, it says it does not market directly to foreign embassies. Under an agreement signed by Trump, the hotel has promised to donate any profits made from foreign governments to the U.S. Treasury. An obscure constitutional provision known as the emoluments clause prohibits the president from profiting from foreign governments without specific approval from Congress.
But groups with foreign interests have found that the location helps attract Washington star power. In May, a pair of business groups promoting Turkish-American relations staged their annual convention at the hotel during a tense moment between the countries.
The Turkish ambassador was there, and a high-ranking State Department official offered his thoughts on a violent protest that led to arrests at the ambassador's residence in Washington. Trump confidant Newt Gingrich stressed the importance of smooth relations in a keynote luncheon speech.
At the convention's end, 190 guests feasted on a three-course dinner at $120 per person, with the bill paid by the event sponsors. Breakfast, dinner and drinks on May 23 alone ran to more than $37,800, including a "Banquet Event Service Charge" of 24 per cent and eight gallons of Trump Signature Segafredo Zanetti Coffee, internal documents show.
A high-end renovation of the historic Old Post Office Pavilion, the 263-room hotel has become a symbol of the tangled ethical questions posed by Trump's presidency. The Trump Organisation, then headed by the billionaire New York developer, leased the property from the General Services Administration in 2013 and pays the federal agency $315,000 in rent each month.
Since Trump's election, his critics have charged that anyone seeking favour from the White House has an incentive to stay in posh rooms that can be booked on the internet for $504 per night or more.
One of Washington's most expensive hotels, the Trump International brought in $24.8 million between its opening last year and mid-April, according to Trump's most recent financial disclosure.
Some hotel industry experts say that number is higher than expected, and senior analyst Michael Bellisario of Robert W. Baird and Co. said, "Anecdotally, it's doing well because people are staying there when they come to visit the White House."
Trump tried to address ethical concerns by turning over the hotel's management to his two eldest sons and vowing to take no hotel profits during his tenure. But he retained his ownership interest, allowing him to eventually profit from the holdings.
The arrangement did little to quell controversy. Early this year, lobbying reports revealed that some veterans groups had been brought in to lobby Congress against a law allowing victims of the September 11, 2001 attacks to sue Saudi Arabia. The veterans groups ran up $340,000 in hotel charges, including about $239,000 for rooms, $98,000 for catering and $2015 for parking, the filings showed.
The bill was ultimately paid by the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia. Trump embarked three months later on a trip to Saudi Arabia - his first international trip. The White House did not respond to questions. The Saudi embassy did not respond to requests for comment.
The Trump hotel has faced lawsuits since its opening. The most recent ones filed by two state attorneys general, members of Congress and competing Washington convention businesses contend that Trump is violating the emoluments clause.
Trump's donation to the US Treasury is aimed for the end of the year, and Tang said the hotel keeps a separate ledger to record any payments from foreign governments.
But Trump critics such as Eleanor Holmes Norton, who worked with Ivanka Trump on the original development plans for the hotel, argue that the novel legal questions posed by the emoluments lawsuits will eventually force the President to give up ownership.
"I can't believe that there's any court that will say the emoluments clause does not apply here, notwithstanding that it has never been tried in court before," Norton said.
For Trump supporters, the hotel offers a safe space in an overwhelmingly Democratic city. For Republican lobbyists, conservative groups and foreign entities, including many that do not typically enjoy White House access, it has become a frequent stop.
The hotel's visibility also has made it a central target for activists representing immigrants, climate science and labour groups who aren't always successful on Capitol Hill but can sometimes make the evening news protesting at the hotel.
In May, Trump's son Eric and his wife, Lara, stopped by while in town for a golf tournament at Trump's Virginia course. Spicer, who promoted the hotel as "absolutely stunning" after Trump was elected, ate alone near the bar.
Lobbying groups and foreign entities held galas in the "Presidential Ballroom" designed by Ivanka Trump to offer larger event space than any other luxury hotel in the city.
The Benjamin Bar, named after Benjamin Franklin, served as a nightly resting spot for White House visitors and a green room for Trump surrogates on their way to or from media hits.
The Trump family's event planner, Lynne Patton, now a senior official in the Department of Housing and Urban Development, posted a video online from the hotel lobby in which she and friends pitched Ivanka Trump's new book.
One Friday evening in May, a group of Russian clerics arrived in the long, black flowing robes and beards of the Eastern Orthodox church for closing ceremonies of the World Summit in Defence of Persecuted Christians, in partnership with the Reverend Franklin Graham and his evangelical organisation, the Billy Graham Evangelistic Association. More than 800 people from 130 countries and territories attended.
The Turkish event from May 21 to 23 was booked before the election, according to organisers, but came as the government of Turkey stepped up its presence in Washington, hiring a Florida-based Trump fundraiser, Brian Ballard, as a lobbyist.
The event was co-chaired by a group headed by K. Ekim Alptekin, founder of a company that paid retired Lt. Gen. Michael Flynn for lobbying work that may have benefited the Turkish government. The former Trump national security adviser is now under investigation by the Pentagon and congressional committees regarding his relationships with foreign governments.
Alptekin surprised ballroom guests during the first morning session by directly addressing the hiring of Flynn's company to "help me understand where the Turkish-American relationship is going and what the obstacles to the relationship are."
Consulting giant Deloitte did not respond to questions about its decision to use the hotel for a June 8 event that attracted hundreds of banking leaders as Congress discussed whether Dodd-Frank financial regulations should be rolled back.
Meanwhile, the ties between the hotel and the White House have only strengthened. First lady Melania Trump chose the hotel's director of rooms as White House usher, adding to a former caddie, hotel spokeswoman and bodyguard from Trump's business who have all found positions in the White House.
Anti-Trump protesters continue to use the venue to speak out on the President's policies. It is not unusual for the hotel to suspend service at its European-style sidewalk cafe and move guests inside.
One evening, hotel staff guided guests inside just in time to miss a man in a wheelchair rolling down the street out front giving the hotel the middle finger as part of a demonstration for disabled rights.
"It's such a symbol of Trump and his excesses," said Donna Norton of MomsRising, a liberal network with more than 1 million members who led about 100 people on a march to the hotel in May.
She said when her protest group arrived, the hotel staff was very polite in turning them away.
"I think they're getting used to it," she said.
Washington Post 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Republican Governor Paul LePage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alptekin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pennsylvania Avenue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eastern Orthodox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Benjamin Franklin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turkish American</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Old Post Office Pavilion</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Norton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Housing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treasury Secretary Steven Mnuchin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump International Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deloitte</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karl Stefanovic</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Debra Lawrance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arabia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Survivor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TheA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turkey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Frost</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saudi Arabia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump Bribes Here</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rudolph Giuliani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HBO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Republican National Committee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Banquet Event Service Charge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>General Services Administration</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump Organisation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump International</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 28</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Defence of Persecuted</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lisa Wilkinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pentagon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>relationsA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Bachelorette</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brian Ballard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lynne Patton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eleanor Holmes Norton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spicer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Summit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anti-Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sasha</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melania Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tarzans</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flynn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Portland Press Herald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elisabeth Moss</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saudi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Texas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>13</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Planet Roxy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>strongA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bachelorette Sam Frost</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Treasuries</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shuster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bachelorette</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump's Virginia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turkish</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dodd-Frank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump's Washington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laurie Oaks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Republicans</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>34</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Benjamin Bar</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Bellisario of Robert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Omarosa Manigault</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gen. Michael Flynn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Comey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington Post</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ivanka Trump</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Florida-based Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Hornery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Summer Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Urban Development</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Republican Party</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Q</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sharknado 5</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roxy Jacenko</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eric</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donna Norton of MomsRising</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patricia Tang</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RSPCA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>K. Ekim Alptekin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>European-style</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rose Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sasha Mielczarek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US-Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pippa Ross</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Department</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GOP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tang</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Make America Great Again</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Survivor 2017</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sean Spicer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FBI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maine</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Capitol Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Billy Graham Evangelistic Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LePage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump Signature Segafredo Zanetti Coffee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newt Gingrich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>U.S Treasury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 21</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reverend Franklin Graham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Al Gore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Romanian President Klaus Iohannis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dana Rohrabacher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kingdom of Saudi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>W. Baird</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corey Lewandowski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
