<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651446162775934996</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>17:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/08/03/33/sea-crustaceans-eat-vic-teen-s-skin</url>
  <title>Sea crustaceans eat Vic teen's skin</title>
  <content>
A teenager left bleeding profusely after sea crustaceans ate his skin at a Melbourne beach remains in hospital.
Shocking images of Sam Kanizay's lower legs and feet have been beamed around the world after the 16-year-old went for a dip at Brighton's Dendy Street Beach on Saturday night to cool his aching muscles following a tough game of footy.
"He went back to his shoes and what he found was blood on his legs," Sam's dad Mr Kanizay told AAP.
"They ate through Sam's skin and made it bleed profusely.
"As soon as we wiped them down, they kept bleeding."
Unable to staunch the flow, Mr Kanizay took his son to hospital, where staff were at a loss to explain what could have turned the teen's legs into what looked like a scene from a horror film.
Mr Kanizay returned to the beach to collect some of the creatures and put them in a dish with meat, which they swarmed.

Related Articles

"What is really clear is these little things really love meat," he said.
Museums Victoria marine biologist Genefor Walker-Smith examined part of the sample and found they were a scavenging crustacean know as lysianassid amphipods.
She said it was possible the bugs contained an anti-coagulant similar to that produced by leeches, which explained the inability to stem the flow of blood.
While the creatures are not venomous and cause no lasting damage, Sam remains in Dandenong Hospital unable to walk.
"Whenever he will move, it will open up those wounds ... so I think there'll be some time, probably, on the couch when he gets home," Mr Kanizay said.
(C)  AAP 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Genefor Walker-Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brighton's Dendy Street Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Kanizay</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Museums Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Kanizay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dandenong Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
