<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651446600862605697</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:22</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/everyone-has-childhood-memories-of-going-to-the-sh/3208394/</url>
  <title>Everyone has childhood memories of going to the show</title>
  <content>
WE ALL have fond childhood memories of our first visit to the local show. Agricultural shows have been part of our history since 1822 and 128 are held in Queensland each year.
The tradition keeps our history alive by engaging, educating and entertaining those who come to see competitions, displays, livestock, poultry and much more.
Sunshine Coast residents are blessed with three quality agricultural shows.
The Sunshine Coast Show has its origins at Woombye where it was established in 1900 before relocating to the larger Nambour Showgrounds in 1909.
The Noosa Show, based at Pomona, dates back to 1909 while the Maleny Show celebrated its 80th birthday this year.
The names may have changed over the years in line with shire boundary alterations but there is no doubt that the past 50 years has seen the events grow in strength and popularity.
Just a few kilometres further away, you'll also find neighbouring towns and villages such as Kenilworth, Eumundi, Mary Valley, Gympie, Woodford, Kilcoy and Caboolture all hosting their own unique shows.
A mix of exhibition, competition, festivities, commerce, education, arts and culture has popularised agricultural shows, with many families regarding them as an annual tradition. Some simply treasure the experience while others take on a more active role by volunteering or competing.
Behind every country show can be found generations of motivated supporters and achievers. How some were first introduced into competition makes interesting reading.
My mother was a good cook but my interests lay elsewhere on the sporting fields. Many years later, in the early 1980s, I mentioned to renowned champion fruit cake-maker Esme Stewart  that even I could make better pikelets than many I had seen at the local show.
Months later, an entry form for the show cooking section mysteriously arrived in my letterbox. I took up the challenge and won first prize but more importantly it provided a reason to engage and become involved in a small way.
In the years which followed, my three daughters were encouraged to participate in the show cooking. Along the way, the family pikelet recipe proved a winner but the competition is now very tough with nine-year-old granddaughter Caitlyn giving the old boy a run for his money.
With winning entries across the board in Junior and Open divisions at Maleny and Nambour shows, she is highly motivated and just loves cooking.
It's ironic that our 35-year family connection with the Sunshine Coast Show began in such an obscure way.
Also noteworthy is the extraordinary service and passion for their craft offered by the stewards and officials. The same names, smiles and warm greetings appear year after year.
Just up the road at Belli Park, Allen Burton may well have supplied the eggs for our cooking as his life revolves around chooks. His great-grandfather Frederick Burton exhibited jersey cattle at the first Woombye Show, grandfather Victor continued the tradition and also showed poultry.
Allen reckons, too, that once it's in your blood, it's there to stay, with his first poultry entry at the age of seven. Thirty years later, he was excited to win the Grand Champion Bird of Show.
Chief stewards are the lifeblood of any agricultural show and there is no better illustration of their dedication than the late Les Dowdle's 50 years, followed by another 30 years from Ron Lait ruling the poultry roost at the Sunshine Coast Show.
Agricultural shows have always been about more than just plants and animals. They recognise the achievements and contributions of ordinary members of the community across a broad range of activities and highlight the interdependence and mutual appreciation between city and country life.
Curiosity and interest is aroused in both young and old as many visitors and competitors discover new opportunities and better ways of doing things. Across the board, pride in representation and presentation shines through at each country show.
For more than 30 years, the Nambour State High School has incorporated agriculture in its curriculum, providing students with opportunities to engage with and gain practical experience in agricultural studies.
Under the guidance of former Head of Department and Sunshine Coast Show stalwart Ray Pembleton and with their own working dairy farm, students really do get to appreciate farm life.
Proudly attending and showing their entries at many local shows, the rewards are written all over the students' faces.
The added bonus is that a future career in agriculture beckons.
The country show has always been regarded as the local community's entertainment event of the year. The first Woombye show included just three sideshow alley rides including one merry-go-round.
The range and quality of sideshow, ring and night entertainment today is amazing and Sunshine Coast families have numerous opportunities to attend and participate.
Admission prices and cost of entry into competitions is family friendly.
The future will remain bright while community support and family ties remain strong and the dedicated bands of volunteers keep rolling up each year.
With growing interest and engagement from within local schools and recent initiatives such as Next Gen, the traditional agricultural show is destined to remain a highlight on our family entertainment calendar.
Long live Miss Showgirl, I say.
Seqwater facing massive shortfall because we are waterwise
University of the Sunshine Coast turns over a new leaf
Hyundai unveils its only fully-electric model in Australia
LIFESTYLE lure was stronger than a high-flying accountancy career.
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
A NATIONAL exhibition of ceramic art has been launched on the Coast
BREAKING: New festival coming to the Sunshine Coast
ONE of Hollywood's most adorable couples is over.
New celebrity cooking show fails to fire for Seven.
The legendary creator isn't so sure about how Netflix works.
*WARNING this story contains spoilers*
Make way for Mackay's newest tech start up
Planning documents lodged on behalf of site owners
Education, student accommodation, bars and music all key to future
Five dates through August for community to have its say on rock wall
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa Show</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Miss Showgirl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mary Valley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of the Sunshine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kenilworth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woodford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woombye</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny Show</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frederick Burton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gympie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Allen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seqwater</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Champion Bird of Show</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour Showgrounds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Allen Burton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woombye Show</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caboolture</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Esme Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Next-gen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eumundi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Head of Department</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kilcoy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour State High School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hyundai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Show</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ron Lait</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caitlyn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les Dowdle's 50</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ray Pembleton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pomona</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belli Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
