<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651446338869596773</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>18:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/how-many-executive-orders-trump-signed-obama-clinton-bush-2017-8</url>
  <title>Here's how many executive orders Trump signed in his first 200 days compared to Obama, Bush, and Clinton</title>
  <content>
Before he became president, Donald Trump  of abusing his power by signing so many executive orders.

But during his first 200 days in office, Trump signed more than Obama averaged in a year.

are assigned numbers and published in the federal register, similar to laws passed by Congress, and they typically direct members of the executive branch to follow a new policy or directive.

have reversed , , and . Trump's nine executive orders he signed on days 101-200 of his presidency established a , , and , to name a few actions.

Scholars have typically used the number of executive orders per term to measure how much presidents have exercised their power. George Washington signed eight his entire time in office, according to the , while Franklin Delano Roosevelt signed more than 3,700.

In his two terms, Obama issued , a total number on par with his modern predecessors, but the lowest per-year average (35) in 120 years. Trump signed 42 executive orders in 200 days.

Here's how Trump compares to his last three predecessors:

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Franklin Delano Roosevelt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Obama</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clinton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George Washington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bush</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
