<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651446587977703537</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/rick-kept-pace-with-the-coasts-pool-fads/3208435/</url>
  <title>Rick kept pace with the Coast's pool fads</title>
  <content>
WE arrived on the Sunshine Coast in 1974, to build a home and raise our children.
I had brought my Bobcat loader (the first on the Sunshine Coast) and all the equipment needed to begin landscape design and construction.
The industry required very heavy manual labour and provision for wet weather conditions, ranging from summer cyclones to winter east coast low wet conditions.
As time progressed, the swimming pool part of my business blossomed to become my main business.
After I had been associated with a large swimming pool company for a period of time, I studied reinforced plastics technology to start my own fibreglass swimming pool factory (Sunpools), firstly in Mountain Creek and later in Fisherman's Rd.
This required skilled staff and the purchase of specialised machinery. This business also encouraged DIY swimming pool installations as well as contract installations.
During this period we also became specialised as sprayed concrete builders and I also became qualified in concrete technology, including arranging sprayed concrete testing.
While pursuing this side of my business I became specialised in underwater glazing, difficult slope construction, skate park construction and waterslide construction, including the popualr Thrill Hill.
The concrete pools were sprayed concrete. They might have been fairly basic pools but most of them are still going now - all those years later.
Before that they had been mostly made of concrete blocks and tended to leak.
In the early days, every time we needed a concrete pump we had to hire one and a crew of people from Brisbane.
We used to have a template we would give to people so they could mark out what they wanted.
They could spend the weekend running around the yard laying it out and I'd tell them that come Monday when I went back to start work, that would be the design they would get.
People go through fads. It was angular pools for a couple of years but then it went back to free-form shapes.
We've done concrete archways, portholes, waterfalls, slippery slides and built the Sunshine Coast's first infinity vanishing edge pool.
By the time I retired 10 years ago we were even installing self-monitoring, self-cleaning pools.
The industry certainly changed and peoples' tastes changed as well, but I'm proud of the way we handled those changes.
Hyundai unveils its only fully-electric model in Australia
Work on next stage of redevelopment due to start next April
Coast's $18m rescue chopper has been shifted by Lifeflight
LIFESTYLE lure was stronger than a high-flying accountancy career.
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
A NATIONAL exhibition of ceramic art has been launched on the Coast
BREAKING: New festival coming to the Sunshine Coast
ONE of Hollywood's most adorable couples is over.
New celebrity cooking show fails to fire for Seven.
The legendary creator isn't so sure about how Netflix works.
*WARNING this story contains spoilers*
Make way for Mackay's newest tech start up
Planning documents lodged on behalf of site owners
Education, student accommodation, bars and music all key to future
Five dates through August for community to have its say on rock wall
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fisherman's Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thrill Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast's $18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LifeFlight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hyundai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DIY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunpools</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mountain Creek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
