<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445767638936137</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>16:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/lifestyle/parenting/mum-slammed-for-video-of-her-straightening-oneyearold-daughters-curly-hair/news-story/84c67b8d6602d5523e4efe2da7d8a9c1</url>
  <title>Mum slammed for video of her straightening one-year-old daughter's curly hair</title>
  <content>
A mum has been slammed for straightening her one-year-old daughter's curly hair. Picture: Instagram.

The SunNews Corp Australia Network

Share

A MUM has been slammed for straightening her one-year-old daughter's curly hair.
Many users criticised mum Crystal Harden for "sexualising" her daughter Aiden, one, at a young age.
Crystal Harden unwittingly started the debate after sharing a video of Aiden with newly-straightened hair, alongside the caption: "Straightened my baby's hair yesterday - she's so gorgeous".
The clip, which shows little Aiden shaking her head to show off her smoothed locks, has since been shared by Instagram account The Shade Room - where it's had more than two million views,

A post shared by Crystal Harden (@i_get_in_your_head) on

Many web users have criticised the mum for using straighteners on the tot, who is nearly two, with many believing that she is too young to have her hair styled in such a way.
One user commented: "Too young gonna damage her hair early on."
Another critic said: "Stop sexualising your daughter."
Others were keen to add that they thought the mum should "let that baby be a damn baby!"
Another added: "She should be playing w/ toys not showing off her damn hairstyle.

"Ughhhhh some mums these days."
However, others were more supportive of Crystal and her daughter's "beautiful" locks.
One such user wrote: "Your baby is so perfect. And her hair is pretty.
"Do what you want with her as long as it doesn't hurt her you're fine.
"Don't let these people tell you what to do."
Crystal later reacted to the comments in an interview on Yahoo, saying: "I received the negative reactions that the majority of people gave me from my own mum.

Aiden. Picture: Instagram.Source:Supplied
"She was like, 'Oh it was too mature to do her hair like that. You shouldn't have posted that. There are creeps out there'."
But, the mum-of-one defended straightening Aiden's hair, adding: "She loved it. She was swinging her hair.
"I took her to the park and the wind was blowing. She just loved it."
She went on to insist: "I don't want her to be preconditioned to think that she has to straighten her curls, because her hair is beautiful curly and it's beautiful straight.
"I just wanted to see herself in a different light and know that she is beautiful any way that she dresses up or however she does her hair."
This article was
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>SunNews Corp Australia Network</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crystal Harden</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aiden</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yahoo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shade Room</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crystal</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ughhhhh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
