<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651446802726071765</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4839995/lets-have-a-chat-about-dying/?cs=2452</url>
  <title>Let's have a chat ... about dying</title>
  <content>
Photo: AjayTvm/Shutterstock.com

Dying to Know day, a national annual day of action dedicated to bringing to life conversations and community actions around death and dying.

It is a GroudSwell initiative to help individuals and communities take action toward end-of-life planning.

GroundSwell Project executive director Jessie Williams said "death cafes", seminars on death and dying and even art exhibitions were among the events planned nationwide for Dying to Know Day.
"There are people all over Australia talking about and keen to change the current approach to death," she said. 
RELATED READING

DID YOU KNOW?

75% of us have not had end of life discussions
60% think we don't talk about death enough
Over 70% of us die in hospital though most of us would prefer to die at home
Very few of us die with an advance care plan (less than 10 percent)
The number of Australians aged 65 and over will double by 2050 increasing our need to plan while well and share our wishes with our loved ones
WE WANT TO ENCOURAGE ALL AUSTRALIANS TO:

develop their death literacy
make their end of life plans such as a will and advance care plans
share these wishes with their families
get informed about end of life and death care options such as dying at home, home and community led funerals and natural burial
be better equipped to support family and friends experiencing death, dying and bereavement
WHAT CAN YOU DO? 

Host an event in your local community or workplace and start a conversation
Host a  or a  event
Take a personal action such as writing your will or having a conversation with a loved one
Sign up for a  and kick start your end of life planning

Photo: http://www.dyingtoknowday.org

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AjayTvm/Shutterstock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CAN YOU DO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jessie Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Know Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GroudSwell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WANT TO ENCOURAGE ALL AUSTRALIANS TO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
