<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651446566502866649</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:14</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/beefys-boss-says-the-proofs-in-the-pies/3208447/</url>
  <title>Beefy's boss says the proof's in the pies</title>
  <content>
MY family has been lovingly baking meat pies on the Sunshine Coast for 20 years.
From humble beginnings as Sunrise Bakery at Aussie World in 1997, our family enterprise has grown into what has been known as Beefy's since 2006 and is soon to become a 10-store bakery business.
Today, from our manufacturing facility at Kunda Park, our Beefy's team bakes the biggest, beefiest meat pies to satisfy the appetites of south-east Queenslanders.
It was my father Ron who had the vision and seized on the early opportunities to grow and expand the business. We grew from one site to two and later took the giant step to move into a factory setting.
This increased our production capacity and really opened the door for expansion. However, it also presented a couple of big challenges.
We had to meet the high costs involved in establishing a factory and expanding. There were certainly some tough years in there with lots of long hours spent at work just to stay afloat.
We really turned the corner in 2007 when we opened our third store on the Bruce Hwy at the Glasshouse Mountains.
The second challenge we faced centred on consistency.
We'd developed a reputation for producing a consistently high-quality product from our bakery sites and we knew we needed to maintain that consistency and quality at our factory if we were to keep the loyalty of our growing customer base.
We managed to do that and our customers' love of Beefy's continued.
We outgrew the old factory and moved to our current Kunda Park factory site in 2009. That factory underwent expansion in 2014.
We have not only continued to open more stores (the new-look 10th Beefy's store is located at Buddina) but have also developed our range to include the Gluten Free Signature Steak Pie to the menu in 2014 and gluten-free home delivery in 2016.
We always put our customers first and the evolution of our business reflects that.
As Sunshine Coast locals' love of Beefy's grew, our manufacturing expanded and we opened more stores in convenient locations and made our pies more accessible.
For example, we opened our first Beefy's drive-through and fourth store at Ningi in 2011 to help meet the needs of customers on the run.
The Beefy's menu has also evolved to meet customers' changing tastes, with new pie flavours and then gluten-free pies added to our range.
The gluten-free range came about because one of our sons has Coeliac Disease and we really wanted him to experience what it was like to eat his very own great-tasting Beefy's pie.
The Beefy's Gluten-Free Signature Steak Pie won Best Gluten-Free Pie at The Official Great Aussie Pie Competition in 2015 and 2016.
Our team has been key to our success with us now employing 175 locals. Many are long-serving - our production manager Rod Hardy has been with us for 20 years - and we all share the same commitment to continuous improvement and delivering what our customers want: bigger, better, beefier meat pies.
Hyundai unveils its only fully-electric model in Australia
Work on next stage of redevelopment due to start next April
Coast's $18m rescue chopper has been shifted by Lifeflight
LIFESTYLE lure was stronger than a high-flying accountancy career.
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
A NATIONAL exhibition of ceramic art has been launched on the Coast
BREAKING: New festival coming to the Sunshine Coast
ONE of Hollywood's most adorable couples is over.
New celebrity cooking show fails to fire for Seven.
The legendary creator isn't so sure about how Netflix works.
*WARNING this story contains spoilers*
Make way for Mackay's newest tech start up
Planning documents lodged on behalf of site owners
Education, student accommodation, bars and music all key to future
Five dates through August for community to have its say on rock wall
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ningi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kunda Park</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Official Great Aussie Pie Competition</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coeliac Disease</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast's $18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beefy's Gluten-Free Signature Steak Pie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gluten Free Signature Steak Pie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LifeFlight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rod Hardy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buddina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glasshouse Mountains</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RON</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queenslanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hyundai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunrise Bakery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie World</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruce Hwy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Best Gluten-Free Pie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
