<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651446420473976572</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>18:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/christian-hackenberg-ordered-off-practice-field-breaking-huddle-2017-8</url>
  <title>Much-maligned Jets quarterback Christian Hackenberg was ordered off the practice field when he failed one his most basic tasks</title>
  <content>
The New York Jets have been looking for an answer to their quarterback woes since Mark Sanchez left the franchise in 2012 and many had hoped that 2016 second-round pick Christian Hackenberg would eventually become the long-term starter under center.

But judging by a few anecdotes coming out of training camp, there's still plenty of room for improvement.

A  noted that Hackenberg was sent off the field on Monday after struggling to break the huddle correctly.

During one rep in seven-on-seven drills, as he approached the line of scrimmage, a coach ordered him to re-huddle. When he broke the huddle again - in the wrong fashion for a second time - he was ordered off the field.

This is just the latest troubling report for Hackenberg. In June, reports from offseason workouts noted that the second-year quarterback had developed . Also, another report from before the NFL Draft noted that the Jets believed that Hackenberg was "" to being ready to be an NFL starter.

Expectations aren't high for the Jets this year, but the team will want to figure out whether or not Hackenberg can be their guy moving forward.

That said, Hackenberg reportedly recovered smoothly from the most recent mishap, with Rohan noting, "The next time Hackenberg took the field, he broke the huddle correctly and threaded a pass about 20 yards downfield for a completion."

The Jets kickoff preseason action on Saturday against the Tennessee Titans, where fans and coaches alike will watching Hackenberg, McCown, and Petty to see who appears best-equipped to lead the team through the season.

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Sanchez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McCown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christian Hackenberg</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tennessee Titans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rohan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NFL Draft</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hackenberg</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York Jets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
