<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651446587977703593</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/agriculture-was-our-backbone-for-generations/3208301/</url>
  <title>Agriculture was our backbone for generations</title>
  <content>
MENTION the Sunshine Coast today and images of a picturesque coastal strip with glorious surfing beaches immediately spring to mind.
But there are equally bright highlights in the lush green hinterland. From top to bottom, the region is renowned for its agricultural and horticultural qualities.
For more than a century, sugar cane was the dominant industry in the region and the driving force behind development.
Centred on Nambour, the sugar industry and farming of tropical fruits such as pineapples and ginger was in full swing in the 1960s.
The closure of the Moreton Central Sugar Mill in 2003 had a huge impact on not only Nambour but other communities and businesses along the coastal strip, as farms closed and livelihoods were ruined.
Fourteen years later, much of the cane land remains idle as it is not suitable for other purposes. An area which once produced more than half a million tonnes of cane annually now grows just 60,000 tonne, with the crop shipped to Maryborough for milling.
Some cane farmers like Troy Apps, whose family farmed near the Maroochy River for four generations, still retain a positive outlook for the industry.
Troy is working with the University of Queensland on new environmentally-sensitive ways of putting nitrogen into the soil and he sees at least one of his three children watching with interest as he works his crops, possibly pondering a career in the 21st Century sugar paddock.
In contrast, Ross Boyle's land at Rosemount had been farmed by the Boyle family for 97 years and the mill closure created a challenge for the family to find a productive use for their property on the rich river flats.
With the sort of tenacity his grandfather showed establishing the cane farm all those years ago, Ross began the development of Rosemount Turf Farm, with a steely determination to be able to celebrate 100 years of Boyle family agriculture on the banks of Petrie Creek.
The old farm is now adding a special green touch to the Coast's growing population base and housing boom.
Another example of low-lying cane land being adopted for alternative farming can be found at Valdora, where Sunshine Coast Regional Council has invested in a 15 megawatt (MW) solar farm.
The council is striving to become Australia's most sustainable region and the solar farm, with 57,960 solar panels already in place, is part of its plan to achieve that vision. The project is expected to provide massive savings in electricity costs in the future and new opportunities to grow community facilities.
Pineapple farming has played second fiddle to sugar cane but it was no less prominent, with its seemingly endless displays for all to see on the rolling hills throughout the hinterland.
This inspired the development in 1971 of the Sunshine Plantation, a tourist attraction and working farm producing an array of tropical fruit, nuts and spices. The Big Pineapple reflected the importance of this industry with more than 200 working farms in the area and was later joined on site by the Big Macadamia Nut.
The Sunshine Coast soon became famous for the "big three" when the Big Cow trundled in on the action just up the road at Yandina.
Visitors came from far and wide to view the attractions and in 1983 the Coast was honoured with a visit by Prince Charles and Lady Diana, who enjoyed a tour around the Sunshine Plantation.
Today the iconic symbol is somewhat a shadow of its former self, reflecting the present state of an industry which now has less than 10 working farms remaining.
Where once pineapples ruled at places like Woombye and Palmwoods in particular, the slopes are progressively being replaced by houses. Stalwarts like Nambour's Don Bambling and Graham Coombs fight to keep the pineapple battle alive.
Buderim is the first home of ginger growing in this country, with successful trials leading to the development of the Buderim Ginger Factory. This facility, in the heart of Buderim, had become a very popular tourist attraction in the 1960s and 1970s but relocation became inevitable as the town and region blossomed.
In 1978 the factory was moved to Yandina, where it continues to be a popular tourist attraction.
The local ginger industry is growing in size and reputation and the pioneering Templeton family has played a dominant role over several generations. Allan Templeton's descendants have built his small ginger farm into Australia's largest, comprising several properties that produce around 2500 tonnes of the world's finest ginger.
Reflections on the agricultural scene would be incomplete without reference to the vital role played by the Nambour-based Maroochy Research Facility.
For more than 50 years, this facility has serviced Australia's subtropical fruit and nut industries and established itself as a global leader in applied research, development and extension. It now embraces all aspects of subtropical and tropical horticulture including response to pests and diseases threatening agricultural prosperity, animal biosecurity and welfare.
The past 50 years have produced significant changes on the local agricultural scene but it is clear that the traditional fighting spirit of those working on the land will continue unabated.
Researched and written by Graham Morton on behalf of the Nambour and District Historical Museum.
Hyundai unveils its only fully-electric model in Australia
Work on next stage of redevelopment due to start next April
Coast's $18m rescue chopper has been shifted by Lifeflight
LIFESTYLE lure was stronger than a high-flying accountancy career.
Sunshine Coast Jazz Club is set to present Diamonds of Swing
Caloundra Chorale and Theatre Co is gearing up for The Secret Garden
Box of Birds art exhibition is coming to Art Nuvo, Buderim
A NATIONAL exhibition of ceramic art has been launched on the Coast
BREAKING: New festival coming to the Sunshine Coast
ONE of Hollywood's most adorable couples is over.
New celebrity cooking show fails to fire for Seven.
The legendary creator isn't so sure about how Netflix works.
*WARNING this story contains spoilers*
Make way for Mackay's newest tech start up
Planning documents lodged on behalf of site owners
Education, student accommodation, bars and music all key to future
Five dates through August for community to have its say on rock wall
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boyle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palmwoods</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Regional Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lady Diana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Petrie Creek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds of Swing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Allan Templeton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big Pineapple</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast's $18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woombye</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graham Coombs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Charles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LifeFlight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moreton Central Sugar Mill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rosemount</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big Macadamia Nut</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Troy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ross Boyle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Chorale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maryborough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>District Historical Museum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Jazz Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Troy Apps</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ross</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy River</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art Nuvo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yandina</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour's Don Bambling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hyundai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour-based Maroochy Research Facility</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graham Morton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rosemount Turf Farm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theatre Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Valdora</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim Ginger Factory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Templeton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big Cow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Plantation</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
