<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651446549322997217</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/real-estate/queensland/north/family-enjoy-an-easycare-indoor-and-outdoor-lifestyle/news-story/2e2ebadc3840872d591906e48d398099</url>
  <title>Family enjoy an easy-care indoor and outdoor lifestyle - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
5 Teatree Close, Samford Valley.

Greg and Vicki Goad have lived at their Samford Valley home for the past 10 years and are ready to downsize.
They moved into the three-bedroom, two-bathroom home at on Australia Day, after Mrs Goad's 60th birthday.

5 Teatree Close, Samford Valley.

Mr Goad said they were getting close to 70 now and had a commitment with their grandchildren.
"We will probably stay around the Ferny Hills or Ferny Grove area," Mr Goad said.
He said he absolutely loved the Samford Valley and surrounds.
"Coming home is just beautiful," he said.
"We have the best neighbours, too."
The Dave Philips architecturally designed home embraces an easy-care indoor and outdoor lifestyle.

5 Teatree Close, Samford Valley.

The property is on 0.90ha, with parklike grounds and is in a convenient location within five minutes to Samford Village.
Mr Goad said he had a history in designing and constructing houses and added some special touches throughout the home.
"I think a family would enjoy the home," Mr Goad said.
"When we bought the block there wasn't a tree on it, we put in well over 1000 trees and shrubs.
"There's a billabong down the back, turtles and fish in the dam, and we have every bird you can think of around here."

5 Teatree Close, Samford Valley.

He said sitting by the dam or on the back patio enjoying a glass of red wine were the perfect places to chill out.
"On a Sunday afternoon, we sit by the dam, boil the billy and have a chat about the week just gone and week to come," Mr Goad said.

5 Teatree Close, Samford Valley.

The property, which is fully fenced, is on an elevated setting that takes full advantage of the leafy mountain views.
There is an automatic double garage with internal access and an extra twin carport.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Goad</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ferny Hills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samford Valley</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Goad's 60</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ferny Grove</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vicki Goad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Teatree Close</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samford Village</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dave Philips</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
