<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651446171365869744</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>17:42</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/08/03/33/sydney-tent-city-to-move-after-mayors-deal</url>
  <title>Sydney tent city to move after mayors deal</title>
  <content>
Sydney City Council trucks are expected to roll into Martin Place's tent city early on Tuesday morning to help residents relocate to a "safe space" and then onto more permanent housing.
However, the long term solution sorely sought by the Lord Mayor of Sydney and proclaimed mayor of the tent city seems no closer.
Ms Moore held a press conference on the steps of Town Hall on Monday evening where she said a deal had been done with Mr Priestley.
She said council would help pack the camp up from Tuesday morning and transfer the approximately 70 residents to a "communal safe space" until temporary and permanent accommodation was found.
The location, facilities, and design of the space were yet to be finalised as of Monday evening.
But Mr Priestley cast doubt on the deal, saying the proposal must include a place for people to sleep.
It wasn't until later that night that Mr Priestley formally agreed to the proposal but would not relinquish his push for people to be able to sleep at the space, AAP understands.

Related Articles

FACS has offered the residents of tent city temporary accommodation on numerous instances, and council expects the relocated individuals to accept those offers where suitable, a spokeswoman for Ms Moore told AAP.
However, if suitable accommodation was not found and the facility was able to house sleepers, people would not be forced to sleep on the street, she said.
(C)  AAP 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Moore</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Priestley</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin Place</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Town Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lord Mayor of Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney City Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FACS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
