<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651446248675282305</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>18:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/bitcoin-auction-for-instagram-model-2017-8</url>
  <title>A model who says she was kidnapped says auctions for women like her go for $300,000 worth of bitcoin</title>
  <content>
The anonymity of bitcoin, the largest cryptocurrency, has made it a darling of criminals and the so-called dark web.

The Italian mafia has used bitcoin , for instance, and the notorious WannaCry hackers .

And the reported kidnapping of a 20-year old mother might provide the latest example of bitcoin being used for nefarious purposes.

Chloe Ayling, a British glamor model, says she was tricked into going to Italy last month for a photo shoot set up by Polish gang members, as reported by . Those criminals, according to Ayling, kidnapped her when she arrived in Milan in order to auction her off . Ayling told police her captors ultimately let her go after they discovered from her Instagram profile she was a new mother, according to , Italy's second largest newspaper.

Ayling told Corriere Della Sera that her abductors could have sold her for at least $US300,000 in bitcoin. Here's what she said over the weekend:

I shouldn't have been caught, as their boss had seen some of my Instagram photos where it was clear that I'm a mum with a child, and that's against the organisation, which operates on the deep web dealing with various crimes, from drug dealing to hits; auctions for kidnapped girls apparently start at $US300,000 worth of bitcoin.

Authorities arrested one person, Lukasz Herba, a Polish man who lives in the UK, in Italy in connection to the kidnapping case, according to , a UK newspaper. Authorities in Britain, Italy, and Poland are investigating further.

Since transactions on bitcoin's blockchain network are decentralized and anonymous, the cryptocurrency provides an attractive option for criminals looking to conduct business outside of the watchful eye of government officials.

Get the latest Bitcoin price

NOW WATCH: Money & Markets videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italy</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lukasz Herba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WannaCry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corriere Della Sera</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Poland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chloe Ayling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Milan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ayling</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Polish</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$300,000</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
