<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651446759776397917</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/brand/before-the-bell/asx-poised-to-edge-higher-20170807-gxrbfr</url>
  <title>ASX poised to edge higher</title>
  <content>
by
Timothy Moore

Local shares are set to edge higher with the Dow on track to close at a record high for the ninth straight day. ASX futures were up 7 points or 0.1 per cent. The Australian dollar slipped 0.1 per cent.
On the top of the local agenda today is the July NAB Business Survey. 
"Not only have Business Conditions been pushing higher to June, but Business Confidence has also risen to above average levels, in contrast to the more cautious spirits of the consumer, the Westpac-Melbourne Institute measure of Consumer Sentiment (out Wednesday) is running somewhat below its long term average," said NAB economics director David de Garis.
Mr de Garis also said the NAB Business Survey has also been reporting a broader-based uplift in business activity, with trend increases in trading, profitability, and employment. "The latter has been pointing to continued rises in prospective employment, the July ABS Labour Force report not due until the week after."

On the local earnings front, there are reports due from IOOF Holdings, Janus Henderson Group, James Hardie Industries and TransUrban.

The spot price of iron ore rose 2.8 per cent to $US76.17 a tonne, according to Metal Bulletin, reflecting surging futures in China. 
Chinese rebar steel futures surged as much as 7 per cent to their highest level in more than four years on Monday as buyers increased their purchases on expectations of reduced supply in the winter ahead due to Beijing-imposed capacity curbs, Reuters reported.
Iron ore futures also jumped more than 7 per cent at one point.
China earlier this year ordered steel and aluminium producers in 28 cities to slash output during winter as it fights smog. Last week, the key steel producing area of Tangshan and other parts of Hebei province have said they will implement the order.

The government then called on steel producers to halve output in four northern provinces - Hebei, Shanxi, Shandong, Henan - as well as Beijing and Tianjin, during the peak winter heating months around late November to late February. The size of the output cuts will depend on how much each region has reduced its emissions.
Today's Agenda

Local data: NAB business survey July, business conditions, business confidence
Earnings: IFL, JHG, JHX, TCL

Overseas data: China July trade; Japan June current account; US NFIB small business optimism
Capital Economics on China's pending trade data: "A sharp drop in the new export orders component of China's official PMI suggests that export growth edged down from 17.3 per cent y/y in June to 15.0 per cent y/y in July. Meanwhile, cooling commodity price inflation is likely to have dragged on the growth of imports. As such, we think that China's trade surplus narrowed slightly in June."
Market Highlights

SPI futures up 7 points or 0.1% to 5713

AUD -0.1% to 79.11 US cents (Overnight range: 0.7899 - 0.7949)
On Wall St, Dow +0.1%, S&P 500 +0.1%, Nasdaq +0.5%
In New York, BHP +1.4%, Rio +2.3%
In Europe, Stoxx 50 -0.1%, FTSE +0.3%, CAC +0.1%, DAX -0.3%

Spot gold flat at $US125842 an ounce
Brent crude -0.3% to $US52.25 a barrel
Iron ore +2.8% to $US76.17 a tonne
Dalian iron ore +1.2% to 571 yuan
Comex copper +0.8%
10-year bond yield: US 2.25%, Germany 0.45%, Australia 2.62%
From Today's 
Financial Review
: The money-laundering scandal could be the tipping point that breaks down CBA's insular approach to technology development.

: Fund managers slam government for failing to protect mum-and-dad investors from franking credit losses.
: Having purged former Naked CEO Alex Malley from the CPA website, remaining board members will now follow him out the door.
United States

US stocks were slightly up in early afternoon trading on Monday, with the Dow on track to close at a record high for the ninth straight day, after squeezing out another all-time high just after the open.
The rise in the Dow also put the blue-chip index on track to close higher for the 10th straight day, its longest streak of consecutive gains since February.
"We have strong earnings that is helping the market," said Kim Forrest, senior equity research analyst at Fort Pitt Capital Group.
"I have seen a lot of companies exceeding their revenue growth and we also have better-than-expected global growth, which are the main drivers for equities."
Analysts, on average, expect S&P 500 earnings to have expanded 12 per cent in the second quarter and project earnings up 9.3 per cent for the September quarter, according to Thomson Reuters I/B/E/S.

Tesla said it would raise about $US1.5 billion through its first-ever high-yield junk bond offering, as the US luxury electric car maker seeks fresh sources of cash to ramp up production of its new Model 3 sedan.
Hedge fund investor Leon Cooperman, the chief executive of Omega Advisors, told cable television network CNBC that his firm's biggest position was a bullish bet on Google parent Alphabet.
Cooperman said that his position in Alphabet shares constituted between 4-4.5 per cent of his fund and cited the company's excess cash and strong earnings growth as reasons for its being "not expensive". He also said First Data Corp was one of his fund's second-largest holdings.
Europe

European stocks held steady after Friday's biggest rally in three weeks spurred by strong US jobs data.
The Stoxx Europe 600 Index slid 0.1 per cent at the close.
ArcelorMittal led a gauge of mining stocks to the best gains among industry groups as steel and iron-ore prices surged. The measure is overtaking the broader benchmark in 2017 after lagging it in the first half. Media stocks slid 0.6 per cent while drug makers fell for the fourth time in five days.
Among shares active on corporate news, Paddy Power Betfair slipped 4.7 per cent after saying chief executive officer Breon Corcoran will step down after 16 years with the betting company.

PostNL fell 5.1 per cent after predicting that full-year operating income will be near the lower end of a previously forecast range.
Data on Monday showed German industrial production unexpectedly slipped in June. That follows evidence last week that momentum at the start of the third quarter lagged behind that of France, Italy and Spain for the first time in 12 years.
Germany's DAX Index slid 0.3 per cent on Monday. The measure has turned into one of the biggest laggards among global peers since a June record.
The Stoxx 600 is down about 3.6 per cent from a peak in May, amid bets that the strengthening euro will trim profit growth for the region's exporters.
Asia

Hong Kong stocks posted modest gains on Monday, buoyed by strength in technology firms as well as Chinese resource and financial shares.
The Hang Seng index ended up 0.5 per cent at 27,690.36 points, while the China Enterprises Index gained 0.5 per cent to 11,054.41.
Information technology firms were the top performers, with the sector index advancing 2.9 per cent.

Social media and gaming giant Tencent Holdings rose 3 per cent to close at a record high of $HK320.60.
China stocks ended higher across the board on Monday, shaking off early losses, as investors bet upcoming data will continue to show strong economic growth.
The blue-chip CSI300 index rose 0.5 per cent to 3726.88 points, while the Shanghai Composite Index gained 0.5 per cent to 3279.46.
Analysts had attributed early losses to investors taking a wait-and-see approach to Chinese data scheduled to start rolling out this week. China will post trade data on Tuesday and inflation on Wednesday. Bank lending numbers could come later this week while industrial output, retail sales and investment readings will be released next Monday.
Currencies

: A rising currency works against the broad economy, and the market.
The Federal Reserve can leave interest rates where they are for now because inflation is not likely to rise much even if the US job market continues to improve, St. Louis Fed president James Bullard said on Monday.
"The current level of the policy rate is likely to remain appropriate over the near term," Bullard told the America's Cotton Marketing Cooperatives 2017 Conference in Nashville, Tennessee.

Bullard said recent readings of low inflation are "concerning" because they may not be temporary but indicative of persistent factors such as better technology that is driving down the price of many goods and services. Bullard does not vote on monetary policy this year at the Fed, though he participates in the central bank's regular policy discussions in Washington.
Capital Economics on US government bond yields: "We forecast that the 10-year US Treasury yield will rise from around 2.25 per cent now to 3.25 per cent next year, as inflation eventually picks up and the Fed tightens the screws. US CPI inflation fell steadily during most of the first half of 2017, from a peak of 2.7 per cent in February to 1.6 per cent in June. This was accompanied by a drop of 40bp or so in 10-year Treasury inflation compensation, from 2.1 per cent to 1.7 per cent, between mid-February and mid-June."
The forecasting firm also said it expects US CPI inflation "to rebound next spring, clearing the way for the Fed to tighten monetary policy substantially. Accordingly, we think that the Treasury market will come under substantial pressure in 2018, if not earlier. Indeed, our end-2017 forecast for the 10-year Treasury yield is 2.75 per cent". 
Mexico's peso slipped to a nearly one-month low against the US dollar as the impending start of talks to renegotiate the North American Free Trade Agreement gave the market a renewed bout of jitters. The peso sank to a record low in January on fears that President Donald Trump would rip up NAFTA, but it has rallied as his administration has taken a more conciliatory tone and moved to renegotiate the 23-year-old accord.
Commodities

A surge in the billet market over the weekend gave iron ore prices a big boost on Monday, Metal Bulletin reported.
Hebei's provincial government announced late last Friday that several cities, including Shijiazhuang, Tangshan and Handan, will see steel production capped at 50 per cent of capacity during the heating season from November to March. The announcement sparked big gains in the ferrous markets - the price of billet increased by 120 yuan ($US17.80) per tonne over the weekend, and rose a further 30 yuan ($US4.50) per tonne on Monday. Prices for finished steel, in turn, rose on Monday.
Oil prices fell as much as 2 per cent on selling triggered by a rebound in production from Libya's largest oil field, along with worries about higher output from OPEC and the United States.

Output at Libya's Sharara field was returning to normal after a brief disruption by armed protesters in the coastal city of Zawiya, the National Oil Corporation (NOC) said. The field has boosted Libya's oil production, which climbed to more than 1 million bpd in late June.
Australian Sharemarket

The benchmark S&P/ASX 200 Index and the broader All Ordinaries Index each lifted 0.9 per cent to 5773.6 points and 5824.5 points, respectively. ​
Street Talk

with Reuters, Bloomberg, AAP
Comments? Questions? Let us know what you think of Before the Bell. You can reach Timothy Moore at  timothy.moore@fairfaxmedia.com.au

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>US1.5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China Enterprises Index</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zawiya</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CNBC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HK320.60</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ArcelorMittal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CAC +0.1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CSI300</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shanxi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mexico</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Naked CEO Alex Malley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tesla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bloomberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAB</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NOC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Bullard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North American Free Trade Agreement</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hang Seng</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thomson Reuters I/B/E/S</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAB Business Survey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Reserve</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US52.25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treasury</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nashville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Libya</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kim Forrest</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Metal Bulletin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Janus Henderson Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DATA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BHP +1.4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JHG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JHX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DAX -0.3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July NAB Business Survey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US CPI</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Sharemarket</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dalian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TCL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stoxx 50 -0.1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hong Kong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germany's DAX Index</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio +2.3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Transurban</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dow +0.1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westpac/Melbourne Institute</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tianjin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Model 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July ABS Labour Force</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Comex</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hebei</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Hardie Industries</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia 2.62</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAFTA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Treasuries</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PMI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wall St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P 500</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SPI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUD -0.1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leon Cooperman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tangshan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BEIJING</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>First Data Corp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US NFIB</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Henan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stoxx Europe 600 Index</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cooperman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Libya's Sharara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Street Talk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paddy Power Betfair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>All Ordinaries Index</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P/ASX 200 Index</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Timothy Moore</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Oil Corporation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P 500 (  ): +0.1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nasdaq +0.5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Louis Fed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Handan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germany 0.45</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tennessee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tencent Holdings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beijing-imposed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fort Pitt Capital Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$2.25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Omega Advisors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Consumer Sentiment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US125842</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dow</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shanghai Composite Index</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bullard</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Breon Corcoran</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reuters</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SHIJIAZHUANG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US4.50</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fed</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stoxx 600</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shandong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Business Confidence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Google</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IOOF Holdings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US76.17</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FTSE +0.3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>America's Cotton Marketing Cooperatives 2017 Conference</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Business Conditions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US17.80</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CPA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OPEC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PostNL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
