<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651445780523838333</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>16:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/business-insider-is-hiring-paid-news-intern-2017-8</url>
  <title>APPLY NOW: Business Insider is hiring a paid breaking news intern</title>
  <content>
Business Insider is hiring an intern to work with our news team this fall.
We're looking for applicants who are news-obsessed, quick to learn, cool under pressure, careful, and appreciative of our approach to journalism.
This is an important internship that will involve working closely with top editors and journalists across our team.
Responsibilities will include spotting and covering important breaking news stories as they unfold. There will be a mixture of original writing and reporting, as well as setting up wires and syndicated posts.

As for qualifications, a journalism background and experience writing for a news site always helps, as do copy-editing skills and light HTML and Photoshop experience. Knowledge of social media and previous writing experience are both useful, too.

with your resume, a cover letter, and links to several clips.

Please note that this internship requires that you work in our Manhattan office. Interns are encouraged to work full-time (40 hours a week) if their schedule allows, and the internship can run for up to six months.

NOW WATCH: Ideas videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insiders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HTML</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manhattan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Business Insider</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photoshop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
