<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651446768366332752</docid>
  <date>07/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/world/turkeys-tayyip-erdogan-claims-germany-abetting-terrorists-20170807-gxrbmi.html</url>
  <title>Turkey's Tayyip Erdogan claims Germany abetting terrorists</title>
  <content>
Ankara: Turkish President Tayyip Erdogan accused Germany on Monday of assisting terrorists by not responding to thousands of files sent to Berlin or handing over suspects wanted by Turkish authorities.
"Germany is abetting terrorists," Erdogan told a conference in the Black Sea province of Rize, in comments likely to further escalate tensions between the two countries.

Up Next

North Korea hits out at new UN sanctions

01:30

More World News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Hundreds on trial over failed Turkey coup

Nearly 500 suspects are on trial for bombing government buildings and attempting to kill President Recip Tayyip Erdogan in 2016.

"We gave (German Chancellor Angela) Merkel 4500 dossiers, but have not received an answer on a single one of them," he told members of his ruling AK Party.
"When there is a terrorist, they can tell us to give that person back. You won't send the ones you have to us, but can ask us for yours. So you have a judiciary, but we don't in Turkey?" he said.

In Berlin, a German government source rejected Erdogan's latest remarks.
"Everything has really been said about this," said the source. "Repeating the same accusations over and over again does not make them any more true."

Already tense relations deteriorated further last month after Turkey arrested 10 rights activists, including a German, as part of a wider security crackdown.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

A Turkish prosecutor has accused them of links to the network of Muslim cleric Fethullah Gulen, whom Ankara blames for a failed coup in July 2016. The US-based Gulen denies any involvement.Photo: AP
Turkey accuses Germany of sheltering Kurdish and far-leftist militants as well as military officers and other people linked to the abortive coup. Berlin denies the accusations.
Tensions between Berlin and Ankara were already running high after the arrest of a Turkish-German journalist and Turkey's refusal to allow German lawmakers to visit troops at a Turkish air base. Photo: AP
Reuters
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurdish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turkey</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US-based Gulen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turkish-German</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ankara</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Black Sea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Recip Tayyip Erdogan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>German Chancellor Angela</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AK Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Erdogan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turkish</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germany</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muslim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berlin</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RiZe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turkish President Tayyip Erdogan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turkey's Tayyip Erdogan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reuters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fethullah Gulen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Merkel 4500</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
